<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haxe Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-19T01:34:05Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Haxe in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Musk-h/Forever-Engine-Android-Port</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T01:34:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-19:/Musk-h/Forever-Engine-Android-Port</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Musk-h/Forever-Engine-Android-Port" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoshubs/FunkinForever&#34;&gt;Forever Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;An open-source, quality of life and performance driven &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newgrounds.com/portal/view/770371&#34;&gt;Friday Night Funkin&#39;&lt;/a&gt; mod engine!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.discordapp.net/attachments/916918345255751690/930068118938730526/legacy.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Friday Night Funkin&#39; Forever Engine is an engine solely based on source code at the moment. Forever Engine is currently in legacy state as it is being rewritten. The legacy version of Forever Engine lacks accessibility and cohesion, something we are currently working to fix with the more newer and updated rewrite. Thank you for your patience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOREVER ENGINE IS ONLY MEANT TO BE USED ON DESKTOP! I AM NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR CRASHES/PROBLEMS WITH HTML5, NOR AM I RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING HTML5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please redirect all future and current enhancements to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoshubs/FNF-Forever-Engine&#34;&gt;new repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forever Engine FEATURES! - Noteskins, Custom UIs, Options Menu with FPS Capping and adjustments A lot of modularity and freedom with options (hopefully in the future EVERYTHING will be toggleable) A restructure and partial remake of the base game&#39;s source code Source Code folder abstraction More streamlined code (only having to set things in one place) AND MORE!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to make an FNF engine that was easier to work with than any other, mostly because I thought about how messy most other engines including the base game were. That doesn&#39;t mean Forever Engine is better than the base game however, Forever is only a tribute to Friday Night Funkin&#39; and its modding community, a small project of mine that I hope people can find enjoyment and use out of!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ADDITIONS IN 0.3&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rewritten Hold notes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;BPM Changes (credit to NebulaZorua)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rewritten Inputs (Thanks ShadowMario for letting me borrow some of your scripts, it was more of an afterthought tbh)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Better camera movement (heavily based on Vs. Sonic.exe)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Just general stability and changes to make sure Legacy is at the very least not broken before moving on to 1.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;CREDITS:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Yoshubs&#34;&gt;Yoshubs&lt;/a&gt; - made the engine. she just so happens to be very fucking stupid for accidentally pushing the martian mixtape source code into forever engine&#39;s base github page&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PixlJacket&#34;&gt;Pixloen&lt;/a&gt; - made a lot of the custom assets that forever engine uses, he also gave me a lot of general advice on how to improve the engine as well as his input on both how to improve upon the base game and how the input system felt and such. ALSO PROGRAMMED SIMPLY JUDGEMENTS AND BACKGROUND DARKEN, He basically co-owns the engine lmao&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gedehari&#34;&gt;Gedehari&lt;/a&gt; - BANGER ASS PROGRAMMER, made the freeplay loading thread to avoid lag issues in freeplay, waveform render code (which will be used soon), freaking EXTERNAL SHADER SUPPORT for modcharts when they&#39;re a thing and so many other things like the crashlogger. I urge you to check out his project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gedehari/IzzyEngine&#34;&gt;Izzy Engine&lt;/a&gt;, which he let me borrow a lot of aspects from which I still owe him for lmao. AWESOME dude I can&#39;t stress this enough&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ImCodist&#34;&gt;ImCodist&lt;/a&gt; - helped with a couple of pull requests and issue fixes, ALSO MADE THE WHOLE ASS FREAKING DIALOGUE SYSTEM, but, I&#39;m not gonna give him any credit at all, because he stole my obsidian soul in minecraft and I will never forgive him for that!!!!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SomeKitten&#34;&gt;Scarlett&lt;/a&gt; - Overall cool friend of mine who knows a lot about programming and math that has helped me out countless times, still going here helping me with pushes, commits, etc. She wrote the finalised math formula for the note quants and fixed the song name issue.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oneilr.newgrounds.com/&#34;&gt;Oneilr&lt;/a&gt; - Cool Guy Oneilr, made some of the custom assets, mostly the animated ones like the custom note splashes to avoid the week 7 embargo as well as some other things like the checkmarks in the options menu.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hellosammu&#34;&gt;HelloSammu&lt;/a&gt; - weird catgirl programmer, they scare me CREDITED MAINTENANCE AND SOME MISC FIXES, also scaleable text for dialogue functions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ninjamuffin99.newgrounds.com/&#34;&gt;ninjamuffin99&lt;/a&gt; - HE MADE THE BASE GAME SO LIKE WITHOUT HIM THIS WOULD NOT BE POSSIBLE GO CHECK HIM OUT RIGHT NOW&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;rest of the rise n&#39; skate team - that mod is the reason im even making an engine right now so like I kind of owe you guys this whole engine and more for that honestly and I will actually do more so stay tuned&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SHOUTOUTS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HThagomizer&#34;&gt;HThagomizer&lt;/a&gt; - not MURDERING ME for accidentally pushing the martian mixtape source code&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_Tsuraran&#34;&gt;Tsuraran&lt;/a&gt; - DOPE ASS CUSTOM MENU MUSIC INCOMING, also made vs skipper with clockwerk which is fucking hilarious ALSO YEAH I&#39;LL BUMP AS WELL AFTER ITS IN THE ENGINE (YES IM WORKING ON IT TOO LMAO)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ClockwerkSmurf&#34;&gt;Clockwerk&lt;/a&gt; - also made vs skipper, oh my god what were you guys thinking&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to Compile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically, all of the files you need are in the engine itself through the setup.bat (Huge thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamebanana.com/tuts/13798&#34;&gt;FNF Source Code Guide&lt;/a&gt; for the download to the file) except for Visual Studio Code, or whatever program you choose to use to program in the engine. If you&#39;ve already worked with fnf, this should work perfectly with you and if it doesn&#39;t then you might have the wrong target settings, or Lime is probably broken, that&#39;s usually what happens with these things, it&#39;s happened to me a ton of times lmao. I&#39;m not a very good programmer. If you want some external sources that will better walk you through how to compile the game, look no further than the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ninjamuffin99/Funkin&#34;&gt;base game github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamebanana.com/tuts/13798&#34;&gt;FNF Source Code Guide&lt;/a&gt;, I really hope they help you out!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Thank you for checking out my engine! Got any questions? DM me at Shubs#0404 on Discord!&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LilDrippyMyFnf/FNF-EchoEngine</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T01:34:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-19:/LilDrippyMyFnf/FNF-EchoEngine</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LilDrippyMyFnf/FNF-EchoEngine" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;from on scratch to github&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Friday Night Funkin&#39; - Echo Engine&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Echo engine first appeared on scratch,it wasn&#39;t published,and the engine was trying to beat meek engine. Sadly the engine stopped on verison 0.6.0,now,it will be REMASTED in a new,better,cleaner way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installion&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;VS CODE&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;maybe a compiler&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 1&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix dad left pose&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bf freestyle spritesheet ( dadbattle )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;dad icon fixed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 2&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Haunty little glow at the end of spookez&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bf freestyle spritesheett again ( some part in south )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When you miss a note,blood will spill on the screen ( monster )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 3&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[ FREESTYLE ] Pico chilled spritesheet ( philly )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pico and Bf serious spritesheet ( blammed )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 4&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Glow in each song&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;dying henchmen ( MILF )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 5&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The snow will become gorey after eggnog&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;bats will appear at the end of coca&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;bones,skin,and blood will fill the snow ( Winter Horrorland )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 6&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dialouge rework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;glowing in spirit ( thorns )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 7&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Steam will pollut the air ( stress )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tankman will laugh at you if you get low accuracy ( 20 or lower )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Creators&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MyFnf - Programmer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Special Thanks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ShadowMario ( some psych engine stuff )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LilDrippyMyFnf/Just-a-simple-game</title>
    <updated>2022-10-19T01:34:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-19:/LilDrippyMyFnf/Just-a-simple-game</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LilDrippyMyFnf/Just-a-simple-game" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;game jam 1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3&gt;ABOUT&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a 13+ game due to blood,gore,voilance,inapproprite language,and smoking&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once apon a time,you lived in a village,you were still young,but that didn&#39;t stop you! You were playing with your friends,until some magical poof destroyed you and your village. all of your friends,and family died,you weren&#39;t even old enough to live 0n your own! 20 years later,you turned 32 at your cousin&#39;s house,everyone was singing,and dancing. But you just promised your self: &#34;i will become a badass soon&#34; and yes,it happened. You smoked,drinked,cussed,even killed someone! Over time,you met darnell,brit,and a wizard&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Feastures&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; dialouge&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; character sprites&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; cutsenes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;We need helpers!&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; pixel artist ( me )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; music&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; coding&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Coding&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;if you wanna be the coder,you must get &lt;a href=&#34;https://haxeflixel.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;haxeflixel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as the engine&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MyFnf - Team leader&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;BushTrain460615 - helper&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Memehoovy - helper&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Release&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;early spring of 2023&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>