<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haxe Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-13T01:37:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Haxe in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>UmbratheUmbreon/PublicDenpaEngine</title>
    <updated>2023-01-13T01:37:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-13:/UmbratheUmbreon/PublicDenpaEngine</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/UmbratheUmbreon/PublicDenpaEngine" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Public Denpa Engine Repo. Will be updated occasionally, but only when an actual pre-release/release happens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PublicDenpaEngine&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Public Denpa Engine Repo. Will be updated occasionally, but only when an actual pre-release/release happens.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[BlueVapor1234] Guy who did most of the programming&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toadette8394] Person who did a lot of helping with programming&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[ThriftySoles] Guy who did OVERDOSE and various misc. arts and music for the engine&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Bethany Clone] Person who helped program some stuff&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Box] Person who helps optimize the engine&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Elecytophyll II] Person who provides ideas and some programming&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Jorge] Person who got the crossfade code and helped get it working&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Megaverse] Person who made the title sceen music&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits to Psych&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Im not writing all of this, its in the engine)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature List (Here We Go)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Customizable Healthbar Position] Enough Said&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Customizable Time Bar Colour] Determined by RGB in settings!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Auto Swapping Time Bar Colour] You can turn it on OR off! (Its based on da opponent&#39;s healthabar colour)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable OG Healthbar] Did you like not having healthbar colours? Bam, there you go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Dynamic Icons] Have you got a winning icon sheet? Can&#39;t use it in that other engine you were using? Well its your lucky day! Our engine allows for the use of 150x150, 300x150, and 450x150 icon sheets, all simultaneously!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Lots of Icon Animations to Choose From] Come get em! We got Gapple&#39;s icon swing, the broken old one, angle snap, we even got boring bopping!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[&#34;Flinch&#34;ing Icons] When the player misses, their icon temporarily turns into the dying icon for that character!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Song Credits] Yeah so this is how the meeting went: &#34;Hey we need to credit the composers&#34; &#34;oh ok, on it&#34; &lt;em&gt;creates an elastic tween with a sprite on a timer&lt;/em&gt; &#34;ok done&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[A Second Opponent] Only 3.99! Comes with an extra strum and icon, as well as camera functions!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Multiple Healthbar Colours] You can select between 1, 2, or 3 different colour combinations! Skid and Pump type deal? 2 healthbar colorus got your back.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable Flixel Trail per Character] Why was this hard coded smh&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Perfect and WTF Ratings] Ever wanted satisfaction for getting a super accurate hit on a note? Bam, PERFECT. oh and WTF exists if youre so bad that a shit doesnt suffice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[A Display for Your Ratings] Ever wanted to see your total of each rating? Thats an option with this!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggles for Ghost Tapping and Botplay Per Song] Do you get annoyed at people spamming to beat your song? Force off ghost tapping natively! Easy solution!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[A Max Combo of 999999] Pretty self explanatory, isn&#39;t it?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Max FPS of 999, and Minimum of 24] IDK who would need more than 360 FPS but go off with the increased range&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[CrossFade] Yes, THAT CrossFade. From Sarvente Engine. It can be toggled per section, or using a specific note. Oh and you can change its behaviour and the sprite limit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[&#34;Wavy&#34; Background Shader] DNB mods moment&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Modchart Dropdown in Chart Editor] Who needs lua scripts when you have a dropdown?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Multikey Support] It goes up to 11k, and as little as 1k. It can even be changed mid song!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Random Mode] Those charts too boring for you? I present infinitely replayable charts that are completely random! Enjoy the jacks my friend!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Ghost Mode] Gotta be on beat to play with this mode! You only get a glimpse of the notes before they turn invisble!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[A Secondary Vocal Track] Do you HATE when bf misses and the opponent stops singing too? No longer a problem! Secondary Vocals are here to help!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Camera Panning on Note Press] You know what im talking about, do I really need to say much more?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable Score Displays] Do you REALLY like one specific engine&#39;s score HUD? Well you&#39;re in luck, You can toggle between popular ones at your mercy!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[A Cool Splash Screen] It&#39;s like SEGA!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Patch Notes Menu] Tell your players what you changed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[BOPPIN Menus] The menus bop to the beat! (Theres even an easter egg for a specific song that gets shaky... hint hint)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Improved Freeplay Menu] What do i write here lmao&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Sound Test Menu (Requires Musik Pak TM)] Play various songs from basically anywhere in a snazzy menu! You can even add your own albums!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Improved Chart Editor] It&#39;s now sorted much better, so finding what you want shouldnt be nearly as hard.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Improved Character Editor] It&#39;s got music now! And it&#39;s got a function to change the stage for more accurate positioning!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Extra Character Options] From Shaking the screen to draining your health to floating, we got it all!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Extra Chart Options] Toggle a bunch of interesting gimmicks, tint the stage to a time of day, all that good stuff.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[New Events] Do that cool darken the stage thing, change the angle or zoom of the cameras, go nuts!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Better Organized Options] These were a pain god help me&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Events Are Ordered From A-Z] Find your events much easier wtih an actually competent order of events!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable Fullscreen] Yeah&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Rating Generosity] Choose how strict you want the scoring system to be!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[No More STUPID Half Transparent Arrows From the Opponent on Middle Scroll] Oops i wrote the description into the title&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable Antimash Feature] IDK why you would use this but its there&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable &#34;Unfeatures&#34;] Did you like the heavily bugged old fnf versions? Well you can toggle some of those behaviors back on!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Combo and Rating Skins] Included: FNF, Denpa, Kade&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Toggleable Combo Popup] Some people like this and some don&#39;t so its toggleable now&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Quartiz] Quartiz&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Insanity Difficulty] Designed for 8k players, this difficulty is sure to give you trouble... if it was charted&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Improved Icons] This one only really applies to the icons without losing states, like the pixel ones and GF.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Pause Menu Options] Ever wanted to tweak your settings without having to back out of the song? Well now with this [Exact Duplicate of the Options Menu] you can change your options on the fly! (Note: Song will be automatically reloaded when you do this!!!)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Cutscene Options] Cutscenes are cool and all but what if you don&#39;t want to see them? Well Denpa Man has got you covered with options to specify when you want those cool cutscenes!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Week 7] Week 7 is dope and having it is better than not!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Menu Mouse Controls] Sometimes scrolling through menus can be an absolute pain, but now with toggleable mouse controls... THAT PROBLEM IS ALL BUT GONE!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Hscript Support] Hard coding can be annoying with long compile times on some devices, and a lot of crashes when you do something wrong... But with Hscript, 1 of those problems are fixed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Player 4] Ever wanted to have 2 opponents? With seperate strum lines? And completely seperate properties? And an extra icon for them? And a loving spouse? Well with Player 4, All but one of those problems can be solved easily and gracefully!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Accuracy Modes] Maybe to you, the accuracy in base FNF doesn&#39;t cut it. Maybe you want some uber accurate accuracy system. Fortunately for you, hyperspecific person out there, Denpa Engine comes packaged with 2 accuracy modes to choose from, Simple and Complex! Complex is so accurate, it rivals other- (Our legal team has advised us to stop there).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Streamlined Charting] Ever had trouble charting in FNF? Not anymore my friend! We&#39;ve got you covered with easy access keybinds and a streamlined UI to help YOU chart your songs!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-[Freeplay Sections] Is there anything much to explain here?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And of course, all of Psych&#39;s 0.5.2h features (not 0.6+, that is GARBO)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;MAKE SURE YOUR HAXE IS 4.2.5 OR HIGHER!!!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run QUICK SETUP.bat&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install Visual Studio Community 2019&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install &#34;MSVC v142 - VS 2019 C++ x64/x86 build tools&#34; and &#34;Windows SDK (10.0.17763.0)&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run the compile command (lime build windows) or run one of the build batch files&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pray that it works&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>