<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-26T01:31:17Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T01:31:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-26:/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A repository detailing data recovery of OnStream tapes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/pictures/onstream-logo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;OnStream Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;The OnStream Data Recovery Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OnStream tapes saw use primarily as a backup storage medium during the early 2000s mostly in Europe due to their affordability.&lt;br&gt; Unfortunately, OnStream ceased operations due to bankruptcy in 2003 and never had the longevity that other tapes had.&lt;br&gt; Not only are the drives rare today, but they are also prone to failure and have numerous software and compatibility difficulties which make it annoying to dump the contents of the tape.&lt;br&gt; So when I was put in a position of needing to recover data from OnStream tapes, it took a lot of effort to recover data.&lt;br&gt; I&#39;ve put together this guide so that hopefully someone else doesn&#39;t also need to spend months on this.&lt;br&gt; I am available to help with OnStream data recovery for the current time, my contact info is on my GitHub profile page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dumping Guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I would strongly recommend reading through this guide without skimming it (I have ADHD so I&#39;m serious when I say this), because if you make the wrong choice, you might make your work MUCH harder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guide has been broken into several sections:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/INTRO.MD&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/DRIVES.MD&#34;&gt;What drive do you need?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/SOFTWARE.MD&#34;&gt;Determining the original software.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Raw Dump Only: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/RAW_DUMP.MD&#34;&gt;Understanding how the data is stored on the tape for raw dumps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Raw Dump Only: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/SPLICES.MD&#34;&gt;Performing a raw dump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/info/TROUBLESHOOTING.MD&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the guide can only go so far. I&#39;ve done my best to document everything, but the guide is just a starting point.&lt;br&gt; I&#39;ve done my best to include as many tools, documentation, and information as possible throughout this repository, and hopefully the guide can give proper context.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;General FAQ/Notes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;How does this jumper block thing work? Don&#39;t worry too much about it. Most of the SCSI PCI cards out there have an automatic termination setting enabled by default in the BIOS settings, and if you&#39;re not connecting any other SCSI devices, then it doesn&#39;t matter what ID is set.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It is possible to use a 68pin to 50pin SCSI converter for the SCSI-2 based devices, but only if the converter properly terminates the 8-bit portion of the bus. Any competent adapter should do this automatically.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It is a good idea to manually spin the tape wheel a little bit before putting a tape in a drive. Due to the age of these tapes, they seem prone to tearing if some manual spinning is not done first.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Helpful Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Kneesnap/onstream-data-recovery/main/archives/&#34;&gt;Archived Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20030130111054/http://www.onstreamdata.com/&#34;&gt;OnStream Website Archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osst.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;&#39;osst&#39; Linux Driver Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Kneesnap/osst&#34;&gt;&#39;osst&#39; Driver Source Code&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/osst/&#34;&gt;Original Repository&lt;/a&gt; [^1])&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaru-dps/Aaru&#34;&gt;Aaru Data Preservation Suite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[^1]: The files shown on the website are not actually the full repository, instead the CVS repo must be directly connected to. For this reason, the Github mirror is preferred.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NightmareXIV/UnbanPluginsCN</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T01:31:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-26:/NightmareXIV/UnbanPluginsCN</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/NightmareXIV/UnbanPluginsCN" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;解除CN客户端Ban限制插件&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;本插件用于解除中国客户端上，取消对已经被禁止的插件使用。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;如何使用&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;在启动游戏或者启动卫月之前运行UnbanPluginsCN.exe。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;启动成功后你所有的插件都能正常加载了。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;自动启动程序&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UnbanPluginsCN现在支持作为服务运行，这意味着您不用每次都手动启动它。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;如何将其设置成服务：&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;将程序解压缩到任何文件夹中（例如：&lt;code&gt;C:\UnbanPluginsCN\&lt;/code&gt;，&lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\UnbanPlugins CN\&lt;/code&gt;）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;以管理员身份运行“install_service.cmd”（右键单击）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;管理员运行成功后提示：Press any key if you&#39;re running it as administrator.（按下任意键）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;至此安装成功此服务。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;请不要同时将其作为服务和程序运行，这会导致程序和服务冲突。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;UnbanPluginsCN&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A program that is designed to unrestrict banned plugins usage on Chinese Dalamud client.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run UnbanPluginsCN.exe before starting the game&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All your plugins should be loadable now&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Autostart&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UnbanPluginsCN now supports running as a service, meaning that you do not need to worry about starting it manually anymore.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How to setup it as a service:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unpack the archive into any folder (for example: &lt;code&gt;C:\UnbanPluginsCN\&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\UnbanPluginsCN\&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;install_service.cmd&lt;/code&gt; as administrator (right click on it)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It should be installed and running!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do not run it as a service and as a program at the same time - it will cause issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/devhome</title>
    <updated>2023-05-26T01:31:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-26:/microsoft/devhome</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/devhome" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Windows Dev Home Application&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/devhome/raw/main/src/Assets/Preview/StoreDisplay-150.png&#34; alt=&#34;dev-home-readme-header&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to the Dev Home repo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the source code for:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/devhome&#34;&gt;Dev Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dev Home core widgets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Related repositories include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/devhomegithubextension&#34;&gt;Dev Home GitHub Extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing and running Dev Home&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Dev Home requires Windows 11 21H2 (build 22000) or later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Microsoft Store [Recommended]&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/devhome&#34;&gt;Dev Home from the Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;. This allows you to always be on the latest version when we release new builds with automatic upgrades.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is our preferred method.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other install methods&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Via GitHub&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For users who are unable to install Dev Home from the Microsoft Store, released builds can be manually downloaded from this repository&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/devhome/releases&#34;&gt;Releases page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Via Windows Package Manager CLI (aka winget)&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/winget-cli&#34;&gt;winget&lt;/a&gt; users can download and install the latest Dev Home release by installing the &lt;code&gt;Microsoft.DevHome&lt;/code&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;winget install --id Microsoft.DevHome -e&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dev Home roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan for Dev Home will be posted shortly and will be updated as the project proceeds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dev Home overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please take a few minutes to review the overview below before diving into the code:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Dev Home dashboard displays Windows widgets. These widgets are built using the Windows widget platform, which relies on Adaptive Cards.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Machine configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The machine configuration tool utilizes the Dev Home GitHub Extension, but isn&#39;t required to clone and install apps. The app installation tool is powered by winget.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Popular apps&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The machine configuration tool provides a list of popular apps when selecting applications to install. This is currently a hard-coded list of applications that have been popular with developers on Windows. Popularity was determined by high levels of installation and usage. As this is a moment in time, we are not accepting submissions for this list. We&#39;re looking to improve the experience with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/devhome/issues/375&#34;&gt;Suggested Apps&lt;/a&gt; so the list can be optimized for developers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documentation for Dev Home can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/devhomedocs&#34;&gt;https://aka.ms/devhomedocs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to work alongside you, our amazing community, to build and enhance Dev Home!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BEFORE you start work on a feature/fix,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; please read &amp;amp; follow our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/devhome/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributor&#39;s Guide&lt;/a&gt; to help avoid any wasted or duplicate effort.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Communicating with the team&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to communicate with the team is via GitHub issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please file new issues, feature requests, and suggestions but &lt;strong&gt;DO search for similar open/closed preexisting issues before creating a new issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to ask a question that you feel doesn&#39;t warrant an issue (yet), please reach out to us via Twitter:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kayla Cinnamon, Product Manager: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cinnamon_msft&#34;&gt;@cinnamon_msft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clint Rutkas, Senior Product Manager: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/crutkas&#34;&gt;@crutkas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ujjwal Chadha, Developer: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ujjwalscript&#34;&gt;@ujjwalscript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Developer guidance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must be running Windows 11 21H2 (build &amp;gt;= 10.0.22000.0) to run Dev Home&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/uwp/get-started/enable-your-device-for-development&#34;&gt;enable Developer Mode in the Windows Settings app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building the code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure your system, please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/devhome/main/.configurations/configuration.dsc.yaml&#34;&gt;configuration file&lt;/a&gt;. This can be applied by either: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dev Home&#39;s machine configuration tool&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;WinGet configuration. If you have the experimental feature enabled, run &lt;code&gt;winget configure .configurations/configuration.dsc.yaml&lt;/code&gt; from the project root so relative paths resolve correctly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Running &amp;amp; debugging&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Visual Studio, you should be able to build and debug Dev Home by hitting &lt;kbd&gt;F5&lt;/kbd&gt;. Make sure to select either the &#34;x64&#34; or the &#34;x86&#34; platform and set DevHome as the selected startup project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>