<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-07-08T01:29:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>cschneegans/unattend-generator</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T01:29:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-08:/cschneegans/unattend-generator</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cschneegans/unattend-generator" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;.NET Core library to create highly customized autounattend.xml files&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;UnattendGenerator&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library forms the basis for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://schneegans.de/windows/unattend-generator/&#34;&gt;online autounattend.xml generator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maassoft/ColorControl</title>
    <updated>2025-07-08T01:29:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-08:/Maassoft/ColorControl</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Maassoft/ColorControl" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Easily change NVIDIA display settings and/or control LG TV&#39;s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ColorControl&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Easily change NVIDIA and AMD display settings, control LG and Samsung tv&#39;s, Game launcher and color profile management&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just extract the .zip file in a folder of your preference. Run ColorControl.exe to start the application. Requires .NET 9 with the following runtimes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.NET Desktop Runtime 9&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.NET ASP.NET Core Runtime 9&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ColorControl stores its settings in the following folder:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;C:\Users\username\AppData\Roaming\Maassoft\ColorControl&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you choose to install the Windows Service then some settings will also be placed here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;C:\Windows\System32\config\systemprofile\AppData\Roaming\Maassoft\ColorControl&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;NVIDIA/AMD controller&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you own a NVIDIA or AMD graphics card, this app allows you not to only adjust basic display settings, but some hidden settings as well. For both NVIDIA and AMD graphics cards, you can configure your own presets to change the color depth (6 to 16 bpc), color format (RGB/YUV), refresh rate, dithering and HDR setting. You can assign a global keyboard shortcut to each preset to change the display settings (and HDR!) with just a couple of key presses. The NVIDIA controller even has some more options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dynamic range: VESA (Full RGB) or CEA (Limited RGB/YUV)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Color space: to change the color space, but most may not be supported by your tv&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dithering: you can define the dithering mode (Temporal or Spatial) and the dithering bit depth&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HDR: toggle HDR and control the SDR brightness setting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA: change driver settings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For a specific setting to be applied, you must include it within the preset. Just click the &#34;Include&#34; menu item and once it is checked, you&#39;re good to go.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Screenshot: &lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/70057942/132135723-688a6177-1906-4941-b92e-e456d71594b0.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LG controller&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you own a recent LG tv or monitor that uses WebOS as its operating system (2018 or newer, older might work), you can control your tv through the app (no NVIDIA or AMD graphics card needed). At startup of the application it will automatically detect your tv&#39;s (see below) if they are on the same network as your pc. If a tv is powered on, it will show a popup by which you can allow ColorControl to send commands to you tv. This will only happen the first time or whenever there&#39;s a change in the required permissions. A new version of ColorControl might need this. It is also possible to add a tv manually by using the &#34;Add&#34; button. A name and ip address are required, the MAC address is only necessary for Wake-On-Lan. You can configure as well when to automatically power your tv on or off:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power on after startup of pc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power on after resume&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on shutdown&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on standby&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on screensaver and on when screensaver deactivates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides powering on and off a lot of the settings can be directly changed via ColorControl.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For experienced users:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open service menu (InStart/EzAdjust)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change TPC/GSR setting directly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Samsung controller&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you own a recent Samsung tv or monitor that uses Tizen as its operating system (2018 or newer, older might work), you can control your tv through the app (no NVIDIA or AMD graphics card needed). At startup of the application it will automatically detect your tv&#39;s (see below) if they are on the same network as your pc. If a tv is powered on, it will show a popup by which you can allow ColorControl to send commands to you tv. This will only happen the first time or whenever there&#39;s a change in the required permissions. A new version of ColorControl might need this. It is also possible to add a tv manually by using the &#34;Add&#34; button. A name and ip address are required, the MAC address is only necessary for Wake-On-Lan. You can configure as well when to automatically power your tv on or off:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power on after startup of pc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power on after resume&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on shutdown&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on standby&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power off on screensaver and on when screensaver deactivates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For experienced users:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open service menu&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Presets&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the presets you can peform actions on your tv you would normally do via the remote control. Properties of a preset:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Name: fill in your own name/description&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Device: select the tv to perform the action on. Defaults to &#34;Globally selected device&#34;, which is the selected device in the top devices drop down.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;App (LG only): select the app to launch that is installed on your tv (optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shortcut: enter the global shortcut to execute this preset&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Steps: steps to execute sequentially. These steps can be: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Remote control buttons: like RIGHT, LEFT, ENTER, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Actions: LG only: directly change picture settings like backlight, contrast, pictureMode, etc. In a dialog you have to specify the value.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA/AMD presets: add NVIDIA or AMD presets here that have to execute as well&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, you can add a trigger to a preset which means it will execute automatically when a process on your pc is running. See for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Maassoft/ColorControl/releases/tag/v4.0.0.0&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Maassoft/ColorControl/releases/tag/v4.0.0.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Screenshot: &lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/70057942/132136067-1a2c205d-a241-4bf2-8d77-550b31606727.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Auto detecting your tv&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check if the TV is listed in Windows Device Manager (Win+X -&amp;gt; Device Manager) under Digital Media Devices. If not then add the TV using Settings (Win+I) -&amp;gt; &#34;Devices&#34; -&amp;gt; &#34;Add Bluetooth or other device&#34; -&amp;gt; &#34;Everything Else&#34;, then select your TV by name. It should now appear in Device Manager. (If your TV is not shown when adding devices then your PC is unable to see the TV on the network, check your network settings on both the PC &amp;amp; TV) NOTE: You may have to add the TV as a device more than once before it appears in Device Manager, as Windows can detect the TV as multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WinPcap is no longer used by default, but if you receive WinPcap errors, download and install Npcap (&lt;a href=&#34;https://nmap.org/npcap/#download&#34;&gt;https://nmap.org/npcap/#download&lt;/a&gt;) in WinPcap compatibility mode. WinPcap is depreciated under windows 10.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the Options-tabpage you can finetune some parameters and/or enable some settings:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Maassoft/ColorControl/raw/master/images/Options.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Command line interface&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is possible to execute presets from the command line. It doesn&#39;t matter whether the user interface of Color Control is already running or not. This is the syntax:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Syntax  : ColorControl command options&#xA;Commands:&#xA;--nvpreset  &amp;lt;preset name or id&amp;gt;: execute NVIDIA-preset&#xA;--amdpreset &amp;lt;preset name or id&amp;gt;: execute AMD-preset&#xA;--lgpreset  &amp;lt;preset name&amp;gt;      : execute LG-preset&#xA;--sampreset &amp;lt;preset name&amp;gt;      : execute Samsung-preset&#xA;--help                         : displays this help info&#xA;Options:&#xA;--nogui     : starts command from the command line and will not open GUI (is forced when GUI is already running)&#xA;--no-refresh: when using LG or Samsung-preset: skip refreshing devices (speeds up executing preset)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: use double quotes if your preset has spaces in it, like this: &lt;code&gt;ColorControl.exe --nvpreset &#34;HDR GSYNC&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Uninstallation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have installed the Windows Service, you&#39;ll first have to set the Elevation-method to &#34;None&#34;. This will stop and uninstall the service. If you have &#34;Automatically start after login&#34; enabled you&#39;ll have to uncheck that so the scheduled task is removed. After that you can close the main application and delete the program&#39;s files. If you want to fully remove all settings you can remove these folders: &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\username\AppData\Roaming\Maassoft\ColorControl&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;C:\Windows\System32\config\systemprofile\AppData\Roaming\Maassoft&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>