<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-12T01:23:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator</title>
    <updated>2023-09-12T01:23:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-12:/SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Desktop implementation of Steam&#39;s mobile authenticator app&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Jessecar96/SteamDesktopAuthenticator/master/icon.png&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; width=&#34;64&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt; Steam Desktop Authenticator &lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; A desktop implementation of Steam&#39;s mobile authenticator app.&lt;br&gt; &lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;We are not affiliated with Steam or Scrap.TF in any way!&lt;/b&gt; This project is run by community volunteers. &lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;WARNING: Recently there have been fake versions of SDA floating around that will steal your Steam account. Never download SDA from any place other than this github repo!&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom:0&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Supports Windows 7 and up.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clicking &#34;Download ZIP&#34; will not work!&lt;/strong&gt; This project uses git submodules so you must use git to download it properly. Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt; is an easy way to do that.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER: We provide no support for you when using Steam Desktop Authenticator! This project is run by community volunteers and is not affiliated with Steam or Scrap.TF. You use this program at your own risk, and accept the responsibility to make backups and prevent unauthorized access to your computer!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REMEMBER: Always make backups of your &lt;code&gt;maFiles&lt;/code&gt; directory! If you lose your encryption key or delete &lt;code&gt;maFiles&lt;/code&gt; by accident AND you didn&#39;t save your revocation code, you are screwed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FINALLY: Using this application is a bad idea, because it COMPLETELY DEFEATS THE PURPOSE of two-factor authentication! If your desktop is infected with a virus, it will be able to hijack the authenticator app and completely subvert the protection. THIS APPLICATION DOES NOT PROTECT YOUR ACCOUNT; IT ONLY ALLOWS YOU TO USE STEAM FEATURES THAT REQUIRE THE AUTHENTICATOR WITHOUT HAVING A PHONE. If you have a phone that supports the Mobile Authenticator, you really shouldn&#39;t use this application!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;IF you lost your &lt;code&gt;maFiles&lt;/code&gt; OR lost your encryption key, go &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/twofactor/manage&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and click &#34;Remove Authenticator&#34; then enter your revocation code that you wrote down when you first added your account to SDA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you did not follow the directions and did not write your revocation code down, you&#39;re well and truly screwed. The only option is beg to &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.steampowered.com/&#34;&gt;Steam Support&lt;/a&gt; and say you lost your mobile authenticator and the revocation code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Detailed setup instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download &amp;amp; Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/net/download/dotnet-framework-runtime/net472&#34;&gt;.NET Framework 4.7.2&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;re using Windows 7. Windows 8 and above should do this automatically for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jessecar96/SteamDesktopAuthenticator/releases&#34;&gt;the releases page&lt;/a&gt; and download the latest .zip (not the source code one).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract the files somewhere very safe on your computer. If you lose the files you can lose access to your Steam account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;Steam Desktop Authenticator.exe&lt;/code&gt; and click the button to set up a new account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Login to Steam and follow the instructions to set it up. &lt;strong&gt;Note: you still need a mobile phone that can receive SMS.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You may be asked to set up encryption, this is to make sure if someone gains access to your computer they can&#39;t steal your Steam account from this program. This is optional but highly recommended.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select your account from the list to view the current login code, and click &lt;code&gt;Trade Confirmations&lt;/code&gt; to see pending trade confirmations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For your safety, remember to get Steam Guard backup codes! Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/twofactor/manage&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; and click &#34;Get Backup Codes,&#34; then print out that page and save it in a safe place. You can use these codes if you lose access to your authenticator.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator/wiki/Updating&#34;&gt;How to update SDA.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SteamDesktopAuthenticatorrr/SteamDesktopAuthenticator/wiki/Using-SDA-on-multiple-computers&#34;&gt;How to use SDA on multiple computers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Command line options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-k [encryption key]&#xA;  Set your encryption key when opened&#xA;-s&#xA;  Auto-minimize to tray when opened&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trade confirmation list is just white or a blank screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First open the &#34;Selected Account&#34; menu, then click &#34;Force session refresh&#34;. If it still doesn&#39;t work after that, open the &#34;Selected Account&#34; menu again, then click &#34;Login again&#34; and login to your Steam account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your problem doesn&#39;t appear on the list or none of the solutions worked, submit an issue on the issue tracker. When posting logs in an issue, please upload it to some site like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pastebin.com&#34;&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building on linux&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First, you will need to install the &lt;code&gt;mono&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;monodevelop&lt;/code&gt; packages, usually available from your standard package repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open monodevelop and select File -&amp;gt; Open. Navigate to the folder where you cloned this program to and open the file &#34;Steam Desktop Authenticator/Steam Desktop Authenticator.sln&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you initialized submodules correctly, you should see two tree hirarchies on the left side of the screen, one labeled &lt;strong&gt;SteamDesktopAuthenticator&lt;/strong&gt; and the other &lt;strong&gt;SteamAuth&lt;/strong&gt;. (If you didn&#39;t, an error will be displayed; go update them!) For both of them, select &#34;Packages&#34;, right click on &#34;Newtonsoft.Json&#34;, and click update. Remember to do this for &lt;strong&gt;both SteamDesktopAuthenticator and SteamAuth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select Project-&amp;gt;Active Configuration-&amp;gt;Release (this will make this application run faster)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select Build-&amp;gt;Build All. The package should now build successfully.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The resulting executable and files will be in &#34;Steam Desktop Authenticator/bin/Release&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter</title>
    <updated>2023-09-12T01:23:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-12:/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PMP-Decrypter&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a tool to decrypt the encrypted password strings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://patchmypc.com&#34;&gt;Patch My PC&lt;/a&gt; settings.xml files.&lt;br&gt; In my case it was the SMTP password, but as there is only one encryption and decryption function in the tool, it should work for all of them.&lt;br&gt; Patch My PC saves the values for the crypto functions in registry keys under:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;HKLM\Software\Patch My PC Publishing Service&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Data1 = Key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Data2 = Salt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Data3 = IV&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter/assets/58529760/641e3174-96dd-4696-aaad-daff5fc1c25c&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I honestly dunno if this is also true for the latest latest latest version, but the one I stumbled upon seems to be from 04/2023 so pretty new.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ACLs on those keys are lax, so can be read by everyone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter/assets/58529760/c9c76d58-5420-47a6-8443-3749a71439ef&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The settings file resides in the application&#39;s main folder and is called &lt;code&gt;Settings.xml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter/assets/58529760/7189fe7c-a669-4a01-aa74-e71b8b248f02&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tool first trys to fetch those key values automagically for you.&lt;br&gt; If not found, you still have the option to specify them manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;PMP-Decrypter.exe &amp;lt;encryptedText&amp;gt; [privateKey] [saltKey] [ivKey]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/LuemmelSec/PMP-Decrypter/assets/58529760/e9bcb1f2-168c-4507-8d05-38a78159bd8e&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Build&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used Visual Studio 2017, .Net Framework 4 and release mode.&lt;br&gt; If you dare, you can use the precompiled version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Countermeasures&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Honestly speaking: If a company which wants to connect to such critical assets takes security like this, I would not recommend using this at all.&lt;br&gt; You could restrict access to the reg keys, so that not everyone is able to read them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you operate it, where ever possible use low privileged, dedicated accounts. Sending mails with your DA account is not the best idea you might have.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>