<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-11-21T01:29:24Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>efcore/EFCore.NamingConventions</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T01:29:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-11-21:/efcore/EFCore.NamingConventions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/efcore/EFCore.NamingConventions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Entity Framework Core plugin to apply naming conventions to table and column names (e.g. snake_case)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Naming Conventions for Entity Framework Core Tables and Columns&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nuget.org/packages/EFCore.NamingConventions/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/nuget/v/EFCore.NamingConventions&#34; alt=&#34;Nuget&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, EF Core will map to tables and columns named exactly after your .NET classes and properties. For example, mapping a typical Customer class to PostgreSQL will result in SQL such as the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;CREATE TABLE &#34;Customers&#34; (&#xA;    &#34;Id&#34; integer NOT NULL GENERATED BY DEFAULT AS IDENTITY,&#xA;    &#34;FullName&#34; text NULL,&#xA;    CONSTRAINT &#34;PK_Customers&#34; PRIMARY KEY (&#34;Id&#34;)&#xA;);&#xA;&#xA;SELECT c.&#34;Id&#34;, c.&#34;FullName&#34;&#xA;    FROM &#34;Customers&#34; AS c&#xA;    WHERE c.&#34;FullName&#34; = &#39;John Doe&#39;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For PostgreSQL specifically, this forces double-quotes to be added since unquoted identifiers are automatically converted to lower-case - and all those quotes are an eye-sore. But even if we&#39;re using another database such as SQL Server, maybe we just hate seeing upper-case letters in our database, and would rather have another naming convention.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Down with same-name identifier tyranny! Simply add a reference to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nuget.org/packages/EFCore.NamingConventions/&#34;&gt;EFCore.NamingConventions&lt;/a&gt; and enable a naming convention in your model&#39;s &lt;code&gt;OnConfiguring&lt;/code&gt; method:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-c#&#34;&gt;protected override void OnConfiguring(DbContextOptionsBuilder optionsBuilder)&#xA;    =&amp;gt; optionsBuilder&#xA;        .UseNpgsql(...)&#xA;        .UseSnakeCaseNamingConvention();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will automatically make all your table and column names have snake_case naming:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;CREATE TABLE customers (&#xA;    id integer NOT NULL GENERATED BY DEFAULT AS IDENTITY,&#xA;    full_name text NULL,&#xA;    CONSTRAINT &#34;pk_customers&#34; PRIMARY KEY (id)&#xA;);&#xA;&#xA;SELECT c.id, c.full_name&#xA;        FROM customers AS c&#xA;        WHERE c.full_name = &#39;John Doe&#39;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Supported naming conventions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UseSnakeCaseNamingConvention: &lt;code&gt;FullName&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;full_name&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UseLowerCaseNamingConvention: &lt;code&gt;FullName&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;fullname&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UseCamelCaseNamingConvention: &lt;code&gt;FullName&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;fullName&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UseUpperCaseNamingConvention: &lt;code&gt;FullName&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;FULLNAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UseUpperSnakeCaseNamingConvention: &lt;code&gt;FullName&lt;/code&gt; becomes &lt;code&gt;FULL_NAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have another naming convention in mind? Open an issue or even submit a PR - it&#39;s pretty easy to do!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Important notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you have an existing database, adding this naming convention will cause a migration to be produced, renaming everything. Be very cautious when doing this (the process currently involves dropping and recreating primary keys).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This plugin will work with any relational database provider and isn&#39;t related to PostgreSQL or Npgsql in any way.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is a community-maintained plugin: it isn&#39;t an official part of Entity Framework Core and isn&#39;t supported by Microsoft in any way.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>greenshot/greenshot</title>
    <updated>2024-11-21T01:29:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-11-21:/greenshot/greenshot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/greenshot/greenshot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Greenshot for Windows - Report bugs &amp; features go here: https://greenshot.atlassian.net or look for information on:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Greenshot - a free screenshot tool optimized for productivity&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the source repository for Greenshot&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is Greenshot?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Greenshot is a light-weight screenshot software tool for Windows with the following key features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Quickly create screenshots of a selected region, window or fullscreen; you can even capture complete (scrolling) web pages from Internet Explorer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easily annotate, highlight or obfuscate parts of the screenshot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Export the screenshot in various ways: save to file, send to printer, copy to clipboard, attach to e-mail, send Office programs or upload to photo sites like Flickr or Picasa, and others. and a lot more options simplyfying creation of and work with screenshots every day.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being easy to understand and configurable, Greenshot is an efficient tool for project managers, software developers, technical writers, testers and anyone else creating screenshots.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://getgreenshot.org/support/&#34;&gt;If you find that Greenshot saves you a lot of time and/or money, you are very welcome to support the development of this screenshot software.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is for Greenshot 1.3, currently in development, but is the next planned release&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Releases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find a list of all releases (stable and unstable) in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/greenshot/greenshot/releases&#34;&gt;Github releases&lt;/a&gt; or in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://getgreenshot.org/version-history/&#34;&gt;version history on our website&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://getgreenshot.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;downloads page on our website&lt;/a&gt; always links to the latest stable release.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>