<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-17T01:30:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Yizzii/YizziCamModV2</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T01:30:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-17:/Yizzii/YizziCamModV2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Yizzii/YizziCamModV2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A simple camera mod with in game UI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;YizziCamModV2&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First Camera Mod with in game UI! (that i know of)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Yizzii/YizziCamModV2/raw/main/cammod.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Features:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Monitor UI (tab to enable, shitty OnGUI but im lazy so cope)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Freecam with gamepad support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spectator with ajustable offset (and a toggle to control it with wasd)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First Person View with smoothing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Third Person View (like gtags default camera just smoother,misc page for settings, front/back and follow head rotation)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow Player (Camera will look at and follow player, misc page for settings, minimum distance and speed)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grabbable Handles (you can only grab right side with right hand and left side with left hand)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Green Screen (in city)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adjustable FOV, Nearclip and smoothing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Controls:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;disable first person view by pressing X/Y&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;disable third person view by pressing X/Y&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;press X/Y to teleport camera in front of you&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;hold grip on banana handle to grab camera&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;press tab on IRL keyboard for monitor UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WASD/arrow keys for freecam(also a toggle for gamepad)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclamers:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This product is not affiliated with Gorilla Tag or Another Axiom LLC and is not endorsed or otherwise sponsored by Another Axiom LLC. Portions of the materials contained herein are property of Another Axiom LLC. ©2021 Another Axiom LLC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;controls can be different depending what you&#39;re playing on(steamvr,oculuspcvr,index, etc.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;if you find any bugs report them to @yizzi. on discord&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T01:30:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-17:/Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ADAMANT push Notification Service for iOS Messenger app&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ADAMANT Notification Service (ANS)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first of &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/adamant-im/adamant-is-working-on-blockchain-messaging-platform-and-push-notifications-service-765972cce50e&#34;&gt;ADAMANT Services&lt;/a&gt;, implemented to make secure instant notifications for ADAMANT iOS application.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: ADAMANT Blockchain and Messenger apps are fully functional without ANS and other Services. The goal of ADAMANT Services and ANS is to provide features that can not be implemented on the Blockchain. More on &lt;a href=&#34;https://adamant.im&#34;&gt;adamant.im&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To deliver notification &lt;strong&gt;privately and secure&lt;/strong&gt;, 4 parties are involved:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User&#39;s device (i. e., iPhone)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ADAMANT&#39;s blockchain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Apple Push Notification Service (APNS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This application, ADAMANT Notification Service (ANS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A workflow runs as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User sends an encrypted signal message with a unique token to an ADAMANT blockchain node. Recipient is ANS&#39;s ADAMANT address. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://aips.adamant.im/AIPS/aip-6&#34;&gt;AIP-6: Signal Messages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ANS polls the blockchain and decrypts the user&#39;s token&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ANS polls the blockchain and filter transactions, where user&#39;s ADM address is the recipient. ANS asks APNS to deliver these transactions (they holds encrypted messages) to a user&#39;s device, specified by unique token.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;APNS notifies a user&#39;s device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User&#39;s device has a secret key and decrypts messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This way a user&#39;s device never communicate with ANS, and ANS don&#39;t know its IP or other identities. They communicate through a blockchain nodes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;ANS application&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This application, ANS, consists of two main parts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSSignalsRegistration&lt;/strong&gt; — console application that polls ADAMANT blockchain nodes for new service signals to get device tokens. Message payload must be serialized in JSON and encrypted as other chat transactions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Payload format:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;token&#34;: &#34;DeviceToken&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;provider&#34;: &#34;apns&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;action&#34;: &#34;add&#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;token&lt;/code&gt;: user&#39;s device token&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;provider&lt;/code&gt;: push service provider &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;apns: for release builds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;apns-sandbox: for debug builds (not yet supported)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;action&lt;/code&gt; (optional): signal action &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;add (default): register new devise&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;remove: unregister device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANSPollingWorker&lt;/strong&gt; — console application that polls ADAMANT nodes for new transactions and checks for registered devices of receivers. If there is a registered device for the recipient of the transaction—sends a notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;QA&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Device token? What about security?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read about Apple Push Notification Service (APNS) and security on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/NetworkingInternet/Conceptual/RemoteNotificationsPG/APNSOverview.html&#34;&gt;Apple&#39;s docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We do not use third party services to send notifications. Your tokens and addresses doesn&#39;t fly around the Internet.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It&#39;s technically impossible to read a message contents from a transaction for ANS and it is impossible to include decrypted message into push contents. To decrypt a message, secret key is needed. And only user device holds it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Starting from version 0.4, ANS includes &lt;code&gt;txn-id&lt;/code&gt; param in the push content with the transaction id. A client app can get the transaction from a blockchain node and decrypt the message on the device, using a locally stored secret key. This is handled by &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/usernotifications/unnotificationserviceextension&#34;&gt;NotificationServiceExtension&lt;/a&gt;, and a passphrase (secret key) is stored securely in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/security/keychain_services&#34;&gt;Keychain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your device token is unique for each application on your device. We can&#39;t find your facebook page with your device token, generated for the ADAMANT app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New device token is generated each time you reinstall an app, or just re-enable notifications. You can just disable notifications for ADAMANT app, and the device token in ANS database becomes useless. Next time ANS will try to send a push notification, Apple will say the token is broken.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;iOS App Badge?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In iOS, app&#39;s badge number is sent to you by a server as a part of a push notification, it&#39;s not handled by an application, as application can be even terminated and unloaded from memory at the moment. ANS doesn&#39;t know how many messages you haven&#39;t read. That&#39;s why ANS shows &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; badge, if there any unread messages. Alternative solution is to handle it locally on a device by the NotificationServiceExtension—an app extension, that can modify notification content.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;.NET Core version&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;APNS requires HTTP/2 connection. dotnet core 2.1 and 2.2 &lt;strong&gt;does not support it&lt;/strong&gt;. The app is build with is 3.0.100-preview5-011568, and it supports HTTP/2. You can create a self-contained build for a machine without 3.0 runtime on a machine with 3.0 SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;dotnet publish -c Release -r linux-64 -o {output path} -f netcoreapp3.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/ru-ru/dotnet/core/rid-catalog&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; about -r, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/ru-ru/dotnet/standard/frameworks&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; about -f, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dotnet.microsoft.com/download&#34;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; dotnet core SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Want to try it out?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You gonna need a dotnet.core runtime to launch ANS. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/net/learn/get-started&#34;&gt;Microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; and download SDK for your platform.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone or download this repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open terminal/console/cmd and type &lt;code&gt;dotnet restore&lt;/code&gt; in the Solution&#39;s folder, or just open the Solution in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.visualstudio.com&#34;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;. VS will automatically restore NuGet dependencies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grab sample config file at Solution&#39;s root, edit your connection strings, nodes, delays, certificates, and save it to &lt;code&gt;{UserHomeDirectory}/.ans/config.json&lt;/code&gt;. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService/master/#configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;At first launch, the application will auto-upgrade your database.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To launch &lt;strong&gt;ANSPollingWorker&lt;/strong&gt;, you need your Apple Push certificate, you can grab it from Apple Developer&#39;s center. Place it in &lt;code&gt;{UserHomeDirectory}/.ans/&lt;/code&gt;, make sure you&#39;ve specified correct path and certificate&#39;s password in the config. Go to terminal, &lt;code&gt;cd ANSPollingWorker&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dotnet run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To launch &lt;strong&gt;ANSRegistrationService&lt;/strong&gt;, type in your ANS account in the config. Go to terminal, &lt;code&gt;cd ANSRegistrationService&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dotnet run&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can run &lt;code&gt;dotnet publish -c Release&lt;/code&gt; to create compiled archives. More about dotnet core, and what to do with this &#39;compiled archives&#39; you can read on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/ru-ru/dotnet/core/tools/dotnet-publish&#34;&gt;Microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You will need a certificate to send a push notifications to APNS, which you can get from your Apple Developer account.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;My own iOS app and ANS server&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are building your own iOS ADAMANT application and want to use your own ANS server, you will need to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Register ADAMANT account for ANS. Just a regular &#39;U&#39; account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In iOS source code, type your ANS account&#39;s address and public key in &lt;code&gt;AdamantResources&lt;/code&gt; struct.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In ANS config, type in your ANS&#39;s ADM account address and private key. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService/master/#configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To create .pfx certificate with ECDSA private key. First, create a key and download it from your &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/account/ios/authkey/&#34;&gt;Apple Developer page&lt;/a&gt;. Put it in some folder. Open Terminal, navigate to this folder, and type:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;openssl req -new -x509 -key key.p8 -out selfsigned.cer&#xA;openssl pkcs12 -export -in selfsigned.cer -inkey key.p8 -out cert.pfx&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Put the .pfx certificate in &lt;code&gt;~/.ans&lt;/code&gt;, and update the config.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Done. iOS application will send device tokens to your ANS ADM account, &lt;strong&gt;ANSRegistrationService&lt;/strong&gt; will poll signal transactions and register tokens, and &lt;strong&gt;ANSPollingService&lt;/strong&gt; will poll new messages/transactions and notify registered devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sample configuration file is located in the Solution&#39;s root directory. Both Polling ans Signal registration services loads config from &lt;code&gt;~/.ans/config.json&lt;/code&gt;, so you have one config file for ANS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Config sections&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Database&lt;/code&gt; (optional): Section for database configuration. Params:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConnectionString&lt;/code&gt; (optional, default: &lt;code&gt;devices&lt;/code&gt;). ConnectionString name. Strings is specified in &lt;code&gt;ConnectionStrings&lt;/code&gt; section, see bellow.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Provider&lt;/code&gt; (optional): Database connection provider. Two providers are supported: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sqlite&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mysql&lt;/code&gt; (default)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ConnectionStrings&lt;/code&gt;: a standard dotnet section for connection strings. Active connection string name specified in &lt;code&gt;Database:ConnectionString&lt;/code&gt; param, default is &lt;code&gt;devices&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Api&lt;/code&gt;: ADAMANT node settings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Server[]&lt;/code&gt;: node addresses. Properties: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip&lt;/code&gt; (string): node address (or ip)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;protocol&lt;/code&gt; (string, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;https&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;port&lt;/code&gt; (int, optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;PollingWorker&lt;/code&gt;: Polling settings. Properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delay&lt;/code&gt; (milliseconds as int, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;2000&lt;/code&gt;): interval between two requests to retrieve new messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;NlogConfig&lt;/code&gt; (string, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;nlog.config&lt;/code&gt;): path to NLog configuration file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Startup&lt;/code&gt; (enum, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;database&lt;/code&gt;): Startup mode. Options: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;database&lt;/code&gt;: Try to load saved last blockchain height from database, and start from this value. If failed or no value saved, switch to &lt;code&gt;network&lt;/code&gt; mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;network&lt;/code&gt;: Try to get last transaction from network and use its height as last height value. If failed or no transaction received, go to &lt;code&gt;initial&lt;/code&gt; mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;initial&lt;/code&gt;: Start from blockchain height 0.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SignalsRegistration&lt;/code&gt;: Signals polling &amp;amp; registration settings. Properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delay&lt;/code&gt; (milliseconds as int, optional, default: 2000): interval between two requests to retrieve new signal transactions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;NlogConfig&lt;/code&gt; (string, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;nlog.config&lt;/code&gt;): path to NLog configuration file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Address&lt;/code&gt; (string, required): ANS&#39;s ADM account address to poll signals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;PrivateKey&lt;/code&gt; (string, required): ANS&#39;s ADM account private key to decrypt signal transactions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Startup&lt;/code&gt; (enum, optional, default: &lt;code&gt;database&lt;/code&gt;): Startup mode. Same options as for &lt;code&gt;PollingWorker:Startup&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ApplePusher&lt;/code&gt;: APNS settings. Sections:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Keys&lt;/code&gt;. Properties: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;keyId&lt;/code&gt; (string): Your developer key id. Created and obtained at your &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/account/ios/authkey/&#34;&gt;Auth Keys page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;teamId&lt;/code&gt; (string): Your app developer team id. Obtained at your Apple Dev &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Adamant-im/adamant-notificationService/master/developer.apple.com/account/#/membership/&#34;&gt;Membership Details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundleAppId&lt;/code&gt; (string): Your application bundle id&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pfxPath&lt;/code&gt; (string): Path to self-signed *.pfx certificate. Certificate must contain ECDSA private key&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pfxPassword&lt;/code&gt; (string): Certificate&#39;s password&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Certificate&lt;/code&gt;. Properties: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;path&lt;/code&gt; (string): Path to APNS *.p12 certificate&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pass&lt;/code&gt; (string): Certificate&#39;s password&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Payload[]&lt;/code&gt;. Apple push notifications payload. Properties: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;transactionType&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; for ADM token transfer, &lt;code&gt;8&lt;/code&gt; for chat transactions and coin transfers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;body&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sound&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant</title>
    <updated>2024-01-17T01:30:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-17:/DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Windows安全基线核查加固助手&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;WindowsBaselineAssistant&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WindowsBaselineAssistant(WBA)是一个用于检测和加固Windows安全基线的辅助工具,借助此工具你可以免去繁琐的手工检测和加固操作,实现一键检测和加固你的Windows安全基线,并可以导出检测或加固结果,解放你的双手~&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;截图&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant/master/assets/image-20240115155426706.png&#34; alt=&#34;UIMain&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;工具运行要求&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.Net Framework 4.0及以上&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;项目依赖库&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SunnyUI 3.6.3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SunnyUI.Common 3.6.3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;System.ValueTuple 4.5.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NPOI 2.5.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;自定义规则&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WBA支持自定义规则以适应不同环境下的检测需求&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WBA的所有规则位于&lt;code&gt;item.xml&lt;/code&gt;文件中,其中检测规则分为&lt;code&gt;registry&lt;/code&gt;和&lt;code&gt;secedit&lt;/code&gt;两种,判定规则分为&lt;code&gt;fixed,enum,greaternumber,lessnumber,array,equals&lt;/code&gt;六种.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;规则格式&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;registry(读取注册表)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;检查源路由配置&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;description&amp;gt;源路由攻击有源地址欺骗、IP欺骗等,为了提高系统的可靠性,需要检查是否启用正确配置源路由攻击保护.&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;registry&amp;lt;/type&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;registry&amp;gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Services\Tcpip\Parameters&amp;lt;/registry&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;regitem&amp;gt;DisableIPSourceRouting&amp;lt;/regitem&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;standard&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/standard&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;assessment&amp;gt;enum&amp;lt;/assessment&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;valuetype&amp;gt;dword&amp;lt;/valuetype&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;名称&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;解释&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;name&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;规则名称&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;description&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;规则描述&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;type&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;registry&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的注册表路径&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;regitem&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测的注册表项&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;standard&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;标准值&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;assessment&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;判定规则(见: 判定规则)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;valuetype&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;注册表数据类型(见: 数据类型)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;secedit(读取config.cfg信息)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;检查密码最长使用期限&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;description&amp;gt;长期修改密码会提高密码暴露风险,所以为了提高系统的保密性.需要检查密码最长使用期限.&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;secedit&amp;lt;/type&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;mark&amp;gt;MaximumPasswordAge&amp;lt;/mark&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;standard&amp;gt;90&amp;lt;/standard&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;assessment&amp;gt;greaternumber&amp;lt;/assessment&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;名称&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;解释&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;name&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;同上&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;description&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;同上&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;type&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;同上&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;mark&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;secedit文件中的键&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;standard&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;同上&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;assessment&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;同上&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;附加标识&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;manual: 用于标识检测项需要手动进行加固&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;manual&amp;gt;1&amp;lt;manual&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant/master/assets/image-20240115160311962.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-20240115160311962&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ignore: 用于标识检测项为已忽略&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;ignore&amp;gt;1&amp;lt;ignore&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DeEpinGh0st/WindowsBaselineAssistant/master/assets/image-20240115160420571.png&#34; alt=&#34;image-20240115160420571&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;判定规则&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;标识符&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;判定规则解释&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;判定结果&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;fixed&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值为一个不固定值&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;手动加固&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;enum&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值为一个枚举类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;等于枚举值: 符合 反之: 不符合&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;greaternumber&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值大于此值时&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;符合 反之: 不符合&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;lessnumber&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值小于此值时&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;符合 反之: 不符合&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;array&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值是一个数组(多行)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;相同: 符合 反之: 不符合&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;equals&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;检测项的标准值等于检测值&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;相同: 符合 反之: 不符合&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;数据类型&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;注册表类型&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;工具映射类型&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;类型解释&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;String&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;字符串类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;ExpandString&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;expandstring&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;可扩展字符串类型的注册表值，通常包含了环境变量&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Binary&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;暂不支持&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;二进制数据类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DWord&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dword&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;32位整数类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;QWord&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;qword&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;64位整数类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;MultiString&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;multistring&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;多行字符串类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Unknown&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;默认&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;未知类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;暂不支持&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;没有特定类型&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;例&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如现在要检测&lt;code&gt;重新传输的TCP连接阈值&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; 检测类型为&lt;code&gt;检索注册表 &lt;/code&gt; 检索的注册表路径为&lt;code&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SYSTEM\\CurrentControlSet\\services\\Tcpip\\Parameters&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; 检测项为&lt;code&gt;TcpMaxHalfOpenRetried&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; 标准值为&lt;code&gt;400&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; 数据类型为&lt;code&gt;DWord&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; 检测值要小于此值时&lt;code&gt;判定符合&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;item&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;检查处于SYN_RCVD 状态下,且至少已经进行了一次重新传输的TCP连接阈值&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;description&amp;gt;xxxxxx&amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;registry&amp;lt;/type&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;registry&amp;gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\services\Tcpip\Parameters&amp;lt;/registry&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;regitem&amp;gt;TcpMaxHalfOpenRetried&amp;lt;/regitem&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;standard&amp;gt;400&amp;lt;/standard&amp;gt;&#xA;&#x9;&amp;lt;assessment&amp;gt;lessnumber&amp;lt;/assessment&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;valuetype&amp;gt;dword&amp;lt;/valuetype&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;更多示例见item.xml&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;致谢&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yhuse/SunnyUI&#34;&gt;SunnyUI .Net界面库&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nuget.org/packages/System.ValueTuple/4.5.0/ReportAbuse&#34;&gt;System.ValueTuple 实现了C#中元组的底层类型&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nissl-lab/npoi&#34;&gt;NPOI POI的.Net实现,用于读写office文档&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;WBA适用所有Windows版本嘛?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;很显然这是不可能的,每个Windows版本的注册表和secedit信息不尽相同,WBA不可能做到适配所有系统&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;为什么加固后,通过Windows管理界面查看配置项未进行更改?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;这通常是你的规则和你的Windows系统不匹配造成的,你需要重新查找检测项在注册表和secedit中的检测位置,并更新的你的规则库&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>