<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-27T01:23:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ResetXPDR/MSFS2020_AutoFPS</title>
    <updated>2024-02-27T01:23:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-27:/ResetXPDR/MSFS2020_AutoFPS</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ResetXPDR/MSFS2020_AutoFPS" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;MSFS2020_AutoFPS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on muumimorko&#39;s idea and code in MSFS_AdaptiveLOD, as further developed by Fragtality in DynamicLOD and myself in DynamicLOD_ResetEdition.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This utility is a new development that is a simplification of, and a slightly different concept to, DynamicLOD_ResetEdition. It aims to improve MSFS performance and smoothness by automatically changing the two settings that impact MSFS performance the most, namely TLOD and cloud quality settings, based on the current AGL and with an easy to use GUI. It provides features such as:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically adjusts TLOD to achieve a user-defined target FPS band based on pre or user-defined maximum and minimum TLODs,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TLOD minimum on ground/landing option, which prioritises TLOD over FPS during these flight phases and also averts exacerbating existing texture tearing issues with DX12,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cloud quality decrease option for when FPS can&#39;t be achieved at the lowest desired TLOD,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatic pause when MSFS loses focus option, particularly useful if using FG due to varying FPS when MSFS gains or loses focus,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatic FPS settling timer on MSFS graphics mode and focus changes to allow FPS to stabilise before being acted upon,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Simultaneous PC, FG and VR mode compatibilty including correct FG FPS display and separate FPS targets for each mode,&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A greatly simplified GUI option that uses pre-defined settings for an automated experience suited to most user scenarios, and&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto restoration of original settings changed by the utility.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This utility can be installed concurrent with any DynamicLOD variant. You just shouldn&#39;t run them at the same time, as they would both be fighting each other with MSFS settings. AutoFPS can detect whether itself or a previous DynamicLOD variant is running and will quit if it finds one. DynamicLOD_ResetEdition 0.3.7 does the same except it doesn&#39;t know about AutoFPS because I started that after 0.3.7 was released, so you need to be aware of that potential conflict if you start DynamicLOD_ResetEdition 0.3.7 after MSFS_AdaptiveLOD. The next DynamicLOD_Reset version will be fully AutoFPS aware.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FG users - The app does detect correct FG FPS when FG is enabled in MSFS, however just because FG is enabled it doesn&#39;t mean FG is always active. Specifically, FG is enabled with DX12 AND HAGS AND FG turned on in MSFS, but it is only active when the MSFS is the focused app. As soon as you switch to any window other than MSFS then FG becomes inactive, not through this app but through your graphics driver, so if you switch to this app and it goes on top of your MSFS window you will see FG Inactive on the app status line because that is what has happened. In order to actually see the app report correct FG FPS, the app needs to be showing on another monitor and MSFS needs to have the focus. If you don&#39;t have a second monitor, it is not possible to see it. Nonetheless, the app will be reading FG FPS correctly and it will be using the Target FG FPS you have set.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This utility directly accesses active MSFS memory locations while MSFS is running to read and set TLOD and cloud quality settings on the fly at a maximum rate of one read and, if required, change per setting per second. The utility will first verify that the MSFS memory locations being used are still valid and if not, likely because of an MSFS version change, will attempt to find where they have been relocated. If it does find the new memory locations and they pass validation tests, the utility will update itself automatically and will function as normal. If it can&#39;t find or validate MSFS memory locations at any time when starting up, the utility will self-restrict to read only mode to prevent the utility making changes to unknown MSFS memory locations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;As such, I believe the app to be robust in its interaction with validated MSFS memory locations and to be responsible in disabling itself if it can&#39;t guarantee that. Nonetheless, this utility is offered as is and no responsibility will be taken for unintended negative side effects. Use at your own risk!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with what MSFS graphics settings do, specifically TLOD and cloud quality, and don&#39;t understand the consequences of changing them, it is highly recommended you do not use this utility. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This utility is unsigned because I am a hobbyist and the cost of obtaining certification is prohibitive to me. As a result, you may get a warning message of a potentially dangerous app when you download it in a web browser like Chrome or from your antivirus program, including Windows Defender. You can either trust this download, based on feedback you can easily find on Avsim and Youtube, make an exception in your browser and/or antivirus program for the download then run a virus scan and malware scan before you install just be sure, otherwise choose not to and not have this utility version.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Installer will install the following Software:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.NET 7 Desktop Runtime (x64)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MobiFlight Event/WASM Module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ResetXPDR/MSFS2020_AutoFPS/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Download here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Under Assests, the MSFS2020_AutoFPS-Installer-vXYZ.exe File)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation / Update / Uninstall&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically: Just run the Installer to do all three of these.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some Notes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MSFS2020_AutoFPS has to be stopped before installing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the MobiFlight Module is not installed or outdated, MSFS also has to be stopped.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you have duplicate MobiFlight Modules installed, in either your official or community folders, the utility may display 0 value Sim Values and otherwise not function. Remove the duplicate versions, rerun the utility installer and it should now work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do not run the Installer as Admin!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the installer will not run at all, Windows SmartScreen is potentially blocking it because the app is so new. The solution to try is: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Right-click on the Installer and select properties&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Check the option &#34;Unblock&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Click on Apply and Ok to save the change&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Then try to install it again&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you wish to retain your settings for an update version, do NOT uninstall first, as that deletes all app files, including the config file. Just run the installer, select update and your settings will be retained.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For Auto-Start either your FSUIPC7.ini or EXE.xml (MSFS) is modified. The Installer does not create a Backup.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The utility may be blocked by Windows Security or your AV-Scanner, try if unblocking and/or setting an Exception helps (for the whole Folder)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Installation-Location is fixed to %appdata%\MSFS2020_AutoFPS (your Users AppData\Roaming Folder) and can&#39;t be changed. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Binary in %appdata%\MSFS2020_AutoFPS\bin&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Logs in %appdata%\MSFS2020_AutoFPS\log&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Config: %appdata%\MSFS2020_AutoFPS\MSFS2020_AutoFPS.config&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If after installing and running the app your simconnect always stays red, try downloading and installing a Microsoft official version of “Microsoft Visual C++ 2015 - 2022 Redistributable”, which may be missing from your Windows installation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you get an &#34;MSFS compatibility test failed - Read Only mode&#34; message there are three possible causes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You may have changed MSFS settings in your usercfg.opt file beyond what is possible to set in the MSFS settings menu. To rectify, go into MSFS settings at the main menu and reset to default (F12) the graphics settings for both PC and VR mode, then make all changes to MSFS within the MSFS settings menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There is an issue with permissions and you may need to run the app as Administrator.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A new version of MSFS has come out that has a different memory map to what the app expects, which has happened only once since MSFS 2020 was released, and the app can&#39;t auto adjust to the new memory location for MSFS settings. If so, I will likely be already aware of it and working on a solution, but if you may be one of the first to encounter it (eg. on an MSFS beta) then please do let me know.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To uninstall, run the installer and select remove on the first window. This will remove all traces of the app, including the desktop icon, MSFS or FSUIPC autostart entries if you used them, and the entire app folder, including your configuration file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage / Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;General &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Starting manually: anytime, but preferably before MSFS or in the Main Menu. The utility will stop itself when MSFS closes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Closing the Window does not close the utiltiy, use the Context Menu of the SysTray Icon.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Clicking on the SysTray Icon opens the Window (again).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Runnning as Admin NOT required (BUT: It is required to be run under the same User/Elevation as MSFS).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Do not change TLOD, OLOD and Cloud Quality MSFS settings manually while in a flight with this app running as it will conflict with what the app is managing and they will not restore to what you set when you exit your flight. If you wish to change the defaults for these MSFS settings, you must do so either without this app running or, if it is, only while you are in the MSFS main menu (ie not in a flight).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connection Status &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Red values indicate not connected, green is connected.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sim Values &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Will not show valid values unless all three connections are green. n/a means not available right now.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Green means the sim value is at or better than target value being sought, red means at lowest level or worse than target value being sought, orange means TLOD is auto adjusting, black is shown otherwise.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FPS shows the FPS averaged over 5 seconds which will smooth out any transient FPS spikes experienced when panning or loading new scenery or objects so that automated MSFS setting changes are minimised.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Priority will show whether FPS or TLOD Min are the current automation priority, with the latter only being shown if the TLOD min for ground/landing is enabled and conditions are such that, because of your flight phase (on or near the ground), working towards TLOD Min now has priority over maintaining FPS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;General &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Target FPS - The most important setting in this app. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Set it to what FPS you want the app to target while running, noting that this value should be at the mid to lower end of what your system is capable of otherwise the app will be unlikely to achieve it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;There is a setting for each graphics mode (PC, FG and VR) which you can only change while in that mode and on the ground or in a flight. This is particularly useful if regularly switching between FG mode and VR mode in your flights as the FG FPS target can be significantly higher than the one for VR. If using FG, the target FPS you set is your desired FG FPS, not the FG inactive FPS you see when this app has the focus instead of MSFS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If you use an FPS cap, or Vsync for the same purpose, you will need to set your target FPS to be around 10% lower than that cap. This allows the automated TLOD increase logic to function properly because it needs FPS to get above the target FPS plus the FPS tolerance to activate an increase in TLOD. If doing so causes unacceptable tearing of the image on your monitor, or breaks motion reprojection if you use it with VR, then this app isn&#39;t suitable for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Use Expert Options - When disabled allows the app to use default settings in conjuction with your chosen target FPS that should produce good automated FPS tracking, provided you have set a realistic FPS target within your system&#39;s performance capability. When enabled, the UI expands to show additional MSFS settings to adjust. If you do not understand these settings and their impact on MSFS performance and graphics quality, it is strongly recommended that you do not use these expert options and you should uncheck this option.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open window on app start - determines the app window&#39;s startup state.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Status Message - On app startup indicates key system messages, such as: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Before loading a flight - whether a newer version of the app is available to download and install&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Loading in to a flight - whether MSFS memory integrity test have failed, and&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Flight is loaded - showing detected DX version, Graphics Mode (PC, FG, or VR), and app pause or FPS settling time status as applicable. The FPS settling timer runs for 6 seconds to allow FPS to settle between pausing/unpausing and VR/PC/FG mode transitions. This allows the FPS to stabilise before engaging automatic functions and should lead to much smaller TLOD changes when seeking the target FPS on such transitions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MSFS Settings &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FPS Tolerance - Determines how much variance from your target FPS must occur before the app will adjust MSFS settings to achieve the target FPS and what nominal magnitude those changes will be. The lower the setting, the more reactive the app will be, the more MSFS settings changes will occur and the changes will be smaller. Vice versa for higher settings. When expert settings are disabled, the default value of 5% should provide the most balanced experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;TLOD Min on Ground/Landing - When enabled, your TLOD will immediately change to TLOD minimum when your flight is loaded and will stay that way any time you are on the ground. Once you take off and start climbing, auto TLOD will kick in gradually on a sliding scale up to 1000 ft AGL, then normal range auto operation above that. On descent to landing, when you cross 2000 ft AGL, the app will progressively adjust your TLOD down so that as you cross 1000 ft AGL it will be at TLOD minimum and there it will stay locked all the way to the ground, taxi and shutdown at the gate. If you are level below 1000 ft AGL, then commence descending, TLOD will rapidly switch to TLOD minimum with no stepping as it thinks you are landing imminently. If you are using cloud quality reduction options, even though you are at TLOD minimum on the ground which would normally cause cloud quality to reduce straight away, it will only reduce if you are below achieving your FPS target FPS and recover again as normal. It is generally recommended to leave this setting enabled, as will happen with expert settings disabled, if you want your TLOD on the ground or when landing to always be TLOD min, otherwise with it disabled you may experience texture corruption with DX12 on the ground, especially at airports.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;TLOD Min - Sets the minimum TLOD the automation algorithm will use. When expert settings are disabled, the app will use 50% of your existing MSFS TLOD setting for this parameter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;TLOD Max - Sets the maximum TLOD the automation algorithm will use. When expert settings are disabled, the app will use 200% of your existing MSFS TLOD setting for this parameter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Decrease Cloud Quality - When enabled, will reduce cloud quality by one level if TLOD has already auto reduced to TLOD Min and FPS is still below target FPS by more than the FPS tolerance. When expert settings are disabled, the app will enable this setting.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Cloud Recovery TLOD - The TLOD level required to cancel an active cloud quality reduction state and restore cloud quality back to its initial higher quality level. This provides a TLOD buffer to account for the increased TLOD achieved by reducing cloud quality to stop FPS adaption constantly toggling on and off. This parameter must be at least 5 TLOD more than TLOD Min and 5 TLOD below TLOD Max and ideally is set to 50 TLOD above TLOD Min provided that the aforementioned conditions can be met. When expert settings are disabled, the app will use your existing MSFS TLOD setting for this parameter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Pause when MSFS loses focus - This will stop TLOD and, if applicable, cloud quality from changing while you are focused on another app and not MSFS. It is particularly useful for when using FG as the FG active and inactive frame rate can vary quite considerably and because FG is not always an exact doubling of non-FG FPS. When expert settings are disabled, the app will enable this setting. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nereziel/cs2-WeaponPaints</title>
    <updated>2024-02-27T01:23:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-27:/Nereziel/cs2-WeaponPaints</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Nereziel/cs2-WeaponPaints" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CS2 Weapon Paints&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfinished, unoptimized and not fully functional ugly demo weapon paints plugin for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.cssharp.dev/docs/guides/getting-started.html&#34;&gt;CSSharp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Created &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/d9CvaYPSFe&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; where you can discuss about plugin.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Consider to donate instead of buying from unknown sources.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/E1E2G0P2O&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/img/githubbutton_sm.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;ko-fi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://steamcommunity.com/tradeoffer/new/?partner=41515647&amp;amp;token=gW2W-nXE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Nereziel/cs2-WeaponPaints/assets/32937653/a0d53822-4ca7-4caf-83b4-e1a9b5f8c94e&#34; alt=&#34;Donate on Steam&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes only paint, seed and wear on weapons and knives&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MySQL based&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Data syncs on player connect&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;!wp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to refresh skins &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(with cooldown in seconds can be configured)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;!ws&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to show website&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;!knife&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to show menu with knives&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Knife change is now limited to have these cvars empty &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;mp_t_default_melee &#34;&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;mp_ct_default_melee &#34;&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Translations support, submit a PR if you want to share your translation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;CS2 Server&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Have working CounterStrikeSharp (&lt;strong&gt;with RUNTIME!&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download from Release and copy plugin to plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run server with plugin, &lt;strong&gt;it will generate config if installed correctly!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;addons/counterstrikesharp/configs/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugins/WeaponPaints/WeaponPaints.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; include database credentials&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In &lt;code&gt;addons/counterstrikesharp/configs/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;core.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; set &lt;strong&gt;FollowCS2ServerGuidelines&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Plugin Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;{&#xA;&#x9;&#34;Version&#34;: 4, // Don&#39;t touch&#xA;&#x9;&#34;DatabaseHost&#34;: &#34;&#34;, // MySQL host&#xA;&#x9;&#34;DatabasePort&#34;: 3306, // MySQL port&#xA;&#x9;&#34;DatabaseUser&#34;: &#34;&#34;, // MySQL username&#xA;&#x9;&#34;DatabasePassword&#34;: &#34;&#34;, // MySQL user password&#xA;&#x9;&#34;DatabaseName&#34;: &#34;&#34;, // MySQL database name&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CmdRefreshCooldownSeconds&#34;: 60, // Cooldown time in refreshing skins (!wp command)&#xA;&#x9;&#34;Prefix&#34;: &#34;[WeaponPaints]&#34;, // Prefix every chat message&#xA;&#x9;&#34;Website&#34;: &#34;example.com/skins&#34;, // Website used in WebsiteMessageCommand (!ws command)&#xA;&#34;Messages&#34;: {&#xA;&#x9;&#34;WebsiteMessageCommand&#34;: &#34;Visit {WEBSITE} where you can change skins.&#34;, // Information about website where player can change skins (!ws command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;SynchronizeMessageCommand&#34;: &#34;Type !wp to synchronize chosen skins.&#34;, // Information about skins refreshing (!ws command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;KnifeMessageCommand&#34;: &#34;Type !knife to open knife menu.&#34;, // Information about knife menu (!ws command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CooldownRefreshCommand&#34;: &#34;You can\u0027t refresh weapon paints right now.&#34;, // Cooldown information (!wp command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;SuccessRefreshCommand&#34;: &#34;Refreshing weapon paints.&#34;, // Information about refreshing skins (!wp command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;ChosenKnifeMenu&#34;: &#34;You have chosen {KNIFE} as your knife.&#34;, // Information about choosen knife (!knife command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;ChosenSkinMenu&#34;: &#34;You have chosen {SKIN} as your skin.&#34;, // Information about choosen skin (!skins command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;ChosenKnifeMenuKill&#34;: &#34;To correctly apply skin for knife, you need to type !kill.&#34;, // Information about suicide after knife selection (!knife command) Set to empty to disable&#xA;&#x9;&#34;KnifeMenuTitle&#34;: &#34;Knife Menu.&#34;,  // Menu title (!knife menu)&#xA;&#x9;&#34;WeaponMenuTitle&#34;: &#34;Weapon Menu.&#34;, // Menu title (!skins menu)&#xA;&#x9;&#34;SkinMenuTitle&#34;: &#34;Select skin for {WEAPON}&#34; // Menu title (!skins menu, after weapon select)&#xA;},&#xA;&#34;Additional&#34;: {&#xA;&#x9;&#34;SkinVisibilityFix&#34;: true, // Enable or disable fix for skin visibility&#xA;&#x9;&#34;KnifeEnabled&#34;: true, // Enable or disable knife feature&#xA;&#x9;&#34;SkinEnabled&#34;: true, // Enable or disable skin feature&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandWpEnabled&#34;: true, // Enable or disable refreshing command&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandKillEnabled&#34;: true, // Enable or disable kill command&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandKnife&#34;: &#34;knife&#34;, // Name of knife menu command, u can change to for e.g, knives&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandSkin&#34;: &#34;ws&#34;, // Name of skin information command, u can change to for e.g, skins&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandSkinSelection&#34;: &#34;skins&#34;, // Name of skins menu command, u can change to for e.g, weapons&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandRefresh&#34;: &#34;wp&#34;, // Name of skin refreshing command, u can change to for e.g, refreshskins&#xA;&#x9;&#34;CommandKill&#34;: &#34;kill&#34;, // Name of kill command, u can change to for e.g, suicide&#xA;&#x9;&#34;GiveRandomKnife&#34;: false,  // Give random knife to players if they didn&#39;t choose&#xA;&#x9;&#34;GiveRandomSkins&#34;: false  // Give random skins to players if they didn&#39;t choose&#xA;},&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#34;ConfigVersion&#34;: 4  // Don&#39;t touch&#xA;}&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Web install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Requires PHP &amp;gt;= 7.4 &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Tested on php ver &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;8.2.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and nginx webserver)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before using website, make sure the plugin is correctly loaded in cs2 server!&lt;/strong&gt; Mysql tables are created by plugin not by website.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy website to web server &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Folder &lt;code&gt;img&lt;/code&gt; not needed)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&#34;https://steamcommunity.com/dev/apikey&#34;&gt;Steam API Key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fill in database credentials and api key in &lt;code&gt;class/config.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Visit website and login via steam&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Web Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Basic website&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Steam login/logout&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change knife, paint, seed and wear&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Issue on Windows servers, no knives are given.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can&#39;t change knife if it&#39;s equpied in cs2 inventory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can cause incompatibility with plugins/maps which manipulates weapons and knives&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt;&#xA;  **Skins are not changing:** Set FollowCSGOGuidelines to false in cssharp’s core.jcon config &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database error table does not exists:&lt;/strong&gt; Plugin is not loaded or configured with mysql credentials. Tables are auto-created by plugin.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knives are disappearing:&lt;/strong&gt; Set in config GiveKnifeAfterRemove to true&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knives are not changing for players:&lt;/strong&gt; You can&#39;t change knife if you have your own equipped&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Use this plugin at your own risk! Using this may lead to GSLT ban or something else Valve come with. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.counter-strike.net/index.php/server_guidelines/&#34;&gt;Valve Server guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Preview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Nereziel/cs2-WeaponPaints/raw/main/website/preview.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;preview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AliveverCom/WinBrowserCrawler</title>
    <updated>2024-02-27T01:23:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-27:/AliveverCom/WinBrowserCrawler</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AliveverCom/WinBrowserCrawler" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliveverCom/WinBrowserCrawler/main/SiteTaskList.png&#34; alt=&#34;App UI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;==================================== &lt;strong&gt;English:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a web crawler and parser running on Windows. Its usage is very simple and intuitive. You don&#39;t need to have any knowledge of web crawling or development to use this software. Moreover, it provides an intuitive web parsing tool so that you can easily extract high-value content from web pages and analyze websites.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It can support crawling various scales of websites.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It provides many modes:&lt;br&gt; a. Default mode (single PC + file storage) can support 100 websites, with 100,000 pages per website.&lt;br&gt; b. Single-server mode (database + object storage) can support 10,000 websites, with 2 million pages per website.&lt;br&gt; c. Cluster mode (not yet provided), supporting crowdsourcing, can support an unlimited number of websites and pages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It supports multi-language web page crawling and parsing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It incorporates many professional strategies for web crawling.&lt;br&gt; a. It can prevent being blacklisted by target websites due to frequent crawling.&lt;br&gt; b. It allows setting regular refreshes for key web pages, enabling monitoring of news and shopping websites.&lt;br&gt; c. It provides &#34;high-priority rules&#34; to consistently focus on high-value web pages.&lt;br&gt; d. It offers &#34;blacklist rules&#34; to skip those pages deemed worthless.&lt;br&gt; e. It provides &#34;anti-malicious code policies&#34; to bypass website anti-fraud policies.&lt;br&gt; f. It offers anti-malicious refresh rules to minimize waste of your network and computational resources.&lt;br&gt; g. It includes content duplication detection to help save storage space wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It offers customizable web parsing algorithms, and you can inherit and override these algorithms through code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;=======================================&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Deutsch: **&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dies ist ein Web-Crawler und Parser, der auf Windows läuft. Die Verwendung ist sehr einfach und intuitiv. Sie benötigen keine Kenntnisse über Web-Crawler oder Entwicklung, um diese Software zu nutzen. Außerdem bietet sie benutzerfreundliche Tools zum Analysieren von Webseiten, damit Sie problemlos hochwertige Inhalte extrahieren und Websites segmentieren können.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Es kann die Erfassung von Websites in verschiedenen Größenordnungen unterstützen.&lt;br&gt; a. Der Standardmodus (einzelner PC + Dateispeicher) kann 100 Websites mit jeweils 100.000 Seiten unterstützen.&lt;br&gt; b. Der Einzelservermodus (Datenbank + Objektspeicher) kann 10.000 Websites mit jeweils 2 Millionen Seiten unterstützen.&lt;br&gt; c. Ein Cluster-Modus (derzeit nicht verfügbar), der Crowdsourcing unterstützt, kann eine unbegrenzte Anzahl von Websites und Seiten unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Es unterstützt das Erfassen und Analysieren von mehrsprachigen Webseiten.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Es enthält viele professionelle Strategien für Web-Crawler.&lt;br&gt; a. Es kann verhindern, dass die Zielwebsite aufgrund häufiger Abfragen in die Schwarze Liste aufgenommen wird.&lt;br&gt; b. Es ermöglicht das Festlegen regelmäßiger Aktualisierungen von Schlüsselseiten, sodass Sie Nachrichten- und E-Commerce-Websites überwachen können.&lt;br&gt; c. Es bietet &#34;High-Priority-Regeln&#34;, um sich stets auf wertvolle Webseiten zu konzentrieren.&lt;br&gt; d. Es bietet &#34;Blacklist-Regeln&#34;, um wertlose Webseiten zu überspringen.&lt;br&gt; e. Es bietet eine &#34;Anti-Malware-Code-Strategie&#34;, damit Sie nicht durch betrügerische Richtlinien der Websites eingeschränkt werden.&lt;br&gt; f. Es bietet Regeln zur Vermeidung von bösartigen Aktualisierungen, um eine möglichst geringe Verschwendung Ihrer Netzwerk- und Rechenressourcen zu gewährleisten.&lt;br&gt; g. Es bietet eine Funktion zur Überprüfung von Inhaltsduplikaten, um Speicherplatz zu sparen.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Es bietet anpassbare Webseiten-Analysealgorithmen, die Sie durch Code-Erweiterung und Neuladen anpassen können.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;=======================================&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** 中文：**&lt;br&gt; 这是一个运行在windows上的网页爬取器和解析器。 它的使用非常简单直观。你不需要具有任何网页爬虫和开发知识就可以使用该软件。并且它还提供了直观的网页解析工具，以便你可以轻松地提取网页中的高价值内容，并对网站进行分。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;它可以支持各种规模的网站抓取。&lt;br&gt; a. 默认模式（单台PC+文件存储）可以支持 100个网站，并且每个网站100k页。&lt;br&gt; b. 单服务器模式（数据库+对象存储）可以支持10k个网站，每个网站2百万页。&lt;br&gt; c. 集群模式（尚未提供），支持众包，可以支持无限网站，和无限网页。&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;它支持多语言网页抓取和解析。&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;它内置了很多专业的网页爬虫的策略。&lt;br&gt; a. 它可以防止由于频繁抓取而被目标网站加入黑名单。&lt;br&gt; b. 它可以设置定期刷新的重点网页，以便你可以监控新闻网站和购物网站。&lt;br&gt; c. 它提供了“高优先级规则”，以便始终聚焦在高价值网页。&lt;br&gt; d. 它提供了“黑名单规则”，以便跳过那些无价值的网页。&lt;br&gt; e. 它提供了“防恶意代码策略”，以便你可以不受网站的防欺诈政策限制。&lt;br&gt; f. 它提供了防恶意刷新规则，以便尽可能避免你的网络和计算资源被浪费。&lt;br&gt; g. 它提供了内容重复检测，以便帮你尽可能节省存储控件。&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;它提供了定制化的网页解析算法，并且你可以通过代码继承和重载这些算法。&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>