<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-02-27T01:29:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor</title>
    <updated>2025-02-27T01:29:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-02-27:/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Project Auditor is an experimental static analysis tool for Unity Projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Project Auditor&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Project Auditor is a static analysis tool that analyzes assets, settings, and scripts of the Unity project and produces a report containing: Code and Settings diagnostics, the last BuildReport, and assets information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package is available as an experimental package, so it is not ready for production use. The features and documentation in this package might change before it is verified for release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feedback, bug reports and feature requests are more than welcome, please enter them &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to install Project Auditor is to &lt;em&gt;clone&lt;/em&gt; the repository to the &lt;code&gt;Packages&lt;/code&gt; folder of your project. Alternatively, it is possible to clone the repository to a different folder. However, note that in this case you will have to add &lt;code&gt;com.unity.project-auditor&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code&gt;Packages/manifest.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Project Auditor is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor/0.11.0/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;Unity Package Distribution License&lt;/a&gt; as of November 18th 2020. Before then, the MIT license was in play.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information on how to install and use Project Auditor, please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor/0.11.0/Documentation~/index.md&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps required to setup a Unity project for Project Auditor development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Tests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to be able to run (existing or new) tests in VS/Rider or within Unity using TestRunner, it is necessary to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;Test Framework&lt;/code&gt; from Package Manager.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the following lines to your &lt;code&gt;Packages/manifest.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &#34;testables&#34;: [&#xA;    &#34;com.unity.project-auditor&#34;&#xA;  ]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Pull Requests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start a new pull request on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor/compare&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Describe the problem you are trying to solve.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Describe the solution you are trying to implement.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mtrive&#34;&gt;mtrive&lt;/a&gt; as reviewer to the pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create the pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once approved, select &lt;code&gt;Squash and merge&lt;/code&gt; and delete the remote branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure to select &lt;code&gt;Unity-Technologies/ProjectAuditor&lt;/code&gt; as base repository and &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; as base branch when creating the Pull Request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The repository owners are committed to maintaining this repository and ensuring that it continues to adhere to Unity Standards for package development. Individual pull requests may take time to be approved if they contain changes that require the package to be re-validated.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>