<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-26T01:32:37Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>edbmods/EdBPrepareCarefully</title>
    <updated>2022-10-26T01:32:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-26:/edbmods/EdBPrepareCarefully</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/edbmods/EdBPrepareCarefully" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EdB Prepare Carefully, a RimWorld mod&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;EdB Prepare Carefully&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing Translations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more translations, the better--they are a great contribution to the mod community. However, while it is appreciated that people take the time to translate the mod to other languages, it&#39;s difficult to keep up with those contributions. Every addition or change to a translation requires a new release of the mod, and taking on that additional effort is not possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, translation pull requests will not be merged into the project. Please consider creating a standalone translation mod for your language like &lt;a href=&#34;https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1205095547&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. These mods don&#39;t include any code--they simply include the translation resources for a given language. With this approach, you can make changes and additions at your own pace, and you can take on the responsibility of releases for the translation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building Prepare Carefully&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solution file was created using Xamarin Studio/MonoDevelop, but it should also work in Visual Studio. Note that the project targets the older 3.5 version of the .NET framework used by the Unity engine on top of which RimWorld is built.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the solution has dependencies on the following RimWorld DLLs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Assembly-CSharp.dll&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UnityEngine.CoreModule.dll&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UnityEngine.IMGUIModule&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UnityEngine.InputLegacyModule&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UnityEngine.TextRenderingModule&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copy those dependencies from the RimWorld game directory into the &#34;Libraries&#34; directory. Be sure to make &lt;em&gt;copies&lt;/em&gt; of the originals--don&#39;t accidentally move/delete them from the original game directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The solution also has a dependency on the following third-party DLL:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;0Harmony.dll&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Harmony DLL is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pardeike/Harmony/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/pardeike/Harmony/releases&lt;/a&gt; and should also be placed in the &#34;Libraries&#34; directory. Prepare Carefully uses version 2.0.0.8 of Harmony. When you download Harmony, you&#39;ll see multiple versions of the DLL organized into various directories. Be sure to use the one in the &#34;Release/net472&#34; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only if you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; create a build that also supports RimWorld 1.0, you will need to get the DLL from the latest Prepare Carefully release for 1.0, along with the DLL for Harmony &lt;em&gt;1.2&lt;/em&gt;. Place these DLLs into the &lt;code&gt;Resources/Assemblies&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The result of the build will be the following DLL:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;EdBPrepareCarefully.dll&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This DLL must be packaged alongside the contents of the &lt;code&gt;Resources&lt;/code&gt; directory to create a working mod. The DLL built by the project should be placed inside a &lt;code&gt;1.1/Assemblies&lt;/code&gt; directory along with the Harmony DLL. The directory structure should look like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;+ EdBPrepareCarefully&#xA;  + 1.1&#xA;    + Assemblies&#xA;      - 0Harmony.dll&#xA;      - EdBPrepareCarefully.dll&#xA;  + About&#xA;  + Assemblies&#xA;  + Defs&#xA;  + Languages&#xA;  + Textures&#xA;  - CHANGLELOG.txt&#xA;  - LICENSE&#xA;  - LoadFolders.xml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If Windows is the OS on which you&#39;re developing, you don&#39;t need to manually create the mod directory. Instead, you can automatically package up the mod by running the &lt;code&gt;dist.bat&lt;/code&gt; script. This will copy all of the mod resources and the DLL into a &lt;code&gt;dist/EdBPrepareCarefully&lt;/code&gt; directory. Copy this &lt;code&gt;EdBPrepareCarefully&lt;/code&gt; directory into your RimWorld &lt;code&gt;Mods&lt;/code&gt; folder to use the mod in your game.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Versioning&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prepare Carefully uses a versioning scheme inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;http://semver.org/&#34;&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt; that combines the major/minor version of RimWorld with the major/minor version of the mod to end up with the following format:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;{RimWorld major version}.{RimWorld minor version}.{mod version for this RimWorld version}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other conventions used to determine the mod version numbers:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mod version numbers always start at &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; and never start at &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some examples:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0.18.2&lt;/strong&gt;: The second release of the mod for the Beta 18 version of RimWorld&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.0.11&lt;/strong&gt;: The eleventh release of the mod for RimWorld 1.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1.1&lt;/strong&gt;: The first release of the mod for RimWorld 1.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>