<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-08T01:24:49Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ascpixi/smolsharp</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T01:24:49Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-08:/ascpixi/smolsharp</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ascpixi/smolsharp" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🐜 Extremely small standalone C# executables using NativeAOT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;🐜 SmolSharp&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SmolSharp is a repository that demonstrates the ability to use NativeAOT to build extremely small binaries without any kind of external utility or linker. For example, for a simple hello world program, by default, NAOT produces a binary that is &lt;code&gt;2998272&lt;/code&gt; bytes in size with the following properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;PublishAot&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/PublishAot&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;Optimize&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/Optimize&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;OptimizationPreference&amp;gt;Size&amp;lt;/OptimizationPreference&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;PublishTrimmed&amp;gt;true&amp;lt;/PublishTrimmed&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;code&gt;SmolSharp.props&lt;/code&gt; file being imported, the compiler produces a binary that is only &lt;code&gt;2069&lt;/code&gt; bytes in size - a 0.07% of the original file-size.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Project Name&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Binary size&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;HelloWorld&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;2069 B&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;A console program that outputs &#34;Hello World&#34;.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Mandelbrot&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;3197 B&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;A windowed program that renders a fractal (the Mandelbrot set).&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Ocean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;7629 B&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;A windowed OpenGL program that renders a ray-marched stylized ocean.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ascpixi/smolsharp/assets/44982772/c70e1e20-7cef-473d-bbf5-67079bec2487&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ascpixi/smolsharp/assets/44982772/c70e1e20-7cef-473d-bbf5-67079bec2487&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h6&gt;Screen capture of the Ocean demo&lt;/h6&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does it work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the functionality of SmolSharp is contained in the &lt;code&gt;SmolSharp.props&lt;/code&gt; file. The following techniques are employed in order to achieve minimal binary sizes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom standard library&lt;/strong&gt; - SmolSharp uses the BFlat zerolib standard library, serving as the primary size-saving technique. However, this results in the lack of any kind of GC and removes all built-in BCL classes and functionality, requiring the use of raw P/Invokes to interface with Windows&#39; APIs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw P/Invokes&lt;/strong&gt; - all external &lt;code&gt;[DllImport]&lt;/code&gt; declarations are specified in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;DirectPInvoke&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; list in the MSBuild &lt;code&gt;.props&lt;/code&gt; file, removing the need for a dynamic loader. To prevent redundant &lt;code&gt;RhpReversePInvoke&lt;/code&gt; calls, every &lt;code&gt;[DllImport]&lt;/code&gt; is marked with the &lt;code&gt;[SuppressGCTransition]&lt;/code&gt; attribute.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ILC configuration&lt;/strong&gt; - several MSBuild properties instruct the IL compiler (ILC) to optimize and generate code with binary size as its top priority. All Win32 resources (usually embedded in the &lt;code&gt;.rsrc&lt;/code&gt; section) are omitted by setting the internal property &lt;code&gt;_Win32ResFile&lt;/code&gt; to an empty string, in a target that executes before the &lt;code&gt;LinkNative&lt;/code&gt; target.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Native object file manipulation&lt;/strong&gt; - the alignment of all sections in the native object file is set to their minimum accepted value using &lt;code&gt;objcopy&lt;/code&gt;. Additionally, since no exception handling is used, the SEH exception data directory (the &lt;code&gt;.pdata&lt;/code&gt; section) is removed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linker flags&lt;/strong&gt; - several MSVC linker flags are specified, significantly reducing the size of the final binary image: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/align:16&lt;/code&gt; - sets section alignment to 16 bytes, which, based on testing, is the minimum accepted value&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/manifestuac:no&lt;/code&gt; - forces the linker to never embed any UAC manifest&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/opt:ref /opt:icf&lt;/code&gt; - enables linker reference optimization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/safeseh:no&lt;/code&gt; - allows the linker to skip embedding SEH data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/emittoolversioninfo:no&lt;/code&gt; - removes linker/compiler version information (the Rich header). &lt;strong&gt;Undocumented.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/emitpogophaseinfo&lt;/code&gt; - removes the debug directory from the final output. &lt;strong&gt;Undocumented.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/nodefaultlib&lt;/code&gt; - excludes CRT libraries from the binary&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/fixed&lt;/code&gt; - instructs the operating system to load the binary at a static address, disabling relocations and making the linker skip emitting the &lt;code&gt;.reloc&lt;/code&gt; section&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/merge:.modules=.rdata&lt;/code&gt; - merges the &lt;code&gt;.modules&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.rdata&lt;/code&gt; sections due to their identical attributes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finishing touches&lt;/strong&gt; - all trailing null bytes are stripped from the binary. Please note that this is not bound to MSBuild - this can also be achieved with calling &lt;code&gt;ilc&lt;/code&gt; calling the linker manually, as demonstrated by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MichalStrehovsky/zerosharp&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;MichalStrehovsky/zerosharp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ascpixi/smolsharp/main/#How-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work&lt;/a&gt; section, the lack of GC means that object allocations are frowned upon, and should be disposed of manually, similarly to C. As all of the BCL classes are missing, this also means that they have to be either re-implemented, or alternatives like the host OS&#39;s built-in APIs need to be used. This project also only works on Windows - it depends on importing Win32 classes, and assumes the output binary format is PE, which is only majorly supported by NT-based OS&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Potential improvements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As this repository focuses on avoiding any kind of external tools, the default MSVC linker was used. However, specialized linkers such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/runestubbe/Crinkler&#34;&gt;Crinkler&lt;/a&gt; can be used in order to compress the whole binary and avoid any unnecessary sections.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to build any given project, simply type in:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34;&gt;dotnet publish -r win-x64 -c release&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the OpenGL ocean demo, you can quickly compress a GLSL fragment shader using the &lt;code&gt;ShaderCompressor&lt;/code&gt; project, included with the repository. The shader compressor is a simple C++ program that calls into Windows&#39;s built-in cabinet compression API in order to create byte arrays that can then be consumed by the compiled application. It&#39;s recommended to also minify your shader - for example, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/laurentlb/Shader_Minifier&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;laurentlb/Shader_Minifier&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;shaderpkg&lt;/code&gt; batch file will use the &lt;code&gt;shader_minifier&lt;/code&gt; binary in the &lt;code&gt;./tools&lt;/code&gt; directory. The main fragment shader for &lt;code&gt;SmolSharp.Ocean&lt;/code&gt; is located in &lt;code&gt;./src/SmolSharp.Ocean/Shaders/frag.glsl&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>xuetaolu/URP_ASE_Tutorial</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T01:24:49Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-08:/xuetaolu/URP_ASE_Tutorial</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/xuetaolu/URP_ASE_Tutorial" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amplify Shader Editor Tutorial with Universal Render Pipeline&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;URP_ASE_Tutorial&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amplify Shader Editor Tutorial with Universal Render Pipeline&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>googleads/googleads-mobile-unity</title>
    <updated>2023-09-08T01:24:49Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-08:/googleads/googleads-mobile-unity</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/googleads/googleads-mobile-unity" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Official Unity Plugin for the Google Mobile Ads SDK&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Google Mobile Ads Unity Plugin&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Google Mobile Ads SDK is the latest generation in Google mobile advertising featuring refined ad formats and streamlined APIs for access to mobile ad networks and advertising solutions. The SDK enables mobile app developers to maximize their monetization in native mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the source code for the Google Mobile Ads Unity plugin. This plugin enables Unity developers to easily serve Google Mobile Ads on Android and iOS apps without having to write Java or Objective-C code. The plugin provides a C# interface for requesting ads that is used by C# scripts in your Unity project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Downloads&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github.com/googleads/googleads-mobile-unity/releases&#34;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt; for the latest official version of the plugin.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instructions on using the plugin, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/developers.google.com/admob/unity/quick-start&#34;&gt;this developer guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a sample application demonstrating how to use Google Mobile Ads see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googleads/googleads-mobile-unity/tree/main/samples&#34;&gt;The HelloWorld Unity project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Suggesting improvements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To file bugs, make feature requests, or to suggest other improvements, please use &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github.com/googleads/googleads-mobile-unity/issues&#34;&gt;github&#39;s issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to also join the developer community on &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/groups.google.com/forum/#!categories/google-admob-ads-sdk/game-engines&#34;&gt;our forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>