<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-07-01T01:30:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>TheAirBlow/HyperSploit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-01T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-01:/TheAirBlow/HyperSploit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TheAirBlow/HyperSploit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bypasses HyperOS restrictions on bootloader unlocking&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HyperSploit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a simple zero depedencies utility to bypass HyperOS restrictions on bootloader unlocking.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why another tool?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This tool is much more user-friendly, is a single file and has zero dependencies&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HyperSploit ships with an older version of Settings to rollback in case you have a patched version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This repo is licenced under an open-source licence instead of all rights reserved.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlocking the bootloader is your responsibility. &lt;br&gt; By using this tool you acknowledge that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Software might stop working properly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can accidentally brick your device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Data that wasn&#39;t backed up will be lost&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Warranty &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be voided&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Each account can only unlock 1 phone per year.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Xiaomi must not have forced your account or device to go through qualification&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A valid SIM-card must be inserted with access to the internet&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You&#39;re running an official version of HyperOS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bypass&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open developer settings and open Mi Unlock Status&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Request unlocking, it will for whatever reason log everything necessary to forge the binding request ourselves &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Xiaomi recently patched it out - they switched to RSA with the private key unknown.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can still rollback to an earlier Settings app though - and it works perfectly!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The tool will prompt you to try and rollback if it detects a patched version.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We disable mobile internet and send a forged request &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;ROM version is modified to be MIUI 14 instead of HyperOS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It might fail due to even more random and arbitrary restrictions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.miui.com/unlock/index.html&#34;&gt;unlocking tool&lt;/a&gt; and check how much you have to wait &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Do not eject the SIM card as the phone will constantly contact Xiaomi&#39;s servers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Do not bind the account to another device or re-bind the same one.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Error trying to downgrade the settings app&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you get &lt;code&gt;Failure [INSTALL_FAILED_USER_RESTRICTED: Install canceled by user]&lt;/code&gt; at this stage, make sure to do the following in developer options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable &lt;code&gt;Install via USB&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable &lt;code&gt;USB debugging (Security Settings)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Near the end of the page, tap &lt;code&gt;Reset to default values&lt;/code&gt; 5 times&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After more options appear, disable &lt;code&gt;Turn on system optimization&lt;/code&gt; (if it still fails, you may need to reboot)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: If you&#39;re on MacOS or on Linux, install ADB and add it to &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download latest binary from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheAirBlow/HyperSploit/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; for your OS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect your Xiaomi device and run the executable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Why does the unlock tool still remind me to wait for N hours? &lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; This tool only bypasses HyperOS restrictions, you still have to comply with MIUI&#39;s.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; I see &lt;code&gt;Couldn&#39;t verify, wait a minute or two and try again&lt;/code&gt; on my device. Why? &lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; This is normal behaviour, don&#39;t worry. We intentionally cut it off to forge a binding request ourselves.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licence&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licenced under &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheAirBlow/HyperSploit/raw/main/LICENCE&#34;&gt;Mozilla Public License Version 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MlgmXyysd&#34;&gt;MlgmXyysd&lt;/a&gt; for making &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MlgmXyysd/Xiaomi-HyperOS-BootLoader-Bypass&#34;&gt;Xiaomi-HyperOS-BootLoader-Bypass&lt;/a&gt; on which this tool is largely based on&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>