<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-06T01:32:03Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>paulov-t/SIT.Core</title>
    <updated>2023-06-06T01:32:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-06:/paulov-t/SIT.Core</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An Escape From Tarkov BepInEx module designed to be used with SPT-Aki with the ultimate goal of &#34;Offline&#34; Coop&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1 style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt; SIT.Core &lt;/h1&gt; An Escape From Tarkov BepInEx module designed to be used with SPT-Aki with the ultimate goal of &#34;Offline&#34; Coop &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Stay in Tarkov project was born due to Battlestate Games&#39; (BSG) reluctance to create the pure PvE version of Escape from Tarkov. The project&#39;s aim is simple, create a Cooperation PvE experience that retains progression. If BSG decide to create the ability to do this on live, this project will be shut down immediately.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must buy the game to use this. You can obtain it here. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.escapefromtarkov.com&#34;&gt;https://www.escapefromtarkov.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is by no means designed for cheats (this project was made because cheats have destroyed the Live experience)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is by no means designed for illegally downloading the game (and has blocks for people that do!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is purely for educational purposes (I am using this to learn Unity, Reverse Engineering &amp;amp; Networking)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I am in no way affiliated with BSG or others (on Reddit or Discord) claiming to be working on a project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/N4N2IQ7YJ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/img/githubbutton_sm.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;ko-fi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please be aware. The Ko-Fi link is buying me a coffee, nothing else!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I do not have some special subset of code that makes it work beyond what is here on GitHub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please do not hand over money expecting help or a solution&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is a hobby, for fun, project. Please don&#39;t treat it seriously.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I do not BS the community. I know this is a semi-broken attempt but will attempt to fix as best I can.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pull Requests are encouraged!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SPT-AKI Requirement&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stay in Tarkov works requires the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.sp-tarkov.com/SPT-AKI/Server&#34;&gt;latest AKI Server&lt;/a&gt; to run. You can learn about SPT-Aki &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sp-tarkov.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DO NOT INSTALL THIS ON TO SPT-Aki CLIENT! ONLY INSTALL THE SERVER!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup Manuals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HAMACHI &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core/raw/master/SETUP-HAMACHI.md&#34;&gt;SETUP-Hamachi.md Document by ppyLEK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Standard (Port Forwarding) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core/raw/master/SETUP-STANDARD.md&#34;&gt;SETUP-Standard.md Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extra Documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core/raw/master/HOSTING.md&#34;&gt;HOSTING.md Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Coop&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Coop Summary&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE AWARE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Coop is in early stages of development.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Most features work (ish) and it is &#34;playable (ish) with likely bugs&#34;. &#34;Playable&#34; and perfect are two very different things. Expect lag (desync), issues and bugs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;My tests have included all maps. The maps that work best are Factory and Labs. Performance is very dependant on the CPU / Internet on the Server and Clients and AI count on the Server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More Information on HOSTING &amp;amp; COOP is in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core/raw/master/HOSTING.md&#34;&gt;HOSTING.md Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PREREQUISITE&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You must have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Aki-Server-Mod&#34;&gt;SPT-Aki mod&lt;/a&gt; installed in your Server for this module to work. If you do not wish to use the Coop module, you must disable it in the BepInEx config file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Can Coop use BSG code?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. BSG server code is hidden from the client for obvious reasons. So BSG&#39;s implementation of Coop use the same online servers as PvPvE. We don&#39;t see this, so we cannot use this.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Coding explanation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The project uses multiple methods of BepInEx Harmony patches coupled with Unity Components to achieve its aims.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Features/Methods that require constant polling between Client-&amp;gt;Server-&amp;gt;Client (Move, Rotate, Look, etc) use Components to send data (AI code runs the Update/LateUpdate command and the function every tick, therefore causing network flood).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Features/Methods that can easily be &#34;replicated&#34; use ModuleReplicationPatch abstract class to easily round trip the call.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All server communication is via JSON TCP Http and Web Socket calls to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.sp-tarkov.com/SPT-AKI/Server&#34;&gt;&#34;Web Server&#34; developed by SPT-Aki&lt;/a&gt; using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/paulov-t/SIT.Aki-Server-Mod&#34;&gt;typescript mod&lt;/a&gt; to handle the &#34;backend&#34; work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CoopGameComponent is attached to the GameWorld object when a Coop ready game is started (any game that isn&#39;t Hideout). CoopGameComponent polls the Server for information and passes the data to the PlayerReplicatedComponent.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SPT-Aki&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Are Aki Modules supported?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following Aki Modules are supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;aki-core&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Aki.Common&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Aki.Reflection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;50/50 on SPT-AKI Client mods. This is dependant on how well written the patches are. If they directly target GCLASSXXX or PUBLIC/PRIVATE then they will likely fail.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why don&#39;t you use Aki Module DLLs?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SPT-Aki DLLs are written specifically for their own Deobfuscation technique and my own technique is not working well with Aki Modules at this moment in time. So I ported many of SPT-Aki features into this module. My end-goal would be to rely on SPT-Aki and for this to be solely focused on SIT only features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to compile?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/paulov-t/SIT.Core/master/COMPILE.md&#34;&gt;Compiling Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to install BepInEx&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.bepinex.dev/articles/user_guide/installation/index.html&#34;&gt;https://docs.bepinex.dev/articles/user_guide/installation/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install to Tarkov&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BepInEx 5 must be installed and configured first (see How to install BepInEx) Place the built .dll in the BepInEx plugins folder&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Test in Tarkov&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Browse to where BepInEx is installed within your Tarkov folder&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open config&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open BepInEx.cfg&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change the following setting [Logging.Console] Enabled to True&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save the config file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run Tarkov through a launcher or bat file like this one (replacing the token with your ID)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;start ./Clients/EmuTarkov/EscapeFromTarkov.exe -token=pmc062158106353313252 -config={&#34;BackendUrl&#34;:&#34;http://127.0.0.1:6969&#34;,&#34;Version&#34;:&#34;live&#34;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If BepInEx is working a console should open and display the module &#34;plugin&#34; as started&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Thanks List&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SPT-Aki team&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MTGA team&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SPT-Aki Modding Community&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Props (AIBushPatch, AIAwakeOrSleepPatch - Currently unused)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kmyuhkyuk (GamePanulHUD - Unused)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;95% of the original core and single-player functionality completed by SPT-Aki teams. There may be licenses pertaining to them within this source.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;None of my own work is Licensed. This is solely a just for fun project. I don&#39;t care what you do with it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>