<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-29T01:26:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Voland163/TFTV</title>
    <updated>2024-04-29T01:26:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-29:/Voland163/TFTV</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Voland163/TFTV" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Terror from the Void mod for Phoenix Point&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Terror from the Void (TFTV)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terror from the Void is an overhaul mod for Phoenix Point.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;REQUIRES ALL DLC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;COMPATIBLE WITH SAVES FROM OPEN BETA&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DO NOT USE BETTER ENEMIES OR BETTER VEHICLES AS BOTH ARE ALREADY INTEGRATED IN THE MOD.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installation&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Get mod enabler &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SnapshotGames/PPModEnabler&#34;&gt;https://github.com/SnapshotGames/PPModEnabler&lt;/a&gt; (Direct download link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SnapshotGames/PPModEnabler/releases/download/v.1.0/PPModEnabler.zip&#34;&gt;https://github.com/SnapshotGames/PPModEnabler/releases/download/v.1.0/PPModEnabler.zip&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extract this PPModEnabler.zip file into the root folder of your Phoenix Point Installation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Get TFTV &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Voland163/TFTV/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Voland163/TFTV/releases&lt;/a&gt; Get the latest release and extract TFTV.zip into the Mods folder in your Phoenix Point installation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Launch the game Launch Phoenix Point. There will be Mods option in the main menu. From there you can activate and customise TFTV. Then launch campaign in a usual way (New game from in-game main menu).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Common issues and how to solve them&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No Mods tab in Title page: If you have previously used Modnix, make sure it is reverted (run Modnix and click “Revert”).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Error message on activating TFTV: exit the game to desktop and launch it again.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you still have problems, or run into any bugs, please visit our Discord!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A complete reworking of the Phoenix Point campaign, with new characters, story, events and reports, and integrated and rationalised in-game lore, including a revamped Oneiric Delirium from the original release. Written by and for sci-fi horror fans!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Completely redesigned classes, focusing on sharply defined fighting roles and strong class identities, and on removing and rebalancing overpowered synergies from the vanilla classes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fight the nightmarish doubles and replicas of your deceased comrades! Revenants are special Pandoran combat forms invested with the mutilated consciousness of your fallen heroes – they will hunt you relentlessly over the course of your campaign!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modular campaign settings, with both very easy and nightmarishly difficult settings, and more than 20 toggles that allow you to fine tune your playthrough to your liking.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Total rework of Legacy of the Ancients; redesigned missions, automata, and ancient weapons, with unique mechanics and reworked lore integration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Total rework of Kaos Engines; massively expanded marketplace that will now sell you faction research, rebalanced Kaos weaponry, and mercenary soldiers with unique gear and abilities! Vehicles and modules have undergone an extensive redesign, with a focus on expanding and specialising their roles over the course of a campaign.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All other DLCs have been rebalanced or reintegrated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A series of UI changes and QOL improvements - loadable soldier loadouts, helmet visibility toggles, and more!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A reworked final mission, with new mechanics and access to unique support troops depending on your factional alliances.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Void Omens! Semi-randomised modifiers to your strategic campaign, that represent humanity’s slide into a waking nightmare.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AI fixes, a stealth overhaul, over 50 vanilla bug fixes, and many, many more features. TERROR FROM THE VOID is a true reimagining of the vanilla experience from the ground up, made by fans who love Phoenix Point.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trailer:] &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/C4zXqvap21U?si=N4q0mnOQZQYD8hT3&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/C4zXqvap21U?si=N4q0mnOQZQYD8hT3&lt;/a&gt; TftV Discord Server: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/Ypt5p5trNx&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/Ypt5p5trNx&lt;/a&gt; TftV Wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.phoenixpoint.com/Terror_from_the_Void&#34;&gt;http://wiki.phoenixpoint.com/Terror_from_the_Void&lt;/a&gt; GitHubi: GitHub - Voland163/TFTV: Terror from the Void mod for Phoenix Point&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of icons come from the most excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://game-icons.net/&#34;&gt;https://game-icons.net/&lt;/a&gt; Many thanks to the authors!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ADVICE FOR NEW PLAYERS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have added 2 additional difficulties: STORY MODE (super easy mode) and ETERMES (impossibly hard). We have also re-balanced the difficulties in between so that LEGEND is very hard, and ROOKIE is very easy. If you are familiar with the base game and have beaten it on any difficulty level, for a first playthrough of TFTV we recommend playing one difficulty level below that.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are new to Phoenix Point then, 1) welcome!, and 2) try playing on Rookie or Veteran.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also make for a more personalised difficulty setting by adjusting the different options on New Game start. Please note that while some options can be adjusted at any time in the Main Screen (Mods—&amp;gt;TFTV—&amp;gt;Settings), others can only be set when starting a new game.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please join our Discord to share and learn tactics, give feedback or submit bug-reports.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIRD PARTY MODS AND LOCALISATIONS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TFTV is NOT COMPATIBLE with 3rd party mods; some of them will work, some won’t, sometimes it is possible to know if they do, sometimes it is not.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to ensure that your mod is going to be compatible with TFTV, you can check our source code on GitHub (link above) and/or contact us on Discord (link above) if you need any help.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you did a localisation for TFTV that you want to share, please also come over to our Discord and let us know about it so we can include it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you feel like it, you can buy me a coffee at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/voland&#34;&gt;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/voland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports</title>
    <updated>2024-04-29T01:26:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-29:/stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ReadMe&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Info&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: The current release is for EFT &lt;strong&gt;29351&lt;/strong&gt; / SIT &lt;strong&gt;1.10.8854.18454&lt;/strong&gt;. To download mods for the old version, EFT &lt;strong&gt;29197&lt;/strong&gt; / SIT &lt;strong&gt;1.10.8839.30073&lt;/strong&gt;, download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports/releases/tag/2.3&#34;&gt;2.3 release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a pack of all ported mods for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/StayInTarkov.Client&#34;&gt;SIT&lt;/a&gt;. All credit goes to the original mod creators, these are just modified to work with SIT.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports/releases/latest&#34;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; or use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT.Manager.Avalonia&#34;&gt;Manager&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommended).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Before Adding&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read the description carefully of the mod you are installing and take note of the mod&#39;s requirements. For example, do not use SAIN and NoBushESP together, as NoBushESP is already baked into SAIN.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Adding mods&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If any mod in the SIT Manager mods section has &#34;Requires extra files&#34; checked, you need to do the following after using the SIT Manager to install mods (using Sit Manager &amp;gt; select a mod &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Install&lt;/code&gt; button):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure your SIT is up to date by going to &lt;code&gt;SIT Manager &amp;gt; tools &amp;gt; Install SIT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Recommended: Create a backup of your &lt;code&gt;sit-game/BepInEx/&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click the &#39;Mod Page&#39; link in the SIT Manager Mods Info section for the mod with &#34;Requires extra files&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the latest version of the mod from the mod page on SPT AKI hub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the downloaded mod archive (usually &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.rar&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.7z&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Take note of the folders in the archive. Here you will need to do a bit of critical thinking. There are two types of mod files, &lt;em&gt;client&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt;. Generally, when you open a mod archive which has &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; server and client mod files, you will see two folders called &lt;code&gt;BepInEx&lt;/code&gt; (client files) and &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; (server files). &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server&lt;/strong&gt; mod files should be placed in the server folder of SIT under &lt;code&gt;[server directory]/user/mods&lt;/code&gt;. So if the mod archive you downloaded has a folder called &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt; in it, you know you need to click into &lt;code&gt;user&lt;/code&gt;, click into &lt;code&gt;mods&lt;/code&gt;, and there you should see a folder with the name of the mod, e.g. &lt;code&gt;MoreCheckmarksBackend&lt;/code&gt;. You must copy this folder from the mod archive to &lt;code&gt;[server directory]/user/mods&lt;/code&gt;. Note how the directory structure of the server folder and the mod archive usually matches (&lt;code&gt;user/mods/[mod name]&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client&lt;/strong&gt; mod files are similar to the server ones, but they go in a different directory. If you see a &lt;code&gt;BepInEx&lt;/code&gt; folder in your downloaded mod archive, you know there may be client mod files to copy over. First, in the mod archive, click into &lt;code&gt;BepInEx/plugins&lt;/code&gt;. If there is only a &lt;code&gt;.dll&lt;/code&gt; file, &lt;strong&gt;you do not need to do anything else here&lt;/strong&gt;. Do not copy any &lt;code&gt;.dll&lt;/code&gt; files from a mod archive to &lt;code&gt;BepInEx/plugins&lt;/code&gt;!! However, if there are &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; files, you will need those. Copy all of those files/folders (again, make sure you do NOT copy the &lt;code&gt;.dll&lt;/code&gt; file), then navigate to &lt;code&gt;[SIT offline install directory]/BepInEx/plugins&lt;/code&gt; and paste them there. Viola! Client mod files have been installed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Step for Server Mods&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to recent updates to the AKI Server, server mods will not load correctly unless you make a simple modification:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Locate the server mod, in &lt;code&gt;server/user/mods&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the mod folder, there will be a file called &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;, open it up in your text editor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Look for the line that says &lt;code&gt;&#34;akiVersion&#34;&lt;/code&gt;, you will need to change the version to &lt;code&gt;3.8.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Repeat this process for all server mods you have installed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Verification&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you start the game open the &#34;LogOutput.log&#34; file in \BepInEx\ and make sure all the plugins have loaded without errors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT.Manager/pulls&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; with the source code for the mod modified to work with SIT. Make sure that the original license for the mod allows you to redistribute the mod with modifications, and always include said license in the project folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Update the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stayintarkov/SIT-Mod-Ports/raw/master/MasterList.json&#34;&gt;MasterList.json&lt;/a&gt; in your pull request so that the &lt;strong&gt;Manager&lt;/strong&gt; can automatically detect and install the mods, otherwise your PR will be denied.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All credits go to the original authors. These are just ports to make the mods work with SIT. If you don&#39;t want your mod here, please bring it up in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/f4CN4n3nP2&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>