<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-07-07T01:30:15Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>xivdev/Penumbra</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T01:30:15Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-07-07:/xivdev/Penumbra</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/xivdev/Penumbra" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FINAL FANTASY XIV modding, but actually good this time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Penumbra&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Penumbra is a runtime mod loader for FINAL FANTASY XIV, with a bunch of other useful features baked in:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No need to back up your install - mods don&#39;t touch game files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Disable and enable mods without restarting the game&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Resolve conflicts between mods by changing mod order&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Files can be edited and are often replicated in-game after a map change or closing and reopening a window&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Either open an issue here or join us in &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/kVva7DHV4r&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are welcome, but please make an issue first before writing any code. It&#39;s possible what you want to implement is out of scope for this project, or could be reworked so that it would provide greater benefit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TexTools Mods&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Penumbra has support for most TexTools modpacks however this is provided on a best-effort basis and support is not guaranteed. Built in tooling will be added to Penumbra over time to avoid many common TexTools use cases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this project is still a work in progress, you can use it by adding the following URL to the custom plugin repositories list in your Dalamud settings An image-based install (and usage) guide to do this is provided by unaffiliated user Serenity: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reniguide.info/&#34;&gt;https://reniguide.info/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/xlsettings&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Experimental tab&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy and paste the repo.json link below&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the + button&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the &#34;Save and Close&#34; button&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You will now see Penumbra listed in the Available Plugins tab in the Dalamud Plugin Installer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do not forget to actually install Penumbra from this tab.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please do not install Penumbra manually by downloading a release zip and unpacking it into your devPlugins folder. That will require manually updating Penumbra and you will miss out on features and bug fixes as you won&#39;t get update notifications automatically. Any manually installed copies of Penumbra should be removed before switching to the custom plugin respository method, as they will conflict.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xivdev/Penumbra/master/repo.json&#34;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xivdev/Penumbra/master/repo.json&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>