<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-23T01:35:28Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kasper/phoenix</title>
    <updated>2024-06-23T01:35:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-23:/kasper/phoenix</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kasper/phoenix" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lightweight macOS window and app manager scriptable with JavaScript&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Phoenix&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;128&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/Phoenix/Images.xcassets/AppIcon.appiconset/icon_128x128@2x.png&#34; alt=&#34;Phoenix&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightweight macOS window and app manager scriptable with JavaScript. You can also easily use languages which compile to JavaScript such as TypeScript. Phoenix aims for efficiency and a very small footprint. If you like the idea of scripting your own window or app management toolkit with JavaScript, Phoenix is probably going to give you the things you want. With Phoenix you can bind keyboard shortcuts and system events, and use these to interact with macOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Current version: 4.0.1 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Requires: macOS 10.14 or higher&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; the default &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch will always be stable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;highly customisable, write your own configuration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;bind keyboard shortcuts and system events to your callback functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;control and interact with your screens, spaces, mouse, apps and windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;log messages, deliver notifications, display content or ask input with modals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;run external commands like you would in the command line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/releases/download/4.0.1/phoenix-4.0.1.tar.gz&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;See previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/releases/&#34;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install, extract the downloaded archive and just drag-and-drop Phoenix to your &lt;code&gt;Applications&lt;/code&gt; folder. When you run Phoenix for the first time, you will be asked to allow it to control your UI. macOS will ask you to open &lt;code&gt;Privacy &amp;amp; Security&lt;/code&gt; in System Settings. Once open, go to the &lt;code&gt;Accessibility&lt;/code&gt; section and enable with the toggle next to Phoenix. An admin account is required to accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, if you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; installed, you can simply run &lt;code&gt;brew install --cask phoenix&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Uninstall&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To uninstall Phoenix, delete the app from your &lt;code&gt;Applications&lt;/code&gt; folder. The configuration file created by Phoenix itself is located in your home folder. Delete &lt;code&gt;~/.phoenix.js&lt;/code&gt; and any related configurations if desired. For developers, you may also need to delete &lt;code&gt;~/.phoenix.debug.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Application preferences are stored in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Preferences/org.khirviko.Phoenix.plist&lt;/code&gt;. For developers, in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Preferences/org.khirviko.Phoenix.debug.plist&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have used the storage, also delete the file &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Phoenix/storage.json&lt;/code&gt;. Again for developers, you may also need to delete &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Phoenix/storage.debug.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For uninstalling additional support files, see the following folders:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Scripts/org.khirviko.Phoenix.Launcher&#xA;~/Library/Caches/org.khirviko.Phoenix&#xA;~/Library/Containers/org.khirviko.Phoenix.Launcher&#xA;~/Library/HTTPStorages/org.khirviko.Phoenix&#xA;~/Library/WebKit/org.khirviko.Phoenix&#xA;&#xA;# For developers&#xA;~/Library/Application Scripts/org.khirviko.Phoenix.Launcher.debug&#xA;~/Library/Caches/org.khirviko.Phoenix.debug&#xA;~/Library/Containers/org.khirviko.Phoenix.Launcher.debug&#xA;~/Library/HTTPStorages/org.khirviko.Phoenix.debug&#xA;~/Library/WebKit/org.khirviko.Phoenix.debug&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phoenix lives on your status bar (or as a background daemon) and can be scripted in JavaScript (or languages which compile to JavaScript such as TypeScript).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/assets/screenshot.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Phoenix&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kasper.github.io/phoenix/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; to get started with your script. Your script should reside in &lt;code&gt;~/.phoenix.js&lt;/code&gt; — the file will be created when you launch Phoenix for the first time. Alternatively — if you prefer — you may also have your script in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Phoenix/phoenix.js&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~/.config/phoenix/phoenix.js&lt;/code&gt;. For ideas, see what other people have built in their configurations in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/wiki/&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to add your own configuration to the Wiki to show other people the nice things you can do. Previous configurations (&amp;lt;= 1.5) are not compatible with 2.0, see Changelog for what changes are needed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kasper.github.io/phoenix/&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/wiki#examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;Changelog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need some basic knowledge about installing the required languages and tools. If you need help, do not hesitate to ask! To get started, you will need:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Xcode 15 or higher&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Xcode command line tools&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First clone the repository from a terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/kasper/phoenix.git&#xA;cd phoenix&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To develop Phoenix, open &lt;code&gt;Phoenix.xcworkspace&lt;/code&gt; in Xcode. Install Xcode from the App Store, if you do not already have it installed. You will also need Xcode command line tools — you will be prompted for this. Everything else should work as is — you can develop, debug, test, build and run Phoenix straight from Xcode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For code formatting, Phoenix uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://clang.llvm.org/docs/ClangFormat.html&#34;&gt;ClangFormat&lt;/a&gt;. You will need to have it in your path to be able to make sure any code changes align with the formatting rules. If you do not have ClangFormat installed, the build process will simply skip linting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install Phoenix from the source, you will need to build the workspace from a terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;xcodebuild -workspace Phoenix.xcworkspace \&#xA;           -scheme Phoenix \&#xA;           -configuration Release \&#xA;           SYMROOT=&#34;$PWD/build/&#34; \&#xA;           clean build&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once complete, you will find a newly built Phoenix app in &lt;code&gt;build/Release/&lt;/code&gt;. After this, you can follow the normal install guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a debug build, change the &lt;code&gt;-configuration&lt;/code&gt; flag to &lt;code&gt;Debug&lt;/code&gt; in the above command. This will place a debug build of the app in &lt;code&gt;build/Debug&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phoenix manages dependencies with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org&#34;&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/a&gt;. Note that you do not need CocoaPods for basic development. However, if you want to install new pods or update existing ones, you will also need:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruby-lang.org&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt; (3.3.3 or higher), it is recommended that you manage Ruby versions with for instance &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rbenv/rbenv/&#34;&gt;rbenv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bundler.io&#34;&gt;Bundler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install Bundler, if you do not already have it installed. To install CocoaPods and its dependencies, use Bundler inside the &lt;code&gt;phoenix&lt;/code&gt; directory to install the required Ruby gems according to the &lt;code&gt;Gemfile&lt;/code&gt;. Once complete, you can install the pods listed in the &lt;code&gt;Podfile&lt;/code&gt; with CocoaPods.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install bundler&#xA;bundle install&#xA;pod install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Objective-C core, Phoenix also uses a JavaScript-based (5.1) library to implement additional features to the API. The minified library is included in the repository in &lt;code&gt;Phoenix/phoenix-min.js&lt;/code&gt; so that everything works as is. However, if you want to develop features for this library, you will also need:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; (22.2.0 or higher), it is recommended that you manage Node.js versions with for instance &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm/&#34;&gt;NVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the development packages listed in &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To build &lt;code&gt;phoenix-min.js&lt;/code&gt; from the source, run the command &lt;code&gt;npm run build&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory. NPM will then build the source from &lt;code&gt;library/src/&lt;/code&gt; and install the new library to &lt;code&gt;Phoenix/phoenix-min.js&lt;/code&gt;. For convenience, this is also handled automatically by Xcode when you build Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://kasper.github.io/phoenix/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for Phoenix is built from the &lt;code&gt;docs/&lt;/code&gt; directory using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docusaurus.io&#34;&gt;Docusaurus&lt;/a&gt;. To develop the documentation locally, navigate to the directory and run the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm install&#xA;npm start&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contribute to this project by creating issues, pull requests and editing the Wiki. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feedback or just want to say hi, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/issues/&#34;&gt;open an issue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/discussions/&#34;&gt;start a discussion&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kasper@kytkemo.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or message on &lt;a href=&#34;https://threads.net/@kasperhirvikoski/&#34;&gt;Threads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Phoenix is currently being developed by Kasper Hirvikoski (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/&#34;&gt;@kasper&lt;/a&gt;) with the generous help of contributions made by many &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kasper/phoenix/graphs/contributors/&#34;&gt;individuals&lt;/a&gt;. It was originally authored by Steven Degutis (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sdegutis/&#34;&gt;@sdegutis&lt;/a&gt;). As it stands now, it has been rewritten from the ground up by Kasper Hirvikoski.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Released under the MIT License. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kasper/phoenix/master/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>