<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-08T01:39:13Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T01:39:13Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-08:/michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A drop-in universal solution for moving text fields out of the way of the keyboard in iOS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;TPKeyboardAvoiding&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A drop-in universal solution for moving text fields out of the way of the keyboard in iOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a hundred and one proposed solutions out there for how to move &lt;code&gt;UITextField&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UITextView&lt;/code&gt; out of the way of the keyboard during editing -- usually, it comes down to observing &lt;code&gt;UIKeyboardWillShowNotification&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UIKeyboardWillHideNotification&lt;/code&gt;, or implementing &lt;code&gt;UITextFieldDelegate&lt;/code&gt; delegate methods, and adjusting the frame of the superview, or using &lt;code&gt;UITableView&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s &lt;code&gt;scrollToRowAtIndexPath:atScrollPosition:animated:&lt;/code&gt;, but most proposed solutions tend to be quite DIY, and have to be implemented for each view controller that needs it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively universal, drop-in solution: &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UITableView&lt;/code&gt; subclasses that handle everything.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the keyboard is about to appear, the subclass will find the subview that&#39;s about to be edited, and adjust its frame and content offset to make sure that view is visible, with an animation to match the keyboard pop-up. When the keyboard disappears, it restores its prior size.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should work with basically any setup, either a UITableView-based interface, or one consisting of views placed manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also automatically hooks up &#34;Next&#34; buttons on the keyboard to switch through the text fields.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For use with &lt;code&gt;UITableViewController&lt;/code&gt; classes, drop &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView.m&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView.h&lt;/code&gt; into your project, and make your UITableView a &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView&lt;/code&gt; in the xib. If you&#39;re not using a xib with your controller, I know of no easy way to make its UITableView a custom class: The path of least resistance is to create a xib for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For non-UITableViewControllers, drop the &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView.m&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView.h&lt;/code&gt; source files into your project, pop a &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt; into your view controller&#39;s xib, set the scroll view&#39;s class to &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView&lt;/code&gt;, and put all your controls within that scroll view. You can also create it programmatically, without using a xib - just use the TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView as your top-level view.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To disable the automatic &#34;Next&#34; button functionality, change the UITextField&#39;s return key type to anything but UIReturnKeyDefault.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These classes currently adjust the contentInset parameter to avoid content moving beneath the keyboard. This is done, as opposed to adjusting the frame, in order to work around an iOS bug that results in a jerky animation where the view jumps upwards, before settling down. In order to facilitate this workaround, the contentSize is maintained to be at least same size as the view&#39;s frame.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licence (Zlib)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2013 Michael Tyson&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is provided &#39;as-is&#39;, without any express or implied warranty. In no event will the authors be held liable for any damages arising from the use of this software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission is granted to anyone to use this software for any purpose, including commercial applications, and to alter it and redistribute it freely, subject to the following restrictions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The origin of this software must not be misrepresented; you must not claim that you wrote the original software. If you use this software in a product, an acknowledgment in the product documentation would be appreciated but is not required.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Altered source versions must be plainly marked as such, and must not be misrepresented as being the original software.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;This notice may not be removed or altered from any source distribution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael Tyson, A Tasty Pixel&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael@atastypixel.com&#34;&gt;michael@atastypixel.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>apontious/One-Ring-to-Cocoa-Bind-Them-All</title>
    <updated>2022-12-08T01:39:13Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-08:/apontious/One-Ring-to-Cocoa-Bind-Them-All</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apontious/One-Ring-to-Cocoa-Bind-Them-All" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two little sample projects to go along with Edge Cases 30: One Ring to Cocoa-Bind Them All.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;One-Ring-to-Cocoa-Bind-Them-All&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two little sample projects to go along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edgecasesshow.com/030-one-ring-to-cocoa-bind-them-all.html&#34;&gt;Edge Cases 30: One Ring to Cocoa-Bind Them All&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>