<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-29T01:34:06Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>yingwang/Fspot</title>
    <updated>2024-01-29T01:34:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-29:/yingwang/Fspot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yingwang/Fspot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fspot&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CocoaLibSpotify&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CocoaLibSpotify is an Objective-C wrapper around our libspotify library. It provides easy access to libspotify&#39;s features in a friendly, KVC/O compliant Objective-C wrapper.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CocoaLibSpotify requires libspotify.framework, which isn&#39;t included in the repository. The Mac Framework and iOS Library Xcode projects include a build step to download and unpack it from developer.spotify.com automatically. If this fails for some reason, download it manually from developer.spotify.com and unpack it into the project folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the latest release notes in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spotify/cocoalibspotify/raw/master/CHANGELOG.markdown&#34;&gt;CHANGELOG.markdown&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Threading&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of CocoaLibSpotify 2.0, the framework uses an internal threading model to run the libSpotify library on a background thread, allowing your application to remain responsive when libSpotify is experiencing heavy load.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, libSpotify is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; thread-safe, and all methods in CocoaLibSpotify that provide access to libSpotify types are guarded to prevent access from the wrong thread. If you must access libSpotify types directly, first file an issue so we can make a thread-aware API in CocoaLibSpotify for your use case, then make sure you call the relevant API on the correct thread, which &lt;code&gt;SPSession&lt;/code&gt; provides various helper macros for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bad:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sp_artist *artist = …; // An artist.&#xA;SPArtist *artistObj = [SPArtist artistWithArtistStruct:artist inSession:session];&#xA;// ^ The above line will throw an assertion for being called on the wrong queue.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, you should create the object on the correct thread and safely pass it back to the target queue (the main queue if you&#39;re doing UI work) for further use:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;SPDispatchAsync(^{&#xA;&#x9;sp_artist *artist = …; // An artist.&#xA;&#x9;SPArtist *artistObj = [SPArtist artistWithArtistStruct:artist inSession:session];&#xA;&#x9;dispatch_async(dispatch_get_main_queue(), ^{ self.artist = artistObj; });&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CocoaLibSpotify provides three macros to assist with threading:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SPDispatchAsync()&lt;/code&gt; takes a block and executes it asynchronously on the libSpotify thread. It works very much like libdispatch&#39;s &lt;code&gt;dispatch_async&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SPDispatchSyncIfNeeded()&lt;/code&gt; takes a block and executes it synchronously on the libSpotify thread, blocking the current code path until completion. Since the libSpotify thread executes blocks on a first-come, first-served basis, internal work may delay execution for a significant amount of time, so using &lt;code&gt;SPDispatchAsync()&lt;/code&gt; is always recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SPAssertOnLibSpotifyThread()&lt;/code&gt; will throw an assertion when called from anything but the libSpotify thread. This can be useful for debugging code using the libSpotify thread.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;A Note On &#34;Loading&#34;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CocoaLibSpotify does a lot of asynchronous loading — tracks, playlists, artists, albums, etc can all finish loading their metadata after you get an object. In the case of user playlists and searching, this can be a number of seconds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; poll these properties - when you do a polling loop you can, in many cases, stop CocoaLibSpotify&#39;s ability to do any work, causing the metadata to never load.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, most objects in the CocoaLibSpotify object model (including metadata classes like &lt;code&gt;SPArtist&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SPTrack&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SPAlbum&lt;/code&gt;, etc and &#34;action&#34; classes like &lt;code&gt;SPSearch&lt;/code&gt; etc) conform to the &lt;code&gt;SPAsyncLoading&lt;/code&gt; protocol, and you can use the &lt;code&gt;SPAsyncLoading&lt;/code&gt; helper class to get a block callback when the given item(s) are loaded. For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#x9;NSArray *someTracks = …; // Some tracks.&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;[SPAsyncLoading waitUntilLoaded:someTracks timeout:10.0 then:^(NSArray *loadedTracks, NSArray *notLoadedTracks) {&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;NSLog(@&#34;The following tracks are loaded: %@&#34;, loadedTracks);&#xA;&#x9;}];&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, CocoaLibSpotify&#39;s properties are Key-Value Observing compliant, and the best practice is to add an observer to the properties you&#39;re interested in to receive a notification callback when the metadata is loaded.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, if you want to know when search results come back, add an observer like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[self addObserver:self forKeyPath:@&#34;search.tracks&#34; options:0 context:nil];&#xA;self.search = [SPSearch searchWithSearchQuery:@&#34;Hello&#34; inSession:[SPSession sharedSession]];&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the tracks in the search are updated, you&#39;ll get a callback:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- (void)observeValueForKeyPath:(NSString *)keyPath ofObject:(id)object change:(NSDictionary *)change context:(void *)context {&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;if ([keyPath isEqualToString:@&#34;search.tracks&#34;])&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;NSLog(@&#34;Search found tracks: %@&#34;, self.search.tracks);&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key-Value Observing is a core technology in the Mac and iOS SDKs, and extensive documentation and examples can be found in Apple&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.apple.com/library/ios/#documentation/General/Conceptual/DevPedia-CocoaCore/KVO.html&#34;&gt;developer documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building - Mac OS X&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Xcode project requires Xcode 4.5 and Mac OS X 10.7 to build since it uses ARC. However, the built binary can be deployed on 64-bit systems running Mac OS X 10.6 or higher.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The built CocoaLibSpotify.framework contains libspotify.framework as a child framework. Sometimes, Xcode gives build errors complaining it can&#39;t find &amp;lt;libspotify/api.h&amp;gt;. If you get this, manually add the directory libspotify.framework is in to your project&#39;s &#34;Framework Search Paths&#34; build setting. For example, if you&#39;re building the CocoaLibSpotify project alongside your application as an embedded Xcode project then copying it into your bundle, you&#39;d have this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$CONFIGURATION_BUILD_DIR/CocoaLibSpotify.framework/Versions/Frameworks&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you&#39;d point to the downloaded libspotify.framework manually, something like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;../../libspotify-12.1.45-Darwin-universal&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building - iOS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Xcode project requires Xcode 4.5 and iOS SDK version 6.0+ to build since it uses ARC. However, the built binary can be deployed on any iOS version from version 4.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The built libCocoaLibSpotify contains libspotify internally as a static library, as well as all of the required header files in a directory called &#34;include&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, you MUST include SPLoginResources.bundle as a resource of your application.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When including libCocoaLibSpotify in your application, you must also link to the following frameworks:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SystemConfiguration.framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CFNetwork.framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libstdc++&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CoreAudio.framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AudioToolbox.framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AVFoundation.framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, you must add the following two items to the &#34;Other Linker Flags&#34; build setting:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;-all_load&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;-ObjC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re building the CocoaLibSpotify project alongside your application as an embedded Xcode project then linking it with your application in a build step, you can tell Xcode where the header files are by adding the following setting to the &#34;Framework Search Paths&#34; build setting of your project:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$CONFIGURATION_BUILD_DIR/include&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, you can simply add all of the header files to your project manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once everything is set up, simply import the following header to get started with CocoaLibSpotify!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;#import &#34;CocoaLibSpotify.h&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The headers of CocoaLibSpotify are well documented, and we&#39;ve provided an Xcode DocSet to provide documentation right in Xcode. With these and the sample projects, you should have everything you need to dive right in!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, there&#39;s an FAQ &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spotify/cocoalibspotify/raw/master/FAQ.markdown&#34;&gt;right here in the repo&lt;/a&gt; that covers common usage questions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Branching&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All development work is done on the &lt;code&gt;dev&lt;/code&gt; branch. When it&#39;s considered stable, it&#39;s merged to &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; with a new version tag.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Unit Tests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CocoaLibSpotify now ships with a number of unit tests, which run inside a standalone application built by the project. If you find a bug in CocoaLibSpotify, please fork the project, add or modify a unit test &lt;em&gt;on the dev branch&lt;/em&gt; so it fails (demonstrating the bug), then issue a pull request. We can then fix the underlying bug and keep your test so it stays that way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run the tests, open the &#34;CocoaLibSpotify Mac Framework&#34; or &#34;CocoaLibSpotify iOS Library&#34; project as needed, then switch to the &#34;CocoaLSTests&#34; scheme in Xcode. Then:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generate a Base64 representation of your appkey by downloading the binary version (not the C file) from &lt;code&gt;developer.spotify.com&lt;/code&gt; and running the following command on it: &lt;code&gt;openssl base64 -in spotify_appkey.key | tr -d &#39;\n&#39;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit the scheme to pass the following arguments on launch: &lt;code&gt;-TestUserName &amp;lt;Your username&amp;gt; -TestPassword &amp;lt;Your password&amp;gt; -AppKey &amp;lt;Base64 appkey&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the &#34;CocoaLSTests&#34; target.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll find examples on how to make a good test in the tests themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems or find any bugs, see our GitHub page for known issues and discussion. For usage questions, please open a question on Stack Overflow with the &lt;code&gt;spotify&lt;/code&gt; tag. Otherwise, we may be available in irc://irc.freenode.net/spotify.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>batosai/CJString</title>
    <updated>2024-01-29T01:34:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-29:/batosai/CJString</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/batosai/CJString" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;NSString category divers helpers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;#NSString+CJString&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NSString category divers helpers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;##Example usage Create slug:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = @&#34;My title&#34;;&#xA;NSLog(@&#34;%@&#34;, [title toSlug]); // return my-title&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Count number occurences in string:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;NSString *title = @&#34;My title&#34;;&#xA;NSLog(@&#34;%i&#34;, [title countOccurencesOfString:@&#34;title&#34;]); // return 1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Creators&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/batosai&#34;&gt;Jérémy Chaufourier&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/chaufourier&#34;&gt;@chaufourier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>zendesk/answer_bot_sdk_ios</title>
    <updated>2024-01-29T01:34:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-29:/zendesk/answer_bot_sdk_ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zendesk/answer_bot_sdk_ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Answer Bot SDK for iOS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Use of this software is subject to important terms and conditions as set forth in the License file&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zendesk/answerbot_sdk_ios&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zendesk/answer_bot_sdk_ios/master/logo/png/AB.png&#34; alt=&#34;AnswerBot&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Your Virtual Customer Assistant.&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Zendesk Answer Bot SDK for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer Bot SDK for mobile is a quick, convenient way to get customer support into your mobile apps. With just a few lines of code, you can provide your end users with answers to their questions instantly. Answer Bot uses machine learning to suggest Help Center articles based on the user&#39;s question.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- ## Demo Applications&#xA;&#xA;There are a number of simple demo applicaitons [here](https://github.com/zendesk/ios_sdk_demo_apps). --&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Integration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use this library in your project you can use CocoaPods, or integrate it manually:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can integrate Answer Bot in your &lt;code&gt;Podfile&lt;/code&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pod &#39;ZendeskAnswerBotSDK&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;The old &lt;code&gt;AnswerBotSDK&lt;/code&gt; has been deprecated&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Manual&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Take the Answer Bot &lt;code&gt;.framework&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.bundle&lt;/code&gt; files that live in the &lt;code&gt;AnswerBotSDK/5.1&lt;/code&gt; folder (depending on which version of Swift you are using).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drag them into your project, and link them to your applications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;##documentation&#34;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables/docs/answer-bot-sdk-ios/about&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for the SDK and &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables/docs/answer-bot-sdk-ios/release_notes&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com&#34;&gt;https://developer.zendesk.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature request&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All enhancement, improvement, and feature request suggestions are welcomed. Please submit them to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/community/topics/200488257-Zendesk-SDKs&#34;&gt;SDK community&lt;/a&gt;. We will normally close feature requests posted to this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2018 Zendesk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading or using the Zendesk Mobile SDK, You agree to the Zendesk Master Subscription Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and Application Developer and API License Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and acknowledge that such terms govern Your use of and access to the Mobile SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If You make any Contributions (defined below) to the Zendesk Mobile SDK, You hereby grant Zendesk a royalty-free, worldwide, transferable, sub-licensable, irrevocable and perpetual license to incorporate into the Service or the Zendesk API or otherwise use and commercially exploit any Contributions. “Contribution” shall mean any work of authorship, including any modifications or additions to the Mobile SDK or derivative works thereof, that is submitted to Zendesk by You.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>