<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-31T01:36:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>erndev/EDStarRating</title>
    <updated>2025-03-31T01:36:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-31:/erndev/EDStarRating</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/erndev/EDStarRating" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Configurable Star Rating control for iOS and OSX&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;EDStarRating &lt;img src=&#34;https://go-shields.herokuapp.com/license-BSD-blue.png&#34; alt=&#34;Version Badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A configurable star rating control for OSX and iOS, similar to those found in iTunes and the App Store.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoadocs.org/docsets/EDStarRating&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cocoapod-badges.herokuapp.com/v/EDStarRating/badge.png&#34; alt=&#34;Badge w/ Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoadocs.org/docsets/EDStarRating&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cocoapod-badges.herokuapp.com/p/EDStarRating/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Badge w/ Platform&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;###Installation&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install EDStarRating is via &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocoapods.org&#34;&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/a&gt;. Add this line to your Podfile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;pod &#39;EDStarRating&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and run &lt;code&gt;pod install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also install it manually by copying these two files to your project: EDStarRating.h and EDStarRating.m&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to use EDStarRating, you can instantiate it programmatically, or create a custom view in Interface Builder and assign it to an ivar of your app. Once you have an instance, you can use the control properties to configure it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#xA;  starRating.starImage = [NSImage imageNamed:@&#34;star.png&#34;];&#xA;  starRating.starHighlightedImage = [NSImage imageNamed:@&#34;starhighlighted.png&#34;];&#xA;  starRating.maxRating = 5.0;&#xA;  starRating.delegate = self;&#xA;  starRating.horizontalMargin = 12;&#xA;  starRating.editable=YES;&#xA;  starRating.displayMode=EDStarRatingDisplayFull;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  starRating.rating= 2.5;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;tintColor support in iOS 7&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you pass to the control a template UIImage (created using rendering mode (UIImageRenderingModeAlwaysTemplate), EDStarRating will tint that image using the control&#39;s tintColor property.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Compatiblity&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This control should work in ARC and not ARC projects. On OS X 10.6+ and iOS 4.x+. But it&#39;s only tested it with ARC enabled in 10.8+ and iOS 6.0+. Let me now if it works fine for you in other environments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/erndev/EDStarRating/raw/master/edstarrating.png&#34; alt=&#34;EDStarRating&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/erndev/EDStarRating/raw/master/edstarrating-ios.png&#34; alt=&#34;EDStarRating&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BSD License. Copyright (c) 2014, Ernesto García All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met: * Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. * Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. * Neither the name of the &#xA; &lt;organization&gt;&#xA;   nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.&#xA; &lt;/organization&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &#34;AS IS&#34; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Star icons&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The star icons and backgrounds used in the sample have been created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://strandeddesign.com&#34;&gt;Dan Deming-Henes &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>