<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-12T01:43:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Ingan121/FSUntether</title>
    <updated>2023-06-12T01:43:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-12:/Ingan121/FSUntether</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Ingan121/FSUntether" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fucking Simple Untether for iOS 15-17&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ___________ __  __      __       __  __             &#xA;   / ____/ ___// / / /___  / /____  / /_/ /_  ___  _____&#xA;  / /_   \__ \/ / / / __ \/ __/ _ \/ __/ __ \/ _ \/ ___/&#xA; / __/  ___/ / /_/ / / / / /_/  __/ /_/ / / /  __/ /    &#xA;/_/    /____/\____/_/ /_/\__/\___/\__/_/ /_/\___/_/        &#xA;                    by Ingan121&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fucking Simple Untethered code execution PoC for iOS 15, 16, and 17&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Compatibility is not guaranteed, USE AT YOUR OWN RISK!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get decrypted TestFlight ipa&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rename it to TestFlight.ipa and place it in the same directory as &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build FSUntether with &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt; in the root of the repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the built IPAs as instructed by &lt;code&gt;build.sh&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You&#39;ll need a paid certificate to retain the original &lt;code&gt;com.apple.TestFlight&lt;/code&gt; bundle ID, if you&#39;re not using TrollStore.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FSUntether currently doesn&#39;t work if the bundle ID is changed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Disable USB restricted mode, connect your phone to your Mac or PC, then reboot the device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;iproxy 1338 1338&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nc localhost 1338&lt;/code&gt; in separate terminals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TestFlight app will crash on launch, but the untether will work fine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tested versions and devices: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;iPhone Xs: 15.1, 15.4.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;iPad Pro 12.9 6th gen: 16.1.1, 16.3.1, 16.4, 16.4.1, 16.5, 17.0DB1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;iPhone 14 Pro Max: 16.1.2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On 14.3 (Xs), &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; starts a few seconds after the first unlock, so there&#39;s no BFU code execution. (But there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LinusHenze/Fugu14&#34;&gt;Fugu14&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/asdfugil/haxx&#34;&gt;permasigning haxx&lt;/a&gt; that work BFU on 14, you know.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Versions below 13 are not tested. Note that the latest TestFlight requires iOS 14 or later. I don&#39;t even know if &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; exists on TestFlight for iOS 13 and below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does this work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;code&gt;TestFlight.app&lt;/code&gt; automatically starts on boot, even before first unlock. That&#39;s all &lt;code&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;How did I find this? Just ran sysdiagnose BFU and found this was the only process in &lt;code&gt;/var&lt;/code&gt; that is started before first unlock.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Getting arbitrary code execution was a bit hard though. Directly replacing &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; with permasigned binaries didn&#39;t seem to work, so I had to modify the library it loads.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Unsandboxing Methods&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unsandboxing method varies per version; there are currently four supported build types.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fully unsandboxed code execution with CVE-2022-26766 (permasigning) and FSUntetherGUI &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supported versions: 15.0-15.4.1, 15.5b1-b4, 15.6b1-b5 (AFU supported on 14)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The code injected to &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; launches FSUntetherGUI with &lt;code&gt;SBSOpenSensitiveURLAndUnlock&lt;/code&gt;. This works while locked because FSUntetherGUI is replacing the Magnifier app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;And FSUntetherGUI launches unsandboxed, standalone iDownload as root.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This iDownload is completely unsandboxed. It can access all the files, execute binaries, kill processes, and so on. Also it isn&#39;t affected by the below lifecycle, running forever on the device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;After launching iDownload, FSUntetherGUI will respring the device to get you back in the lock screen. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ingan121/FSUntether/raw/756c69061d9eb661fe1612c7806902553f8dfb7e/FSUntetherGUI/FSUntetherGUI/FSUntetherGUIApp.swift#L30&#34;&gt;related comment&lt;/a&gt; for why.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FSUntetherGUI shows only a black screen when locked. I guess it has to do with the &lt;code&gt;com.apple.QuartzCore.secure-mode&lt;/code&gt; entitlement (Magnifier, Camera, Notes, Calculator, etc. have it), but I don&#39;t know how to use it to get the app contents showing when locked.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Semi-unsandboxed code execution with CVE-2022-26766 (permasigning) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supported versions: same as 1.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This unsandbox only has filesystem access. Also, it cannot access some sensitive paths like Calendar.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The latter restriction can be worked around by adding &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ingan121/FSUntether/raw/756c69061d9eb661fe1612c7806902553f8dfb7e/iDownload/entitlements.plist#L48&#34;&gt;these entitlements&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; but I didn&#39;t do that.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Note that adding fully unsandboxing entitlements (like &lt;code&gt;com.apple.private.security.no-container&lt;/code&gt;) to &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; doesn&#39;t work for some reason. Only &lt;code&gt;com.apple.security.exception.files.absolute-path.read-write&lt;/code&gt; works, and this is what this unsandbox is using.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Semi-unsandboxed code execution with CVE-2022-46689 (MacDirtyCow) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supported versions: 15.0-15.7.1, 16.0-16.1.2 (14 and below are NOT supported)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This unsandbox also only has filesystem access and sensitive paths are unavailable either.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;grant_full_disk_access&lt;/code&gt; in iDownload while unlocked to grant the required permissions and get full disk access. After first granting the permission, you can run this command while locked, too.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sandboxed code execution &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supported versions: 15.0-17.0DB1 (AFU supported on 14)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;No unsandboxing at all. Things like &lt;code&gt;ls /var&lt;/code&gt; will fail.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Some notes about the untether&#39;s lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; and the injected code start right after the app is installed. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If the app is signed with an enterprise cert and the cert has not been trusted yet, it doesn&#39;t start at all. It can be started after trusting the cert, and it will start when the app is reinstalled or the device is rebooted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Untether is not that fast. It usually starts 1-3 seconds before or after the Apple logo disappears.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re in Setup.app because of an update, it will not start before first unlock. It starts after unlocking and tapping the first button in Setup.app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The injected code will become dormant a few minutes after starting. The port is still open and you can connect to it but iDownload won&#39;t respond. Nothing gets printed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The code will completely stop more minutes later. The port is also closed and the connection will fail. (But &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt; itself still runs.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The process also randomly gets started in the background. I don&#39;t know the condition and timing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Note: if iproxy prints &lt;code&gt;No connected device found&lt;/code&gt; when the connection is failing, it means your device is not being properly detected. Please check if your device is not USB restricted (Settings → Passcode → Accessories must be ON), the cable is OK, or if some software like VMware is interfering with your connection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Todo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get the original TestFlight functionality working&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Or get FSU working after changing the bundle ID (it doesn&#39;t currently)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find out how to build an executable that can directly replace &lt;code&gt;TestFlightServiceExtension&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find out how to show the GUI app content when locked&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FSUntetherGUI is currently abandoned as I downgraded my Xs to iOS 14.3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LinusHenze&#34;&gt;@LinusHenze&lt;/a&gt; for iDownload from Fugu14 and the CoreTrust exploit&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opa334&#34;&gt;@opa334&lt;/a&gt; for TrollStore&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/comex&#34;&gt;@comex&lt;/a&gt; for sbsutils&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zhuowei&#34;&gt;@zhuowei&lt;/a&gt; for MacDirtyCow codes&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EthanArbuckle/Apollo-CustomApiCredentials</title>
    <updated>2023-06-12T01:43:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-12:/EthanArbuckle/Apollo-CustomApiCredentials</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/EthanArbuckle/Apollo-CustomApiCredentials" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tweak to use your own reddit API credentials in Apollo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Use your own reddit API credentials in Apollo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Creating an API credential:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;sign out of all accounts in Apollo before installing&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sign into your reddit account (on desktop) and go here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/prefs/apps&#34;&gt;https://reddit.com/prefs/apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;code&gt;are you a developer? create an app...&lt;/code&gt; button&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fill in the fields&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;name: Use whatever&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;code&gt;Installed App&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;description: bs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;about url: bs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;redirect uri: &lt;code&gt;apollo://reddit-oauth&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;create app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;After creating the app you&#39;ll get a client identifier; it&#39;ll be a bunch of random characters. Put it in &lt;code&gt;Tweak.m&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;static NSString * const kRedditClientID = @&#34;CLIENT_ID_GOES_HERE&#34;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;build and install&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now Apollo will still use the original API creds for other services (like imgur), but i&#39;ll update this to support replacing those as well&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>zendesk/sdk_conversation_kit_ios</title>
    <updated>2023-06-12T01:43:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-12:/zendesk/sdk_conversation_kit_ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zendesk/sdk_conversation_kit_ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The ZendeskSDKConversationKit library for communicating with the Zendesk Sunshine Conversations backend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Use of this software is subject to important terms and conditions as set forth in the License file&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ZendeskSDKConversationKit for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ZendeskSDKConversationKit library is used to communicate with the Zendesk Sunshine Conversations backend in iOS projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find our documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&#34;&gt;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature requests and issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All feature requests and issues are welcomed. Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zendesk/sdk_conversation_kit_ios/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to find out how to contact us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2020 Zendesk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading or using the Zendesk ZendeskSDKConversationKit SDK, You agree to the Zendesk Master Subscription Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and Application Developer and API License Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and acknowledge that such terms govern Your use of and access to the ZendeskSDKHTTPClient SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If You make any Contributions (defined below) to the ZendeskSDKConversationKit SDK, You hereby grant Zendesk a royalty-free, worldwide, transferable, sub-licensable, irrevocable and perpetual license to incorporate into the Service or the Zendesk API or otherwise use and commercially exploit any Contributions. “Contribution” shall mean any work of authorship, including any modifications or additions to the Mobile SDK or derivative works thereof, that is submitted to Zendesk by You.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>