<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-26T01:39:42Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ChrisRisner/iOS-MobileServices-TicTacToeLeaderboard</title>
    <updated>2023-04-26T01:39:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-26:/ChrisRisner/iOS-MobileServices-TicTacToeLeaderboard</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ChrisRisner/iOS-MobileServices-TicTacToeLeaderboard" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repo will house an iOS tic tac toe game which uses Mobile Services to maintain a leaderboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;iOS - Mobile Services - Tic Tac Toe Leaderboard&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an iOS leaderboard sample which makes use of Windows Azure Mobile Services for it&#39;s data storage. It will track different player&#39;s wins, losses, and ties from playing a game of Tic Tac Toe. This sample was built using XCode, the iOS Framework, and the iOS Mobile Services SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below you will find requirements and deployment instructions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OSX - This sample was built on OSX Lion (10.7.4) but should work with more current releases of OSX.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;XCode - This sample was built with XCode 4.4 and requires at least XCode 4.0 due to use of storyboards and ARC.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows Azure Account - Needed to create and run the Mobile Service. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.windowsazure.com/en-us/pricing/free-trial/&#34;&gt;Sign up for a free trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Source Code Folders&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;/source/start - This contains code for the application prior to adding in Mobile Services.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;/source/end - This contains code for the application with Mobile Services and requires client side changes noted below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;/source/scripts - This contains server side scripts you&#39;ll need to set on your Mobile Service as noted below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#Setting up your Mobile Service After creating your Mobile Service in the Windows Azure Portal, you&#39;ll need to create a table named &#34;PlayerRecords&#34;. After creating that table, alter it&#39;s insert and read scripts using the following scripts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;/source/scripts/PlayerRecords.insert.script&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;/source/scripts/PlayerRecords.read.script&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#Client Application Changes In order to run the client applicaiton, you&#39;ll need to change a few settings in your application. After opening the source code in Xcode, open the TicTacToeService.m file. Find the init method and change the &amp;lt;YourMobileServiceUrl&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;YourApplicationKey&amp;gt; to match the values from the Mobile Service you&#39;ve created.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For additional questions or feedback, please contact the &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:chrisner@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;team&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>