<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-02T01:36:50Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HexFiend/HexFiend</title>
    <updated>2022-12-02T01:36:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-02:/HexFiend/HexFiend</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HexFiend/HexFiend" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A fast and clever hex editor for macOS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/HexFiend/HexFiend/master/docs/screenshot.png?raw=true&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Hex Fiend&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A fast and clever open source hex editor for macOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the latest version from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ridiculousfish/HexFiend/releases&#34;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ridiculousfish/HexFiend/workflows/CI/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;CI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insert, delete, rearrange.&lt;/strong&gt; Hex Fiend does not limit you to in-place changes like some hex editors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work with huge files.&lt;/strong&gt; Hex Fiend can handle as big a file as you’re able to create. It’s been tested on files as large as 118 GB.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small footprint.&lt;/strong&gt; Hex Fiend does not keep your files in memory. You won’t dread launching or working with Hex Fiend even on low-RAM machines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast.&lt;/strong&gt; Open a huge file, scroll around, copy and paste, all instantly. Find what you’re looking for with fast searching.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary diff.&lt;/strong&gt; Hex Fiend can show the differences between files, taking into account insertions or deletions. Simply open two files in Hex Fiend and then use the File &amp;gt; Compare menus.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart saving.&lt;/strong&gt; Hex Fiend knows not to waste time overwriting the parts of your files that haven’t changed, and never needs temporary disk space.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data inspector.&lt;/strong&gt; Interpret data as integer or floating point, signed or unsigned, big or little endian.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary templates.&lt;/strong&gt; Visualize the structure of a file through scripting. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ridiculousfish/HexFiend/tree/master/templates&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embeddable!&lt;/strong&gt; It’s really easy to incorporate Hex Fiend’s hex or data views into your app using the Hex Fiend framework. Its permissive BSD-style license won’t burden you. See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ridiculousfish.com/hexfiend/docs/&#34;&gt;API reference&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>