<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-09T01:30:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>infracost/vscode-infracost</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/infracost/vscode-infracost</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;See cost estimates for Terraform right in your editor💰📉&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Infracost VSCode Extension&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Infracost&#39;s VSCode extension shows you cost estimates for Terraform right in your editor! Prevent costly infrastructure changes before they get into production.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Infracost&#39;s extension shows a snapshot of the total cost of resources right above their Terraform definitions. Infracost&#39;s output updates on file save. This helps with a few use-cases:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare configs, instance types, regions etc&lt;/strong&gt;: copy/paste a code block, make changes and compare them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick cost estimate&lt;/strong&gt;: write a code block and get a cost estimate without having to use AWS, Google or Azure cost calculators, or read the long/complicated pricing web pages.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catch costly typos&lt;/strong&gt;: if you accidentally type 22 instead of 2 as the instance count, or 1000GB volume size instead of 100, the cost estimate will immediately pick that up and let you know.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/resources.gif?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;code&gt;resource&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;module&lt;/code&gt; blocks support showing cost estimates. Infracost&#39;s VSCode extension even supports showing prices on &lt;strong&gt;3rd party module blocks&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/modules.gif?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a simple monthly cost isn&#39;t enough for you, just click the overview to show a detailed breakdown of what components affect the price.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/webview.gif?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the video below to see the Infracost extension in action!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/6455139/169564807-320bbbf7-647f-4248-882f-2a6bbf9449b2.mp4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/videooverlay.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Extension Demo&#34;&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. Install Infracost CLI&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/#1-install-infracost&#34;&gt;this step&lt;/a&gt; to install the Infracost CLI, which is used by this VSCode extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;2. Get an API key&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/#2-get-api-key&#34;&gt;this step&lt;/a&gt; to get a free API key that&#39;s used by the CLI to get prices from our Cloud Pricing API, e.g. get prices for instance types.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No cloud credentials or secrets are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/faq/#what-data-is-sent-to-the-cloud-pricing-api&#34;&gt;sent&lt;/a&gt; to the API and you can also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/cloud_pricing_api/self_hosted/&#34;&gt;self-host&lt;/a&gt; it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Infracost does not make any changes to your Terraform state or cloud resources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;3. Install VSCode extension&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open VSCode and install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Infracost.infracost&#34;&gt;Infracost extension&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will also install the the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=HashiCorp.terraform&#34;&gt;Hashicorp Terraform extension&lt;/a&gt; extension if you don&#39;t already have it. &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/infracost-install.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4. Use extension&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigate to any Terraform file, if you&#39;ve done the prior steps correctly you&#39;ll see costs above &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/supported_resources/overview/&#34;&gt;supported blocks&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/maintf.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Infracost VSCode extension requires you to have:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;VSCode &lt;strong&gt;v1.67.0&lt;/strong&gt; or above.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Infracost CLI version &lt;strong&gt;v0.10.6&lt;/strong&gt; or above &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs&#34;&gt;installed&lt;/a&gt; and registered with a valid API key.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=HashiCorp.terraform&#34;&gt;Terraform VSCode extension&lt;/a&gt; installed and enabled in VSCode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How can I supply input variables to Infracost VSCode extension?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To supply input variables for your Terraform projects, you must include a var file called &lt;code&gt;terraform.tfvars&lt;/code&gt; at the root level of your Terraform project. Alternatively, you can use several files with the suffix &lt;code&gt;*.auto.tfvars&lt;/code&gt;, e.g. &lt;code&gt;dev.auto.tfvars&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;prod.auto.tfvars&lt;/code&gt;. Currently, only HCL variable files are supported you can follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/infracost/issues/1773&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; for updates on support for JSON variable files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How can I configure the currency Infracost uses?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set the currency, run &lt;code&gt;infracost configure set currency EUR&lt;/code&gt; (or any other ISO 4217 currency code). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/faq/#can-i-show-costs-in-a-different-currency&#34;&gt;This FAQ&lt;/a&gt; has more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When opening a workspace with a large number of Terraform projects for the first time. Infracost will evaluate all the projects and download any required modules. This means that it might take some time before pricing information is available. If you&#39;re worried that Infracost VSCode extension isn&#39;t working in your workspace but haven&#39;t got any error messages, it is likely that Infracost is still indexing your workspace. The extension has a status bar on the right-hand side of the editor which will show a loading state when Infracost is running.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/loading.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Terragrunt is not supported. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/issues/4&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; for more information for future updates about Terragrunt support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Infracost &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/features/usage_based_resources/&#34;&gt;usage files&lt;/a&gt; are not yet supported. This means that resources that solely use usage costs will have a &lt;code&gt;0.00&lt;/code&gt; cost shown:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/zero-cost.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/issues/6&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; to receive updates on usage file support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/features/cli_commands/#diff&#34;&gt;Diff functionality&lt;/a&gt; is not yet supported. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/issues/8&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; to receive updates on diff support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;VSCode Infracost does not yet work with Infracost &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infracost.io/docs/features/config_file/&#34;&gt;config files&lt;/a&gt;. Multi project support is available using Infracost native auto-detection. This means that the first time running in a multi-project workspace might be quite slow. Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/issues/7&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; to receive updates on config file support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Locating Infracost error logs&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re having problems with the extension and your problem isn&#39;t any of the &lt;strong&gt;known issues&lt;/strong&gt; above, you can find the Infracost extension logs using the following method:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the extension terminal using the top menu (Terminal-&amp;gt;New Terminal)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Infracost Debug&lt;/strong&gt; from the dropdown. &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/infracost-debug-log.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There are sometimes additional CLI logs hidden in the &lt;strong&gt;log (Window)&lt;/strong&gt; output. &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/raw/master/.github/assets/error-logs.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The log there might give you more information for a problem you can fix on your own, e.g. syntax errors. If it&#39;s something more ominous please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/infracost/vscode-infracost/issues&#34;&gt;raise an issue&lt;/a&gt;, so that we can identify and fix the problem. Please include as much of the log information as you can and any other helpful information like OS and VSCode workspace size.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We love any contribution, big or small. If you want to change the Infracost VSCode extension, we recommend you use VSCode to build and develop the extension locally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; install all the dependencies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the repo in VSCode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=HashiCorp.terraform&#34;&gt;Terraform VSCode extension&lt;/a&gt; in VSCode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Inside the editor, press F5. VSCode will compile and run the extension in a new Development Host window.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a Terraform project, and navigate to a valid file. If all the previous steps have been followed correctly, you should see Infracost cost estimates above supported resource blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;re finished with your work, open a PR, and we&#39;ll be happy to review it as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>yangshun/tech-interview-handbook</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;💯 Curated interview preparation materials for busy engineers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Tech Interview Handbook&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook/master/website/static/img/logo.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Tech Interview Handbook&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;br&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/&#34;&gt;Read on the website&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt; Follow us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.com/techinterviewhandbook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/techinterviewhb&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/techinterviewhandbook&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/software-engineering-interview-guide/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook/master/assets/start-reading-button.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Start Reading Tech Interview Handbook&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not everyone has the time to do a few hundred LeetCode questions. Here are &lt;em&gt;free and curated&lt;/em&gt; technical interview preparation materials for busy engineers, brought to you by me, the author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teamblind.com/post/New-Year-Gift---Curated-List-of-Top-75-LeetCode-Questions-to-Save-Your-Time-OaM1orEU&#34;&gt;Blind 75&lt;/a&gt;. Over 500,000 people have benefitted from this handbook!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides the usual algorithm questions, other &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt; stuff includes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/coding-interview-study-plan/&#34;&gt;Best practice questions&lt;/a&gt; for coding interviews&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/grind75&#34;&gt;Grind 75&lt;/a&gt; the next evolution of Blind 75, bigger and better.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/coding-interview-prep/&#34;&gt;How to prepare&lt;/a&gt; for coding interviews&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/coding-interview-cheatsheet/&#34;&gt;Coding interview best practices&lt;/a&gt; - Straight-to-the-point Do&#39;s and Don&#39;ts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/algorithms/study-cheatsheet/&#34;&gt;Algorithm cheatsheets and tips&lt;/a&gt; categorized by topic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/resume/&#34;&gt;Step-by-step Software Engineer resume guide&lt;/a&gt; to prepare a FAANG-ready resume&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org/behavioral-interview-questions/&#34;&gt;Behavioral questions&lt;/a&gt; asked by the top tech companies&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontendinterviewhandbook.com&#34;&gt;Front end interview preparation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help from you in contributing content would be very much appreciated!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why would you read this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has &lt;strong&gt;practical&lt;/strong&gt; content that covers all phases of a technical interview, from applying for a job to passing the interviews to offer negotiation. Technically competent candidates might still find the non-technical content helpful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The information in this repository is condensed. Ultimately, the key to succeeding in technical interviews is consistent practice and I don&#39;t want to bore you with too many words. I tell you the minimum you need to know on how to go about navigating the interview process, you go and practice and land your dream job.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Who is this for?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anybody who wants to land a job at a tech company but is new to technical interviews, seasoned engineers who have not been on the other side of the interviewing table in a while and want to get back into the game, or anyone who wants to be better at technical interviewing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;💡 Stop grinding LeetCode aimlessly! Study coding question patterns efficiently with &lt;a href=&#34;https://designgurus.org/link/kJSIoU?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdesigngurus.org%2Fcourse%3Fcourseid%3Dgrokking-the-coding-interview&#34;&gt;Grokking the Coding Interview&lt;/a&gt; by Design Gurus 💡 &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How is this repository different?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many awesome books like &#34;Cracking the Coding Interview&#34; and interview-related repositories out there on GitHub, what makes this repository different? The difference is that many existing interview repositories contain mainly links to external resources whereas this repository contains top-quality curated content directly for your consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, existing resources focus mainly on algorithm questions and lack coverage for more domain-specific and non-technical questions. This handbook aims to cover content beyond the typical algorithmic coding questions. 😎&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Looking for interview courses?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1873647&amp;amp;u=3114753&amp;amp;m=114505&amp;amp;urllink=&amp;amp;afftrack=&#34;&gt;AlgoMonster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AlgoMonster aims to help you ace the technical interview &lt;strong&gt;in the shortest time possible&lt;/strong&gt;. By Google engineers, AlgoMonster uses a data-driven approach to teach you the most useful key question patterns and has contents to help you quickly revise basic data structures and algorithms. Best of all, AlgoMonster is not subscription-based - pay a one-time fee and get &lt;strong&gt;lifetime access&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1873647&amp;amp;u=3114753&amp;amp;m=114505&amp;amp;urllink=&amp;amp;afftrack=&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join today for a 70% discount →&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://designgurus.org/link/kJSIoU?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdesigngurus.org%2Fcourse%3Fcourseid%3Dgrokking-the-coding-interview&#34;&gt;Grokking the Coding Interview: Patterns for Coding Questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course by Design Gurus expands upon the questions on the recommended practice questions but approaches the practicing from a questions pattern perspective, which is an approach I also agree with for learning and have personally used to get better at coding interviews. The course allows you to practice selected questions in Java, Python, C++, JavaScript and also provides sample solutions in those languages. &lt;strong&gt;Learn and understand patterns, not memorize answers!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://designgurus.org/link/kJSIoU?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdesigngurus.org%2Fcourse%3Fcourseid%3Dgrokking-the-coding-interview&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get lifetime access today →&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Looking for Front End content?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Front-end-related content has been moved to a separate website - &lt;a href=&#34;https://frontendinterviewhandbook.com&#34;&gt;Front End Interview Handbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Looking for System Design content?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re still working on System Design content. In the meanwhile, check out Design Gurus&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://designgurus.org/link/kJSIoU?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdesigngurus.org%2Fcourse%3Fcourseid%3Dgrokking-the-system-design-interview&#34;&gt;Grokking the System Design Interview course&lt;/a&gt;, which in our opinion is one of the most useful resources for getting started on system design interviews preparation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/docusaurus&#34;&gt;Docusaurus&lt;/a&gt; website has been created to provide a better reading experience. Check out the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinterviewhandbook.org&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;💡 Stop the grind and study with a plan! Developed by Google engineers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1873647&amp;amp;u=3114753&amp;amp;m=114505&amp;amp;urllink=&amp;amp;afftrack=&#34;&gt;AlgoMonster&lt;/a&gt; is the fastest way to get a software engineering job. &lt;a href=&#34;https://shareasale.com/r.cfm?b=1873647&amp;amp;u=3114753&amp;amp;m=114505&amp;amp;urllink=&amp;amp;afftrack=&#34;&gt;Join today for a 70% discount!&lt;/a&gt; 💡&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in how data structures are implemented, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yangshun/lago&#34;&gt;Lago&lt;/a&gt;, a Data Structures and Algorithms library for JavaScript. It is pretty much still WIP but I intend to make it into a library that can be used in production and also a reference resource for revising Data Structures and Algorithms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are no formal contributing guidelines at the moment as things are still in flux and we might find a better approach to structure content as we go along. You are welcome to contribute whatever you think will be helpful to fellow engineers. If you would like to contribute content for different domains, feel free to create an issue or submit a pull request and we can discuss further.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project exists thanks to all the people who contributed. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;]. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yangshun/tech-interview-handbook/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/contributors.svg?width=890&amp;amp;button=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Backers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all our backers! 🙏 [&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook#backer&#34;&gt;Become a backer&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook#backers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/backers.svg?width=890&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/yangshun&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/assets/img/custom_images/orange_img.png&#34; alt=&#34;Buy Me A Coffee&#34; style=&#34;height: auto !important; width: auto !important;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Support this project by becoming a sponsor. Your logo/profile picture will show up here with a link to your website. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook#sponsor&#34;&gt;Become a sponsor&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/0/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/0/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/1/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/1/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/2/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/2/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/3/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/3/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/4/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/4/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/5/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/5/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/6/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/6/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/7/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/7/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/8/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/8/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/9/website&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/tech-interview-handbook/sponsor/9/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am providing code in the repository to you under an open source license. Because this is my personal repository, the license you receive to my code is from me and not my employer (Meta).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>sunface/rust-by-practice</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/sunface/rust-by-practice</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Learning Rust By Practice, narrowing the gap between beginner and skilled-dev with challenging examples, exercises and projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice/raw/master/en/assets/header.jpg?raw=true&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;span&gt;English&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span&gt; | &lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice/raw/master/zh-CN/src/why-exercise.md&#34;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Practice Rust with challenging examples, exercises and projects&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice/stargazers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/sunface/rust-by-practice?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Stars Count&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hirust.cn&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/RustCn-orange&#34; alt=&#34;studyrut&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-CC_BY_4.0-green?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book was designed for easily diving into and get skilled with Rust, and it&#39;s very easy to use: All you need to do is to make each exercise compile without ERRORS and Panics !&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reading online&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://practice.rs&#34;&gt;https://practice.rs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Part of our examples and exercises are borrowed from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rust-lang/rust-by-example&#34;&gt;Rust By Example&lt;/a&gt;, thanks for your great works!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although they are so awesome, we have our own secret weapons :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are three parts in each chapter: examples, exercises and practices&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Besides examples, we have &lt;code&gt;a lot of exercises&lt;/code&gt;, you can Read, Edit and Run them ONLINE&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Covering nearly all aspects of Rust, such as async/await, threads, sync primitives, optimizing, standard libraries, tool chain, data structures and algorithms etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every exercise has its own solutions&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The overall difficulties are a bit higher and from easy to super hard: easy 🌟 medium 🌟🌟 hard 🌟🌟🌟 super hard 🌟🌟🌟🌟&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we want to do is fill in the gap between learning and getting started with real projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🏅 Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sunface/rust-by-practice/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🏆 Special thanks to our English editor:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Tanish-Eagle&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/71984506?v=4?s=100&#34; width=&#34;160px&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;sub&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tanish-Eagle&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Running locally&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://rust-lang.github.io/mdBook/&#34;&gt;mdbook&lt;/a&gt; building our exercises. You can run locally with below steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ git clone git@github.com:sunface/rust-by-practice.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install mdbook using Cargo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ cargo install mdbook&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For Book in English&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ cd rust-by-practice &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mdbook serve en/&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For Book in Chinese&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ cd rust-by-practice &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mdbook serve zh-CN/&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Some of our exercises&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟🌟🌟 Tuple struct looks similar to tuples, it has added meaning the struct name provides but has no named fields. It&#39;s useful when you want give the whole tuple a name, but don&#39;t care the fields&#39;s names.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-rust&#34;&gt;&#xA;// fix the error and fill the blanks&#xA;struct Color(i32, i32, i32);&#xA;struct Point(i32, i32, i32);&#xA;fn main() {&#xA;    let v = Point(___, ___, ___);&#xA;    check_color(v);&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;fn check_color(p: Color) {&#xA;    let (x, _, _) = p;&#xA;    assert_eq!(x, 0);&#xA;    assert_eq!(p.1, 127);&#xA;    assert_eq!(___, 255);&#xA; }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟🌟 Within the destructuring of a single variable, both by-move and by-reference pattern bindings can be used at the same time. Doing this will result in a partial move of the variable, which means that parts of the variable will be moved while other parts stay. In such a case, the parent variable cannot be used afterwards as a whole, however the parts that are only referenced (and not moved) can still be used.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-rust&#34;&gt;&#xA;// fix errors to make it work&#xA;#[derive(Debug)]&#xA;struct File {&#xA;    name: String,&#xA;    data: String,&#xA;}&#xA;fn main() {&#xA;    let f = File {&#xA;        name: String::from(&#34;readme.md&#34;),&#xA;        data: &#34;Rust By Practice&#34;.to_string()&#xA;    };&#xA;&#xA;    let _name = f.name;&#xA;&#xA;    // ONLY modify this line&#xA;    println!(&#34;{}, {}, {:?}&#34;,f.name, f.data, f);&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟🌟 A match guard is an additional if condition specified after the pattern in a match arm that must also match, along with the pattern matching, for that arm to be chosen.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-rust,editable&#34;&gt;&#xA;// fill in the blank to make the code work, `split` MUST be used&#xA;fn main() {&#xA;    let num = Some(4);&#xA;    let split = 5;&#xA;    match num {&#xA;        Some(x) __ =&amp;gt; assert!(x &amp;lt; split),&#xA;        Some(x) =&amp;gt; assert!(x &amp;gt;= split),&#xA;        None =&amp;gt; (),&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>