<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-08T01:26:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>EFForg/rayhunter</title>
    <updated>2025-03-08T01:26:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-08:/EFForg/rayhunter</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rust tool to detect cell site simulators on an orbic mobile hotspot&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.eff.org/files/styles/media_browser_preview/public/banner_library/rayhunter-banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rayhunter Logo - An Orca taking a bite out of a cellular signal bar&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Rayhunter&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/actions/workflows/check-and-test.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Tests&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rayhunter is an IMSI Catcher Catcher for the Orbic mobile hotspot.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS CODE IS PROOF OF CONCEPT AND SHOULD NOT BE RELIED UPON IN HIGH RISK SITUATIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The Hardware&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rayhunter has been built and tested for the Orbic RC400L mobile hotspot. It may work on other orbics and other linux/qualcom devices, but this is the only one we have tested on. Buy the orbic &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Orbic-Verizon-Hotspot-Connect-Enabled/dp/B08N3CHC4Y&#34;&gt;using bezos bucks&lt;/a&gt; Or on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_nkw=orbic+rc400l&#34;&gt;Ebay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: We don&#39;t currently support automated installs on windows, you will have to follow the manual install instructions below&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/EFForg/rayhunter/releases&#34;&gt;Rayhunter release bundle&lt;/a&gt; and extract it. &lt;strong&gt;If you are installing from the cloned github repository please see the development instructions below, running &lt;code&gt;install-linux.sh&lt;/code&gt; from the git tree will not work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Turn on the Orbic device and plug it into your computer using a USB-C Cable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the install script inside the bundle corresponding to your platform (&lt;code&gt;install-linux.sh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;install-mac.sh&lt;/code&gt;). The Linux installer has only been tested on the latest version of Ubuntu. If it fails you will need to follow the install steps outlined in &lt;strong&gt;Development&lt;/strong&gt; below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once finished, Rayhunter should be running! You can verify this by visiting the web UI as described below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once installed, Rayhunter will run automatically whenever your Orbic device is running. It serves a web UI that provides some basic controls, such as being able to start/stop recordings, download captures, and view heuristic analyses of captures. You can access this UI in one of two ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Over wifi: Connect your phone/laptop to the Orbic&#39;s wifi network and visit &lt;code&gt;http://192.168.1.1:8080&lt;/code&gt; (click past your browser warning you about the connection not being secure, Rayhunter doesn&#39;t have HTTPS yet!) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Note that you&#39;ll need the Orbic&#39;s wifi password for this, which can be retrieved by pressing the &#34;MENU&#34; button on the device and opening the 2.4 GHz menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Over usb: Connect the Orbic device to your laptop via usb. Run &lt;code&gt;adb forward tcp:8080 tcp:8080&lt;/code&gt;, then visit &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080&lt;/code&gt;. For this you will need to install the Android Debug Bridge (ADB) on your computer, you can copy the version that was downloaded inside the releases/platform-tools/` folder to somewhere else in your path or you can install it manually. You can find instructions for doing so on your platform &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xda-developers.com/install-adb-windows-macos-linux/#how-to-set-up-adb-on-your-computer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, (don&#39;t worry about instructions for installing it on a phone/device yet).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Do I need an active SIM card to use Rayhunter?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It Depends&lt;/strong&gt;. Operation of Rayhunter does require the insertion of a SIM card into the device, but whether that SIM card has to be currently active for our tests to work is still under investigation. If you want to use the device as a hotspot in addition to a research device an active plan would of course be necessary, however we have not done enough testing yet to know whether an active subscription is required for detection. If you want to test the device with an inactive SIM card, we would certainly be interested in seeing any data you collect, and especially any runs that trigger an alert!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Help, Rayhunter&#39;s line is red! What should I do?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the circumstances that might lead to a positive CSS signal are quite varied, so we don&#39;t have a universal recommendation for how to deal with the a positive signal. You might also want to turn off your phone until you are out of the area (or put it on airplane mode,) and tell your friends to do the same!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contact an EFF technologist with more information &amp;amp; a copy of the QMDL in question at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@eff.org&#34;&gt;info@eff.org&lt;/a&gt;. Please note that this file may contain sensetive information such as your IMSI and the unique IDs of cell towers you were near which could be used to ascertain your location at the time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Does Rayhunter work outside of the US?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Probably&lt;/strong&gt;. Some Rayhunter users have reported successfully using it in other countries with unlocked devices and SIM cards from local telcos. We can&#39;t guarantee whether or not it will work for you though.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Should I get a locked or unlocked orbic device? What is the difference?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use a non verizon SIM card you will probably need an unlocked device. But it&#39;s not clear how locked the locked devices are nor how to unlock them, we welcome any experimentation and information regarding the use of unlocked devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Does Rayhunter work on any other devices besides the Orbic RC400L?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe&lt;/strong&gt;. We have not tested Rayhunter on any other hardware but we would love to expand the supported platforms. We will consider giving official support to any hardware platform that can be bought for around $20-30USD. The Rayhunter daemon should theoretically work on any linux/android device that has a qualcomm chip with a /dev/diag interface and root access, though our installer script has only been tested with an Orbic. If you get it working on another device, please let us know!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install ADB on your computer using the instructions above, and make sure it&#39;s in your terminal&#39;s PATH &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can verify if ADB is in your PATH by running &lt;code&gt;which adb&lt;/code&gt; in a terminal. If it prints the filepath to where ADB is installed, you&#39;re set! Otherwise, try following one of these guides: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/652936/adding-android-sdk-platform-tools-to-path-downloaded-from-umake&#34;&gt;linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.repeato.app/setting-up-adb-on-macos-a-step-by-step-guide/&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yadav-ajay/a-step-by-step-guide-to-setting-up-adb-path-on-windows-0b833faebf18&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;If you&#39;re on x86 linux&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install rust the usual way and then install cross compiling dependences:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt install curl build-essential libc6-armhf-cross libc6-dev-armhf-cross gcc-arm-linux-gnueabihf&#xA;rustup target add x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu&#xA;rustup target add armv7-unknown-linux-gnueabihf&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now you can root your device and install Rayhunter by running &lt;code&gt;./tools/install-dev.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;If you&#39;re on windows or can&#39;t run the install scripts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Root your device on windows using the instructions here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://xdaforums.com/t/resetting-verizon-orbic-speed-rc400l-firmware-flash-kajeet.4334899/#post-87855183&#34;&gt;https://xdaforums.com/t/resetting-verizon-orbic-speed-rc400l-firmware-flash-kajeet.4334899/#post-87855183&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Build for arm using &lt;code&gt;cargo build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run tests using &lt;code&gt;cargo test_pc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Push the scripts in &lt;code&gt;scripts/&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d&lt;/code&gt; on device and make a directory called &lt;code&gt;/data/rayhunter&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;adb shell&lt;/code&gt; (and sshell for your root shell if you followed the steps above)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;you also need to copy &lt;code&gt;config.toml.example&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/data/rayhunter/config.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then run &lt;code&gt;./make.sh&lt;/code&gt; this will build the binary and push it over adb. Restart your device or run &lt;code&gt;/etc/init.d/rayhunter_daemon start&lt;/code&gt; on the device and you are good to go.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Write your code and write tests&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Build for arm using &lt;code&gt;cargo build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run tests using &lt;code&gt;cargo test_pc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;push to the device with &lt;code&gt;./make.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build docs locallly using &lt;code&gt;RUSTDOCFLAGS=&#34;--cfg docsrs&#34; cargo doc --no-deps --all-features --open&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEGAL DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong&gt; Use this program at your own risk. We beilieve running this program does not currently violate any laws or regulations in the United States. However, we are not responsible for civil or criminal liability resulting from the use of this software. If you are located outside of the US please consult with an attorney in your country to help you assess the legal risks of running this program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Good Hunting!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>GuijiAI/duix.ai</title>
    <updated>2025-03-08T01:26:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-08:/GuijiAI/duix.ai</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Duix - Silicon-Based Digital Human SDK 🌐🤖 &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/README_ZH.md&#34;&gt;[Chinese]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;width: 100%; text-align: center;&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/res/logo_en.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto;&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📖 Documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/duix-android/dh_aigc_android/README.md&#34;&gt;[android]&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/duix-ios/GJLocalDigitalDemo/GJLocalDigitalSDK.md&#34;&gt;[ios]&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;📑 &lt;a href=&#34;https://jexopm4t2a.feishu.cn/wiki/Ef1VwGHtRiUIQIkQl1hco2ISnFc&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/app/id6451088879&#34;&gt;Duix App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Duix App. Feel free to download it and experience the advanced digital human interaction features we offer.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join our wechat or Discord community for support and discussions. Follow Twitter,to watch the latest digital human videos created based on the open-source capabilities of DUIX.&lt;br&gt; 💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/18%E7%BE%A4%E4%BA%8C%E7%BB%B4%E7%A0%81.jpg&#34;&gt;Join our WeChat (微信)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; 😄 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/8jh28PVsMU&#34;&gt;Join our Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; ✨ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HuapengSima&#34;&gt;Follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DUIX, short for “Dialogue User Interface System”, is an AI-powered digital human interaction platform created by Silicon-based Intelligence. By open-sourcing the capabilities of digital human interaction, developers can easily integrate large-scale models, automatic speech recognition (ASR), and text-to-speech (TTS) capabilities, enabling real-time interaction with digital humans. It supports one-click deployment on multiple platforms including Android and iOS, allowing each developer to effortlessly create intelligent and personalized digital human agents, and apply them in various industries.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also provide you with a one-stop comprehensive digital human multimodal real-time interaction SDK integration solution - DUIX Interactive Digital Human SDK. This SDK product is based on technologies such as speech recognition (ASR), speech synthesis (TTS), natural language understanding (NLP), AIGC, and Large Language Model (LLM) , achieving an intelligent human-computer interaction experience that is &#34;able to hear, see, speak, and understand you&#34;. It is suitable for multiple enterprise application scenarios such as intelligent customer service and smart screens. View details:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 😄&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.guiji.cn/session/create&#34;&gt;Quickly set up DUIX digital human conversations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; 😄&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.guiji.cn/platform&#34;&gt;DUIX SDK version and price&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; 😄&lt;a href=&#34;https://guiji.cn/duix-light-document/introduce/&#34;&gt;DUIX SDK Open Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Low deployment cost: No need for customers to provide technical teams for cooperation, supports low-cost rapid deployment on various terminals and large screens.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Low network dependence: Suitable for virtual assistant self-service in scenarios such as subways, banks, and government affairs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diverse functions: Can meet the diverse needs of video, media, customer service, finance, radio, and television in multiple industries according to customer requirements.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Source Code Directory Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;duix-android: android demo       &#xA;duix-ios: ios demo &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Open Documentation Entry&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For android, refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/duix-android/dh_aigc_android/README_en.md&#34;&gt;README_en.md&lt;/a&gt; For ios, refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/duix-ios/GJLocalDigitalDemo/GJLocalDigitalSDK_en.md&#34;&gt;GJLocalDigitalSDK_en.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to deploy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document provides a detailed description of the integration process for developers working on this project. It is important to note that each developer may encounter different stages of the process during integration. This document is intended for developers to use as a reference.&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/Interface%20Reference%20Handbook_ZH.pdf&#34;&gt;Interface Reference Handbook_ZH&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/main/Interface%20Reference%20Handbook_EN.pdf&#34;&gt;Interface Reference Handbook_EN&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download Digital Human Local Model&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We offer a selection of digital human models for download and use. We will update the local model packages from time to time so that you can download and utilize the latest models. Below is the list of currently available local model packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;male&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/andrew.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/MoneyGod.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/SuShi.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E8%89%BE%E7%91%9E%E5%85%8B.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E5%AD%90%E8%BD%A9.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;andrew&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651705983152197/61025/651705983152197_ccf3256b2449c76e77f94276dffcb293.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MoneyGod&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651644573884485/61002/651644573884485_2387469906049706416017f105e5340f.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Su Shi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651660515688517/61011/651660515688517_825de648c30be80a89110dd0e63ecb3b.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eric&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719193748558/airuike_20240409.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zi Xuan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194036608/zixuan_20240411v2.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E7%94%B7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ming Xuan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194633518/mingxuan_20240624.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;female&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/Arya.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/Shirley.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/Guanyin.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res//%E8%8B%8F%E8%8F%B2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E6%85%95%E5%AE%B9%E6%99%93.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651637733658693/61000/651637733658693_2e0a4278a73411a2ff04ef1a849d2a6d.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shirley&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651686686687301/61026/651686686687301_846161843f9ffdaaeace716bf3436be5.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guanyin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/dhp-tools/dhp-tools/651622691811397/60996/651622691811397_ebe9bd2db8e26c1a7b07932b4a55c45c.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sophie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719193425133/sufei_20240409.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mu Rong Xiao&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719193516102/murongxiao_20240410.zip&#34;&gt;下载&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E5%86%B7%E7%84%B1.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/Amelia.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E8%B5%B5%E9%9B%85.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E5%BF%86%E7%91%B6.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E5%BF%83%E5%A6%8D.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold Flame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719193451931/lengyan_20240407.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amelia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719193625986/amelia_20240411.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zhao Ya&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194234727/zhaoya_20240411.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yi Yao&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194263441/yiyao_20240418.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xin Yan&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194373660/xinyan_20240411.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E6%99%93%E8%90%B1.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E6%80%9D%E7%91%B6.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E8%AF%97%E9%9B%85.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/%E5%A5%B3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiao Xuan&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194313414/xiaoxuan_20240418.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Si Yao&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194450521/siyao_20240418.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shi Ya&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194516880/shiya_20240409.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Sister&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://digital-public.obs.cn-east-3.myhuaweicloud.com/duix/digital/model/1719194007931/bendi1_0329.zip&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please download the model files according to your needs. We recommend that you carefully read the accompanying documentation after downloading to ensure the correct installation and use of the models.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Business case presentation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Mobile Phone and General Terminal Screen Cases&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/lvshi/lvshi-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/yisheng/yisheng-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/peiban/peiban-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/laoshi/laoshi-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Lawyer &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/lvshi/lvshi.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Doctor&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/yisheng/yisheng.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Companion&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/peiban/peiban.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;** Speaking Tutor&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/540p/laoshi/laoshi.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;**&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Low-end Terminal Screen Cases&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/caishen/caishen-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/guanyin/guanyin-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/sushi/sushi-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/nvyou/nvyou-bg.jpg&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God of Wealth &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/caishen/caishen.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guanyin Bodhisattva&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/guanyin/guanyin.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Su Shi&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/sushi/sushi.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Girlfriend &lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/270p/nvyou/nvyou.mp4&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;1. Are free avatar models available for commercial use? Do they support digital human customization? Are they based on photos or videos?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: The free avatar models are not available for commercial use! If needed, we can support digital human customization. Our digital human customization is based on videos. You can customize a unique digital human for use in the SDK. However, the customized digital human service is a paid service. You can contact us by scanning the QR code on WeChat.&lt;br&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/GuijiAI/duix.ai/raw/main/res/ssx.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;2. How to customize a digital avatar?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: To customize a silicon-based digital human, you need to shoot a 3-5 minute video featuring a real person speaking directly to the camera. The specific posture and content of the speech can be determined according to the actual usage scenario. For example, if the video is for legal consultation purposes, you can choose to appear in formal attire and speak about legal-related content, ensuring consistency with the overall context. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;3. How is the customization of digital avatars charged?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: We provide digital human customization that includes the avatar&#39;s appearance and voice, compatible with our SDK open-source interface. For additional customization needs, you can contact our customer service via email.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;4. How can the digital avatar be updated?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: Currently, the open-source version mainly provides public models. Customization is available upon request.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;5. Is there an API interface for avatar cloning&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: The training service currently only supports deployment on our internal servers for invocation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;6. Does the broadcasted wav file support streaming data?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: Streaming support is currently under modification and optimization, and it is not supported at the moment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;7. Are there callback methods for the start and end of the broadcast?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: Callback methods for the start and end of the broadcast are detailed in the SDK documentation. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;8. Are there any API controls for the digital human&#39;s actions?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: The API for controlling digital human actions is not supported at the moment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;9. How to replace downloaded files?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: The replacement of downloaded files is detailed in the code.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;10、Would you like to learn about the integrated solution or more advanced versions?&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer: Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://guiji.cn/duix-light-document/introduce/&#34;&gt;https://guiji.cn/duix-light-document/introduce/&lt;/a&gt; to experience more features.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;···For more FAQs, please refer to 📑 &lt;a href=&#34;https://jexopm4t2a.feishu.cn/wiki/Ef1VwGHtRiUIQIkQl1hco2ISnFc&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version Record&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.0.4&lt;/strong&gt;: Fixed an issue where some devices’ default gl float low precision caused the avatar to not display properly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.0.3&lt;/strong&gt;: Optimized local rendering&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We have drawn on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wenet-e2e/wenet&#34;&gt;wenet&lt;/a&gt; for audio features.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;end_sub@hotmail.com&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Star History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://star-history.com/#GuijiAI/duix.ai&amp;amp;Date&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=GuijiAI/duix.ai&amp;amp;type=Date&#34; alt=&#34;Star History Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>