<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-03T01:28:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>leptos-rs/leptos</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T01:28:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-03:/leptos-rs/leptos</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/leptos-rs/leptos" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Build fast web applications with Rust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;picture&gt; &#xA; &lt;source srcset=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/leptos-rs/leptos/main/docs/logos/Leptos_logo_pref_dark_RGB.svg&#34; media=&#34;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/leptos-rs/leptos/main/docs/logos/Leptos_logo_RGB.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Leptos Logo&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/picture&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/leptos&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/crates/v/leptos.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;crates.io&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;docs.rs&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/YdRAhS7eQB&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/1031524867910148188?color=%237289DA&amp;amp;label=discord&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/%23leptos:matrix.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Matrix-leptos-grey?logo=matrix&amp;amp;labelColor=white&amp;amp;logoColor=black&#34; alt=&#34;Matrix&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leptos.dev&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://leptos-rs.github.io/leptos/&#34;&gt;Book&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos/latest/leptos/&#34;&gt;Docs.rs&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://codesandbox.io/p/sandbox/leptos-rtfggt?file=%2Fsrc%2Fmain.rs%3A1%2C1&#34;&gt;Playground&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/YdRAhS7eQB&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find a list of useful libraries and example projects at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/awesome-leptos&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;awesome-leptos&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Leptos&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-rust&#34;&gt;use leptos::*;&#xA;&#xA;#[component]&#xA;pub fn SimpleCounter(initial_value: i32) -&amp;gt; impl IntoView {&#xA;    // create a reactive signal with the initial value&#xA;    let (value, set_value) = create_signal(initial_value);&#xA;&#xA;    // create event handlers for our buttons&#xA;    // note that `value` and `set_value` are `Copy`, so it&#39;s super easy to move them into closures&#xA;    let clear = move |_| set_value(0);&#xA;    let decrement = move |_| set_value.update(|value| *value -= 1);&#xA;    let increment = move |_| set_value.update(|value| *value += 1);&#xA;&#xA;    // create user interfaces with the declarative `view!` macro&#xA;    view! {&#xA;        &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&#xA;            &amp;lt;button on:click=clear&amp;gt;Clear&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&#xA;            &amp;lt;button on:click=decrement&amp;gt;-1&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&#xA;            // text nodes can be quoted or unquoted&#xA;            &amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&#34;Value: &#34; {value} &#34;!&#34;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&#xA;            &amp;lt;button on:click=increment&amp;gt;+1&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&#xA;        &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;// we also support a builder syntax rather than the JSX-like `view` macro&#xA;#[component]&#xA;pub fn SimpleCounterWithBuilder(initial_value: i32) -&amp;gt; impl IntoView {&#xA;    use leptos::html::*;&#xA;&#xA;    let (value, set_value) = create_signal(initial_value);&#xA;    let clear = move |_| set_value(0);&#xA;    let decrement = move |_| set_value.update(|value| *value -= 1);&#xA;    let increment = move |_| set_value.update(|value| *value += 1);&#xA;&#xA;    // the `view` macro above expands to this builder syntax&#xA;    div().child((&#xA;        button().on(ev::click, clear).child(&#34;Clear&#34;),&#xA;        button().on(ev::click, decrement).child(&#34;-1&#34;),&#xA;        span().child((&#34;Value: &#34;, value, &#34;!&#34;)),&#xA;        button().on(ev::click, increment).child(&#34;+1&#34;)&#xA;    ))&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;// Easy to use with Trunk (trunkrs.dev) or with a simple wasm-bindgen setup&#xA;pub fn main() {&#xA;    mount_to_body(|| view! {&#xA;        &amp;lt;SimpleCounter initial_value=3 /&amp;gt;&#xA;    })&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About the Framework&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leptos is a full-stack, isomorphic Rust web framework leveraging fine-grained reactivity to build declarative user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What does that mean?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full-stack&lt;/strong&gt;: Leptos can be used to build apps that run in the browser (client-side rendering), on the server (server-side rendering), or by rendering HTML on the server and then adding interactivity in the browser (server-side rendering with hydration). This includes support for HTTP streaming of both data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos/latest/leptos/struct.Resource.html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Resource&lt;/code&gt;s&lt;/a&gt;) and HTML (out-of-order or in-order streaming of &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos/latest/leptos/fn.Suspense.html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Suspense/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; components.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isomorphic&lt;/strong&gt;: Leptos provides primitives to write isomorphic &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos_server/0.2.5/leptos_server/index.html&#34;&gt;server functions&lt;/a&gt;, i.e., functions that can be called with the “same shape” on the client or server, but only run on the server. This means you can write your server-only logic (database requests, authentication etc.) alongside the client-side components that will consume it, and call server functions as if they were running in the browser, without needing to create and maintain a separate REST or other API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web&lt;/strong&gt;: Leptos is built on the Web platform and Web standards. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos_router/latest/leptos_router/&#34;&gt;router&lt;/a&gt; is designed to use Web fundamentals (like links and forms) and build on top of them rather than trying to replace them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framework&lt;/strong&gt;: Leptos provides most of what you need to build a modern web app: a reactive system, templating library, and a router that works on both the server and client side.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fine-grained reactivity&lt;/strong&gt;: The entire framework is built from reactive primitives. This allows for extremely performant code with minimal overhead: when a reactive signal’s value changes, it can update a single text node, toggle a single class, or remove an element from the DOM without any other code running. (So, no virtual DOM overhead!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declarative&lt;/strong&gt;: Tell Leptos how you want the page to look, and let the framework tell the browser how to do it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some resources for learning more about Leptos:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leptos-rs.github.io/leptos/&#34;&gt;Book&lt;/a&gt; (work in progress)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/leptos/tree/main/examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/leptos/latest/leptos/&#34;&gt;API Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/leptos/tree/main/docs/COMMON_BUGS.md&#34;&gt;Common Bugs&lt;/a&gt; (and how to fix them!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; Note&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the examples assume you’re using &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; version of Rust and the &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; feature of Leptos. To use &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; Rust, you can either set your toolchain globally or on per-project basis.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; as a default toolchain for all projects (and add the ability to compile Rust to WebAssembly, if you haven’t already):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rustup toolchain install nightly&#xA;rustup default nightly&#xA;rustup target add wasm32-unknown-unknown&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to use &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; only in your Leptos project however, add &lt;a href=&#34;https://rust-lang.github.io/rustup/overrides.html#the-toolchain-file&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rust-toolchain.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file with the following content:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;[toolchain]&#xA;channel = &#34;nightly&#34;&#xA;targets = [&#34;wasm32-unknown-unknown&#34;]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; feature enables the function call syntax for accessing and setting signals, as opposed to &lt;code&gt;.get()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.set()&lt;/code&gt;. This leads to a consistent mental model in which accessing a reactive value of any kind (a signal, memo, or derived signal) is always represented as a function call. This is only possible with nightly Rust and the &lt;code&gt;nightly&lt;/code&gt; feature.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo-leptos&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/cargo-leptos&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo-leptos&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a build tool that&#39;s designed to make it easy to build apps that run on both the client and the server, with seamless integration. The best way to get started with a real Leptos project right now is to use &lt;code&gt;cargo-leptos&lt;/code&gt; and our starter templates for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/start&#34;&gt;Actix&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leptos-rs/start-axum&#34;&gt;Axum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cargo install cargo-leptos&#xA;cargo leptos new --git https://github.com/leptos-rs/start&#xA;cd [your project name]&#xA;cargo leptos watch&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open browser to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What’s up with the name?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Leptos&lt;/em&gt; (λεπτός) is an ancient Greek word meaning “thin, light, refined, fine-grained.” To me, a classicist and not a dog owner, it evokes the lightweight reactive system that powers the framework. I&#39;ve since learned the same word is at the root of the medical term “leptospirosis,” a blood infection that affects humans and animals... My bad. No dogs were harmed in the creation of this framework.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Is it production ready?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;People usually mean one of three things by this question.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the APIs stable?&lt;/strong&gt; i.e., will I have to rewrite my whole app from Leptos 0.1 to 0.2 to 0.3 to 0.4, or can I write it now and benefit from new features and updates as new versions come?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The APIs are basically settled. We’re adding new features, but we’re very happy with where the type system and patterns have landed. I would not expect major breaking changes to your code to adapt to future releases, in terms of architecture.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there bugs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m sure there are. You can see from the state of our issue tracker over time that there aren’t that &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; bugs and they’re usually resolved pretty quickly. But for sure, there may be moments where you encounter something that requires a fix at the framework level, which may not be immediately resolved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Am I a consumer or a contributor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may be the big one: “production ready” implies a certain orientation to a library: that you can basically use it, without any special knowledge of its internals or ability to contribute. Everyone has this at some level in their stack: for example I (@gbj) don’t have the capacity or knowledge to contribute to something like &lt;code&gt;wasm-bindgen&lt;/code&gt; at this point: I simply rely on it to work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several people in the community using Leptos right now for internal apps at work, who have also become significant contributors. I think this is the right level of production use for now. There may be missing features that you need, and you may end up building them! But for internal apps, if you’re willing to build and contribute missing pieces along the way, the framework is definitely usable right now.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Can I use this for native GUI?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sure! Obviously the &lt;code&gt;view&lt;/code&gt; macro is for generating DOM nodes but you can use the reactive system to drive any native GUI toolkit that uses the same kind of object-oriented, event-callback-based framework as the DOM pretty easily. The principles are the same:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use signals, derived signals, and memos to create your reactive system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create GUI widgets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use event listeners to update signals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create effects to update the UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The 0.7 update originally set out to create a &#34;generic rendering&#34; approach that would allow us to reuse most of the same view logic to do all of the above. Unfortunately, this has had to be shelved for now due to difficulties encountered by the Rust compiler when building larger-scale applications with the number of generics spread throughout the codebase that this required. It&#39;s an approach I&#39;m looking forward to exploring again in the future; feel free to reach out if you&#39;re interested in this kind of work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How is this different from Yew?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yew is the most-used library for Rust web UI development, but there are several differences between Yew and Leptos, in philosophy, approach, and performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VDOM vs. fine-grained:&lt;/strong&gt; Yew is built on the virtual DOM (VDOM) model: state changes cause components to re-render, generating a new virtual DOM tree. Yew diffs this against the previous VDOM, and applies those patches to the actual DOM. Component functions rerun whenever state changes. Leptos takes an entirely different approach. Components run once, creating (and returning) actual DOM nodes and setting up a reactive system to update those DOM nodes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; This has huge performance implications: Leptos is simply much faster at both creating and updating the UI than Yew is.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Yew was created in an era in which browser-rendered single-page apps (SPAs) were the dominant paradigm. While Leptos supports client-side rendering, it also focuses on integrating with the server side of your application via server functions and multiple modes of serving HTML, including out-of-order streaming.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How is this different from Dioxus?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like Leptos, Dioxus is a framework for building UIs using web technologies. However, there are significant differences in approach and features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VDOM vs. fine-grained:&lt;/strong&gt; While Dioxus has a performant virtual DOM (VDOM), it still uses coarse-grained/component-scoped reactivity: changing a stateful value reruns the component function and diffs the old UI against the new one. Leptos components use a different mental model, creating (and returning) actual DOM nodes and setting up a reactive system to update those DOM nodes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web vs. desktop priorities:&lt;/strong&gt; Dioxus uses Leptos server functions in its fullstack mode, but does not have the same &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Suspense&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;-based support for things like streaming HTML rendering, or share the same focus on holistic web performance. Leptos tends to prioritize holistic web performance (streaming HTML rendering, smaller WASM binary sizes, etc.), whereas Dioxus has an unparalleled experience when building desktop apps, because your application logic runs as a native Rust binary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h3&gt;How is this different from Sycamore?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sycamore and Leptos are both heavily influenced by SolidJS. At this point, Leptos has a larger community and ecosystem and is more actively developed. Other differences:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Templating DSLs:&lt;/strong&gt; Sycamore uses a custom templating language for its views, while Leptos uses a JSX-like template format.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#39;static&lt;/code&gt; signals:&lt;/strong&gt; One of Leptos’s main innovations was the creation of &lt;code&gt;Copy + &#39;static&lt;/code&gt; signals, which have excellent ergonomics. Sycamore is in the process of adopting the same pattern, but this is not yet released.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perseus vs. server functions:&lt;/strong&gt; The Perseus metaframework provides an opinionated way to build Sycamore apps that include server functionality. Leptos instead provides primitives like server functions in the core of the framework.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>anthropics/prompt-eng-interactive-tutorial</title>
    <updated>2024-12-03T01:28:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-03:/anthropics/prompt-eng-interactive-tutorial</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/anthropics/prompt-eng-interactive-tutorial" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anthropic&#39;s Interactive Prompt Engineering Tutorial&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to Anthropic&#39;s Prompt Engineering Interactive Tutorial&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course introduction and goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course is intended to provide you with a comprehensive step-by-step understanding of how to engineer optimal prompts within Claude.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After completing this course, you will be able to&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Master the basic structure of a good prompt&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Recognize common failure modes and learn the &#39;80/20&#39; techniques to address them&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Understand Claude&#39;s strengths and weaknesses&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build strong prompts from scratch for common use cases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course structure and content&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course is structured to allow you many chances to practice writing and troubleshooting prompts yourself. The course is broken up into &lt;strong&gt;9 chapters with accompanying exercises&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as an appendix of even more advanced methods. It is intended for you to &lt;strong&gt;work through the course in chapter order&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each lesson has an &#34;Example Playground&#34; area&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom where you are free to experiment with the examples in the lesson and see for yourself how changing prompts can change Claude&#39;s responses. There is also an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1jIxjzUWG-6xBVIa2ay6yDpLyeuOh_hR_ZB75a47KX_E/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;answer key&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: This tutorial uses our smallest, fastest, and cheapest model, Claude 3 Haiku. Anthropic has &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.anthropic.com/claude/docs/models-overview&#34;&gt;two other models&lt;/a&gt;, Claude 3 Sonnet and Claude 3 Opus, which are more intelligent than Haiku, with Opus being the most intelligent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This tutorial also exists on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/19jzLgRruG9kjUQNKtCg1ZjdD6l6weA6qRXG5zLIAhC8/edit?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Google Sheets using Anthropic&#39;s Claude for Sheets extension&lt;/a&gt;. We recommend using that version as it is more user friendly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you are ready to begin, go to &lt;code&gt;01_Basic Prompt Structure&lt;/code&gt; to proceed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each chapter consists of a lesson and a set of exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Beginner&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Basic Prompt Structure&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Being Clear and Direct&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Assigning Roles&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Intermediate&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Separating Data from Instructions&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Formatting Output &amp;amp; Speaking for Claude&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 6:&lt;/strong&gt; Precognition (Thinking Step by Step)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 7:&lt;/strong&gt; Using Examples&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Advanced&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 8:&lt;/strong&gt; Avoiding Hallucinations&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 9:&lt;/strong&gt; Building Complex Prompts (Industry Use Cases)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Complex Prompts from Scratch - Chatbot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Complex Prompts for Legal Services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise:&lt;/strong&gt; Complex Prompts for Financial Services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise:&lt;/strong&gt; Complex Prompts for Coding&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Congratulations &amp;amp; Next Steps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Appendix:&lt;/strong&gt; Beyond Standard Prompting&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Chaining Prompts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Tool Use&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search &amp;amp; Retrieval&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>