<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-05-05T01:29:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>jj-vcs/jj</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T01:29:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-05-05:/jj-vcs/jj</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Git-compatible VCS that is both simple and powerful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;title-block&#34; style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;Jujutsu—a version control system&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;jj logo&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/docs/images/jj-logo.svg?sanitize=true&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;320&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/martinvonz/jj&#34; alt=&#34;Release&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/release-date/martinvonz/jj&#34; alt=&#34;Release date&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/martinvonz/jj&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dkmfj3aGQN&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/968932220549103686.svg?label=&amp;amp;logo=discord&amp;amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;amp;color=7389D8&amp;amp;labelColor=6A7EC2&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.libera.chat/?channel=#jujutsu&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/irc-%23jujutsu-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;IRC&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/install-and-setup&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/tutorial&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/roadmap&#34;&gt;Development Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/#contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is a powerful &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Version_control&#34;&gt;version control system&lt;/a&gt; for software projects. You use it to get a copy of your code, track changes to the code, and finally publish those changes for others to see and use. It is designed from the ground up to be easy to use—whether you&#39;re new or experienced, working on brand new projects alone, or large scale software projects with large histories and teams.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is unlike most other systems, because internally it abstracts the user interface and version control algorithms from the &lt;em&gt;storage systems&lt;/em&gt; used to serve your content. This allows it to serve as a VCS with many possible physical backends, that may have their own data or networking models—like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mercurial-scm.org/&#34;&gt;Mercurial&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.breezy-vcs.org/&#34;&gt;Breezy&lt;/a&gt;, or hybrid systems like Google&#39;s cloud-based design, &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/W71BTkUbdqE?t=645&#34;&gt;Piper/CitC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, we use Git repositories as a storage layer to serve and track content, making it &lt;strong&gt;compatible with many of your favorite Git-based tools, right now!&lt;/strong&gt; All core developers use Jujutsu to develop Jujutsu, right here on GitHub. But it should hopefully work with your favorite Git forges, too.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We combine many distinct design choices and concepts from other version control systems into a single tool. Some of those sources of inspiration include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt;: We make an effort to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/discussions/49&#34;&gt;be fast&lt;/a&gt;—with a snappy UX, efficient algorithms, correct data structures, and good-old-fashioned attention to detail. The default storage backend uses Git repositories for &#34;physical storage&#34;, for wide interoperability and ease of onboarding.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercurial &amp;amp; Sapling&lt;/strong&gt;: There are many Mercurial-inspired features, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/revsets/&#34;&gt;revset&lt;/a&gt; language to select commits. There is &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-comparison/#the-index&#34;&gt;no explicit index&lt;/a&gt; or staging area. Branches are &#34;anonymous&#34; like Mercurial, so you don&#39;t need to make up a name for each small change. Primitives for rewriting history are powerful and simple. Formatting output is done with a robust template language that can be configured by the user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darcs&lt;/strong&gt;: Jujutsu keeps track of conflicts as &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/conflicts/&#34;&gt;first-class objects&lt;/a&gt; in its model; they are first-class in the same way commits are, while alternatives like Git simply think of conflicts as textual diffs. While not as rigorous as systems like Darcs (which is based on a formalized theory of patches, as opposed to snapshots), the effect is that many forms of conflict resolution can be performed and propagated automatically.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And it adds several innovative, useful features of its own:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working-copy-as-a-commit&lt;/strong&gt;: Changes to files are &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/working-copy/&#34;&gt;recorded automatically&lt;/a&gt; as normal commits, and amended on every subsequent change. This &#34;snapshot&#34; design simplifies the user-facing data model (commits are the only visible object), simplifies internal algorithms, and completely subsumes features like Git&#39;s stashes or the index/staging-area.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operation log &amp;amp; undo&lt;/strong&gt;: Jujutsu records every operation that is performed on the repository, from commits, to pulls, to pushes. This makes debugging problems like &#34;what just happened?&#34; or &#34;how did I end up here?&#34; easier, &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; when you&#39;re helping your coworker answer those questions about their repository! And because everything is recorded, you can undo that mistake you just made with ease. Version control has finally entered &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Undo#History&#34;&gt;the 1960s&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic rebase and conflict resolution&lt;/strong&gt;: When you modify a commit, every descendent is automatically rebased on top of the freshly-modified one. This makes &#34;patch-based&#34; workflows a breeze. If you resolve a conflict in a commit, the &lt;em&gt;resolution&lt;/em&gt; of that conflict is also propagated through descendants as well. In effect, this is a completely transparent version of &lt;code&gt;git rebase --update-refs&lt;/code&gt; combined with &lt;code&gt;git rerere&lt;/code&gt;, supported by design.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!WARNING] The following features are available for use, but experimental; they may have bugs, backwards incompatible storage changes, and user-interface changes!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safe, concurrent replication&lt;/strong&gt;: Have you ever wanted to store your version controlled repositories inside a Dropbox folder? Or continuously backup repositories to S3? No? Well, now you can!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fundamental problem with using filesystems like Dropbox and backup tools like &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; on your typical Git/Mercurial repositories is that they rely on &lt;em&gt;local filesystem operations&lt;/em&gt; being atomic, serialized, and non-concurrent with respect to other reads and writes—which is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; true when operating on distributed file systems, or when operations like concurrent file copies (for backup) happen while lock files are being held.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is instead designed to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/technical/concurrency/&#34;&gt;safe under concurrent scenarios&lt;/a&gt;; simply using rsync or Dropbox and then using that resulting repository should never result in a repository in a &lt;em&gt;corrupt state&lt;/em&gt;. The worst that &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; happen is that it will expose conflicts between the local and remote state, leaving you to resolve them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The command-line tool is called &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; for now because it&#39;s easy to type and easy to replace (rare in English). The project is called &#34;Jujutsu&#34; because it matches &#34;jj&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is relatively young, with lots of work to still be done. If you have any questions, or want to talk about future plans, please join us on Discord &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dkmfj3aGQN&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/968932220549103686.svg?label=&amp;amp;logo=discord&amp;amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;amp;color=7389D8&amp;amp;labelColor=6A7EC2&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, start a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/discussions&#34;&gt;GitHub Discussion&lt;/a&gt;, or send an IRC message to &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.libera.chat/?channel=#jujutsu&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#jujutsu&lt;/code&gt; on Libera Chat&lt;/a&gt;. The developers monitor all of these channels[^bridge].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[^bridge]: To be more precise, the &lt;code&gt;#jujutsu&lt;/code&gt; Libera IRC channel is bridged to one of the channels on jj&#39;s Discord. Some of the developers stay on Discord and use the bridge to follow IRC.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;News and Updates 📣&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; Repository has moved to the &lt;code&gt;jj-vcs&lt;/code&gt; GitHub organisation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Version 0.24 is released which adds &lt;code&gt;jj file annotate&lt;/code&gt;, which is equivalent to &lt;code&gt;git blame&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;hg annotate&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Martin gave a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LV0JzI8IcCY&#34;&gt;presentation about Jujutsu&lt;/a&gt; at Git Merge 2024.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Version 0.14 is released, which deprecates &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/CHANGELOG.md#0140---2024-02-07&#34;&gt;&#34;jj checkout&#34; and &#34;jj merge&#34;&lt;/a&gt;, as well as &lt;code&gt;jj init --git&lt;/code&gt;, which is now just called &lt;code&gt;jj git init&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Version 0.10.0 is released! Now includes a bundled merge and diff editor for all platforms, &#34;immutable revsets&#34; to avoid accidentally &lt;code&gt;edit&lt;/code&gt;-ing the wrong revisions, and lots of polish.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Martin gave a presentation about Google&#39;s plans for Jujutsu at Git Merge 2022! See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1F8j9_UOOSGUN9MvHxPZX_L4bQ9NMcYOp1isn17kTC_M/view&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bx_LGilOuE4&#34;&gt;recording&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Related Media&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mar 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Chris Krycho started &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLelyiwKWHHAq01Pvmpf6x7J0y-yQpmtxp&#34;&gt;a YouTube series about Jujutsu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Chris Krycho published an article about Jujutsu called &lt;a href=&#34;https://v5.chriskrycho.com/essays/jj-init/&#34;&gt;jj init&lt;/a&gt; and Steve Klabnik followed up with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://steveklabnik.github.io/jujutsu-tutorial/&#34;&gt;Jujutsu Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Jujutsu was featured in an LWN.net article called &lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/958468/&#34;&gt;Jujutsu: a new, Git-compatible version control system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jan 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Martin&#39;s Talk about Jujutsu at Git Merge 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bx_LGilOuE4&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; and the associated &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1F8j9_UOOSGUN9MvHxPZX_L4bQ9NMcYOp1isn17kTC_M/view&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wiki also contains a more extensive list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jj-vcs/jj/wiki/Media&#34;&gt;media references&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT] Jujutsu is an &lt;strong&gt;experimental version control system&lt;/strong&gt;. While Git compatibility is stable, and most developers use it daily for all their needs, there may still be work-in-progress features, suboptimal UX, and workflow gaps that make it unusable for your particular use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/install-and-setup&#34;&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt; to obtain and configure &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to get started is probably to go through &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/tutorial&#34;&gt;the tutorial&lt;/a&gt;. Also see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-comparison&#34;&gt;Git comparison&lt;/a&gt;, which includes a table of &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; vs. &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you become more familiar with Jujutsu, the following resources may be helpful:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/FAQ&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/glossary&#34;&gt;Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jj help&lt;/code&gt; command (e.g. &lt;code&gt;jj help rebase&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jj help -k &amp;lt;keyword&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; command (e.g. &lt;code&gt;jj help -k config&lt;/code&gt;). Use &lt;code&gt;jj help --help&lt;/code&gt; to see what keywords are available.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using a &lt;strong&gt;prerelease&lt;/strong&gt; version of &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt;, you would want to consult &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/prerelease/&#34;&gt;the docs for the prerelease (main branch) version&lt;/a&gt;. You can also get there from the docs for the latest release by using the website&#39;s version switcher. The version switcher is visible in the header of the website when you scroll to the top of any page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Compatible with Git&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is designed so that the underlying data and storage model is abstract. Today, only the Git backend is production-ready. The Git backend uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://libgit2.org/&#34;&gt;libgit2&lt;/a&gt; C library and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Byron/gitoxide&#34;&gt;gitoxide&lt;/a&gt; Rust library.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Git backend is fully featured and maintained, and allows you to use Jujutsu with any Git remote. The commits you create will look like regular Git commits. You can fetch branches from a regular Git remote and push branches to the remote. You can always switch back to Git.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is how you can explore a GitHub repository with &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/demos/git_compat.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can even have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/git-compatibility#co-located-jujutsugit-repos&#34;&gt;&#34;co-located&#34; local repository&lt;/a&gt; where you can use both &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; commands interchangeably.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The working copy is automatically committed&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu uses a real commit to represent the working copy. Checking out a commit results a new working-copy commit on top of the target commit. Almost all commands automatically amend the working-copy commit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The working-copy being a commit means that commands never fail because the working copy is dirty (no &#34;error: Your local changes to the following files...&#34;), and there is no need for &lt;code&gt;git stash&lt;/code&gt;. Also, because the working copy is a commit, commands work the same way on the working-copy commit as on any other commit, so you can set the commit message before you&#39;re done with the changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/demos/working_copy.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The repo is the source of truth&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Jujutsu, the working copy plays a smaller role than with Git. Commands snapshot the working copy before they start, then they update the repo, and then the working copy is updated (if the working-copy commit was modified). Almost all commands (even checkout!) operate on the commits in the repo, leaving the common functionality of snapshotting and updating of the working copy to centralized code. For example, &lt;code&gt;jj restore&lt;/code&gt; (similar to &lt;code&gt;git restore&lt;/code&gt;) can restore from any commit and into any commit, and &lt;code&gt;jj describe&lt;/code&gt; can set the commit message of any commit (defaults to the working-copy commit).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Entire repo is under version control&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All operations you perform in the repo are recorded, along with a snapshot of the repo state after the operation. This means that you can easily revert to an earlier repo state, or to simply undo a particular operation (which does not necessarily have to be the most recent operation).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/demos/operation_log.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Conflicts can be recorded in commits&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an operation results in &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/glossary#conflict&#34;&gt;conflicts&lt;/a&gt;, information about those conflicts will be recorded in the commit(s). The operation will succeed. You can then resolve the conflicts later. One consequence of this design is that there&#39;s no need to continue interrupted operations. Instead, you get a single workflow for resolving conflicts, regardless of which command caused them. This design also lets Jujutsu rebase merge commits correctly (unlike both Git and Mercurial).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic conflict resolution:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/demos/resolve_conflicts.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Juggling conflicts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/demos/juggle_conflicts.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Automatic rebase&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever you modify a commit, any descendants of the old commit will be rebased onto the new commit. Thanks to the conflict design described above, that can be done even if there are conflicts. Bookmarks pointing to rebased commits will be updated. So will the working copy if it points to a rebased commit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Comprehensive support for rewriting history&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Besides the usual rebase command, there&#39;s &lt;code&gt;jj describe&lt;/code&gt; for editing the description (commit message) of an arbitrary commit. There&#39;s also &lt;code&gt;jj diffedit&lt;/code&gt;, which lets you edit the changes in a commit without checking it out. To split a commit into two, use &lt;code&gt;jj split&lt;/code&gt;. You can even move part of the changes in a commit to any other commit using &lt;code&gt;jj squash -i --from X --into Y&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tool is fairly feature-complete, but some important features like support for Git submodules are not yet completed. There are also several performance bugs. It&#39;s likely that workflows and setups different from what the core developers use are not well supported, e.g. there is no native support for email-based workflows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, all core developers use &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; to work on &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt;. I (Martin von Zweigbergk) have almost exclusively used &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; to develop the project itself since early January 2021. I haven&#39;t had to re-clone from source (I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve even had to restore from backup).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be changes to workflows and backward-incompatible changes to the on-disk formats before version 1.0.0. Even the binary&#39;s name may change (i.e. away from &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt;). For any format changes, we&#39;ll try to implement transparent upgrades (as we&#39;ve done with recent changes), or provide upgrade commands or scripts if requested.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several tools trying to solve similar problems as Jujutsu. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/latest/related-work&#34;&gt;related work&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome outside contributions, and there&#39;s plenty of things to do, so don&#39;t be shy. Please ask if you want a pointer on something you can help with, and hopefully we can all figure something out.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do have &lt;a href=&#34;https://jj-vcs.github.io/jj/prerelease/contributing/&#34;&gt;a few policies and suggestions&lt;/a&gt; for contributors. The broad TL;DR:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bug reports are very welcome!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Every commit that lands in the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is code reviewed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please behave yourself, and obey the Community Guidelines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; a mandatory CLA you must agree to. Importantly, it &lt;strong&gt;does not&lt;/strong&gt; transfer copyright ownership to Google or anyone else; it simply gives us the right to safely redistribute and use your changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Mandatory Google Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I (Martin von Zweigbergk, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:martinvonz@google.com&#34;&gt;martinvonz@google.com&lt;/a&gt;) started Jujutsu as a hobby project in late 2019, and it has evolved into my full-time project at Google, with several other Googlers (now) assisting development in various capacities. That said, &lt;strong&gt;this is not a Google product&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jujutsu is available as Open Source Software, under the Apache 2.0 license. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for details about copyright and redistribution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;/code&gt; logo was contributed by J. Jennings and is licensed under a Creative Commons License, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jj-vcs/jj/main/docs/images/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;docs/images/LICENSE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>aipotheosis-labs/aci</title>
    <updated>2025-05-05T01:29:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-05-05:/aipotheosis-labs/aci</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ACI.dev is the open source platform that connects your AI agents to 600+ tool integrations with multi-tenant auth, granular permissions, and access through direct function calling or a unified MCP server.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/frontend/public/aci-dev-full-logo.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;ACI.dev Logo&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ACI: Open-Source Infra to Power Unified MCP Servers&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://trendshift.io/repositories/13645&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://trendshift.io/api/badge/repositories/13645&#34; alt=&#34;aipotheosis-labs%2Faci | Trendshift&#34; style=&#34;width: 250px; height: 55px;&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;55&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aci.dev/docs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Documentation-34a1bf&#34; alt=&#34;Documentation&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://badge.fury.io/py/aci-sdk&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badge.fury.io/py/aci-sdk.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;PyPI version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2.0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache_2.0-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/UU2XAnfHJh&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-Join_Chat-7289DA.svg?logo=discord&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/AipoLabs&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/AipoLabs?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Follow&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] This repo is for the ACI.dev platform. If you&#39;re looking for the &lt;strong&gt;Unified MCP&lt;/strong&gt; server built with ACI.dev, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-mcp&#34;&gt;aci-mcp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACI.dev is the open-source infrastructure layer for AI-agent tool-use. It gives your agents intent-aware access to 600+ tools with multi-tenant auth, granular permissions, and dynamic tool discovery—exposed as either direct function calls or through a &lt;strong&gt;Unified Model-Context-Protocol (MCP) server&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of writing separate OAuth flows and API clients for Google Calendar, Slack, and more, use ACI.dev to manage authentication and provide your AI agents with unified, secure function calls. Access these capabilities through our &lt;strong&gt;Unified&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-mcp&#34;&gt;MCP server&lt;/a&gt; or via our lightweight &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-python-sdk&#34;&gt;Python SDK&lt;/a&gt;, compatible with any LLM framework.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Build production-ready AI agents without the infrastructure headaches.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/frontend/public/aci-architecture-intro.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;ACI.dev Architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; Join us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/UU2XAnfHJh&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; to help shape the future of Open Source AI Infrastructure.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 🌟 &lt;strong&gt;Star ACI.dev to stay updated on new releases!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/stargazers&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/aipotheosis-labs/aci?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Stars&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📺 Demo Video&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GSR9P53-_7E?feature=shared&#34;&gt;ACI.dev &lt;strong&gt;Unified MCP Server&lt;/strong&gt; Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GSR9P53-_7E?feature=shared&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/frontend/public/umcp-demo-thumbnail.png&#34; alt=&#34;ACI.dev Unified MCP Server Demo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;✨ Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;600+ Pre-built Integrations&lt;/strong&gt;: Connect to popular services and apps in minutes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Access Methods&lt;/strong&gt;: Use our unified MCP server or our lightweight SDK for direct function calling.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-tenant Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;: Built-in OAuth flows and secrets management for both developers and end-users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Agent Reliability&lt;/strong&gt;: Natural language permission boundaries and dynamic tool discovery.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framework &amp;amp; Model Agnostic&lt;/strong&gt;: Works with any LLM framework and agent architecture.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;100% Open Source&lt;/strong&gt;: Everything released under Apache 2.0 (backend, dev portal, integrations).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💡 Why Use ACI.dev?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACI.dev solves your critical infrastructure challenges for production-ready AI agents:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication at Scale&lt;/strong&gt;: Connect multiple users to multiple services securely.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery Without Overload&lt;/strong&gt;: Find and use the right tools without overwhelming LLM context windows.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Permissions&lt;/strong&gt;: Control agent capabilities with human-readable boundaries.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build Once, Run Anywhere&lt;/strong&gt;: No vendor lock-in with our open source, framework-agnostic approach.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🧰 Common Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Assistant Chatbots:&lt;/strong&gt; Build chatbots that can search the web, manage calendars, send emails, interact with SaaS tools, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research Agent:&lt;/strong&gt; Conducts research on specific topics and syncs results to other apps (e.g., Notion, Google Sheets).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outbound Sales Agent:&lt;/strong&gt; Automates lead generation, email outreach, and CRM updates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Support Agent:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides answers, manages tickets, and performs actions based on customer queries.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🔗 Quick Links&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managed Service:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aci.dev/&#34;&gt;aci.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aci.dev/docs&#34;&gt;aci.dev/docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Available Tools List:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aci.dev/tools&#34;&gt;aci.dev/tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python SDK:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-python-sdk&#34;&gt;github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-python-sdk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unified MCP Server:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-mcp&#34;&gt;github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-mcp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agent Examples Built with ACI.dev:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-agents&#34;&gt;github.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci-agents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aci.dev/blog&#34;&gt;aci.dev/blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/UU2XAnfHJh&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/AipoLabs&#34;&gt;Twitter/X&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/company/aipotheosis-labs-aipolabs/posts/?feedView=all&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💻 Getting Started: Local Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run the full ACI.dev platform (backend server and frontend portal) locally, follow the individual README files for each component:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/backend/README.md&#34;&gt;backend/README.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/frontend/README.md&#34;&gt;frontend/README.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;👋 Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions! Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Integration Requests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Missing any integrations (apps or functions) you need? Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aipotheosis-labs/aci/main/.github/ISSUE_TEMPLATE/integration_request.yml&#34;&gt;Integration Request Template&lt;/a&gt; and submit an integration request! Or, if you&#39;re feeling adventurous, you can submit a PR to add the integration yourself!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Star History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.star-history.com/#aipotheosis-labs/aci&amp;amp;Date&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=aipotheosis-labs/aci&amp;amp;type=Date&#34; alt=&#34;Star History Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>