<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-07-03T01:28:28Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>moby/moby</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T01:28:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-07-03:/moby/moby</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/moby/moby" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Moby Project - a collaborative project for the container ecosystem to assemble container-based systems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Moby Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/moby/moby/master/docs/static_files/moby-project-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Moby Project logo&#34; title=&#34;The Moby Project&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moby is an open-source project created by Docker to enable and accelerate software containerization.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It provides a &#34;Lego set&#34; of toolkit components, the framework for assembling them into custom container-based systems, and a place for all container enthusiasts and professionals to experiment and exchange ideas. Components include container build tools, a container registry, orchestration tools, a runtime and more, and these can be used as building blocks in conjunction with other tools and projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Principles&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moby is an open project guided by strong principles, aiming to be modular, flexible and without too strong an opinion on user experience. It is open to the community to help set its direction.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modular: the project includes lots of components that have well-defined functions and APIs that work together.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Batteries included but swappable: Moby includes enough components to build fully featured container systems, but its modular architecture ensures that most of the components can be swapped by different implementations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Usable security: Moby provides secure defaults without compromising usability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Developer focused: The APIs are intended to be functional and useful to build powerful tools. They are not necessarily intended as end user tools but as components aimed at developers. Documentation and UX is aimed at developers not end users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Audience&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Moby Project is intended for engineers, integrators and enthusiasts looking to modify, hack, fix, experiment, invent and build systems based on containers. It is not for people looking for a commercially supported system, but for people who want to work and learn with open source code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Relationship with Docker&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The components and tools in the Moby Project are initially the open source components that Docker and the community have built for the Docker Project. New projects can be added if they fit with the community goals. Docker is committed to using Moby as the upstream for the Docker Product. However, other projects are also encouraged to use Moby as an upstream, and to reuse the components in diverse ways, and all these uses will be treated in the same way. External maintainers and contributors are welcomed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Moby project is not intended as a location for support or feature requests for Docker products, but as a place for contributors to work on open source code, fix bugs, and make the code more useful. The releases are supported by the maintainers, community and users, on a best efforts basis only, and are not intended for customers who want enterprise or commercial support; Docker EE is the appropriate product for these use cases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Legal&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brought to you courtesy of our legal counsel. For more context, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/moby/moby/raw/master/NOTICE&#34;&gt;NOTICE&lt;/a&gt; document in this repo.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use and transfer of Moby may be subject to certain restrictions by the United States and other governments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is your responsibility to ensure that your use and/or transfer does not violate applicable laws.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bis.doc.gov&#34;&gt;https://www.bis.doc.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Licensing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moby is licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/moby/moby/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for the full license text.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>actualbudget/actual-server</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T01:28:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-07-03:/actualbudget/actual-server</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/actualbudget/actual-server" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Actual&#39;s server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the main project to run &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actualbudget/actual&#34;&gt;Actual&lt;/a&gt;, a local-first personal finance tool. It comes with the latest version of Actual, and a server to persist changes and make data available across all devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Actual is a local-first personal finance tool. It is 100% free and open-source, written in NodeJS, it has a synchronization element so that all your changes can move between devices without any heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in contributing, or want to know how development works, see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/contributing/&#34;&gt;contributing&lt;/a&gt; document we would love to have you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to say thanks? Click the ⭐ at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have a wide range of documentation on how to use Actual. This is all available in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/&#34;&gt;Community Documentation&lt;/a&gt;, including topics on &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/install/&#34;&gt;installing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/budgeting/&#34;&gt;Budgeting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/accounts/&#34;&gt;Account Management&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://actualbudget.org/docs/getting-started/tips-tricks&#34;&gt;Tips &amp;amp; Tricks&lt;/a&gt; and some documentation for developers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Feature Requests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current feature requests can be seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actualbudget/actual/issues?q=is%3Aissue+label%3A%22needs+votes%22+sort%3Areactions-%2B1-desc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Vote for your favorite requests by reacting 👍 to the top comment of the request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add new feature requests, open a new Issue of the &#34;Feature Request&#34; type.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor</title>
    <updated>2024-07-03T01:28:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-07-03:/ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Elden Ring Save Editor. Compatible with PC and Playstation saves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ER Save Editor&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor/raw/master/icon/readme.md&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor/assets/131625063/e1d40274-066a-4b72-b010-de9170090b60&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tool for editing Elden Ring save files. Compatible with PC and Playstation Save Wizard exported saves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use with caution:&lt;/strong&gt; This tool should be used responsibly. Always backup your save file before making any edits. This is a hobby project developed during spare time and is intended for easier character build making. I do not endorse or condone cheating online.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Import characters from other save files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change pc save file SteamID&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modify player name&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change player gender&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit player stats&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modify soul count&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add items, weapons, armors, ashes of war, and talismans to inventory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add items in bulk to speed up build making process.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Browse inventory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change player equipment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Activate/deactivate Sites of Grace, summoning pools, colosseums, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Revive or kill bosses&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Activate/deactivate invasion regions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More features will be added in future updates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Permissions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use this save editor for learning or development purposes. However, I do not authorize its use for creating tools or modifications that enable actions online outside the bounds of what the game allows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Q: Will this ban me?&lt;br&gt; A: There&#39;s no guarantee that you won&#39;t be banned. None of these features have been tested online.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any bugs or issues while using the save editor, please report them. When reporting bugs, try to provide reproducible steps so I can debug effectively.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nordgaren/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ClayAmore/ER-Save-Editor/assets/131625063/710c9ee6-c3df-4665-be6b-d96bce1ebf46&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>