<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-05T01:30:48Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SheerSt/pokewilds</title>
    <updated>2022-11-05T01:30:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-05:/SheerSt/pokewilds</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SheerSt/pokewilds" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PokeWilds - A Gen 2 Game/Engine using libGDX&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PokeWilds&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/SheerSt/pokemon-wilds-public/raw/main/github1.png&#34; alt=&#34;PokeWilds&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Play&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong&gt; this is currently in Alpha. Things are getting there, but still not fully complete. I am working hard to find and fix bugs; however, &lt;strong&gt;expect to find bugs.&lt;/strong&gt; If you find a bug, please consider creating an issue here on github describing it (that would help me out a ton).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows - Download pokemon-wilds-windows64 from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SheerSt/pokewilds/releases/latest/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/SheerSt/pokewilds/releases/latest/&lt;/a&gt; and extract files. Open the unzipped directory and run pokemon-wilds.exe. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If the exe is not running, alternatively try running pokemon-wilds.jar in the same directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Controls: Arrow keys to move, keyboard Z = A button, keyboard X = B button, keyboard Enter = Start button. Hold keyboard X to run.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full list of pokemon, their habitats, harvestable items, field moves, spawn locations and more info can be found here - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1b6tkjKaDcFCYxvhWDHQi2B18lhtqgueFNNOP8ZdtTLs&#34;&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1b6tkjKaDcFCYxvhWDHQi2B18lhtqgueFNNOP8ZdtTLs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PokeWilds is a Gen 2 game/engine built using libGDX. It uses procedural generation to create large worlds with different biomes, each with their own unique monsters. The levels of wild monsters increase the further you explore, meaning that some biomes with rare mons are difficult to get to. Your monsters can help you explore the world by usual means (cut, fly, surf etc), but there are also be new HMs that allow you to interact with the world in new ways, like building structures/houses, jumping up ledges, starting fires, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been using a set of techniques to &#39;rip&#39; sprites and animations from the console game very accurately - as such, the game is intended to look and feel just like the console games, with some extra capabilities (see core/assets/attacks/). The benefit from using libGDX is that the engine can support cross-platform play, multiplayer, huge maps, and fullscreen mode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the future I hope that the game can also support graphics from other generations, as well as a map editor mode that could serve as a platform for custom games.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting / Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If world generation takes longer than 5 min, try closing the game and retrying.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If your system language isn&#39;t English, the game will sometimes fail to generate maps. Please see the following article for changing installing an English language pack, and switching to it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/install-a-language-for-windows-ccd853d3-9ecd-7da7-9ef0-72b4a055410a&#34;&gt;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/install-a-language-for-windows-ccd853d3-9ecd-7da7-9ef0-72b4a055410a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There is an issue where the game won&#39;t open if an &#39;!&#39; is included in the path to the game&#39;s directory. Move the game outside of the directory containing &#39;!&#39; in the name and reopen the game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The games cli output can help narrow down issues. How to run the game in cli mode (windows 10): &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open the folder containing pokemon-wilds.exe&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shift + right-click in the folder and select &#39;Open powershell window here&#39;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Type &#39;cmd&#39; in the window and press enter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;type pokemon-wilds.exe into the window and press enter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The game will open. Various info will be periodically written to the powershell window, like which song is playing. Error messages will also display here.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cli output like &lt;code&gt;Opengl not supported&lt;/code&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Try updating your graphics drivers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Try switching from your dedicated graphics to integrated graphics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the game stops loading your save file (ie it&#39;s corrupted), you can try using the save file&#39;s backup with contains your second-to-last save. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The backup save is named &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;game-name&amp;gt;.sav.backup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Rename &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;game-name&amp;gt;.sav.backup&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;new-game-name&amp;gt;.sav.zip&lt;/code&gt; and extract contents &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Extracted contents need to be a directory called &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;new-game-name&amp;gt;.sav/&lt;/code&gt; with game, map0,0 etc files inside&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Load&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dev mode instructions and capabilities:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Starting the game in dev mode (windows 10): &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open the folder containing pokemon-wilds.exe&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shift + right-click in the folder and select &#39;Open powershell window here&#39;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Type &lt;code&gt;cmd&lt;/code&gt; in the window and press enter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;type &lt;code&gt;pokemon-wilds.exe dev&lt;/code&gt; into the window and press enter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Paint tiles anywhere by clicking on the screen &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press ctrl to reduce the brush size and alt to increase the brush size&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press C and V to cycle through tiles&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Holding space bar will: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make you run really fast&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Prevent wild encounters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Allow you to walk through walls&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;L key - takes a full-map screenshot and puts it in the game directory (game will freeze for a bit)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use WASD to pan the camera around the map.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use Q and E to zoom the camera in/out.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;v0.8 (Latest) Updates and Changes:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Water types can Surf.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Surf or Fly to the edge of the map to generate a new World. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The new world will not contain dungeons from previous worlds (regi dungeon, mansion and desert ruins currently)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Psychic types know Teleport. Build warp tiles and teleport to them (from the Menu or the Map) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Interact with a warp tile to set label text (visible from the Map or when walking over the tile)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The new world will contain content from the most recent version of the game (even if an old save file is used)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Guide menu added (contains game faqs)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gen 3+ monsters now use their gen 8 (or highest available) stats and learnsets. ie no more prism stats or learnsets. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This will inevitably introduce some bugs since it&#39;s a big change.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can build signs and gravestones now. Interact to set sign text.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Special / Physical split added. Move category displayed in-battle now. Special / Physical split is toggle-able via the settings.txt file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Large trees are now cuttable by fully-evolved grass types.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Berry trees - cutting berry trees will yield berry seeds. Berry seeds will grow different types of berry trees depending on the soil they are planted in. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;desert -&amp;gt; rawst, beach -&amp;gt; pecha, forest -&amp;gt; persim, snow -&amp;gt; aspear, savanna -&amp;gt; cheri, graveyard -&amp;gt; chesto, &#xA;    &lt;secret&gt;&#xA;      -&amp;gt; lum.&#xA;    &lt;/secret&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Monster storage box added &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Monsters can be nicknamed or released while using the storage box.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various sub-biomes added - volcano, tidal, wooded lake, graveyard, savanna. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Each contains unique monsters, buried items and activities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Spiritomb urn can be found in the graveyard.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Tides go up twice per day and down twice per day.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Animated coastline added to whole island.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There&#39;s a lot more here but I&#39;ll let people explore and find out :)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various biomes improved or updated - tundra and mountains (various small tweaks elsewhere).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fairy types now drop Stardust, Fighting types drop Binding Band, Ghost types drop Life Force.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tundra and Wooded Lake house variants added.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can build an upstairs to houses. Place new floor in an upstairs using &#39;Floor&#39; tiles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A house can contain a number of floors equal to the number of exterior walls it has, extending vertically.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can change bed sheets by building a floor over the bed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New trainer types added (Thank you to everyone who contributed backsprites! they look awesome :)) - more info in the wilds-dex doc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Campfires should cause less lag at night (code optimizations added)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvements made to a certain legendary battle (WIP).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&#39;Kiln&#39; can be built indoors. Balls can be upgraded at the Kiln (new Balls include quick ball, timer ball, net ball, dive ball, nest ball, dream ball, heal ball. Dusk ball, great ball and ultra ball moved to the Kiln)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Many monster overworld sprites updated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various new monsters added.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additions to battle mechanics - trap damage fixed, recoil damage added, selfdestruct effect added, and various others.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keybinding for keyboards added (settings.txt in the game directory).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mods support added for some things &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Monster base stats, learnsets, and egg moves can be modded. normal.pal no longer required for some monsters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New player types can be added in the mods/ folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;All music can be modded by mirroring the folder structure from the git repo in the mods/ folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;All graphics can be modded by mirroring the folder structure from the git repo in the mods/ folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various bug fixes and tweaks. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Night is brighter now.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UI&#39;s updated to Gen 2 style.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special thank-you to everyone who has contributed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Battle sprites:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits to Nuuk on discord (nuukiie on twitter) for many battle sprites.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits to the Prism team for many battle sprites.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Whimsicott battle sprites - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cottonee battle and overworld sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Morelull front animation and overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Morelull back sprite - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stunfisk battle and overworld sprites - Skymaury on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Carbink battle sprites - Skymaury on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gothitelle battle sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gothorita battle sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gothita battle sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minccino battle sprites - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cinccino battle sprites - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Oranguru battle and overworld sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diancie battle and overworld sprites - Iustinus Tempus on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Komala battle sprites - Village on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pyukumuku battle sprites - Village on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Durant battle and overworld sprites - GenDraconis on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Indeedee Male and Indeedee Female battle and overworld sprites - Gyu on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Liepard battle and overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom normal form back sprite - PotatoCheep on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom normal form front and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lickilicky battle sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drampa battle sprites - Lavios on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Decidueye battle sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Munchlax battle sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tyrunt battle sprites - SharkGuy on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tyrantrum battle sprites - SharkGuy on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bewear battle and overworld sprites - Potato Q on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stufful front sprites - Potato Q and Sadfish on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stufful back and overworld sprites - Potato Q on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minior battle and overworld sprites - MKNZ on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grimmsnarl battle sprites - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Greninja battle and overworld sprites - EnzoDaiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zoroark battle and overworld sprites - Sorrel on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gourgeist back sprite - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gourgeist front sprites - nik11dy6 on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dedenne battle sprites - Skymaury on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hawlucha battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Meltan battle and overworld sprites - Scoobleblablebly on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Toxel battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Frogadier and overworld battle sprites - EnzoDaiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Froakie battle and overworld sprites - EnzoDaiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Popplio battle and overworld sprites - Kishibird on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom Mow form battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom Fan form battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom Frost form battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom Wash form battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rotom Heat form battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scorbunny battle sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dartrix battle sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Oshawott battle sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Starly battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Staravia battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deino, Zweilous, Hydreigon front sprites - PotatoCheep on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deino, Zweilous, Hydreigon back sprites - bugcut on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alolan Grimer battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alolan Muk battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cramorant battle and overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Happiny battle sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Impidimp battle sprites - IncuTyph on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Falinks battle and overworld sprites - CynderQuill on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mime Jr. battle sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Slurpuff battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flabebe, Floette, Florges battle and overworld sprites - SharkGuy on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kubfu battle sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Honedge battle sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Raboot battle sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sinistea battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Heatmor battle and overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Farfetch&#39;d battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sirfetch&#39;d battle and overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Yamask battle and overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Mr. Mime front animation - Scarlax, BloodlessNS and ShadowOne333 on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mr. Rime front animation - Menu and Scarlax on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gossifleur and Eldegoss battle and overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copperajah front sprites - Exet on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copperajah back sprite - SheerSt on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Aegislash Shield/Sword Forme battle and overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Doublade battle and overworlds sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wooloo battle sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dubwool battle and overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lunala battle and overworld sprites - Sage on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Woobat, Swoobat battle sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vanillite battle sprites - Toastknight on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Toxtricity (lowkey and regular) battle and overworld sprites - sun_dew on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lillipup, Herdier, and Stoutland battle and overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bounsweet front sprites - Quilchess on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bounsweet back sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Steenee battle sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fomantis battle sprites - Toastknight on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Axew battle sprites - GenDraconis on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Karrablast and Escavalier battle sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shelmet and Accelgor battle sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Polteageist battle and overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Mr. Mime and Mr. Rime back sprites - Scarlax on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Incineroar battle sprites - Toastknight on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Foongus battle sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mimikyu battle sprites - TerraTerraCotta on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Turtwig battle and overworld sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Inkay battle sprites - Vandom on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Torterra overworld and battle sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sliggoo and Goodra battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cofagrigus battle and overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shiinotic battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grotle battle sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Timburr battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Goomy front animation - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Goomy back sprite and shiny colors - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Burmy and Wormadam battle sprites (all forms) - sun_dew on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clobbopus battle and overworld sprites - SharkGuy on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kleavor battle sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Corsola back sprite - ICantBelieveItsNotBowser on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Corsola front sprites - ICantBelieveItsNotBowser and SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Yamask front sprites - EeVeeEe and Goose on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Yamask back sprite - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stonjourner front animation - PotatoCheep and SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Snom, Frosmoth front sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Snom back sprite - ash on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Frosmoth back sprite - Molk and EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cosmog, Cosmoem front sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Phione front and back sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pumpkaboo front and back sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runegris front animation - Scarlax and EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runegris back sprite - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Applin front sprites - ICantBelieveItsNotBowser on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Applin back sprites - ICantBelieveItsNotBowser and betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Probopass, Mantyke battle sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Luvdisc, Sandygast, Palossand battle sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ambipom battle sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Duraludon front sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Duraludon back sprite - PotatoCheep on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bronzor and Bronzong battle sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sandile line front sprites - Goose and Sadfish on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sandile line back and overworld sprites - Sadfish on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sigilyph battle sprites - Sadfish on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Darumaka and Galarian Darumaka battle sprites - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Darmanitan battle sprites - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Zen Darmanitan back sprite - Sir Feralipogchamp on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zen Darmanitan front sprite - Sir Feralipogchamp on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zen Darmanitan back sprite - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Darmanitan front sprite - Poisonous Gas on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Darmanitan back sprite - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Elgyem and Beheeyem battle sprites - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hippopotas and Hippowdon battle and overworld sprites - Sadfish on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Camerupt front sprites - Poisonous Gas and Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alolan Exeggutor battle sprites - Gmerc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regirock, Registeel, Regice, and Regigigas battle sprites - Mr Dustman, Sadfish and Poisonous Gas on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regieleki and Regidrago battle sprites - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Corphish battle and overworld sprites - sir feralipogchamp on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Crawdaunt battle sprites - sir feralipogchamp, Mr Dustman, Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Overworld sprites:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credits to Megaman-Omega on Deviantart for many overworld sprites.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Phantump overworld sprites - Goose on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alolan Raichu, Galar Yamask, Cacturne, Mantyke, Mantine, and Remoraid overworld sprites - Sadfish on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trevenant, Sandslash, Ekans, Arbok, Sharpedo, Dratini, Dragonair, Dragonite, Ledyba, Hoothoot, Sandshrew, Aipom, Ambipom, Miltank, Sudowoodo, Horsea, Seadra, Kingdra, Smoochum, Noctowl, Nidoking and Jinx overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Golduck, Hatenna, Kabuto, Mightyena, Noivern, Omanyte, Omastar, Pelipper, Psyduck, Wailmer, and Wailord overworld sprites - Gargoyle on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pumpkaboo, Snom, Frosmoth, Sandygast, Palossand, Goomy, Hoppip, Azurill, Dodrio, Doduo, Entei, Gloom, Gourgeist, Vileplume, Starmie, Quagsire, Oddish, Staryu, Skiploom, Jumpluff, Poliwag, Sunflora, Politoed, Poliwhirl, Poliwrath, Raikou, Suicune, Sunkern, Applin, Alolan Marowak, Bellosom, Heracross, Primeape, Marowak, Bellossom and Delibird overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bidoof overworld sprites - LuxBeacon and betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bibarel, Buizel, Floatzel, Hatterene, Minun, Noibat, Pikipek, Plusle, Trumbeak, Appletun, Happiny, Drowzee, Luvdisc, Manaphy, Phione, Flapple, Octillery, Stonjourner, Corphish, Crawdaunt, Duraludon, Dedenne, Carbink, Electrike, Diancie, Munchlax and Volbeat overworld sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Qwilfish overworld sprites - kyro909 on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Toucannon overworld sprites - Invader and LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Murkrow and Honchkrow overworld sprites - Invader on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grimer, Muk, Pinsir, Diglett, Dugtrio, Wooloo, Mr. Mime overworld sprites - Snak on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Voltorb overworld sprites - Goose and Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pancham, Dhelmise, Klefki, Honedge overworld sprites - Et3rniti on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Carvanha, Starly, and Staravia overworld sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Probopass, Mime Jr, Oshawott, Girafarig and Pachirisu overworld sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drilbur, Excadrill, Hydreigon, Zweilous and Deino overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NidoranF, Nidorina, Nidoqueen, Skarmory, Tauros, Jirachi, Cosmog, Cosmoem and Aerodactyl overworld sprites - Sage on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NidoranM overworld sprites - Sir Fear-ali on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Milcery and Cufant overworld sprites - SkwovetSquire and LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cottonee, Dewott overworld sprite - hades da god on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Whimsicott overworld sprite - hades da god and Et3rniti on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pangoro overworld sprite - hades da god and SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lilligant, Golett, Petilil, Ledian and Golurk overworld sprites - Sayaka on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clefairy overworld sprites - Meowmie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hattrem overworld sprites - Filth-sama on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Croagunk overworld sprites - SCHLIEMONI on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shuckle overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cramorant overworld sprites - Sadfish on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cubone overworld sprites - uchuu on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Combee and Vespiquen battle and overworld sprites - TerraTerraCotta on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cutiefly and Ribombee battle and overworld sprites - TerraTerraCotta on discord (and Sadfish for Cutiefly overworld sprites)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sigilyph overworld sprites - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Darumaka overworld sprites - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Darumaka overworld sprites - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Darmanitan overworld sprites - Sadfish and Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Darmanitan and Zen Darmanitan overworld sprites - Poisonous Gas and Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Elgyem and Beheeyem overworld sprites - Sadfish and Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wooper, Wingull, Linoone and Unown overworld sprites - Snak on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Weedle, Kakuna, Beedrill, Abomasnow, Rattata, and Raticate overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Larvesta, Poochyena and Nosepass overworld sprites - Sadfish on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maractus overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zigzagoon overworld sprites - Miserable Pile Of Secrets and Kalvinz on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regieleki overworld sprites and &#39;alternate&#39; Regi overworld sprites - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regidrago, Regirock, Regice and Registeel overworld sprites - sir feralipogchamp on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Crawdaunt overworld sprites - sir feralipogchamp on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dwebble overworld sprites - Sadfish, Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Crustle overworld sprites - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Litwick, Lampent and Chandelure overworld sprites - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Snover overworld sprites - Turner on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stantler overworld sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kubfu overworld sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Seel and Dewgong overworld sprites - Potato Q on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grubbin, Charjabug and Vikavolt overworld sprites - Elusiveplayer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Treecko, Torchic overworld sprites - Filth-sama on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zorua overworld sprites - Sorrel on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Venonat, Venomoth overworld sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wooloo overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mawile overworld sprites - Iustinus Tempus on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Latias and Latios overworld sprites - Elusiveplayer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shiinotic overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Buizel and Floatzel overworld sprites - Filth-sama on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Piplup, Prinplup and Empoleon overworld sprites - Elusiveplayer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mudkip, Marshtomp and Swampert overworld sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Igglybuff, Jigglypuff, Wigglytuff overworld sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gothita, Gothorita, Gothitelle overworld sprites - Roffles on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scorbunny, Raboot, Cinderace overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cleffa overworld sprites - Meowmie/Tabby on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lickitung, Lickilicky overworld sprites - Shaqtothefuture on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Magnemite, Magneton, Magnezone overworld sprites - ElusivePlayer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chinchou, Lanturn overworld sprites - ElusivePlayer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pachirisu overworld sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Plusle, Minun overworld sprites - Lux and GenDraconis on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drampa overworld sprites - Lavios on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Noibat and Noivern overworld sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Audino overworld sprites - Gyu on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Happiny overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mimikyu overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Beheeyem overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Toucannon overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Duraludon overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Octillery overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dartrix and Decidueye overworld sprites - Ayinai on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hypno overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wobbuffet overworld sprites - Scoobleblablebly on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Combusken, Blaziken overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trubbish overworld sprites - SaltExplosion on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grovyle, Sceptile overworld sprites - Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swadloon and Leavanny overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Krabby and Wurmple overworld sprites - Jiggy on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Goomy overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sligoo, Goodra overworld sprites - OtDxRaichunite on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nincada, Ninjask and Shedinja overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Granbull overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Skitty and Delcatty overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Slakoth, Vigoroth and Slaking overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cascoon, Dustox, Silcoon, and Beautifly overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spoink and Grumpig overworld sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Urshifu overworld sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Mr. Mime, Mr. Rime overworld sprites - Lux and EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copperajah overworld sprites - hades da god on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Seedot overworld sprites - hades da god on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Celebi overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Venipede overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scolipede overworld sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runerigus overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galar Yamask overworld sprites - EeVeeEe and Hibiwiki on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Calyrex overworld sprites - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Quilladin and Chesnaught overworld sprites - peach-n-key and LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tepig overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pikipek, Trumbeak overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Snivy overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fomantis overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Budew, Roselia and Roserade overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Joltik and Galvantula overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vanillite, Vanillish overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vanilluxe overworld sprites - Kazdraws0w0 on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nuzleaf overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kommo-o overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gulpin, Swalot overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pignite overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Obstagoon overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Purrloin overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shelmet and Accelgor overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Karrablast and Escavalier overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Oddish, Gloom, Vileploom, Primeape, Poliwag, Poliwhirl, Poliwrath, Snorlax, Raikou, Entei, and Suicune overworld sprite edits - JappaWakka on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wimpod overworld sprites - HERO on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Solosis, Duosion, and Reuniclus overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Servine, Serperior overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lurantis overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shellos East and Shellos West overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cyndaquil, Quilava and Typhlosion overworld sprites - Invader and MegamanOmega on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hisuian Typhlosion overworld sprites - Invader on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hisuian Growlithe overworld sprites - Bugcut on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fennekin overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wynaut overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cursola overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Corsola overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Corsola overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ursaluna overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rookidee overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deoxys overworld sprites (all forms) - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hisuian Decidueye, Samurott and Hisuian Samurott overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hisuian Voltorb and Hisuian Electrode overworld sprites - MapleSyrup on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pawniard and Bisharp overworld sprites - Sayaka on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Meditite and Medicham overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rufflet and Kingler overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regigigas and Corvisquire overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chimchar, Infernape and Monferno overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Castform and Cloyster overworld sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Farfetch&#39;d, Galarian Ponyta and Galarian Rapidash overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sewaddle overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blipbug overworld sprites - Rolyer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drizzile overworld sprites - E.splash on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tapu Fini, Tapu Bulu, Tapu Lele, Tapu Koko and Hatenna overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hatterene, Tyrantrum, Primarina, Hisuian Braviary and Braviary overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gorebyss, Huntail, Clamperl and Corviknight overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Burmy and Wormadam overworld sprites (all forms) - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Doduo and Dodrio overworld sprite edits - JappaWakka on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mankey overworld sprites - Rolyer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nidorino overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Burmy and Wormadam overworld sprites (all forms) - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shellder overworld sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sewaddle overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blipbug overworld sprites - Rolyer on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kabutops overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sobble and Drizzile overworld sprites - E.splash on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Meowth and Persian overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vullaby and Mandibuzz overworld sprites - Sayaka on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Axew, Fraxure and Haxorus overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Litten overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Magearna overworld sprites (both forms) - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Grapploct overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tynamo overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bonsly overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tyrunt overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Braixen and Delphox overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rowlet overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tsareena overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hattrem overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Victini overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fletchling overworld sprites - Kommie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spheal and Sealeo overworld sprites - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Golisopod overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Garbodor overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shiftry overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Steenee overworld sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kleavor overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Timburr, Gurdurr, and Conkeldurr overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Overworld animations:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Galarian Darumaka, Alolan Exeggutor, Pangoro, Runerigus, Thwackey, Yamask overworld sleep animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;abomasnow, ambipom, azurill, bidoof, budew, cascoon, chimchar, corphish, crawdaunt, empoleon, hippopotas_f, hippopotas_m, lickilicky, marshtomp, mothim, mudkip, nincada, onix, piplup, regice, regigigas, regirock, registeel, roserade, rotom, seedot, seel, shedinja, shellder, shiftry, silcoon, snorunt, swampert, torchic, wurmple overworld sleep animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clobbopus, Cufant, Duraludon, Frosmoth, Grapploct, Hatenna, Hatterene, Hattrem, Indeedee female, Indeedee male, Pincurchin, Polteageist, Sinistea, Sizzlipede, Snom, Stonjourner, Toxel, Toxtricity amped, Toxtricity Lowkey overworld sleeping animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cranidos headbutt OW animation - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;blipbug, corviknight, corvisquire, cramorant, drizzile, dubwool, eldegoss, foongus, gossifleur, grookey, inteleon, leavanny, munna, raboot, rookidee, scorbunny, seismitoad, silicobra, skwovet, sobble, swadloon, thievul, thwackey, wimpod, wooloo, yamper overworld sleep animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;wimpod OW sleep animation - Aaamdacuaga and Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All furfrou form OW sleep animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unown OW sleep animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vivillon sleeping OW animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;minior sleep spinning animation - Blumiau and Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;araquanid, bewear, charjabug, drampa, fomantis, golisopod, grubbin, kommo-o, lurantis, mimikyu, morelull, oranguru, palossand, pikipek, sandygast, shiinotic, stufful, togedemaru, toucannon, trumbeak, turtonator, vikavolt, yungoos overworld sleep animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;skorupi, spewpa, spritzee, swanna, talonflame, throh, tirtouga overworld sleep animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;corphish, crawdaunt, crobat, gloom, hoppip, kabutops, oddish overworld cut animations - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;absol, zangoose overworld cut animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;chimecho overworld idle animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;chingling overworld overworld idle animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;raticate_alolan, rattata_alolan, bellsprout, grotle, raticate, rattata, torterra, victreebel, weepinbell overworld cut animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;brionne, cryogonal, dartrix, decidueye, durant, incineroar, litleo, litten, phantump, popplio, primarina, rowlet, scatterbug, scrafty, scraggy, simipour, simisage, simisear, skiddo, torracat, tranquill, trevenant, tympole, unfezant_female, unfezant_male, watchog, zebstrika overworld sleep animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;bellossom, bisharp, budew, cacnea, cacturne, dewott, gallade, samurott_hisuian, sneasel_hisuian, lombre, lotad, ludicolo, nuzleaf, oshawott, parasect, pawniard, roselia, roserade, samurott, seedot, shiftry, shroomish, sunflora, vileplume, weavile overworld cut animations - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;gardevoir overworld sleep animation - Adrian der Cube on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Parasect Cut OW animation fixes - Aaamdacuaga&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;hisuian electrode, turtwig, kleavor, sirfetch&#39;d, alolan sandslash, hisuian voltorb overworld cut animations - Indie on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;jumpluff, trecko, sceptyle, grovyle Cut overworld animations - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Aipom, Ambipom, Ampharos, Azumarill, Azurill, Bayleef, Bonsly, Chikorita, Croconaw, Cyndaquil, Dunsparce, Feraligatr, Flaaffy, Forretress, Furret, Girafarig, Gligar, Ledian, Ledyba, Mareep, Marill, Meganium, Misdreavus, Mismagius, Natu, Pineco, Quagsire, Quilava, Sentret, Sudowoodo, Togekiss, Togepi, Togetic, Totodile, Typhlosion, Wobbuffet, Wooper, Wynaut, Xatu, Yanma, Yanmega, Corsola, Corsola_galarian, Cursola, Donphan, Gliscor, Granbull, Heracross, Larvitar, Magcargo, Mamoswine, Mantine, Mantyke, Miltank, Phanpy, Piloswine, Pupitar, Shuckle, Skarmory, Slugma, Smeargle, Sneasel, Snubbull, Stantler, Swinub, Teddiursa, Tyranitar, Ursaluna, Ursaring, Weavile, Wyrdeer, Beautifly, Blaziken, Breloom, Cascoon, Combusken, Delcatty, Dustox, Exploud, Gallade, Gardevoir, Grovyle, Hariyama, Kirlia, Linoone, Lombre, Loudred, Ludicolo, Makuhita, Marshtomp, Masquerain, Mightyena, Mudkip, Nincada, Ninjask, Nosepass, Nuzleaf, Obstagoon, Pelipper, Poochyena, Probopass, Ralts, Sableye, Sceptile, Seedot, Shedinja, Shiftry, Shroomish, Silcoon, Skitty, Slakoth, Surskit, Swampert, Swellow, Taillow, Torchic, Treecko, Whismur, Wingull, Wurmple, Zigzagoon, Absol, Aggron, Altaria, Anorith, Armaldo, Aron, Bagon, Cacnea, Cacturne, Camerupt, Castform, Chimecho, Chingling, Corphish, Cradily, Crawdaunt, Dusclops, Dusknoir, Duskull, Electrike, Flygon, Froslass, Glalie, Grumpig, Gulpin, Illumise, Lairon, Lileep, Lunatone, Manectric, Mawile, Minun, Numel, Plusle, Roserade, Roselia, Salamence, Sealeo, Shelgon, Snorunt, Solrock, Spheal, Spinda, Spoink, Swablu, Swalot, Torkoal, Trapinch, Vibrava, Volbeat, Beldum, Buneary, Bibarel, Bidoof, Bronzong, Bronzor, Buizel, Burmy_plant, Burmy_sand, Burmy_trash, Chimchar, Combee, Combee_f, Cranidos, Drifblim, Drifloon, Empoleon, Floatzel, Gabite, Garchomp, Gastrodon_east, Gastrodon_west, Gible, Grotle, Infernape, Lopunny, Luxio, Luxray, Metagross, Metang, Monferno, Mothim, Pachirisu, Piplup, Prinplup, Rampardos, Shellos_east, Shellos_west, Shieldon, Shinx, Spiritomb, Staraptor, Staravia, Starly, Torterra, Turtwig, Vespiquen, Wormadam, Abomasnow, Carnivine, Conkeldurr, Cottonee, Darmanitan_galarian, Darmanitan, Darumaka, Dewott, Drilbur, Excadrill, Gurdurr, Herdier, Hippopotas, Krookodile, Krokorok, Liepard, Lilligant, Lillipup, Lucario, Maractus, Oshawott, Purrloin, Riolu, Rotom_fan, Rotom_frost, Rotom_heat, Rotom_mow, Rotom, Rotom_wash, Samurott_hisui, Samurott, Sandile, Scolipede, Serperior, Servine, Sewaddle, Sigilyph, Snivy, Snover, Stoutland, Swoobat, Tepig, Timburr, Venipede, Whimsicott, Whirlipede, Woobat, Accelgor, Axew, Beheeyem, Bisharp, Braixen, Braviary_hisuian, Braviary, Chandelure, Chesnaught, Chespin, Cofagrigus, Deino, Delphox, Duosion, Elgyem, Escavalier, Fennekin, Froakie, Frogadier, Galvantula, Garbodor, Golett, Golurk, Gothorita, Gothita, Gothitelle, Greninja, Heatmor, Hydreigon, Joltik, Karrablast, Lampent, Larvesta, Litwick, Pawniard, Quilladin, Reuniclus, Rufflet, Shelmet, Solosis, Stunfisk, Trubbish, Vanillish, Vanillite, Vanilluxe, Volcarona, Vullaby, Yamask, Zoroark, Zorua, Zweilous, Aegislash_blade, Aegislash_shield, Baltoy, Carbink, Chatot, Cherrim, Cherrim_sunshine, Cherubi, Dedenne, Dewgong, Doublade, Glameow, Goodra, Goomy, Gourgeist, Hawlucha, Hippowdon_f, Hippowdon_m, Honedge, Houndoom, Houndour, Klefki, Kricketot, Kricketune, Magnemite, Magneton, Magnezone, Medicham, Meditite, Noibat, Noivern, Phantump, Porygon2, Porygonz, Porygon, Pumpkaboo, Purugly, Seviper, Skuntank, Sliggoo, Starmie, Staryu, Stunky, Sunflora, Swirlix, Toxicroak, Trevenant, Tropius, Tyrantrum, Tyrunt, Walrein, Zangoose, Amaura, Appletun, Applin, Araquanid, Archen, Archeops, Arctozolt, Aromatisse, Audino, Aurorus, Avalugg, Barbaracle, Beartic, Bergmite, Binacle, Blitzle, Boldore, Boltund, Bunnelby, Carkol, Carracosta, Castform_rainy, Castform_sunny, Castform_windy, Centiskorch, Chewtle, Cinderace, Coalossal, Comfey, Crabominable, Crabrawler, Croagunk, Cubchoo, Deerling_autumn, Deerling_spring, Deerling_summer, Deerling_winter, Dewpider, Geodude_alolan, Golem_alolan, Graveler_alolan, Meowth_alolan, Ninetales_alolan, Perrserker, Rattata_alolan, Raticate_alolan, Sandshrew_alolan, Sandslash_alolan, Vulpix_alolan, Zigzagoon_galarian, Diggersby, Dottler, Dracovish, Dracozolt, Dragapult, Drakloak, Drapion, Drednaw, Dreepy, Druddigon, Ducklett, Eiscue, Emboar, Espurr, Falinks, Ferroseed, Ferrothorn, Flabebe_blue, Flapple, Fletchinder, Fletchling, Floette_blue, Florges_blue, Fraxure, Frillish_f, Frillish_m, Gigalith, Glaceon, Gogoat, Goodra_hisui, Greedent, Grookey, Gumshoos, Haxorus, Heliolisk, Klang, Klinklang, Klink, Linoone_galarian, Mandibuzz, Meowth_galarian, Sliggoo_hisuian, Slowbro_galarian, Slowking_galarian, Sneasel_hisuian, Stunfisk_galarian, Weezing_galarian, Zoroark_hisuian, Zorua_hisuian overworld sleep animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;aerodactyl, blissey, chansey, ditto, dragonair, dragonite, dratini, eevee, espeon, flareon, glaceon, happiny, hitmonchan, hitmontop, jolteon, jynx, kabutops, kabuto, kangaskhan, kleavor, koffing, lapras, leafeon, lickilicky, lickitung, mime jr, mr mime, mr rime, munchlax, omanyte, omastar, pinsir, rhydon, rhyhorn, rhyperior, scizor, scyther, smoochum, snorlax, sylveon, tangela, tangrowth, tauros, umbreon, vaporeon, weezing overworld sleep animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;arbok, beedrill, bellossom, blastoise, bulbasaur, butterfree, caterpie, charizard, charmander, charmeleon, clefable, clefairy, cleffa, crobat, ekans, fearow, golbat, igglybuff, ivysaur, jigglypuff, kakuna, metapod, nidoking, nidoqueen, nidoran_f, nidoran_m, nidorina, nidorino, ninetales, parasect, paras, pichu, pidgeotto, pidgeot, pidgey, pikachu, raichu, rattata, raticate, sandshrew, sandslash, spearow, squirtle, venomoth, venonat, venusaur, vulpix, wartortle, weedle, wigglytuff, zubat overworld sleep animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;abra, alakazam, arcanine, bellsprout, cubone, diglett, dodrio, doduo, dugtrio, electrode, exeggcute, exeggutor, farfetch_d, geodude, golduck, golem, graveler, grimer, grimer, growlithe, hitmonlee, kadabra, kingler, krabby, machamp, machoke, machop, marowak, marowak, meowth, meowth, muk, muk, onix, persian, persian, politoed, poliwag, poliwhirl, poliwrath, ponyta, rapidash, slowbro, slowking, slowpoke, slowpoke, steelix, victreebel, voltorb, weepinbell overworld sleep animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Treecko, Grovile and Sceptile overworld cut animations - Impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Exeggcute, Exeggutor and Leafeon Cut overworld animations - Impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alolan Exeggutor Cut overworld animation - Impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nidoqueen headbutt overworld animation - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mr. Mime, Skitty, Delcatty, and Persian idle overworld animations - Blumiau on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Squirtle, Wartortle and Blastoise Headbutt OW Animations - DerpKip on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Smeargle painting OW animation - Queen Kami on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Krabby Cut OW animation - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sandslash Cut OW animation - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ampharos Power OW animation - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Abra teleport idle animation - impl on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chikorita, Bayleef, Meganium, Bulbasaur, Ivysaur, Venusaur, Breloom, Pinsir, Scyther, Scizor, Haxorus Cut overworld animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pidgey, Spearow, Pidove, Rookidee, Starly overworld pecking animations - Galenorla on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Player sprites:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hilda and Rosa back sprites - Solo993 on Deviantart&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chase, Mark, Mint, Rosa, Brendan, May, Elaine and Leaf overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hilda overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Brendan back sprite - Lockerz102 and A.J. Nitro&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lucas battle and overworld sprites - SkwovetSquire and LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kate back and overworld sprites - Lux and Toastknight on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nate back and overworld sprites - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Elio (SM and USUM) back sprites - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lyra back, walking and fishing sprites - Twilier / Reshidove on Deviantart&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lyra running, sleeping and sitting sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Brendan back sprite - Lockerz102 and A.J. Nitro&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hilbert, Hilda, Rosa, Calem, Serena back sprites - Solo993 on Deviantart&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hilbert overworld sprites - Gargoyle on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hilda overworld sprites - EeVeeEe on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rosa, Chase overworld sprites - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Calem, Serena, Gloria overworld sprites - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;May, Chase, Red, Leaf back sprites - Gargoyle on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gloria back sprite - Gargoyle on discord and LunaMaddalena on deviantart&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mint back sprite - LunaMaddalena on deviantart (edit by Badsy the Edgecat on discord)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mark back sprite - LunaMaddalena on deviantart (edit by LuxBeacon on discord)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lunick, Summer, Kellyn, Ben overworld and back sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Victor back sprite - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Victor overworld sprites - LuxBeacon and SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Music:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;X/Y Snowbelle City demake - Seiiccubus on discord and YouTube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RSE Mount Chimney demake - Seiiccubus on discord and YouTube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;D/P Valor Lakefront demake - Seiiccubus on discord and YouTube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;D/P Solaceon Town demake - Seiiccubus on discord and YouTube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;B/W Route 6 demake - Seiiccubus on discord and YouTube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diamond/Pearl League demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Black/White Dreamyard demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diamond/Pearl Route 216 demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diamond/Pearl Eterna Forest demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Black/White Route 10 demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RSE Route 113 demake - Seiiccubus on discord and youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regigigas battle music - Zame on Youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regi battle music - Alifib on youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mansion Remix music - GlitchxCity on Youtube&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Attack animations:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Psychic Fangs, Air Cutter, Cotton Guard, Fairy Wind, Fake Out, Fire Fang, Ice Fang, Meteor Mash, Poison Fang, Psychic Fangs, Psycho Cut, Signal Beam, Silver Wind, Smelling Salts, Thunder Fang, and Wish attack animations - peach-n-key on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Baby-doll Eyes attack animation - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Razor Shell, V-create attack animations - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Struggle Bug attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scale Shot attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Strength Sap attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dual Wingbeat attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Freeze Dry, Rage Powder, Follow Me, and Sludge Wave attack animations - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;High Horsepower and Body Press attack animations - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;King&#39;s Shield attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Heavy Slam and Stomping Tantrum attack animations - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power Up Punch attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Electroweb attack animation - Ventilatore on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defog attack animation - Ventilatore on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Helping Hand attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Psyshield Bash attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ally Switch attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Low Sweep attack animation - Ventilatore on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Heal Pulse attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ingrain attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sticky Web attack animation - Ventilatore on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tailwind attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dire Claw attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fishious Rend attack animation - SkwovetSquire and CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gurdurr battle sprites - Molk on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stealth Rock attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spiky Shield attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Baneful Bunker attack animation - GML on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Frenzy Plant attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hydro Cannon attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blast Burn attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wide Guard attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Snarl attack animation - Ventilatore on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flip Turn attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Heat Crash attack animation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Yawn attack animation - peach-n-key on discord, edits by CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Slack Off attack animation - peach-n-key on discord, edits by CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Crush Grip attack sprites - Mr Dustman on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rips of many attack animations - Liminalia on github&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spanish translation - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;French translation - Charade on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Brazilian-Portuguese translation - Kedöshim on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;German translation - 𝔼z̶𝓊𝓹Δɔʞ on discord / ITWinVis on Github&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hisuian and Spooky house sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Savanna house sprites - CuervoTerras on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cries from PLA-exclusives - Morningdew on RelicCaste&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fence gate sprite - Sakaya on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Item descriptions - betsybugaboo on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gen 2 item bag menu images - ForeverBurning on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follower dialogue - SkwovetSquire and LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wilds-Dex google doc - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Waterfall animation - Quilchess on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Puddle ripple animation - ICantBelieveItsNotBowser on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Phione/Manaphy egg - SkwovetSquire on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Storage chest sprite - TerraTerraCotta on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Berry tree sprites - LuxBeacon on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tundra biome house tileset - Internet_Goblin on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wooded Lake biome house tileset - Gargoyle on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various code help (bug fixes, adding sprites, and more) - ForeverBurning on discord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fossil item icons - SkwovetSquire on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Relic castle tile devamps - SkwovetSquire on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ruined fossil lab tiles - SkwovetSquire on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Interior paintings, plushes, couches, vanity mirrors, windows, and pots - TerraTerraCotta on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various interior paintings - SkwovetSquire on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Indoor clock sprite - boomtox the boombox on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fence sprite - boomtox the boombox on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cacturn &#39;dust tornado&#39; sprite - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trapinch &#39;trapping&#39; sprite - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deadbush tree sprite - Epharam on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Player sprite while moving through sand pit - Epharam on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regigigas &#39;standing&#39; sprite in dungeon - Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Campfire sprite coloration and torch sprites - boomtox-the-boombox on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Punching bag sprite - Goose on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regi dungeon concept and mechanics - Internet_Goblin, Sadfish, Mr Dustman on discord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manik-Needlemouse on Deviantart for the ghost overworld sprite&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lidangzzz/How-to-run</title>
    <updated>2022-11-05T01:30:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-05:/lidangzzz/How-to-run</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lidangzzz/How-to-run" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;立党老师的润学（零基础转码/移民/留学/海外创业/永居）笔记&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;立党的转码/润学/移民/找工作笔记&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Github Page只读版：&lt;a href=&#34;https://lidangzzz.github.io/How-to-run/&#34;&gt;https://lidangzzz.github.io/How-to-run/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;第一章 零基础转码篇&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;你的第一门编程语言，Python。Coursera上的Python for Everbody （UMich）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/python?specialization=python&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/learn/python?specialization=python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;你的第二门也是最重要的Computer Science课程，数据结构和算法 （UCSD）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/data-structures-algorithms?=#courses&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/data-structures-algorithms?=#courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;前端入门（Reactjs）： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Meta的Coursera零基础前端转码课：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/meta-front-end-developer&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/meta-front-end-developer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如果只看文字版，推荐W3CSchool教程： &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;HTML：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/html/default.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.w3schools.com/html/default.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;CSS：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/css/default.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.w3schools.com/css/default.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;JavaScript：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.w3schools.com/js/default.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;其他参考文档： &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Reactjs官方文档：&lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/tutorial/tutorial.html&#34;&gt;https://reactjs.org/tutorial/tutorial.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;MDN文档（权威JavaScript、CSS、HTML文档）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/&#34;&gt;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;TypeScript文档：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/&#34;&gt;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;互动的codeing bootcamp：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/front-end-development-libraries/#bootstrap&#34;&gt;https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/front-end-development-libraries/#bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;后端入门： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;后端语言（个人强烈且只推荐Java）Java（Duke）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/object-oriented-programming&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/object-oriented-programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;后端框架（推荐Springboot）Springboot：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9SGDpanrc8U&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9SGDpanrc8U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;数据库（推荐PostgreSQL，同时可以学MongoDB、Redis、MySQL等）SQL与PostgreSQL：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/postgresql-for-everybody?#courses&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/postgresql-for-everybody?#courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Amazon Web Service：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3hLmDS179YE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3hLmDS179YE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;课程以外重要的基本技能： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;正确使用Git：&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/using-git/about-git&#34;&gt;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/using-git/about-git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;IDE与编辑器： &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio Code入门教程：&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/introvideos/basics&#34;&gt;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/introvideos/basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Jetbrains全家桶使用指南（IDEA、PyCharm、WebStorm等）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/help/&#34;&gt;https://www.jetbrains.com/help/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Visual Studio入门教程：&lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/vs/getting-started/&#34;&gt;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/vs/getting-started/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Markdown文档基本语法：&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/writing-on-github/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax&#34;&gt;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/writing-on-github/getting-started-with-writing-and-formatting-on-github/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Linux command line tools手册：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-linux-commands-handbook/&#34;&gt;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/the-linux-commands-handbook/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;面试： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;初级版 Cracking the Coding Interview，北美码农面试经典入门圣经： &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;纸质版（请尽量购买正版）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/Cracking-Coding-Interview-Programming-Questions/dp/0984782850&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;电子版（请勿用于商用并遵守版权法律）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Avinash987/Coding/raw/master/Cracking-the-Coding-Interview-6th-Edition-189-Programming-Questions-and-Solutions.pdf&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Avinash987/Coding/blob/master/Cracking-the-Coding-Interview-6th-Edition-189-Programming-Questions-and-Solutions.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Leetcode，所有古今中外大小厂的算法题都在这里，至少30道，上不封顶：&lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/explore/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/explore/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;以下是完整的Computer Science基础课，时间充裕的前提下，建议完整学一遍： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UC Berkeley CS 61A. The Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCuteugW6eO65Awk83I6ehoA/playlists&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCuteugW6eO65Awk83I6ehoA/playlists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UC Berkeley CS61B. Data Structures：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h59h5DoNhL4&amp;amp;list=PLgNUCz66KaWRSVzIeT_qB2yBgHocLmRWI&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h59h5DoNhL4&amp;amp;list=PLgNUCz66KaWRSVzIeT_qB2yBgHocLmRWI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data Science（感兴趣可以学习，但不建议作为零基础转码方向）： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning-introduction&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning-introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Deep Learning by Andrew Ng: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning#courses&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/deep-learning#courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;IBM Data Science: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/ibm-data-science#courses&#34;&gt;https://www.coursera.org/professional-certificates/ibm-data-science#courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;美国最便宜的正规名校Online CS Master项目 Gatech Online CS Master： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;优势：顶级名校、正规Master学位、全美最便宜 $9000；&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;缺点：远程、没有CPT/OPT（无法工作实习），适合已经有绿卡、可L1 transfer或者在国内转码刷学历；&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;地址 &lt;a href=&#34;https://omscs.gatech.edu/&#34;&gt;https://omscs.gatech.edu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;不计成本地肉身到硅谷转码 NEU CS Align Master in Computer Science： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;优势：顶级名校、正规Master、自带co-op实习，肉身在硅谷到处开车面试，门槛低，不需要Computer Science本科学位，转码国际学生刷题找工氛围浓厚；&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;缺点：贵（学费预算 $70000）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;地址：&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.khoury.northeastern.edu/programs/align-masters-of-science-in-computer-science/&#34;&gt;https://www.khoury.northeastern.edu/programs/align-masters-of-science-in-computer-science/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;讨论与求助： &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Telegram（讨论）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/lidang&#34;&gt;https://t.me/lidang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Discord（求助、答疑、资源共享等）：&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/kCdnP3w49E&#34;&gt;https://discord.com/invite/kCdnP3w49E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;立党Twitter： &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lidangzzz&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/lidangzzz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;第二章 你的资质适合转码吗？请完成如下测试&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;学完Python和数据结构后，请尝试独立完成以下Leetcode题目：&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.1 Two Sum &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/two-sum/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/two-sum/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.9 Palindrome Number &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/palindrome-number/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/palindrome-number/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.21 Merge Two Sorted Lists &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/merge-two-sorted-lists/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/merge-two-sorted-lists/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.26 Remove Duplicates from Sorted Array &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/remove-duplicates-from-sorted-array/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/remove-duplicates-from-sorted-array/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.89 Gray Code &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/gray-code/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/gray-code/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.94 Binary Tree Inorder Traversal &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/binary-tree-inorder-traversal/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/binary-tree-inorder-traversal/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.226 Invert Binary Search Tree &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/invert-binary-tree/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/invert-binary-tree/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.231 Power of Two &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/power-of-two/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/power-of-two/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.257 Binary Tree Paths &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/binary-tree-paths/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/binary-tree-paths/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.264 Ugly Number II &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/ugly-number-ii/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/ugly-number-ii/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No.334 Reverse String &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/problems/reverse-string/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/problems/reverse-string/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果以上11道题目可以做对，或者看答案后可以正确理解，关掉答案后能够正确回答———恭喜你，你具备转码的潜质和资质，可以正式认真考虑从零基础转码了（着手申请硕士项目、开始系统从零自学Computer Science的所有基础课程）！&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>grafana/phlare</title>
    <updated>2022-11-05T01:30:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-05:/grafana/phlare</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/grafana/phlare" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🔥 horizontally-scalable, highly-available, multi-tenant continuous profiling aggregation system&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Grafana Phlare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grafana/phlare/main/images/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Grafana Phlare logo&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Grafana Phlare is an open source software project for aggregating continuous profiling data. Continuous profiling is an observability signal that allows you to understand your workload&#39;s resources (CPU, memory, etc...) usage down to the exact lines of code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grafana Phlare is fully integrated with Grafana allowing you to &lt;strong&gt;correlate&lt;/strong&gt; with other observability signals, like metrics, logs, and traces.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Explore UI&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grafana/phlare/main/images/grafana-profiles.gif&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Core features of Grafana Phlare include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to install:&lt;/strong&gt; Using its monolithic mode, you can get Grafana Phlare up and running with just one binary and no additional dependencies. On Kubernetes a single helm chart allows to deploy in different mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Horizontal scalability:&lt;/strong&gt; You can run Grafana Phlare across multiple machines, which makes it effortless for you to scale the database to handle the profiling volumes your workload generates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High availability:&lt;/strong&gt; Grafana Phlare replicates incoming profiles, ensuring that no data is lost in the event of machine failure. This means you can rollout without interrupting profiles ingestion and analysis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheap, durable profile storage:&lt;/strong&gt; Grafana Phlare uses object storage for long-term data storage, allowing it to take advantage of this ubiquitous, cost-effective, high-durability technology. It is compatible with multiple object store implementations, including AWS S3, Google Cloud Storage, Azure Blob Storage, OpenStack Swift, as well as any S3-compatible object storage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natively multi-tenant:&lt;/strong&gt; Grafana Phlare&#39;s multi-tenant architecture enables you to isolate data and queries from independent teams or business units, making it possible for these groups to share the same database.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Deploying Grafana Phlare&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information about how to deploy Grafana Phlare, refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/operators-guide/deploy-kubernetes/&#34;&gt;Deploy Grafana Phlare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Grafana Phlare, read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/operators-guide/getting-started/&#34;&gt;Getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before deploying Grafana Phlare in a production environment, read:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/operators-guide/architecture/&#34;&gt;An overview of Grafana Phlare’s architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/operators-guide/configuring/&#34;&gt;Configure Grafana Phlare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/operators-guide/deploy-kubernetes/&#34;&gt;Deploy in Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the following links to access Grafana Phlare documentation:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/latest/&#34;&gt;Latest release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.com/docs/phlare/next/&#34;&gt;Upcoming release&lt;/a&gt;, at the tip of the main branch&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To contribute to Grafana Phlare, refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grafana/phlare/tree/main/docs/internal/contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing to Grafana Phlare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Join the Grafana Phlare discussion&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or feedback regarding Grafana Phlare, join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grafana/phlare/discussions&#34;&gt;Grafana Phlare Discussion&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, consider joining the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grafana/phlare/main/TODO-doc-link&#34;&gt;Grafana Phlare Community Call&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is always welcome, and you can also share it via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://grafana.slack.com/archives/C049PLMV8TB&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#phlare&lt;/code&gt; Slack channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grafana Phlare is distributed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grafana/phlare/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;AGPL-3.0-only&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>