<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-17T01:25:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:25:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The C++ Core Guidelines are a set of tried-and-true guidelines, rules, and best practices about coding in C++&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://isocpp.github.io/CppCoreGuidelines/CppCoreGuidelines&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/master/cpp_core_guidelines_logo_text.png&#34; alt=&#34;C++ Core Guidelines&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&#34;Within C++ is a smaller, simpler, safer language struggling to get out.&#34; -- &lt;cite&gt;Bjarne Stroustrup&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/master/CppCoreGuidelines.md&#34;&gt;C++ Core Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; are a collaborative effort led by Bjarne Stroustrup, much like the C++ language itself. They are the result of many person-years of discussion and design across a number of organizations. Their design encourages general applicability and broad adoption but they can be freely copied and modified to meet your organization&#39;s needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guidelines themselves are found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/master/CppCoreGuidelines.md&#34;&gt;CppCoreGuidelines&lt;/a&gt;. The document is in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.github.com/gfm/&#34;&gt;GH-flavored MarkDown&lt;/a&gt;. It is intentionally kept simple, mostly in ASCII, to allow automatic post-processing such as language translation and reformatting. The editors maintain one &lt;a href=&#34;http://isocpp.github.io/CppCoreGuidelines/CppCoreGuidelines&#34;&gt;version formatted for browsing&lt;/a&gt;. Note that it is manually integrated and can be slightly older than the version in the master branch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Guidelines are a constantly evolving document without a strict &#34;release&#34; cadence. Bjarne Stroustrup periodically reviews the document and increments the version number in the introduction. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/releases&#34;&gt;Checkins that increment the version number&lt;/a&gt; are tagged in git.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the guidelines make use of the header-only Guidelines Support Library. One implementation is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/GSL&#34;&gt;GSL: Guidelines Support Library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Background and scope&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of the guidelines is to help people to use modern C++ effectively. By &#34;modern C++&#34; we mean C++11 and newer. In other words, what would you like your code to look like in 5 years&#39; time, given that you can start now? In 10 years&#39; time?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guidelines are focused on relatively higher-level issues, such as interfaces, resource management, memory management, and concurrency. Such rules affect application architecture and library design. Following the rules will lead to code that is statically type-safe, has no resource leaks, and catches many more programming logic errors than is common in code today. And it will run fast -- you can afford to do things right.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are less concerned with low-level issues, such as naming conventions and indentation style. However, no topic that can help a programmer is out of bounds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our initial set of rules emphasizes safety (of various forms) and simplicity. They may very well be too strict. We expect to have to introduce more exceptions to better accommodate real-world needs. We also need more rules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will find some of the rules contrary to your expectations or even contrary to your experience. If we haven&#39;t suggested that you change your coding style in any way, we have failed! Please try to verify or disprove rules! In particular, we&#39;d really like to have some of our rules backed up with measurements or better examples.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will find some of the rules obvious or even trivial. Please remember that one purpose of a guideline is to help someone who is less experienced or coming from a different background or language to get up to speed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rules are designed to be supported by an analysis tool. Violations of rules will be flagged with references (or links) to the relevant rule. We do not expect you to memorize all the rules before trying to write code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rules are meant for gradual introduction into a code base. We plan to build tools for that and hope others will too.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributions and LICENSE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comments and suggestions for improvements are most welcome. We plan to modify and extend this document as our understanding improves and the language and the set of available libraries improve. More details are found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/isocpp/CppCoreGuidelines/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=32f291566cf7&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Referral_Invite&amp;amp;utm_medium=Referral_Program&amp;amp;utm_source=CopyPaste&#34;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt; for hosting the Standard C++ Foundation website.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>n0a/telegram-get-remote-ip</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:25:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/n0a/telegram-get-remote-ip</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/n0a/telegram-get-remote-ip" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Get IP address on other side audio call in Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Telegram get remote IP&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;New 2023 version written in python, against bash.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script is intended to be used to determine the IP address of the interlocutor in the telegram messenger.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You must have tshark installed to use it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attention! To determine the IP address, you must be in each other&#39;s contacts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/thW5I0x.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get caller IP&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://desktop.telegram.org/&#34;&gt;Telegram desktop&lt;/a&gt; client on Linux or Mac.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install tshark (&lt;strong&gt;sudo apt install tshark&lt;/strong&gt; or download for macOS &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireshark.org/download.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s comes with wireshark).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run script, call and wait for an answer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Profit! You have received the IP address of the interlocutor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Get &amp;amp; Run (Ubuntu 20 example)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ sudo apt update&#xA;$ sudo apt install -y python3-pip python3-venv tshark&#xA;$ git clone https://github.com/n0a/telegram-get-remote-ip&#xA;$ cd telegram-get-remote-ip&#xA;$ python3 -m venv venv&#xA;$ source ./venv/bin/activate&#xA;$ sudo pip3 install -r requirements.txt&#xA;$ sudo python3 tg_get_ip.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or specify the interface immediately at startup:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ sudo python3 -i en0 tg_get_ip.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS.&lt;/strong&gt; Possible work with termux on android smartphones. Root authority is required to capture traffic.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Для русскоязыных пользователей&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Более подробно об утилите можно почитать у меня в блоге: &lt;a href=&#34;https://n0a.pw/telegram-get-remote-ip/&#34;&gt;https://n0a.pw/telegram-get-remote-ip/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>keras-team/keras</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:25:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/keras-team/keras</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/keras-team/keras" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning for humans&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Keras: Deep Learning for humans&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/keras.io/img/keras-logo-2018-large-1200.png&#34; alt=&#34;Keras logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository hosts the development of the Keras library. Read the documentation at &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/&#34;&gt;keras.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About Keras&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras is a deep learning API written in Python, running on top of the machine learning platform &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tensorflow/tensorflow&#34;&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/a&gt;. It was developed with a focus on enabling fast experimentation and providing a delightful developer experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purpose of Keras is to give an &lt;em&gt;unfair advantage&lt;/em&gt; to any developer looking to ship ML-powered apps.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt; -- but not simplistic. Keras reduces developer &lt;em&gt;cognitive load&lt;/em&gt; to free you to focus on the parts of the problem that really matter. Keras focuses on ease of use, debugging speed, code elegance &amp;amp; conciseness, maintainability, and deployability (via TFServing, TFLite, TF.js).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible&lt;/strong&gt; -- Keras adopts the principle of &lt;em&gt;progressive disclosure of complexity&lt;/em&gt;: simple workflows should be quick and easy, while arbitrarily advanced workflows should be &lt;em&gt;possible&lt;/em&gt; via a clear path that builds upon what you&#39;ve already learned.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerful&lt;/strong&gt; -- Keras provides industry-strength performance and scalability: it is used by organizations and companies including NASA, YouTube, and Waymo. That&#39;s right -- your YouTube recommendations are powered by Keras, and so is the world&#39;s most advanced driverless vehicle.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Keras &amp;amp; TensorFlow 2&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/&#34;&gt;TensorFlow 2&lt;/a&gt; is an end-to-end, open-source machine learning platform. You can think of it as an infrastructure layer for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Differentiable_programming&#34;&gt;differentiable programming&lt;/a&gt;. It combines four key abilities:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Efficiently executing low-level tensor operations on CPU, GPU, or TPU.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Computing the gradient of arbitrary differentiable expressions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scaling computation to many devices, such as clusters of hundreds of GPUs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Exporting programs (&#34;graphs&#34;) to external runtimes such as servers, browsers, mobile and embedded devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras is the high-level API of TensorFlow 2: an approachable, highly-productive interface for solving machine learning problems, with a focus on modern deep learning. It provides essential abstractions and building blocks for developing and shipping machine learning solutions with high iteration velocity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras empowers engineers and researchers to take full advantage of the scalability and cross-platform capabilities of TensorFlow 2: you can run Keras on TPU or on large clusters of GPUs, and you can export your Keras models to run in the browser or on a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;First contact with Keras&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core data structures of Keras are &lt;strong&gt;layers&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;models&lt;/strong&gt;. The simplest type of model is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/guides/sequential_model/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sequential&lt;/code&gt; model&lt;/a&gt;, a linear stack of layers. For more complex architectures, you should use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/guides/functional_api/&#34;&gt;Keras functional API&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to build arbitrary graphs of layers or &lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/guides/making_new_layers_and_models_via_subclassing/&#34;&gt;write models entirely from scratch via subclassing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the &lt;code&gt;Sequential&lt;/code&gt; model:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from tensorflow.keras.models import Sequential&#xA;&#xA;model = Sequential()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stacking layers is as easy as &lt;code&gt;.add()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from tensorflow.keras.layers import Dense&#xA;&#xA;model.add(Dense(units=64, activation=&#39;relu&#39;))&#xA;model.add(Dense(units=10, activation=&#39;softmax&#39;))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once your model looks good, configure its learning process with &lt;code&gt;.compile()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;model.compile(loss=&#39;categorical_crossentropy&#39;,&#xA;              optimizer=&#39;sgd&#39;,&#xA;              metrics=[&#39;accuracy&#39;])&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to, you can further configure your optimizer. The Keras philosophy is to keep simple things simple, while allowing the user to be fully in control when they need to be (the ultimate control being the easy extensibility of the source code via subclassing).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;model.compile(loss=tf.keras.losses.categorical_crossentropy,&#xA;              optimizer=tf.keras.optimizers.SGD(&#xA;                  learning_rate=0.01, momentum=0.9, nesterov=True))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can now iterate on your training data in batches:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;# x_train and y_train are Numpy arrays.&#xA;model.fit(x_train, y_train, epochs=5, batch_size=32)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evaluate your test loss and metrics in one line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;loss_and_metrics = model.evaluate(x_test, y_test, batch_size=128)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or generate predictions on new data:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;classes = model.predict(x_test, batch_size=128)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;What you just saw is the most elementary way to use Keras.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, Keras is also a highly-flexible framework suitable to iterate on state-of-the-art research ideas. Keras follows the principle of &lt;strong&gt;progressive disclosure of complexity&lt;/strong&gt;: it makes it easy to get started, yet it makes it possible to handle arbitrarily advanced use cases, only requiring incremental learning at each step.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In pretty much the same way that you were able to train &amp;amp; evaluate a simple neural network above in a few lines, you can use Keras to quickly develop new training procedures or exotic model architectures. Here&#39;s a low-level training loop example, combining Keras functionality with the TensorFlow &lt;code&gt;GradientTape&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import tensorflow as tf&#xA;&#xA;# Prepare an optimizer.&#xA;optimizer = tf.keras.optimizers.Adam()&#xA;# Prepare a loss function.&#xA;loss_fn = tf.keras.losses.kl_divergence&#xA;&#xA;# Iterate over the batches of a dataset.&#xA;for inputs, targets in dataset:&#xA;    # Open a GradientTape.&#xA;    with tf.GradientTape() as tape:&#xA;        # Forward pass.&#xA;        predictions = model(inputs)&#xA;        # Compute the loss value for this batch.&#xA;        loss_value = loss_fn(targets, predictions)&#xA;&#xA;    # Get gradients of loss wrt the weights.&#xA;    gradients = tape.gradient(loss_value, model.trainable_weights)&#xA;    # Update the weights of the model.&#xA;    optimizer.apply_gradients(zip(gradients, model.trainable_weights))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more in-depth tutorials about Keras, you can check out:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/getting_started/intro_to_keras_for_engineers/&#34;&gt;Introduction to Keras for engineers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/getting_started/intro_to_keras_for_researchers/&#34;&gt;Introduction to Keras for researchers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/guides/&#34;&gt;Developer guides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keras.io/getting_started/learning_resources/&#34;&gt;Other learning resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras comes packaged with TensorFlow 2 as &lt;code&gt;tensorflow.keras&lt;/code&gt;. To start using Keras, simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tensorflow.org/install&#34;&gt;install TensorFlow 2&lt;/a&gt;. You can then import Keras as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from tensorflow import keras&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release and compatibility&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keras has &lt;strong&gt;nightly releases&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;code&gt;keras-nightly&lt;/code&gt; on PyPI) and &lt;strong&gt;stable releases&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;code&gt;keras&lt;/code&gt; on PyPI). The nightly Keras releases are usually compatible with the corresponding version of the &lt;code&gt;tf-nightly&lt;/code&gt; releases (e.g. &lt;code&gt;keras-nightly==2.7.0.dev2021100607&lt;/code&gt; should be used with &lt;code&gt;tf-nightly==2.7.0.dev2021100607&lt;/code&gt;). We don&#39;t maintain backward compatibility for nightly releases. For stable releases, each Keras version maps to a specific stable version of TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The table below shows the compatibility version mapping between TensorFlow versions and Keras versions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the release branches can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keras-team/keras/releases&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the release binaries can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.org/project/keras/#history&#34;&gt;Pypi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can ask questions and join the development discussion:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.tensorflow.org/&#34;&gt;TensorFlow forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;On the &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/keras-users&#34;&gt;Keras mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Opening an issue&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also post &lt;strong&gt;bug reports and feature requests&lt;/strong&gt; (only) in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keras-team/keras/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Opening a PR&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions! Before opening a PR, please read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keras-team/keras/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;our contributor guide&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keras-team/governance/raw/master/keras_api_design_guidelines.md&#34;&gt;API design guideline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>