<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub All Languages Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-26T01:28:20Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of All Languages in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microg/GmsCore</title>
    <updated>2024-12-26T01:28:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-26:/microg/GmsCore</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microg/GmsCore" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Free implementation of Play Services&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;microG Services&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microg/GmsCore/actions/workflows/build.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/microg/GmsCore/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microg/GmsCore/master/TRANSLATION.md&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/widget/microg/svg-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Translation status&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;microG Services is a FLOSS (Free/Libre Open Source Software) framework to allow applications designed for Google Play Services to run on systems, where Play Services is not available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microg/GmsCore/wiki&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt; for downloads and instructions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Translations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to help translate microG, take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microg/GmsCore/master/TRANSLATION.md&#34;&gt;TRANSLATION&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright 2013-2024 microG Project Team&#xA;&#xA;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;);&#xA;you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.&#xA;You may obtain a copy of the License at&#xA;&#xA;    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#xA;&#xA;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software&#xA;distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS,&#xA;WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.&#xA;See the License for the specific language governing permissions and&#xA;limitations under the License.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>openai/openai-openapi</title>
    <updated>2024-12-26T01:28:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-26:/openai/openai-openapi</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/openai/openai-openapi" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OpenAPI specification for the OpenAI API&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;OpenAPI spec for the OpenAI API&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openapis.org/&#34;&gt;OpenAPI&lt;/a&gt; specification for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference&#34;&gt;OpenAI API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Public mirror - do not send pull requests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a public mirror of the internal OpenAI REST API specification. Pull requests to this spec document will not be merged. In the future, we may enable contributions and corrections via contribution to the spec, but for now they cannot be accepted. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OpenSPG/KAG</title>
    <updated>2024-12-26T01:28:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-26:/OpenSPG/KAG</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;KAG is a logical form-guided reasoning and retrieval framework based on OpenSPG engine and LLMs. It is used to build logical reasoning and factual Q&amp;A solutions for professional domain knowledge bases. It can effectively overcome the shortcomings of the traditional RAG vector similarity calculation model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;KAG: Knowledge Augmented Generation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://spg.openkg.cn/en-US&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/OpenSPG-1.png&#34; width=&#34;520&#34; alt=&#34;openspg logo&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/README.md&#34;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/README_cn.md&#34;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/README_ja.md&#34;&gt;日本語版ドキュメント&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2409.13731&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/arXiv-2409.13731-b31b1b&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG/releases/latest&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/OpenSPG/KAG?color=blue&amp;amp;label=Latest%20Release&#34; alt=&#34;Latest Release&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt; &lt;img height=&#34;21&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache--2.0-ffffff?labelColor=d4eaf7&amp;amp;color=2e6cc4&#34; alt=&#34;license&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;1. What is KAG?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;KAG is a logical reasoning and Q&amp;amp;A framework based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenSPG/openspg&#34;&gt;OpenSPG&lt;/a&gt; engine and large language models, which is used to build logical reasoning and Q&amp;amp;A solutions for vertical domain knowledge bases. KAG can effectively overcome the ambiguity of traditional RAG vector similarity calculation and the noise problem of GraphRAG introduced by OpenIE. KAG supports logical reasoning and multi-hop fact Q&amp;amp;A, etc., and is significantly better than the current SOTA method.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of KAG is to build a knowledge-enhanced LLM service framework in professional domains, supporting logical reasoning, factual Q&amp;amp;A, etc. KAG fully integrates the logical and factual characteristics of the KGs. Its core features include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Knowledge and Chunk Mutual Indexing structure to integrate more complete contextual text information&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Knowledge alignment using conceptual semantic reasoning to alleviate the noise problem caused by OpenIE&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Schema-constrained knowledge construction to support the representation and construction of domain expert knowledge&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logical form-guided hybrid reasoning and retrieval to support logical reasoning and multi-hop reasoning Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;⭐️ Star our repository to stay up-to-date with exciting new features and improvements! Get instant notifications for new releases! 🌟&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/star-kag.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Star KAG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;2. Core Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;2.1 Knowledge Representation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the context of private knowledge bases, unstructured data, structured information, and business expert experience often coexist. KAG references the DIKW hierarchy to upgrade SPG to a version that is friendly to LLMs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For unstructured data such as news, events, logs, and books, as well as structured data like transactions, statistics, and approvals, along with business experience and domain knowledge rules, KAG employs techniques such as layout analysis, knowledge extraction, property normalization, and semantic alignment to integrate raw business data and expert rules into a unified business knowledge graph.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/kag-diag.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KAG Diagram&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This makes it compatible with schema-free information extraction and schema-constrained expertise construction on the same knowledge type (e. G., entity type, event type), and supports the cross-index representation between the graph structure and the original text block.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This mutual index representation is helpful to the construction of inverted index based on graph structure, and promotes the unified representation and reasoning of logical forms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;2.2 Mixed Reasoning Guided by Logic Forms&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/kag-lf-solver.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logical Form Solver&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;KAG proposes a logically formal guided hybrid solution and inference engine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The engine includes three types of operators: planning, reasoning, and retrieval, which transform natural language problems into problem solving processes that combine language and notation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this process, each step can use different operators, such as exact match retrieval, text retrieval, numerical calculation or semantic reasoning, so as to realize the integration of four different problem solving processes: Retrieval, Knowledge Graph reasoning, language reasoning and numerical calculation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;3. Release Notes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;3.1 Latest Updates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;2024.11.21 : Support Word docs upload, model invoke concurrency setting, User experience optimization, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;2024.10.25 : KAG initial release&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;3.2 Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;domain knowledge injection, domain schema customization, QFS tasks support, Visual query analysis, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logical reasoning optimization, conversational tasks support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kag-model release, kag solution for event reasoning knowledge graph and medical knowledge graph&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kag front-end open source, distributed build support, mathematical reasoning optimization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;4. Quick Start&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;4.1 product-based (for ordinary users)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4.1.1 Engine &amp;amp; Dependent Image Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommend System Version:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;macOS User：macOS Monterey 12.6 or later&#xA;Linux User：CentOS 7 / Ubuntu 20.04 or later&#xA;Windows User：Windows 10 LTSC 2021 or later&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;macOS / Linux User：Docker，Docker Compose&#xA;Windows User：WSL 2 / Hyper-V，Docker，Docker Compose&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the following commands to download the docker-compose.yml file and launch the services with Docker Compose.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# set the HOME environment variable (only Windows users need to execute this command)&#xA;# set HOME=%USERPROFILE%&#xA;&#xA;curl -sSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/openspg/refs/heads/master/dev/release/docker-compose.yml -o docker-compose.yml&#xA;docker compose -f docker-compose.yml up -d&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4.1.2 Use the product&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigate to the default url of the KAG product with your browser: &lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:8887&#34;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:8887&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openspg.yuque.com/ndx6g9/wc9oyq/yexegklu44bqqicm&#34;&gt;Quick Start for Product Mode&lt;/a&gt; for detailed introduction.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;4.2 toolkit-based (for developers)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4.2.1 Engine &amp;amp; Dependent Image Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the 3.1 section to complete the installation of the engine &amp;amp; dependent image.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4.2.2 Installation of KAG&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS / Linux developers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;# Create conda env: conda create -n kag-demo python=3.10 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; conda activate kag-demo&#xA;&#xA;# Clone code: git clone https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG.git&#xA;&#xA;# Install KAG: cd KAG &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pip install -e .&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows developers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;# Install the official Python 3.8.10 or later, install Git.&#xA;&#xA;# Create and activate Python venv: py -m venv kag-demo &amp;amp;&amp;amp; kag-demo\Scripts\activate&#xA;&#xA;# Clone code: git clone https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG.git&#xA;&#xA;# Install KAG: cd KAG &amp;amp;&amp;amp; pip install -e .&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4.2.3 Use the toolkit&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openspg.yuque.com/ndx6g9/wc9oyq/yexegklu44bqqicm#cikso&#34;&gt;Quick Start for Developer Mode&lt;/a&gt; guide for detailed introduction of the toolkit. Then you can use the built-in components to reproduce the performance results of the built-in datasets, and apply those components to new busineness scenarios.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;5. Technical Architecture&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/kag-arch.png&#34; alt=&#34;KAG technical architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KAG framework includes three parts: kg-builder, kg-solver, and kag-model. This release only involves the first two parts, kag-model will be gradually open source release in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;kg-builder implements a knowledge representation that is friendly to large-scale language models (LLM). Based on the hierarchical structure of DIKW (data, information, knowledge and wisdom), IT upgrades SPG knowledge representation ability, and is compatible with information extraction without schema constraints and professional knowledge construction with schema constraints on the same knowledge type (such as entity type and event type), it also supports the mutual index representation between the graph structure and the original text block, which supports the efficient retrieval of the reasoning question and answer stage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;kg-solver uses a logical symbol-guided hybrid solving and reasoning engine that includes three types of operators: planning, reasoning, and retrieval, to transform natural language problems into a problem-solving process that combines language and symbols. In this process, each step can use different operators, such as exact match retrieval, text retrieval, numerical calculation or semantic reasoning, so as to realize the integration of four different problem solving processes: Retrieval, Knowledge Graph reasoning, language reasoning and numerical calculation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;6. Contact us&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG&#34;&gt;https://github.com/OpenSPG/KAG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenSPG&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://spg.openkg.cn/&#34;&gt;https://spg.openkg.cn/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/_static/images/openspg-qr.png&#34; alt=&#34;Contact Us: OpenSPG QR-code&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;7. Differences between KAG, RAG, and GraphRAG&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;KAG introduction and applications&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/OpenSPG/discussions/52&#34;&gt;https://github.com/orgs/OpenSPG/discussions/52&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;8. Citation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use this software, please cite it as below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.13731&#34;&gt;KAG: Boosting LLMs in Professional Domains via Knowledge Augmented Generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;KGFabric: A Scalable Knowledge Graph Warehouse for Enterprise Data Interconnection&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@article{liang2024kag,&#xA;  title={KAG: Boosting LLMs in Professional Domains via Knowledge Augmented Generation},&#xA;  author={Liang, Lei and Sun, Mengshu and Gui, Zhengke and Zhu, Zhongshu and Jiang, Zhouyu and Zhong, Ling and Qu, Yuan and Zhao, Peilong and Bo, Zhongpu and Yang, Jin and others},&#xA;  journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2409.13731},&#xA;  year={2024}&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;@article{yikgfabric,&#xA;  title={KGFabric: A Scalable Knowledge Graph Warehouse for Enterprise Data Interconnection},&#xA;  author={Yi, Peng and Liang, Lei and Da Zhang, Yong Chen and Zhu, Jinye and Liu, Xiangyu and Tang, Kun and Chen, Jialin and Lin, Hao and Qiu, Leijie and Zhou, Jun}&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenSPG/KAG/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Apache License 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>