<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-16T01:42:06Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:42:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Node.js sample project for trying out the VS Code Dev Containers extension&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Try Out Development Containers: Node.js&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode://ms-vscode-remote.remote-containers/cloneInVolume?url=https://github.com/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/static/v1?label=Dev%20Containers&amp;amp;message=Open&amp;amp;color=blue&amp;amp;logo=visualstudiocode&#34; alt=&#34;Open in Dev Containers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;development container&lt;/strong&gt; is a running &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; container with a well-defined tool/runtime stack and its prerequisites. You can try out development containers with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/features/codespaces&#34;&gt;GitHub Codespaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/vscode-remote/containers&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code Dev Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a sample project that lets you try out either option in a few easy steps. We have a variety of other &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/search?q=org%3Amicrosoft+vscode-remote-try-&amp;amp;type=Repositories&#34;&gt;vscode-remote-try-*&lt;/a&gt; sample projects, too.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; If you already have a Codespace or dev container, you can jump to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node/main/#things-to-try&#34;&gt;Things to try&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setting up the development container&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;GitHub Codespaces&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow these steps to open this sample in a Codespace:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click the Code drop-down menu and select the &lt;strong&gt;Open with Codespaces&lt;/strong&gt; option.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;+ New codespace&lt;/strong&gt; at the bottom on the pane.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more info, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/free-pro-team@latest/github/developing-online-with-codespaces/creating-a-codespace#creating-a-codespace&#34;&gt;GitHub documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;VS Code Dev Containers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you already have VS Code and Docker installed, you can click the badge above or &lt;a href=&#34;https://vscode.dev/redirect?url=vscode://ms-vscode-remote.remote-containers/cloneInVolume?url=https://github.com/microsoft/vscode-remote-try-node&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get started. Clicking these links will cause VS Code to automatically install the Dev Containers extension if needed, clone the source code into a container volume, and spin up a dev container for use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow these steps to open this sample in a container using the VS Code Dev Containers extension:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If this is your first time using a development container, please ensure your system meets the pre-reqs (i.e. have Docker installed) in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/vscode-remote/containers/getting-started&#34;&gt;getting started steps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To use this repository, you can either open the repository in an isolated Docker volume:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;F1&lt;/kbd&gt; and select the &lt;strong&gt;Dev Containers: Try a Sample...&lt;/strong&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Choose the &#34;Node&#34; sample, wait for the container to start, and try things out! &#xA;    &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;     &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Under the hood, this will use the &lt;strong&gt;Dev Containers: Clone Repository in Container Volume...&lt;/strong&gt; command to clone the source code in a Docker volume instead of the local filesystem. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/storage/volumes/&#34;&gt;Volumes&lt;/a&gt; are the preferred mechanism for persisting container data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Or open a locally cloned copy of the code:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository to your local filesystem.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;F1&lt;/kbd&gt; and select the &lt;strong&gt;Dev Containers: Open Folder in Container...&lt;/strong&gt; command.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Select the cloned copy of this folder, wait for the container to start, and try things out!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Things to try&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have this sample opened, you&#39;ll be able to work with it like you would locally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This container runs as a non-root user with sudo access by default. Comment out &lt;code&gt;&#34;remoteUser&#34;: &#34;node&#34;&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;.devcontainer/devcontainer.json&lt;/code&gt; if you&#39;d prefer to run as root.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some things to try:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;server.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Try adding some code and check out the language features.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Notice that &lt;code&gt;eslint&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;vscode-eslint&lt;/code&gt; extension are already installed in the container since the &lt;code&gt;.devcontainer/devcontainer.json&lt;/code&gt; lists &lt;code&gt;&#34;dbaeumer.vscode-eslint&#34;&lt;/code&gt; as an extension to install automatically when the container is created.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terminal:&lt;/strong&gt; Press &lt;kbd&gt;Ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;Shift&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;`&lt;/kbd&gt; and type &lt;code&gt;uname&lt;/code&gt; and other Linux commands from the terminal window.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build, Run, and Debug:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;server.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Add a breakpoint (e.g. on line 20).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;F5&lt;/kbd&gt; to launch the app in the container.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Once the breakpoint is hit, try hovering over variables, examining locals, and more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Continue (&lt;kbd&gt;F5&lt;/kbd&gt;). You can connect to the server in the container by either: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Clicking on &lt;code&gt;Open in Browser&lt;/code&gt; in the notification telling you: &lt;code&gt;Your service running on port 3000 is available&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Clicking the globe icon in the &#39;Ports&#39; view. The &#39;Ports&#39; view gives you an organized table of your forwarded ports, and you can access it with the command &lt;strong&gt;Ports: Focus on Ports View&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Notice port 3000 in the &#39;Ports&#39; view is labeled &#34;Hello Remote World.&#34; In &lt;code&gt;devcontainer.json&lt;/code&gt;, you can set &lt;code&gt;&#34;portsAttributes&#34;&lt;/code&gt;, such as a label for your forwarded ports and the action to be taken when the port is autoforwarded. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If we didn&#39;t know the port was 3000, we could&#39;ve used a regex instead of &#34;3000&#34; in the &lt;code&gt;&#34;portsAttributes&#34;&lt;/code&gt;, such as &#34;.+/server.js&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; In Dev Containers, you can access your app at &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:3000&lt;/code&gt; in a local browser. But in a browser-based Codespace, you must click the link from the notification or the &lt;code&gt;Ports&lt;/code&gt; view so that the service handles port forwarding in the browser and generates the correct URL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebuild or update your container&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may want to make changes to your container, such as installing a different version of a software or forwarding a new port. You&#39;ll rebuild your container for your changes to take effect.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open browser automatically:&lt;/strong&gt; As an example change, let&#39;s update the &lt;code&gt;portsAttributes&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;.devcontainer/devcontainer.json&lt;/code&gt; file to open a browser when our port is automatically forwarded.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;code&gt;.devcontainer/devcontainer.json&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Modify the &lt;code&gt;&#34;onAutoForward&#34;&lt;/code&gt; attribute in your &lt;code&gt;portsAttributes&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;&#34;notify&#34;&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;&#34;openBrowser&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press &lt;kbd&gt;F1&lt;/kbd&gt; and select the &lt;strong&gt;Dev Containers: Rebuild Container&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Codespaces: Rebuild Container&lt;/strong&gt; command so the modifications are picked up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright © Microsoft Corporation All rights reserved.&lt;br&gt; Licensed under the MIT License. See LICENSE in the project root for license information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>redhat-openshift-ecosystem/community-operators-prod</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:42:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/redhat-openshift-ecosystem/community-operators-prod</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/redhat-openshift-ecosystem/community-operators-prod" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;community-operators metadata backing OpenShift OperatorHub&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Openshift Community Operators&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.shields.io/:license-apache-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo is the canonical source for Kubernetes Operators that appear on &lt;a href=&#34;https://openshift.com&#34;&gt;OpenShift Container Platform&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okd.io/&#34;&gt;OKD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt; The index catalog &lt;code&gt;registry.redhat.io/redhat/redhat-operator-index:v&amp;lt;OCP Version&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is built from this repository and it is consumed by Openshift and OKD to create their sources and built their catalog. To know more about how Openshift catalog are built see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.openshift.com/container-platform/4.6/operators/understanding/olm-rh-catalogs.html#olm-rh-catalogs_olm-rh-catalogs&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full documentation is generated via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mkdocs.org/&#34;&gt;mkdoc&lt;/a&gt; and is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://redhat-openshift-ecosystem.github.io/community-operators-prod/&#34;&gt;https://redhat-openshift-ecosystem.github.io/community-operators-prod/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;IMPORTANT NOTICE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some APIs versions are deprecated and are OR will no longer be served on the Kubernetes version &lt;code&gt;1.22/1.25/1.26&lt;/code&gt; and consequently on vendors like Openshift &lt;code&gt;4.9/4.12/4.13&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does it mean for you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Operator bundle versions using the removed APIs can not work successfully from the respective releases. Therefore, it is recommended to check if your solutions are failing in these scenarios to stop using these versions OR by setting the &lt;code&gt;&#34;olm.properties&#34;: &#39;[{&#34;type&#34;: &#34;olm.maxOpenShiftVersion&#34;, &#34;value&#34;: &#34;&amp;lt;OCP version&amp;gt;&#34;}]&#39;&lt;/code&gt; to block cluster admins upgrades when they have Operator versions installed that can &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; work well in OCP versions higher than the value informed. Also, by defining a valid OCP range via the annotation &lt;code&gt;com.redhat.openshift.versions&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt;metadata/annotations.yaml&lt;/code&gt; for our solution does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; end up shipped on OCP/OKD versions where it cannot be installed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;WARNING: &lt;code&gt;olm.maxOpenShiftVersion&lt;/code&gt; should ONLY be used if you are 100% sure that your Operator bundle version cannot work in upper releases. Otherwise, you might provide a bad user experience. Be aware that cluster admins will be unable to upgrade their clusters with your solution installed. Then, suppose you do not provide any upper version and a valid upgrade path for those who have your Operator installed be able to upgrade it and consequently be allowed to upgrade their cluster version (i.e from OCP 4.10 to 4.11). In that case, cluster admins might choose to uninstall your Operator and no longer use it so that they can move forward and upgrade their cluster version without it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please, make sure you check the following announcements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redhat-openshift-ecosystem/community-operators-prod/discussions/138&#34;&gt;How to deal with removal of v1beta1 CRD removals in Kubernetes 1.22 / OpenShift 4.9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redhat-openshift-ecosystem/community-operators-prod/discussions/1182&#34;&gt;Kubernetes API removals on 1.25/1.26 and Openshift 4.12/4.13 might impact your Operator. How to deal with it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Bugs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the issue tracker in this repository to report bugs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SonarSource/docker-sonarqube</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:42:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/SonarSource/docker-sonarqube</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SonarSource/docker-sonarqube" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🐳 SonarQube in Docker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About this Repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SonarSource/docker-sonarqube/actions/workflows/qa.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/SonarSource/docker-sonarqube/actions/workflows/qa.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;QA&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the Git repo of the official Docker image for &lt;a href=&#34;https://registry.hub.docker.com/_/sonarqube/&#34;&gt;SonarQube&lt;/a&gt;. See the Hub page for the full readme on how to use the Docker image and for information regarding contributing and issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The full readme is generated over in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker-library/docs&#34;&gt;docker-library/docs&lt;/a&gt;, specifically in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker-library/docs/tree/master/sonarqube&#34;&gt;docker-library/docs/sonarqube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Have Question or Feedback?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For support questions (&#34;How do I?&#34;, &#34;I got this error, why?&#34;, ...), please first read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sonarqube.org&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and then head to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.sonarsource.com/&#34;&gt;SonarSource forum&lt;/a&gt;. There are chances that a question similar to yours has already been answered.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be aware that this forum is a community, so the standard pleasantries (&#34;Hi&#34;, &#34;Thanks&#34;, ...) are expected. And if you don&#39;t get an answer to your thread, you should sit on your hands for at least three days before bumping it. Operators are not standing by. :-)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to see a new feature, please create a new thread in the forum &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.sonarsource.com/c/suggestions/features&#34;&gt;&#34;Suggest new features&#34;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that we are not actively looking for feature contributions. We typically accept minor improvements and bug-fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, if you would like to submit a code contribution, please create a pull request for this repository. Please explain your motives to contribute this change: what problem you are trying to fix, what improvement you are trying to make.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2015-2020 SonarSource.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/lgpl.txt&#34;&gt;GNU Lesser General Public License, Version 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>