<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-16T01:53:15Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>iam-veeramalla/aws-devops-zero-to-hero</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T01:53:15Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-16:/iam-veeramalla/aws-devops-zero-to-hero</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/iam-veeramalla/aws-devops-zero-to-hero" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AWS zero to hero repo for devops engineers to learn AWS in 30 Days. This repo includes projects, presentations, interview questions and real time examples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;aws-devops-zero-to-hero&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AWS zero to hero repo for devops engineers to learn AWS in 30 Days. This repo includes projects, presentations, interview questions and real time examples. Each day&#39;s class will provide real-time knowledge on AWS services, allowing you to apply what you&#39;ve learned and gain practical skills in working with AWS in a DevOps context.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 1: Introduction to AWS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will learn what is private and public cloud. Why companies are moving to public cloud, what are the advantages of moving to cloud.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, you will be introduced to the basics of AWS, including the core services and their significance in DevOps practices. Finally learn how to set up an AWS account and navigate the AWS Management Console.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 2: IAM (Identity and Access Management)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will explore IAM, which is used for managing access to AWS resources. You&#39;ll learn how to create IAM users, groups, and roles, and how to apply permissions and security best practices to ensure proper access control.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 3: EC2 Instances&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll dive into EC2, which provides virtual servers in the cloud. You&#39;ll learn how to launch EC2 instances, connect to them using SSH, and understand key concepts such as instance types, security groups, and key pairs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your First AWS Project&lt;/strong&gt;: Deploy a simple web application(such as jenkins) on the ec2 instance and access the application from outside AWS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 4: AWS Networking (VPC)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS networking concepts, with a specific focus on VPC (Virtual Private Cloud). You&#39;ll learn how to create and configure VPCs, subnets, and route tables, enabling you to design and manage the network infrastructure for your applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 5: AWS Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day emphasizes security best practices in AWS. You&#39;ll learn how to implement security measures such as security groups, network ACLs (Access Control Lists), and IAM policies to ensure the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of your AWS resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 6: AWS Route 53&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; Configure and manage a domain name using Route 53. You&#39;ll register a domain, set up DNS records, and explore advanced features such as health checks, routing policies, and DNS-based failover.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 7: Secure VPC Setup with EC2 Instances&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Design and configure a VPC: Create a VPC with custom IP ranges. Set up public and private subnets. Configure route tables and associate subnets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Implement network security: Set up network access control lists (ACLs) to control inbound and outbound traffic. Configure security groups for EC2 instances to allow specific ports and protocols.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Provision EC2 instances: Launch EC2 instances in both the public and private subnets. Configure security groups for the instances to allow necessary traffic. Create and assign IAM roles to the instances with appropriate permissions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Networking and routing: Set up an internet gateway to allow internet access for instances in the public subnet. Configure NAT gateway or NAT instance to enable outbound internet access for instances in the private subnet. Create appropriate route tables and associate them with the subnets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;SSH key pair and access control: Generate an SSH key pair and securely store the private key. Configure the instances to allow SSH access only with the generated key pair. Implement IAM policies and roles to control access and permissions to AWS resources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Test and validate the setup: SSH into the EC2 instances using the private key and verify connectivity. Test network connectivity between instances in different subnets. Validate security group rules and network ACL settings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By implementing this project, you&#39;ll gain hands-on experience in setting up a secure VPC with EC2 instances, implementing networking and routing, configuring security groups and IAM roles, and ensuring proper access control. This project will provide a practical understanding of how these AWS services work together to create a secure and scalable infrastructure for your applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 8: AWS Interview Questions on EC2, IAM and VPC&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 9: Amazon S3&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on Amazon S3, a scalable object storage service. You&#39;ll learn how to create S3 buckets, upload and download objects, and organize data using S3 features like versioning, lifecycle policies, and access control.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 10: AWS CLI&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 11: AWS CloudFormation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day introduces Infrastructure as Code (IaC) using AWS CloudFormation. You&#39;ll learn how to create CloudFormation templates to automate the provisioning of resources, manage stacks, and ensure consistent infrastructure across deployments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll work on creating a CloudFormation template that provisions a fully configured application stack, including EC2 instances, networking components, and security groups.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 12: AWS CodeCommit&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on AWS CodeCommit, a managed source control service. You&#39;ll learn how to set up a Git repository in CodeCommit, collaborate with team members, and manage version control of your codebase.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure a CodeCommit repository for a team project, including setting up access control and collaboration workflows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 13: AWS CodePipeline&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll dive into AWS CodePipeline, a fully managed continuous delivery service. You&#39;ll learn how to build end-to-end CI/CD pipelines by configuring source, build, and deployment stages, automating the entire software release process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll create a CI/CD pipeline using CodePipeline for an application deployment, including source code integration, build, and automatic deployment to a target environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 14: AWS CodeBuild&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on AWS CodeBuild, a fully managed build service. You&#39;ll learn how to configure build projects in CodeBuild, define build specifications, and perform build and testing processes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure and run CodeBuild for a project, including defining build specifications and integrating with other AWS services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 15: AWS CodeDeploy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS CodeDeploy, a service for automating application deployments to various compute environments. You&#39;ll learn how to create deployment groups, configure deployment strategies, and perform automatic rollbacks if necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll implement a Blue/Green deployment strategy for a sample application using CodeDeploy, ensuring zero-downtime deployments and easy rollback options.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 16: AWS CloudWatch&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on monitoring AWS resources using AWS CloudWatch. You&#39;ll learn how to create alarms, set up notifications, and collect metrics to gain insights into the health and performance of your applications and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll set up CloudWatch alarms for critical metrics of an application, define appropriate threshold conditions, and configure notification actions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 17: AWS Lambda&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day introduces serverless computing with AWS Lambda. You&#39;ll learn how to create and deploy serverless functions, trigger them based on events, and leverage Lambda to build scalable and event-driven architectures.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 18: AWS CloudWatch Events and EventBridge&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on AWS CloudWatch Events and EventBridge, services for event-driven architectures. You&#39;ll learn how to create event rules, configure event targets, and build serverless event-driven workflows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll build a serverless event-driven workflow using CloudWatch Events and EventBridge, demonstrating the integration and automation of different AWS services based on events.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 19: AWS CloudTrail and Config&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS CloudTrail and AWS Config, which provide auditing and compliance capabilities. You&#39;ll learn how to track API calls using CloudTrail and ensure compliance with AWS Config rules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure CloudTrail to log API activities and set up AWS Config rules to enforce compliance policies for your AWS resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 20: AWS DynamoDB&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS DynamoDB, a NoSQL database service. You&#39;ll learn how to create and manage DynamoDB tables, perform CRUD operations, and leverage DynamoDB&#39;s scalability and performance capabilities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll build a serverless API using DynamoDB as the backend storage, allowing data retrieval and modification operations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 21: AWS ECS (Elastic Container Service)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on AWS ECS, a fully managed container orchestration service. You&#39;ll learn how to run and manage containers using ECS, including creating task definitions, managing services, and scaling with auto-scaling capabilities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll deploy a multi-container application using ECS, configure auto-scaling policies, and ensure high availability and efficient resource utilization.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 22: AWS ECR (Elastic Container Registry)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS ECR, a fully managed container registry for storing and managing container images. You&#39;ll learn how to push and pull Docker images to and from ECR, enabling seamless integration with ECS and other container services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll build a CI/CD pipeline that automatically builds, pushes, and deploys Docker images to ECR, ensuring streamlined container image management.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 23: AWS EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day introduces AWS EKS, a fully managed Kubernetes service. You&#39;ll learn how to deploy and manage Kubernetes clusters using EKS, including launching worker nodes, configuring networking, and deploying applications using Kubernetes manifests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll deploy a sample application on EKS using Kubernetes manifests, demonstrating the capabilities of running containerized applications on a managed Kubernetes service.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 24: AWS CloudWatch Logs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS CloudWatch Logs, a service for collecting and analyzing log data. You&#39;ll learn how to configure log groups, streams, and filters to centralize log management and gain insights into application behavior and troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll set up CloudWatch Logs for a production application, configure log groups and streams, and create filters to extract relevant log data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 25: AWS Secrets Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on AWS Secrets Manager, a service for storing and managing secrets such as database credentials, API keys, and other sensitive information. You&#39;ll learn how to store, retrieve, and rotate secrets securely in your applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure Secrets Manager to store and manage secrets, integrate secret retrieval in an application, and implement secret rotation policies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 26: AWS Auto Scaling&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll dive into AWS Auto Scaling, a service for automatically adjusting the capacity of your AWS resources based on demand. You&#39;ll learn how to configure Auto Scaling groups, scaling policies, and scaling based on metrics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure an Auto Scaling group for an application, define scaling policies based on metrics such as CPU utilization, and observe the dynamic scaling behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 27: AWS RDS (Relational Database Service)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day introduces AWS RDS, a managed database service for relational databases. You&#39;ll learn how to create and manage RDS instances, configure backups, snapshots, and replication to ensure high availability and data durability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll provision an RDS instance, configure backups and snapshots, and test replication scenarios for a sample database.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 28: AWS Elastic Load Balancer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS Elastic Load Balancer, a service for distributing incoming application traffic across multiple targets. You&#39;ll learn how to configure and manage load balancers to ensure high availability, fault tolerance, and scalability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll configure an Elastic Load Balancer for an application, define target groups, and observe the load balancing behavior across instances.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 29: AWS Systems Manager&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll explore AWS Systems Manager, a management service for AWS resources. You&#39;ll learn how to use Systems Manager to manage EC2 instances, perform patch management, automate administrative tasks, and configure resource compliance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll leverage Systems Manager to manage EC2 instances, perform common administrative tasks, and ensure compliance with configuration policies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 30: AWS Cloud Migration Strategies and Tools&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This day focuses on learning how to migrate applications to AWS cloud. What are the most popular strategies and tools used to achieve the cloud migration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Day 31: AWS Best Practices and Job Preparation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the final day, you&#39;ll review best practices for AWS services, including security, cost optimization and performance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OWASP/API-Security</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T01:53:15Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-16:/OWASP/API-Security</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OWASP/API-Security" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OWASP API Security Project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;OWASP API Security Top 10&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is designed to address the ever-increasing number of organizations that are deploying potentially sensitive APIs as part of their software offerings. These APIs are used for internal tasks and to interface with third parties. Unfortunately, many APIs do not undergo the rigorous security testing that would help make them secure from an attack.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OWASP API Security Project seeks to provide value to software developers and security assessors by underscoring the potential risks in insecure APIs, and illustrating how these risks may be mitigated. In order to facilitate this goal, the OWASP API Security Project will create and maintain a Top 10 API Security Risks document, as well as a documentation portal for best practices when creating or assessing APIs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While working as developers or information security consultants, many people have encountered APIs as part of a project. While there are some resources to help create and evaluate these projects (such as the OWASP REST Security Cheat Sheet), there has not be a comprehensive security project designed to assist builders, breakers, and defenders in the community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project aims to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create the OWASP Top Ten API Security Risks document, which can easily underscore the most common risks in the area.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a documentation portal for developers to build APIs in a secure manner.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Work closely with the security community to maintain living documents that evolve with security trends.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Leaders&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/User:ErezYalon&#34;&gt;Erez Yalon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/User:Inon&#34;&gt;Inon Shkedy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:paulo.silva@owasp.org&#34;&gt;Paulo Silva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The OWASP API Security Project documents are free to use!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OWASP API Security Project is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 license&lt;/a&gt;, so you can copy, distribute, and transmit the work. You can also adapt it, and use it commercially, as long as you attribute the work. If you alter, transform, or build upon this work, you may distribute the resulting work only under the same or similar license to this one.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LinkedInLearning/java-unit-testing-with-codespaces-3266042</title>
    <updated>2023-07-16T01:53:15Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-16:/LinkedInLearning/java-unit-testing-with-codespaces-3266042</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LinkedInLearning/java-unit-testing-with-codespaces-3266042" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Java Unit Testing with Codespaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Java: Practice Unit Testing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Java: Practice Unit Testing. The full course is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/java-practice-unit-testing?dApp=59033956&amp;amp;leis=LAA&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D560DAQG64CVbQvghgw/learning-public-crop_288_512/0/1682710101423?e=2147483647&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=T9hyFxJmfPX1w1oqV7Nyy-ph9XukOqwycWKoB1TZRR8&#34; alt=&#34;Java: Practice Unit Testing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beauty of test-driven development is that it allows you to iterate your codebase one step at a time, testing and reworking individual cases as you go. Not only does this reduce the likelihood of bugs and errors, it also helps you write more effective and more reliable code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course, instructor Bethan Palmer covers the essentials of unit testing in Java to showcase the benefits of test-driven development. Explore practical topics including common assertions, comparing arrays, and testing exceptions as well as some of the more advanced features of JUnit, the Java unit testing framework that lets you run parameterized tests. Along the way, take advantage of the opportunity to practice writing your own unit tests with hands-on, interactive coding exercises in GitHub Codespaces.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has branches for each of the videos in the course. You can use the branch pop up menu in github to switch to a specific branch and take a look at the course at that stage, or you can add &lt;code&gt;/tree/BRANCH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; to the URL to go to the branch you want to access.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Branches&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The branches are structured to correspond to the videos in the course. The naming convention is &lt;code&gt;CHAPTER#_MOVIE#&lt;/code&gt;. As an example, the branch named &lt;code&gt;02_03&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to the second chapter and the third video in that chapter. Some branches will have a beginning and an end state. These are marked with the letters &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;beginning&#34; and &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;end&#34;. The &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the beginning of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the end of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch holds the final state of the code when in the course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When switching from one exercise files branch to the next after making changes to the files, you may get a message like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;error: Your local changes to the following files would be overwritten by checkout:        [files]&#xA;Please commit your changes or stash them before you switch branches.&#xA;Aborting&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Add changes to git using this command: git add .&#xA;Commit changes using this command: git commit -m &#34;some message&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instructor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bethan Palmer&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Software Developer&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out my other courses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/instructors/bethan-palmer&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>