<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-01T01:52:05Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs-contrib</title>
    <updated>2024-10-01T01:52:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-01:/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs-contrib</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs-contrib" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documentation for the Microsoft Graph REST API&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Graph documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your interest in Microsoft Graph documentation! For the best experience, we recommend you view this content on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/graph&#34;&gt;Microsoft Graph Developer Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Give us your feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coming soon:&lt;/strong&gt; In March 2024, we will be phasing out the current feedback mechanism for content (GitHub issues) described below and replacing it with a new feedback system. For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/ContentUserFeedback&#34;&gt;https://aka.ms/ContentUserFeedback&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is important to us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To let us know about any questions or issues you find in the documentation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/contribute/content/provide-feedback#use-the-standard-experience&#34;&gt;leave feedback using the standard experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We also encourage you to fork, make the fix, and do a pull request of your proposed changes. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs-contrib/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt; for contributing guidelines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To let us know about your programming experience, what you would like to see in future versions, code samples, and so on, enter your suggestions and ideas at &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-developer-platform/idb-p/Microsoft365DeveloperPlatform/label-name/Microsoft%20Graph&#34;&gt;Microsoft 365 Developer Platform Tech Community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs</title>
    <updated>2024-10-01T01:52:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-01:/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository is used for Windows client for IT Pro content on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn how to contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is interested can contribute to the topics. When you contribute, your work will go directly into the content set after being merged. It will then be published to &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Learn&lt;/a&gt; and you will be listed as a contributor at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-docs-pr/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-docs-pr/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Quickly update an article using GitHub.com&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributors who only make infrequent or small updates can edit the file directly on GitHub.com without having to install any additional software. This article shows you how. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/videoplayer/embed/RE1XQTG&#34;&gt;This two-minute video&lt;/a&gt; also covers how to contribute.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Make sure you&#39;re signed in to GitHub.com with your GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Browse to the page you want to edit on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the right-hand side of the page, click &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; (pencil icon).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/quick-update-edit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Edit button on Microsoft Learn.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The corresponding topic file on GitHub opens, where you need to click the &lt;strong&gt;Edit this file&lt;/strong&gt; pencil icon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/quick-update-github.png&#34; alt=&#34;Edit button on github.com.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The topic opens in a line-numbered editing page where you can make changes to the file. Files in GitHub are written and edited using Markdown language. For help on using Markdown, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&#34;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Select the &lt;strong&gt;Preview changes&lt;/strong&gt; tab to view your changes as you go.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re finished making changes, go to the &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; section at the bottom of the page:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A brief title is required. By default, the title is the name of the file, but you can change it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optionally, you can enter more details in the &lt;strong&gt;Add an optional extended description&lt;/strong&gt; box.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re ready, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/propose-file-change.png&#34; alt=&#34;Propose file change section.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Comparing changes&lt;/strong&gt; page that appears, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Create pull request&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/comparing-changes-page.png&#34; alt=&#34;Comparing changes page.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Open a pull request&lt;/strong&gt; page that appears, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Create pull request&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/open-a-pull-request-page.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open a pull request page.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] Your permissions in the repo determine what you see in the last several steps. People with no special privileges will see the &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; section and subsequent confirmation pages as described. People with permissions to create and approve their own pull requests will see a similar &lt;strong&gt;Commit changes&lt;/strong&gt; section with extra options for creating a new branch and fewer confirmation pages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The point is: click any green buttons that are presented to you until there are no more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The writer identified in the metadata of the topic will be notified and will eventually review and approve your changes so the topic will be updated on Microsoft Learn. If there are questions or issues with the updates, the writer will contact you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Legal Notices&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors grant you a license to the Microsoft documentation and other content in this repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs/public/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file, and grant you a license to any code in the repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs/public/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The licenses for this project do not grant you rights to use any Microsoft names, logos, or trademarks. Microsoft&#39;s general trademark guidelines can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&#34;&gt;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy information can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors reserve all others rights, whether under their respective copyrights, patents, or trademarks, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>