<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Kotlin Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-09T01:36:01Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Kotlin in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:36:01Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open SSTP Client for Android&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open SSTP Client for Android &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/raw/main/images/icon.png&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an open-sourced Secure Socket Tunneling Protocol (MS-SSTP) client for Android, developed for accessing to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vpnazure.net/&#34;&gt;VPN Azure Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.softether.org/&#34;&gt;SoftEther VPN Server&lt;/a&gt;). So no test with other servers is done. Its behavior may be still unstable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can download and install the latest version via &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=kittoku.osc&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;. Some of previous versions are released as apk file on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/releases&#34;&gt;the releases page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;Host&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Username&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Password&lt;/code&gt; preferences and turn the switch on. If a key icon gets to show on the right side of the status bar, establishing a VPN connection has been succeeded. To disconnect the connection, turn the switch off in the home tab or tap the notification.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/main/images/example_home.png&#34; width=&#34;25%&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/main/images/example_setting_2.png&#34; width=&#34;25%&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/main/images/example_tile.png&#34; width=&#34;25%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setting tab&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some settings to be noted are written below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Add Trusted Certificates (SSL Layer)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you choose a certain directory, the client uses ONLY certificates in the directory, but the default certificate store. I made this option for debugging.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PPP Network Protocol&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can choose what network protocol PPP layer tries enabling. Remember, IPv6 option just gives the device a link local address, never guarantees that you can communicate perfectly with IPv6 protocol.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Custom DNS Server Address&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can specify DNS server to use in this option. Packets associated with this address is routed to the VPN tunnel. If you specify a IPv4(v6) address and disable IPv4(v6) network, domain names possibly cannot be resolved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enable App-Based Rule&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code&gt;Select Allowed Apps&lt;/code&gt; option, you can specify the apps which use the VPN tunnel. Even allowed apps cannot use the VPN tunnel if their routes are not on the routeing table. So when you use this option, enabling &lt;code&gt;Add Default Route&lt;/code&gt; option is recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notice&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Host&lt;/code&gt; preference can also contain IP address, but cannot include a port number. You can configure it in the setting tab.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your device needs to install a self-signed certificate and disable &lt;code&gt;Verify Hostname&lt;/code&gt; option to access to a server using it&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A server must enable DHCP&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Only &lt;strong&gt;PAP&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;MS-CHAPv2&lt;/strong&gt; authentication protocols can be enabled. No EAP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Debugging&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is almost impossible that I can debug a problem caused in any environments but my own. In a networking app, there are many possible reasons to cause the problem and I cannot identify the real one unless the problem can be reproduced in my environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So it is strongly encouraged that you should debug by yourself. With &lt;code&gt;Select Cipher Suites&lt;/code&gt; option, this client tries to use &lt;code&gt;TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_128_CBC_SHA&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;TLS_RSA_WITH_AES_256_CBC_SHA&lt;/code&gt; as a cipher suite so that you can decrypt and investigate packets with software like WireShark. I think there can be a similar app for Android. Don&#39;t forget the great software, Android Studio and its emulator (v^ー°)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have Windows Server OS. So I don&#39;t officially support accessing to it, but there is a successful case. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kittoku/Open-SSTP-Client/issues/8#issuecomment-590241322&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under MIT. Be sure you use this software at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>