<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Kotlin Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-20T01:42:30Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Kotlin in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T01:42:30Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-20:/hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ProtoHax implementation on Android which is a cheat for Minecraft: BE&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ProtoHax-Android&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; width=&#34;159px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax/stable/icon.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ProtoHax-Android is the Android implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax&#34;&gt;ProtoHax&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source cheat for Minecraft: Bedrock Edition that works through the network layer. This repository contains the Android-specific code for the cheat.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No modifications to Minecraft client&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Seamless switching/adapting multiple versions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Full control of the packet layer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you notice any bugs or missing features in the Android-specific code, you can let us know by opening an issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re having issues with the cheat features themselves, please send the issue to the main repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please notice that this is an &lt;strong&gt;English-only&lt;/strong&gt; repository, so all issues and pull requests must be in English, if you can&#39;t speak English, please use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.google.com/&#34;&gt;translator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is subject to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html&#34;&gt;GNU General Public License v3.0&lt;/a&gt;. This does only apply for source code located directly in this clean repository. During the development and compilation process, additional source code may be used to which we have obtained no rights. Such code is not covered by the GPL license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who are unfamiliar with the license, here is a summary of its main points. This is by no means legal advice nor legally binding.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actions that you are allowed to do:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Share&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modify&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you do decide to use ANY code from the source:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You must disclose the source code of your modified work and the source code you took from this project. This means you are not allowed to use code from this project (even partially) in a closed-source (or even obfuscated) application.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your modified application must also be licensed under the GPL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gradle.org/current/userguide/declaring_repositories.html#sec:case-for-maven-local&#34;&gt;local maven repository&lt;/a&gt;, you need to build and publish &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax&#34;&gt;ProtoHax&lt;/a&gt; to the repository before you can build, sorry for inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;With Android Studio&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Import the project into Android Studio&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect your Android device to your computer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build and run the project on your device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;With Gradle&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/hax0r31337/ProtoHax-Android.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CD into the local repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect your Android device to your computer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;gradlew app:assembleDebug&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions to ProtoHax! If you would like to contribute, please fork the repository and make changes as you&#39;d like. Pull requests are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please use ProtoHax at your own risk. We &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; take responsibility for any bans or punishments that may occur as a result of using this cheat.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>