<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Kotlin Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-07-07T01:32:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Kotlin in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>twofas/2fas-android</title>
    <updated>2024-07-07T01:32:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-07-07:/twofas/2fas-android</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/twofas/2fas-android" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Source code for 2FAS Android app&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Source 2FAS for Android&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the official Android app for the Open Source 2FAS project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is 2FAS?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2FAS (Two-Factor Authentication Service) is a user authentication method that provides an additional layer of security for online accounts. In addition to a username and password, 2FAS uses a second factor, such as a one-time password (OTP) shown on a user&#39;s phone, to verify a user&#39;s identity. This helps prevent unauthorized access to accounts, even if a password is compromised.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for time-based one-time passwords (TOTP) and HMAC-based on-time passwords (HOTP)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compatible with any service that supports the TOTP and HOTP standard, including Google, Microsoft, and Dropbox&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easy to set up and use&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Graphics&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that the graphics used in this app are not part of the open source project and are subject to their own separate licensing terms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bug Reporting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use GitHub for bug reports. Please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/twofas/2fas-android/issues&#34;&gt;2FAS for Android issues page&lt;/a&gt; to search for and report any bugs you may have found. Before adding a new issue, please search for existing issues to avoid duplicates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For reporting security issues only, please send a detailed description of the vulnerability to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@2fas.com&#34;&gt;security@2fas.com&lt;/a&gt;. Do not use this address for general inquiries or bug reports unrelated to security concerns.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the app from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2fas.com&#34;&gt;releases page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the app on your Android device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the on-screen instructions to set up 2FAS for your online accounts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions to the Open Source 2FAS project. If you would like to contribute, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/twofas/2fas-android/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contribution guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Donations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to support the development of the Open Source 2FAS project, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://2fas.com/donate&#34;&gt;make a donation&lt;/a&gt;. All donations will be used to support the ongoing development and maintenance of the project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We appreciate your support!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) Two Factor Authentication Service, Inc. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.en.html&#34;&gt;GNU General Public License v3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>