<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Kotlin Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-27T01:40:03Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Kotlin in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>rodit/SnapMod</title>
    <updated>2022-09-27T01:40:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-27:/rodit/SnapMod</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rodit/SnapMod" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Xposed module for Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;SnapMod&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xposed module for Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set SnapMod up, download and install the latest apk from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rodit/SnapMod/releases&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. When you open it, it will ask to install some bindings. Press &#39;Download&#39; and be sure to kill and restart Snapchat afterwards. The latest and only fully supported version of Snapchat is &lt;strong&gt;11.96.0.31&lt;/strong&gt; (as of SnapMod 1.8.5). Mappings &lt;strong&gt;will not&lt;/strong&gt; be downloaded for previous versions of Snapchat automatically, only for the latest supported version. If you are using an older version, you must manually place the mappings in &lt;code&gt;/data/data/xyz.rodit.snapmod/files/[build].json&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/Android/data/xyz.rodit.snapmod/files/[build].json&lt;/code&gt; on your internal storage where &lt;code&gt;[build]&lt;/code&gt; is the version code of Snapchat the mappings correspond to. Note, there is no guarentee the newest version of Snapmod will work with old mappings (it usually will not for a couple of features).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a full list of features and their status, please visit the wiki &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rodit/SnapMod/wiki/Features&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature Suggestions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to suggest a new feature, please do so in &lt;strong&gt;Discussions&lt;/strong&gt;. Please do not create an Issue for feature suggetsions (they will be moved to Discussions).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have an issue please post a log from LSPosed (I have no interest in supporting other Xposed implementations, although SnapMod should work fine with them) and a description of the issue. It is &lt;strong&gt;extremely&lt;/strong&gt; unhelpful to just say &#34;something doesn&#39;t work&#34; or &#34;I can&#39;t download stories.&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If anything doesn&#39;t work, the first thing you should try is killing and relaunching Snapchat (through the system settings app, not recent app list) &lt;strong&gt;TWICE&lt;/strong&gt; and then trying again. This will ensure any cached mappings are updated. This is especially important after updating SnapMod and its mappings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Donations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although this is a personal project I do entirely for fun (and it will most likely stay that way), if you would like to support the development of SnapMod, you can do so by donating:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PayPal: &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/roditmod&#34;&gt;https://paypal.me/roditmod&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cashapp: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cash.app/rodit9&#34;&gt;https://cash.app/rodit9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;BTC: bc1qr06chdv85jf9v7ldf7l24lrgp6ad7av8y7jwyc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ETH: 0x90659C0556b37107359FA32b40AA74c593590E04&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;XRP: rDgNCbi4eCeczpzGHGs3XHsR5C3SyUCr5r&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>