<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Kotlin Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-04T01:31:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Kotlin in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam</title>
    <updated>2023-11-04T01:31:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-04:/simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Bluetooth LE Spam&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on utilizing the built-in Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) functionality of Android smartphones to create Phantom Bluetooth Device Advertisements, similar to what is known, for instance, in the case of the Flipper Zero. While there are other apps available that provide similar functionality, the objective of this app is to enhance convenience and user-friendliness in the process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This project is in its early stages of development. Contributions from anyone are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Google Fast Pair&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This app is capable of spoofing BLE advertisers that mimic the usage of the Google Fast Pair Service, leading to an influx of unwanted pop-up notifications on the receiving device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For additional information about the Google Fast Pair Service, you can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/nearby/fast-pair/landing-page&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Microsoft Swift Pair&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This app can spoof BLE advertisers that mimic devices supporting the Microsoft Swift Pairing Service. If Swift Pair notifications are enabled on a nearby Windows 10 (or later) device, it will receive a flood of notifications regarding nearby devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For additional information about the Microsoft Swift Pair Service, you can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/design/component-guidelines/bluetooth-swift-pair&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Range&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the official Bluetooth Low Energy API provided by Google&#39;s Android SDK allows you to set the TX Power level and include it in the advertiser&#39;s payload, but doesn&#39;t permit direct modification of the byte values actually transmitted in the payload, the range of the Fast Pair functionality is somewhat limited. The receiving devices calculate the transmitter&#39;s proximity based on the actual received signal strength and the transmitted byte in the payload, which contains the TX Power level the transmitter used. However, devices like the Flipper Zero have the capability to modify this byte, significantly extending their range.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can clone the repository and open it in Android Studio to install the app, or simply use the installable APK files from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam/releases&#34;&gt;Release Section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credit&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobile-hacker.com/author/boni11/&#34;&gt;mh from mobile-hacker.com&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mobile-hacker.com/2023/09/07/spoof-ios-devices-with-bluetooth-pairing-messages-using-android/&#34;&gt;Article / Guideline&lt;/a&gt; about using the nRF Connect App to Spoof iOS Devices&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Willy-JL&#34;&gt;Willy-JL&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ECTO-1A&#34;&gt;ECTO-1A&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Spooks4576&#34;&gt;Spooks4567&lt;/a&gt; for their contribution in the BLE Spam App on the Flipper Zero&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/furiousMAC&#34;&gt;FuriousMAC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hexway&#34;&gt;Hexway&lt;/a&gt; for their prior researches&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;And special thanks to anyone else who has been involved in prior research and publications related to this topic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam/main/Assets/Screenshots/ScreenshotFastPairing.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/simondankelmann/Bluetooth-LE-Spam/main/Assets/Screenshots/ScreenshotSwiftPair.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer for Bluetooth Low Energy Protocol Investigation Repository&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains code for the investigation and experimentation of the Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) protocol. Please be aware of the following disclaimers before using or contributing to this repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Purpose: The code and information provided in this repository are intended for educational and research purposes. It is not intended for any malicious or harmful activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Legal Compliance: Users are responsible for ensuring that their use of the code and information in this repository complies with all applicable laws and regulations, including those governing wireless communication and intellectual property rights.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;No Warranty: The code and information provided in this repository are provided &#34;as is&#34; without any warranties, expressed or implied. The authors and contributors are not responsible for any consequences resulting from the use of this code.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Risks: Experimenting with BLE protocols can have potential security and privacy implications. Users should exercise caution and use this code responsibly, respecting the privacy and security of devices and systems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Contribution Guidelines: If you contribute to this repository, ensure that your contributions are in compliance with the project&#39;s goals and the repository&#39;s license. By contributing, you agree to license your contributions under the same license as this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support: This repository is not maintained for production use. The authors and contributors may not provide support or updates regularly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By using and contributing to this repository, you agree to these disclaimers and guidelines. If you do not agree, please refrain from using or contributing to this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any questions or concerns, please contact the repository maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lmj0011/save-on-device</title>
    <updated>2023-11-04T01:31:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-04:/lmj0011/save-on-device</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lmj0011/save-on-device" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Android app that allows you to save a file shared from another app to your device.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lmj0011/save-on-device/master/.github/readme-images/ic_launcher-playstore.png&#34; width=&#34;48&#34;&gt; Save On Device&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;an Android app that allows you to save files on your device from other apps using the share functionality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lmj0011/save-on-device/master/.github/readme-images/demo.gif&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save files from other apps to local storage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save copied text to local storage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/name.lmj001.savetodevice/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fdroid.gitlab.io/artwork/badge/get-it-on.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on F-Droid&#34; height=&#34;80&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=name.lmj001.savetodevice&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://play.google.com/intl/en_us/badges/images/generic/en-play-badge.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; height=&#34;80&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright 2023 Landan Jackson&#xA;&#xA;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;);&#xA;you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.&#xA;You may obtain a copy of the License at&#xA;&#xA;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#xA;&#xA;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software&#xA;distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS,&#xA;WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.&#xA;See the License for the specific language governing permissions and&#xA;limitations under the License.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>