<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PHP Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-08-17T02:05:55Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PHP in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>dtyq/magic</title>
    <updated>2025-08-17T02:05:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-08-17:/dtyq/magic</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/dtyq/magic" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Super Magic (超级麦吉). The first open-source all-in-one AI productivity platform (Generalist AI Agent + Workflow Engine + IM + Online collaborative office system)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dtyq/magic/master/README.md&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;README in English&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/English-d9d9d9&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dtyq/magic/master/README_CN.md&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;简体中文版自述文件&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/简体中文-d9d9d9&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/super-magic-publish-header-en.png?v=20250515&#34; alt=&#34;Magic Open Source Product Matrix&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;🔥 Magic - First Open-Source All-in-One AI Productivity Platform&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Static Badge&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Official Website-301AD2&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic/releases&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://poser.pugx.org/dtyq/magic/v/stable&#34; alt=&#34;Stable Version&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic/graphs/commit-activity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Commits last month&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/dtyq/magic?labelColor=%20%2332b583&amp;amp;color=%20%2312b76a&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Issues closed&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-search?query=repo%3Adtyq%2Fmagic%20is%3Aclosed&amp;amp;label=issues%20closed&amp;amp;labelColor=%20%237d89b0&amp;amp;color=%20%235d6b98&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic/discussions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Discussion posts&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/discussions/dtyq/magic?labelColor=%20%239b8afb&amp;amp;color=%20%237a5af8&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Static Badge&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Build with Magic 🔮-301AD2&#34; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic aims to help enterprises of all sizes quickly build and deploy AI applications to achieve a 100x increase in productivity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Magic Product Matrix&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic is the first &lt;strong&gt;&#34;open-source all-in-one AI productivity platform&#34;&lt;/strong&gt;, not a single AI product, but a comprehensive product matrix with rich capabilities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/super-magic-open-source-projects-en.png?v=20250515&#34; alt=&#34;Product Matrix&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/super-magic&#34;&gt;Super Magic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - A &lt;strong&gt;general-purpose AI Agent&lt;/strong&gt; designed for complex task scenarios&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic&#34;&gt;Magic IM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - An enterprise-grade instant messaging system that integrates AI Agent conversations with internal enterprise communication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic&#34;&gt;Magic Flow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - A powerful visual AI workflow orchestration system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamshare OS&lt;/strong&gt; (Coming soon) - An enterprise-grade online collaborative office system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above AI products, we have also open-sourced some of the infrastructure we used to build these products:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/agentlang&#34;&gt;Agentlang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - A language-first AI Agent Framework for building AI agents with natural language (currently available in Python version, TypeScript version coming soon)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magiclens&#34;&gt;Magic Lens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - A powerful and flexible HTML to Markdown conversion tool that uses an extensible rule system to accurately convert complex HTML documents to concise Markdown format&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic Use&lt;/strong&gt; (Coming soon) - A revolutionary browser operation tool specifically designed for AI Agents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic Space&lt;/strong&gt; (Coming soon) - A new static content hosting management system specifically designed for AI Agents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandbox OS&lt;/strong&gt; (Coming soon) - A powerful sandbox system for AI Agent runtime&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Super Magic&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A powerful &lt;strong&gt;general-purpose AI Agent&lt;/strong&gt; specially designed for complex task scenarios. Through a multi-agent design system and rich tool capabilities, Super Magic supports intelligent abilities such as &lt;strong&gt;autonomous task understanding&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;autonomous task planning&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;autonomous action&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;autonomous error correction&lt;/strong&gt;. It can understand natural language instructions, execute various business processes, and deliver final target results. As the flagship product of the Magic product matrix, Super Magic provides powerful secondary development capabilities through open source, allowing enterprises to quickly build and deploy intelligent assistants that meet specific business needs, greatly improving decision-making efficiency and quality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/super-magic-buffett.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Super Magic&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Super Magic Case Studies&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.cn/share/777665156986277889&#34;&gt;Analysis of Investment Insights from Buffett&#39;s 2025 Shareholders Meeting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.cn/share/774280936479625217&#34;&gt;Analysis of Stocks Related to Beijing Humanoid Robot Half Marathon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.cn/share/777461325648195584&#34;&gt;Summary of Key Points from &#39;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.cn/share/777604044873928705&#34;&gt;Auntie Jenny IPO Analysis and Investment Recommendations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.cn/share/771022574397648897&#34;&gt;SKU Sales Forecast Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For more case studies, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Magic Flow&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic Flow is a powerful visual AI workflow orchestration system that allows users to build complex AI Agent workflows on a free canvas. It has the following core features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;: Intuitive drag-and-drop interface allows designing complex AI workflows without coding, easily implementing various functional combinations through node connections.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich Component Library&lt;/strong&gt;: Built-in variety of preset components, including text processing, image generation, code execution modules, meeting diverse business needs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Model Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Compatible with any large model following the OpenAI API protocol, flexibly choosing AI capabilities suitable for business scenarios.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Integration Capability&lt;/strong&gt;: Seamless integration with Magic IM and other third-party IM systems (WeCom, DingTalk, Feishu), enabling cross-platform collaboration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Extensions&lt;/strong&gt;: Support for custom tool node development to meet specific business scenario requirements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time Debugging and Monitoring&lt;/strong&gt;: Providing comprehensive debugging and monitoring functions to help quickly identify and solve problems in workflows, ensuring stable operation of AI applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/magic-flow.png&#34; alt=&#34;Magic Flow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an important component of the Magic product matrix, Magic Flow can be seamlessly integrated with other Magic products to create a complete enterprise-level AI application ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/super-magic-multi-agents-and-events-en.png?v=20250515&#34; alt=&#34;Magic Multi-Agents and Events&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Magic IM&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic IM is an enterprise-grade AI Agent conversation system designed specifically for internal knowledge management and intelligent customer service scenarios. It provides rich conversational capabilities, supporting multi-turn dialogues, context understanding, knowledge base retrieval, and other functions, allowing enterprises to quickly build intelligent customer service, knowledge assistants, and other applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magic IM has the following core features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Base Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Powerful knowledge base management functions, supporting import of various document formats, automatic indexing, and semantic retrieval, ensuring AI answers based on authentic enterprise knowledge.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversation Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Comprehensive conversation management, supporting topic distinction for different conversation content, enabling both AI Agent conversations and communication with people within the organization.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Chat Capability&lt;/strong&gt;: Powerful group chat functionality, supporting real-time collaborative discussions among multiple people, with AI intelligently participating in group chats and providing instant answers, promoting efficient team communication and knowledge sharing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-organizational Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;: Support for multi-organization deployment and strict organizational data isolation, with each organization having independent data space and access permissions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Security&lt;/strong&gt;: Strict data isolation and access control mechanisms, multi-level permission management, safeguarding sensitive enterprise information and ensuring no data leakage between organizations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://public-cdn.letsmagic.cn/static/img/magic-im-group-chat-en.png?v=20250515&#34; alt=&#34;Magic IM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Teamshare OS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teamshare OS is a modern enterprise-grade collaborative office platform designed to enhance team collaboration efficiency and knowledge management. As an important component of the Magic product matrix, Teamshare deeply integrates AI capabilities into daily office scenarios, achieving intelligent workflows and knowledge management.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teamshare OS has the following core features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligent Document Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Support for online editing, collaboration, and version control of various document formats, AI-assisted content generation and optimization, making team document management more efficient.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic Table&lt;/strong&gt;: Powerful multi-dimensional data management tool, supporting custom field types, diverse views, and automated workflows, combined with AI capabilities to achieve intelligent data processing, meeting diverse data management needs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Collaboration Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Intuitive project boards and task management, supporting custom workflows, combined with AI intelligent analysis to provide project progress forecasting and resource optimization suggestions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge Base&lt;/strong&gt;: Powerful knowledge consolidation and retrieval system, automatically structuring internal enterprise documents to form sustainable accumulated enterprise knowledge assets.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensive Integration Capability&lt;/strong&gt;: Seamless integration with Magic product matrix, while supporting connection with mainstream office software and enterprise applications, creating a unified work platform.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Magic Table&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/user-attachments/assets/6ef46e66-292c-4a8a-8a00-a3b9fb7beec7&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/user-attachments/assets/6ef46e66-292c-4a8a-8a00-a3b9fb7beec7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Magic Doc&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/user-attachments/assets/7327f331-be7d-4aeb-8e19-0949adde66b2&#34;&gt;https://gist.github.com/user-attachments/assets/7327f331-be7d-4aeb-8e19-0949adde66b2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 Using Super Magic&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Cloud Service&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We provide &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;cloud services&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;Super Magic&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;Magic IM&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;Magic Flow&lt;/a&gt;, allowing anyone to start trying and using them with zero setup, providing all features of the open-source version. &lt;em&gt;Currently, an invitation code is required for access, which can be applied for online and granted for trial use after approval.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Magic for Enterprises/Organizations&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We provide more powerful management capabilities and features for teams and enterprises. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bd@dtyq.com?subject=%5BGitHub%5DBusiness%20License%20Inquiry&#34;&gt;Send us an email&lt;/a&gt; to discuss enterprise needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Self-hosted Community Edition&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Docker 24.0+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Docker Compose 2.0+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Start the System Using Docker&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Clone repository&#xA;git clone https://github.com/dtyq/magic.git&#xA;cd magic&#xA;&#xA;# Start service in foreground&#xA;./bin/magic.sh start&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Other Commands&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Start service in background&#xA;./bin/magic.sh daemon&#xA;&#xA;# Check service status&#xA;./bin/magic.sh status&#xA;&#xA;# View logs&#xA;./bin/magic.sh logs&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Configure Environment Variables&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Configure Magic environment variables, must configure at least one large language model&#39;s environment variables to use Magic normally&#xA;cp .env.example .env&#xA;&#xA;# Configure Super Magic environment variables, must configure any large language model that supports OpenAI format to use it normally&#xA;./bin/magic.sh status&#xA;cp config/.env_super_magic.example .env_super_magic&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Access Services&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;API Service: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:9501&#34;&gt;http://localhost:9501&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Web Application: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8080&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8080&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Account &lt;code&gt;13812345678&lt;/code&gt;：Password &lt;code&gt;letsmagic.ai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Account &lt;code&gt;13912345678&lt;/code&gt;：Password &lt;code&gt;letsmagic.ai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RabbitMQ Management Interface: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:15672&#34;&gt;http://localhost:15672&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Username: admin&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Password: magic123456&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Official Website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.letsmagic.ai&#34;&gt;https://www.letsmagic.ai&lt;/a&gt; Documentation: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.letsmagic.cn/en&#34;&gt;https://docs.letsmagic.cn/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who want to contribute code, please refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dtyq/magic/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribution Guide&lt;/a&gt;. Also, please consider supporting Magic through social media, events, and conferences. The development of Magic relies on your support.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you discover a security vulnerability in Magic, please send an email to the Magic official team at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:team@dtyq.com&#34;&gt;team@dtyq.com&lt;/a&gt;. All security vulnerabilities will be promptly addressed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📄 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository follows the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dtyq/magic/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Magic Open Source License&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially Apache 2.0 but with some additional restrictions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🙏 Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all developers who have contributed to Magic!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://star-history.com/#dtyq/magic&amp;amp;Date&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=dtyq/magic&amp;amp;type=Date&#34; alt=&#34;Star History Chart&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>