<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-15T01:37:36Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ruudmens/LazyAdmin</title>
    <updated>2023-07-15T01:37:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-15:/ruudmens/LazyAdmin</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ruudmens/LazyAdmin" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SysAdmin scripts for you to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;LazyAdmin.nl Scripts Repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a number of scripts that I have written or enhanced to make day-to-day life easier for system administators. These are provided for free to the community under an MIT License. An explantion or guide on how to use the scripts can be found on my blog LazyAdmin.nl&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Download the contents of this repository to your workstation.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use a script you can copy it onto your workstation and open the PowerShell window in that location. To read more about running PowerShell scripts, you can read this article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lazyadmin.nl/powershell/run-a-powershell-script/&#34;&gt;https://lazyadmin.nl/powershell/run-a-powershell-script/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Launch PowerShell and make sure Set-ExecutionPolicy is set to RemoteSigned or Bypass&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to write your own PowerShell script with this complete guide: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lazyadmin.nl/powershell/powershell-script/&#34;&gt;https://lazyadmin.nl/powershell/powershell-script/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contribution&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a fork of the project into your own reposity. Make all your necessary changes and create a pull request with a description on what was added or removed and details explaining the changes in lines of code. If approved, I will merge it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Licensing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the MIT License (the “License”); you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE (SCRIPTS) ARE PROVIDED &#34;AS IS&#34;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>