<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-25T02:30:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>enchanted-sword/dashboard-unfucker</title>
    <updated>2023-08-25T02:30:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-25:/enchanted-sword/dashboard-unfucker</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/enchanted-sword/dashboard-unfucker" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;unfucks the twitterification of tumblr&#39;s dashboard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;dashboard-unfucker&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfucks the twitterification of tumblr&#39;s dashboard by reverting it to the old layout as closely as possible&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two versions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version A: unfucker.user.js&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version B: unfucker-noflags.user.js&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version A uses window property flags to completely disable the vertical nav layout update for your browser, as well as offering other features such as reverting the activity feed and messaging updates, re-enabling the use of the legacy post editor, and more. However, this process is finicky, and does not appear to work for all users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version B uses CSS and jQuery to simply move elements around on the page so that it resembles the non-vertical nav layout. This method isn&#39;t as thorough, but it should work for all users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The script was originally designed for Tampermonkey. Certain versions of the script may work with Violentmonkey and Greasemonkey, but due to the volume of problems they seem to encounter, neither are officially supported at the current time, although this will hopefully change in the future. If you want to use a non-userscript injection method, such as an adblocker, simply replace all instances of &lt;code&gt;unsafeWindow&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tampermonkey.net/index.php&#34;&gt;Tampermonkey&lt;/a&gt; extension for your browser.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on either &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enchanted-sword/dashboard-unfucker/raw/main/unfucker.user.js&#34;&gt;unfucker.user.js&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enchanted-sword/dashboard-unfucker/raw/main/unfucker-noflags.user.js&#34;&gt;unfucker-noflags.user.js&lt;/a&gt; (the former is the recommended option) to install.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Not fully tested on chromium or safari, but sources seem to say that it does work as intended.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re missing the dashboard tabs header (the navbar with following, for you, followed tags, etc.), prior to versions 3.5.0a and 4.0.0b it was disabled default, and can be reenabled via the first option in config menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If it injects, but ends up wonky, chances are you just need to do a full reload of the page (ctrl + shift + r).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;ve updated script versions but it doesn&#39;t fix a version-specific bug, it&#39;s likely because of browser caching, closing and reopening the browser usually fixes it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the main content divider takes up the full width of the screen, that isn&#39;t caused by this script, that&#39;s the XKit Panorama feature, which can be disabled in the XKit config menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known issues / Incompatibilities&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The script apparently conflicts with HTTPS Everywhere extension on Firefox.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The script apparently conflicts with New XKit. However, it works just fine with XKit Rewritten.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The script is currently incompatibile with the Firemonkey extension.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When first enabling the legacy editor toggle for text posts, an error popup will appear in the new post window. However, this popup can be safely dismissed and the editor will work normally.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>