<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-06T01:40:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>3cqs-coder/SymBot</title>
    <updated>2023-06-06T01:40:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-06:/3cqs-coder/SymBot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SymBot is a user friendly, self-hosted and automated DCA (Dollar Cost Averaging) cryptocurrency bot solution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/111208586/221390681-d13b9bce-dafb-4b55-a6f1-1bc5218cd204.png&#34; alt=&#34;SymBot Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SymBot is a user friendly, self-hosted and automated DCA (Dollar Cost Averaging) cryptocurrency bot solution. Create and manage your bots entirely from your web browser or with simple built-in APIs. Best of all, your exchange credentials and keys always remain in your hands... not any other third-party.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/111208586/219070191-abe2ef94-ca5a-43a9-867c-2c2ff9609699.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SymBot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#installation-docker&#34;&gt;Docker Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#upgrading&#34;&gt;Upgrading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#telegram-setup&#34;&gt;Telegram Setup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#api-information&#34;&gt;API Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#api-sample-usage&#34;&gt;API Sample Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#resetting-symbot&#34;&gt;Resetting SymBot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linux, MacOS, or Windows based system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; must be installed on your system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mongodb.com&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; installed or a cloud host provider&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Access to a cryptocurrency exchange such as Binance or Coinbase&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reliable high-speed internet connection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;1GB RAM minimum but recommended at least 4GB&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Trading requires your system and internet connection to be running 24/7. Any interruption could result in missed trades, signals, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would rather run SymBot using Docker then skip this section and go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/3cqs-coder/SymBot/main/#installation-docker&#34;&gt;Docker Installation&lt;/a&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a command line terminal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change directory to where SymBot files are located&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait until all packages are downloaded and installed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modify the app and bot configuration files as necessary (see below)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;npm start&lt;/code&gt;. You can also use &lt;code&gt;npm start consolelog&lt;/code&gt; to display all logging to the console for testing purposes. The same information is also logged to files in the &lt;code&gt;logs&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a web browser and type: &lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:3000&#34;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:3000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Recommended additional steps (optional)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To have SymBot run in the background it is recommended to use the Node.js process manager called &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&#39;s how to use it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; by typing: &lt;code&gt;npm install pm2 -g&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a file called &lt;code&gt;ecosystem.config.js&lt;/code&gt; and place the below configuration into it:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;module.exports = {&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;apps: [&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;{&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;name: &#39;symbot&#39;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;namespace: &#39;symbot&#39;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;script: &#39;/home/symbot/symbot.js&#39;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;kill_timeout: 8000,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;max_memory_restart: &#39;4000M&#39;&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;}&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;  ]&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Replace &lt;code&gt;/home/symbot/symbot.js&lt;/code&gt; with the actual location where SymBot resides on your server and save the file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tell &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; to start SymBot with a one time only command by typing: &lt;code&gt;pm2 start ecosystem.config.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;pm2 save&lt;/code&gt; to save the configuration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you don&#39;t already have &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; starting at system boot time, type this with root privileges: &lt;code&gt;pm2 startup&lt;/code&gt;. Then type: &lt;code&gt;pm2 save&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SymBot will now start automatically even when the system is rebooted. With the above configuration &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; will monitor SymBot and if memory exceeds roughly four gigabytes, a kill signal will be sent to SymBot. &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; will wait eight seconds before terminating the process to give SymBot some time to safely shut itself down. &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; will then start SymBot again. You can change those settings to suit your own server requirements and needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation (Docker)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker can be a great way to get SymBot up and running fast with all the necessary dependencies such as MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Docker build files can be modified as necessary, but should only be done if you&#39;re familiar with how they work. Running SymBot under Docker is considered experimental and performing any upgrades could cause unexpected issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a command line terminal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change directory to where SymBot files are located&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;strong&gt;app.json&lt;/strong&gt; configuration file and set &lt;code&gt;mongo_db_url&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;mongodb://symbot:symbot123@database/symbot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make any additional changes to the app and bot configuration files as necessary (see below)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change directory to &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; in the same location where SymBot files are located&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;docker-compose -p symbot up -d --build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait for Docker to build everything and all containers to start&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a web browser and type: &lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:3000&#34;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:3000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mongo Express is also installed which can be used to access MongoDB visually by opening a web browser to &lt;a href=&#34;http://127.0.0.1:3010&#34;&gt;http://127.0.0.1:3010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Upgrading&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When upgrading to a new version of SymBot it is recommended to follow the basic steps below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stop all running SymBot instances &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If using &lt;strong&gt;pm2&lt;/strong&gt; suggested in the installation above, you can type: &lt;code&gt;pm2 stop ecosystem.config.js&lt;/code&gt; in a command line terminal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make a backup of the directory to where all current SymBot files are located&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract new SymBot files to existing directory. If prompted, be sure to allow new files to replace the original or you may be running portions of a previous version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy existing configuration files from backup created previously&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compare parameters in the new SymBot configuration files such as &lt;strong&gt;app.json&lt;/strong&gt; to existing files if any have been added or removed. Any changes must be added to existing configurations or this may cause SymBot to not start or run properly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; to ensure all modules are installed properly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start SymBot and verify the new version is running&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Monitor logs for a few minutes either on the console, log files, or the web interface to ensure everything is operating as before&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are running SymBot behind any other services such as Apache, Nginx, Cloudflare, etc. you may need to clear caches in order for the latest upgraded files to be served properly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These files are located in the &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; directory&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;app.json&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;password&lt;/code&gt; is a hashed password used to login to the SymBot web interface. The default password is automatically set as &#34;&lt;em&gt;admin&lt;/em&gt;&#34; the very first time SymBot is started. This is not a plain text password, but rather an encrypted form of it, so it should not be manually entered or you may not be able to login properly. It is strongly recommended to change the default password using the web interface configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;api_key&lt;/code&gt; is a UUID v4 value that is randomly generated the first time SymBot starts. It is used to make API calls to SymBot. This can be set to most any string value you choose.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;web_server&lt;/code&gt; contains settings for the SymBot web server. The default port is 3000.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bots&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;start_conditions&lt;/code&gt; contains keys and descriptions such as &lt;code&gt;asap&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;api&lt;/code&gt; for various start conditions that can be used to start bots and deals. The keys should never be changed after the initial start of SymBot or they will not match previous bots and deals.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pair_autofill_blacklist&lt;/code&gt; is an array of trading pairs that you don&#39;t want automatically filled in the pair selection box when creating or updating bots and clicking one of the stablecoin buttons such as USD or USDT. You can use full pairs such as BTC/USD or wildcards such as BTC/*. This can be useful to prevent bots from starting deals using stablecoin pairs such as USDT/USD as those will generally have little volatility in typical market conditions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;telegram&lt;/code&gt; contains an optional Telegram token id and user id to send SymBot notifications to. This includes system warnings such as detected connectivity issues, bot and deal start / stops, and more! You must first create a Telegram bot with &lt;code&gt;@BotFather&lt;/code&gt; to use (see below).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mongo_db_url&lt;/code&gt; is the URL to your MongoDB instance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;WARNING: If you run multiple instances of SymBot using the same database you will mess up your bots!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;For quick set up, create a free account at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.mongodb.com&#34;&gt;https://cloud.mongodb.com&lt;/a&gt; and copy the URL given into the app config. It begins with something like: mongodb+srv://&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If running a local MongoDB instance, specifying &lt;code&gt;mongodb://127.0.0.1:27017/SymBot&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;mongodb://localhost:27017/SymBot&lt;/code&gt; should work fine, but setting up a username and password is also recommended&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;For better security running your own local database is recommended&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;signals&lt;/code&gt; contains a section to use signals with SymBot. There is a 3CQS signals section by default. If you have an API key just copy it there or create an account at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.3CQS.com&#34;&gt;https://www.3CQS.com&lt;/a&gt; to get one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bot.json&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This contains all default settings for your bot and exchange information. For test purposes, always leave &lt;code&gt;sandBox: true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Valid exchanges include binance, binanceus, coinbase, and many others. SymBot uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ccxt/ccxt&#34;&gt;CCXT&lt;/a&gt; library so if the exchange is supported, you should be able to connect to it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Most bot settings do not need to be set here since they can be set when creating a bot in the web interface&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;server.json&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This file is created the very first time SymBot is started. It contains an automatically generated UUID v4 &lt;code&gt;server_id&lt;/code&gt;. The primary purpose is to ensure if there are ever multiple instances of SymBot running, they do not accidentally conflict with the database used. When SymBot starts it will compare the &lt;code&gt;server_id&lt;/code&gt; value in this file to the database entry. If they do not match, SymBot will shut down.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This file should never be copied to another folder or server if you plan to run additional instances of SymBot, or manually edited unless you have a good reason to do so.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Telegram Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Telegram with SymBot is a great way to know when bot deals start and finish, but also getting notifications when issues are detected, such as being unable to connect to your exchange.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You just need to create a Telegram bot with &lt;code&gt;@BotFather&lt;/code&gt;. Here are some simple steps on how to do that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a Telegram chat with &lt;code&gt;@BotFather&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once there you may need to type or click on &lt;code&gt;/start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;/newbot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choose a name that will be displayed when you receive messages from Telegram. For simplicity, just use: &lt;strong&gt;SymBot&lt;/strong&gt;. This does not need to be unique to Telegram.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Now you need to choose a unique Telegram username. This can be just about any string value, but it must end in the word &lt;strong&gt;bot&lt;/strong&gt;. For example: &lt;strong&gt;MySymBotServer123_bot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the username you chose was not already taken, then you should receive a token that looks something like: &lt;strong&gt;12345:AbCdEfG_123Abc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a chat with your new bot &lt;strong&gt;MySymBotServer123_bot&lt;/strong&gt; (use the actual name of your bot)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type or click on &lt;code&gt;/start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy your Telegram bot token into the SymBot &lt;strong&gt;app.json&lt;/strong&gt; configuration file. You must also enter your own Telegram id or SymBot will not allow messages to be sent. If you don&#39;t know your Telegram id, open a chat with &lt;code&gt;@userinfobot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Restart SymBot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;API Information&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take more control of your bots and deals using SymBot APIs. You can easily enable or disable bots and start deals using triggers or signals from 3CQS, TradingView, your own custom scripts and strategies, or from any of your other favorite providers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Create bot&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botName&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Bot name will be generated if omitted&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pair&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;array&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;List of pairs used for the bot&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;active&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Enabled: true / Disabled: false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;createStep&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Set to &#34;getOrders&#34; to preview all DCA orders without creating the bot&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;firstOrderAmount&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Initial or base order amount for each deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderAmount&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Amount for every additional DCA / safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderStepPercent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Price deviation percentage to open safety orders&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderSizeMultiplier&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Multiplies the amount of funds used by the last safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderStepPercentMultiplier&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Multiplies the price deviation percentage used by the last safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaTakeProfitPercent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Take profit percentage the bot will use to close successful deals&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaMaxOrder&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum DCA / safety orders allowed per deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dealMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum deals allowed before bot is disabled. Set to 0 for unlimited (Can reset for multi-pair bots or when re-enabled)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pairMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum pairs allowed to start per bot. Set to 0 for unlimited&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pairDealsMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum number of same pair deals that can run concurrently. Default is maximum one deal per pair when empty or set to 0.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;volumeMin&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Minimum 24h volume (specified in millions) symbol must have to start&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;startCondition&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;asap&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Start deals using &#34;&lt;em&gt;asap&lt;/em&gt;&#34; or by &#34;&lt;em&gt;api&lt;/em&gt;&#34;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/bots/create&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Update bot&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Bot ID to be updated&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botName&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Bot name will be generated if omitted&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pair&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;array&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;List of pairs used for the bot&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;active&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Enabled: true / Disabled: false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;firstOrderAmount&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Initial or base order amount for each deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderAmount&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Amount for every additional DCA / safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderStepPercent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Price deviation percentage to open safety orders&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderSizeMultiplier&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Multiplies the amount of funds used by the last safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaOrderStepPercentMultiplier&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Multiplies the price deviation percentage used by the last safety order&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaTakeProfitPercent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Take profit percentage the bot will use to close successful deals&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaMaxOrder&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum DCA / safety orders allowed per deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dealMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum deals allowed before bot is disabled. Set to 0 for unlimited (Can reset for multi-pair bots or when re-enabled)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pairMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum pairs allowed to start per bot. Set to 0 for unlimited&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pairDealsMax&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum number of same pair deals that can run concurrently. Default is maximum one deal per pair when empty or set to 0.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;volumeMin&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Minimum 24h volume (specified in millions) symbol must have to start&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;startCondition&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;asap&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Start deals using &#34;&lt;em&gt;asap&lt;/em&gt;&#34; or by &#34;&lt;em&gt;api&lt;/em&gt;&#34;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/bots/update&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Get bots&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;active&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Enabled = true / Disabled = false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /api/bots&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enable bot&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/bots/{botId}/enable&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Disable bot&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/bots/{botId}/disable&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Update deal&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaTakeProfitPercent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;number&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Take profit percentage the bot will use to close successful deals&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dcaMaxOrder&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Maximum DCA / safety orders allowed per deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dealLast&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Prevents a new deal from starting after this deal completes. Setting only applies to this deal. If you have multiple deals running with the same pair, this will not affect the other deals.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/deals/{dealId}/update_deal&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Panic sell deal&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Closes deal and sells at current market price&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/deals/{dealId}/panic_sell&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Get active deals&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Returns all current active deals&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /api/deals&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Get completed deals&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;from&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Returns most recent completed deals if start from date is not specified&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;to&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Returns all completed deals up to end of date specified&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Returns completed deals for specified bot id&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /api/deals/completed&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Start deal&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;botId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;signalId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Used to identify signal that started deal&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pair&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Only required for multi-pair bots&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;POST /api/bots/{botId}/start_deal&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Get markets&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;exchange&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Exchange to retrieve market data for&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pair&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Symbol pair pricing and data to retrieve. Omitting will return all valid symbols for specified exchange&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /api/markets&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Show TradingView chart&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mandatory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Values (default)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;jquery&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Automatically add required jQuery script to display charts&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;script&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;boolean&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Automatically add required TradingView script to display charts&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;containerId&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Element id used for the TradingView chart container&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;theme&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;dark&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Theme to be used can be &#34;&lt;em&gt;light&lt;/em&gt;&#34; or &#34;&lt;em&gt;dark&lt;/em&gt;&#34;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;exchange&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;binance&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Exchange to be used for chart&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;pair&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;string&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;BTC_USDT&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Symbol pair to be used for chart&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;width&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Width of chart in pixels&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;height&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;integer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Height of chart in pixels&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GET /api/tradingview&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;API Sample Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Create bot&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;-d &#39;{&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;pair&#34;: [ &#34;BTC/USD&#34; ],&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;botName&#34;: &#34;&#34;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;active&#34;: false,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;createStep&#34;: &#34;&#34;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;firstOrderAmount&#34;: 20,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderAmount&#34;: 45,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercent&#34;: 1.3,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderSizeMultiplier&#34;: 1.08,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercentMultiplier&#34;: 1.0,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaTakeProfitPercent&#34;: 1.5,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaMaxOrder&#34;: 46,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dealMax&#34;: 0,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;startCondition&#34;: &#34;asap&#34;&#xA;&#x9;}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots/create&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Update bot&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;-d &#39;{&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;pair&#34;: [ &#34;BTC/USD&#34;, &#34;ETH/USD&#34; ],&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;botId&#34;: &#34;{botId}&#34;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;botName&#34;: &#34;&#34;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;active&#34;: false,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;firstOrderAmount&#34;: 20,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderAmount&#34;: 45,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercent&#34;: 1.3,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderSizeMultiplier&#34;: 1.08,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercentMultiplier&#34;: 1.0,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaTakeProfitPercent&#34;: 1.5,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaMaxOrder&#34;: 46,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dealMax&#34;: 0,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;startCondition&#34;: &#34;api&#34;&#xA;&#x9;}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots/update&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Get DCA orders without creating bot&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;-d &#39;{&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;pair&#34;: [ &#34;BTC/USD&#34; ],&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;createStep&#34;: &#34;getOrders&#34;,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;firstOrderAmount&#34;: 20,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderAmount&#34;: 45,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercent&#34;: 1.3,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderSizeMultiplier&#34;: 1.08,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaOrderStepPercentMultiplier&#34;: 1.0,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaTakeProfitPercent&#34;: 1.5,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaMaxOrder&#34;: 46&#xA;&#x9;}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots/create&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Get bots&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X GET \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;&#39;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots?active=true&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Enable bot&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots/{botId}/enable&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Update deal&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;-d &#39;{&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaTakeProfitPercent&#34;: 1.5,&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;dcaMaxOrder&#34;: 12&#xA;&#x9;}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/deals/{dealId}/update_deal&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Panic sell deal&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/deals/{dealId}/panic_sell&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Get active deals&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X GET \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;&#39;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/deals&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Get completed deals&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X GET \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;&#39;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/deals/completed?from=2023-03-01&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Start deal&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X POST \&#xA;-H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;-d &#39;{ &#34;pair&#34;: &#34;BTC/USD&#34; }&#39; \&#xA;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/bots/{botId}/start_deal&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Get markets&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -i -X GET \&#xA;-H &#39;Accept: application/json&#39; \&#xA;-H &#39;api-key: {API-KEY}&#39; \&#xA;&#39;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/markets?exchange=binance&amp;amp;pair=BTC_USDT&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;TradingView chart&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://127.0.0.1:3000/api/tradingview?script=true&amp;amp;exchange=binance&amp;amp;pair=BTC_USDT&amp;amp;theme=dark&amp;amp;width=1000&amp;amp;height=600&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Resetting SymBot&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;*** CAUTION *** This will purge all data from the SymBot database!&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to reset the SymBot database for any reason, you can do so only from the command line. It will first ask to confirm, then display a reset code you must enter, and confirm again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stop any running instances of SymBot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Type: &lt;code&gt;npm start reset&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;node ./symbot.js reset&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;What exchanges does SymBot support?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SymBot uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ccxt/ccxt&#34;&gt;CCXT&lt;/a&gt; (CryptoCurrency eXchange Trading) library which supports many popular exchanges such as Binance and Coinbase. If your exchange is listed then you should be able to connect to it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Can I run SymBot on my home network?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Yes, however using a trusted hosting provider is a more stable choice. Trading requires your system to be running 24/7 along with an uninterrupted high-speed internet connection. Most established hosting data centers have readily available support teams to assist with system related issues, fully equipped with generators in case of power failures, redundant fiber connections, and operate inside hurricane resistant buildings. If your home experiences a power outage or any other unexpected issues, that may result in unplaced orders or missed trading signals which could impact your deals significantly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;How many DCA bots can I run at the same time?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can technically run an unlimited number of bots, however any limitations mostly come from how often your exchange allows APIs to be accessed, and the amount of resources your system (server) has such as CPU, memory, etc. The more bots you run generally requires additional API calls to your exchange and more system processing capability to manage all of your deals efficiently.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;If my system is restarted will my deals be lost?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SymBot is designed with resiliency in mind. Providing there are no issues with your database or other technical problems that caused your system to reboot, your bot deals will automatically resume upon restart. It is recommended to monitor the logs for a period of time to ensure everything is operating as expected.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;If I disable a DCA bot will it sell my deals?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No. Disabling a DCA bot will only prevent new deals from being started. Any existing deals that are running will continue until they complete or if you choose to panic sell.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Why are my deals not updating or not getting pricing?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your exchange credentials may be incorrect or you may be getting blocked, rate-limited, or experiencing some type of connectivity issues. Some exchanges also restrict access by region, so your server&#39;s IP address must reside in a location that is allowed. Check the logs for any error messages or unusual activity. You can do this from a command line terminal or in the SymBot web interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Why is my system suddenly using more CPU or memory?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SymBot is continuously monitoring and processing data from exchanges, potential signal providers you&#39;re using such as from 3CQS, accessing the database, or performing house-keeping tasks like purging old logs. During times of increased market volatility, more data could be coming in faster and may stay in memory for longer periods of time or as necessary. It is normal to see spikes in CPU or memory usage, but if either remain excessively high for extended periods of time you may want to look into it further. Many times upgrading your CPU, increasing system memory, or upgrading hard drive capacity tend to resolve most issues and provide much better performance and an improved trading experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All investment strategies and investments involve risk of loss. All information found here, including any ideas, opinions, views, predictions, forecasts, or suggestions, expressed or implied herein, are for informational, entertainment or educational purposes only and should not be construed as personal investment advice. Conduct your own due diligence, or consult a licensed financial advisor or broker before making any and all investment decisions. Any investments, trades, speculations, or discussions made on the basis of any information found here, expressed or implied herein, are committed at your own risk, financial or otherwise. Use at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kunjgit/GameZone</title>
    <updated>2023-06-06T01:40:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-06:/kunjgit/GameZone</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This open source repository contains collection of games build on basic tech stacks in web development . Use your creativity and build your own game and contribute to the repository by making PR &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;display:none;&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&#xA; &lt;h1&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Activities/Video%20Game.png&#34; alt=&#34;Video Game&#34; width=&#34;50&#34; height=&#34;50&#34;&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;10&#34;&gt; GameZone&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;!-- repo intro --&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;4&#34;&gt;This open source repository contains a collection of games built on basic tech stacks in web development. Use your creativity, build your own game and contribute to the repository by making a PR  &lt;br&gt; Make sure you star the repository and show your love to us &lt;br&gt; Also join the discord server for GameZone and start collaborating with others  &lt;/font&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/fgwk4XZfxG&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Discord-%235865F2.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=discord&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/tokei/lines/github/kunjgit/GameZone&#34; alt=&#34;Lines of code&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/kunjgit/GameZone&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub issues&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/kunjgit/GameZone&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub forks&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr/kunjgit/GameZone&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub pull requests&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/kunjgit/GameZone?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Repo stars&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/kunjgit/GameZone&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/website?down_color=red&amp;amp;down_message=offline&amp;amp;up_color=blue&amp;amp;up_message=online&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fkunjgit.github.io%2FGameZone%2F&#34; alt=&#34;Website&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- tech stacks --&gt;  &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Travel%20and%20places/High%20Voltage.png&#34; alt=&#34;High Voltage&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;Tech Stack&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;center&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA; &lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/HTML5-E34F26.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=HTML5&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/JavaScript-F7DF1E.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=JavaScript&amp;amp;logoColor=black&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Bootstrap-7952B3.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=Bootstrap&amp;amp;logoColor=black&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/CSS3-1572B6.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=CSS3&amp;amp;logoColor=black&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Tailwind%20CSS-06B6D4.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=Tailwind-CSS&amp;amp;logoColor=black&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;div&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xA; &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/center&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- lets get started --&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Travel%20and%20places/Rocket.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rocket&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Let&#39;s get started&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- contribution steps --&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository &lt;code&gt;git clone &#34;url of the repo&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Raise and issue to add new game or to enhancement for a game (Have a look at few things you have to take care during raising issue )&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Select appropriate issue template&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make sure your idea is unique and interesting &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t alter the issue title. You are supposed to write your issue name after that only. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Issue Title]: Your Issue&lt;/code&gt; make sure you just add your issue name&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;ex .&lt;code&gt;[New game]: Super Mario&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make sure you select the program in which you are participating &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait till you have been assigned the issue&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After you have been assigned the issue start working on the code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create your new branch using &lt;code&gt;git checkout -b &amp;lt;name of your branch&amp;gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Having your code into the repository &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make your game folder into &lt;code&gt;Games&lt;/code&gt; folder by the naming convention mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kunjgit/GameZone/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING_GUIDELINE.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING GUIDELINE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Add your code files (index.html,style.css,script.js) in your game folder&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file in your folder and add all the functionalities and how you can play that game in that README file , also include screenshots of working game , video of a game explaining (if required).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To create &lt;code&gt;Your_Folder/README.md &lt;/code&gt; checkout the template &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kunjgit/GameZone/main/Games/FOLDER_README_TEMPLATE.md&#34;&gt;GAME README TEMPLATE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Now take one good screenshot of your game that you want to display it on our website and add into &lt;code&gt;assets/images&lt;/code&gt; (follow the naming convention &amp;lt;your_folder_name&amp;gt;.png or .jpeg or .jpg)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;add your folders link and name in main README.md (the one you are reading currently)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Push your changes to Github using &lt;code&gt;git push origin &amp;lt;name your branch&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit your changes for review by creating PR&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And you are done !&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I will review your code and I will merge your code to the main branch of this repository and you will notified for the same&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you having queries in basic flow of github learn it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kunjgit/GameZone/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING_GUIDELINE.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING GUIDELINE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Smilies/Robot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Robot&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Games&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- list of the games --&gt; &#xA;&lt;center&gt; &#xA; &lt;table&gt; &#xA;  &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;No.&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;Name of the game&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Master_Typing&#34;&gt;Master Typing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tilting_Maze&#34;&gt;Tilting Maze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Simon_Game_Challenge&#34;&gt;Simon Game Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Snake_Game&#34;&gt;Snake Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Dino_Runner_Game&#34;&gt;Dino Runner Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Whack_a_Mole&#34;&gt;Whack a Mole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Doraemon_Jump&#34;&gt;Doraemon Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Black_Jack&#34;&gt;Black Jack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Memory_Game&#34;&gt;Memory Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Word_Guessing_Game&#34;&gt;Word Guessing Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Ludo_Game&#34;&gt;Ludo Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Piano&#34;&gt;Piano Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Atari_Breakout&#34;&gt;Atari Breakout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Chrome_Dinosaur_Game&#34;&gt;Dinosaur Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Colour_Guessing_Game&#34;&gt;Guess The Colour by RGB Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Guess_The_Number&#34;&gt;Guess The Number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/race_car&#34;&gt;Race car game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DP-NOTHING/GameZone/tree/contri/Games/Aim_Training&#34;&gt;Aim Training&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Alien_Shooters&#34;&gt;Alien Shooter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Fruit_Ninja&#34;&gt;Fruit Ninja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Doodle_Jump&#34;&gt;Doodle Jump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Alphabet&#34;&gt;Alphabet Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Candy_Crush&#34;&gt;Candy Crush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Word_Association_Game&#34;&gt;Word Association Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tic_Tac_Toe&#34;&gt;Tic Tac Toe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Flappy_Bird&#34;&gt;Flappy Bird Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hithub.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Trivia_It&#34;&gt;Trivia It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Minesweeper&#34;&gt;Minesweeper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;29&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Himanshu07-debug/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Dice_Showdown_Game&#34;&gt;Dice ShowDown Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Pac_Man_Game&#34;&gt;Pac_Man Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Brick_Breaker&#34;&gt;Brick Breaker Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Magic_Square&#34;&gt;Magic Square Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Fight_Game&#34;&gt;Fight Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Lighthouse&#34;&gt;Lighthouse Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Lights_Out&#34;&gt;Lights Out Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Word_Scramble_Game&#34;&gt;Word Scramble Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;37&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tetris&#34;&gt;Tetris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;38&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Interactive_Quizzing&#34;&gt;Interactive Quizzing Application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;39&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Planet_Defense&#34;&gt;Planet Defense Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Rabbit_Rush&#34;&gt;Rabbit Rush Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Wordle&#34;&gt;Wordle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;42&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Roll_Race&#34;&gt;Roll Race Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;43&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Menja&#34;&gt;Menja Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;44&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Typing_Speed_Test_Game&#34;&gt;Typing Speed Test Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tile_Game&#34;&gt;Tile_Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Stick_Hero_Game&#34;&gt;Stick_Hero_Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;47&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Starwars_Character_Game&#34;&gt;Starwars_Character_Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;48&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Traffic_Run&#34;&gt;Traffic_Run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;49&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Love_Result_Predictor&#34;&gt;Love Result Predictor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Snake_and_ladders&#34;&gt;Snake and Ladders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tower_Defense&#34;&gt;Tower Defense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;52&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Shr-reny/GameZone/tree/b367981bcb5c3654f79fb23b4ffd41e159e9cc24/Games/Bird_game&#34;&gt;Bird Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;53&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Bubble_Blast_Game&#34;&gt;Bubble Blast Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;54&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Emoji_Charades&#34;&gt;Emoji Charades&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;55&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Roshnijeewani3457/GameZone/tree/new/Games/Drum_And_Kit&#34;&gt;Drum And Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;56&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/its-me-abhishek/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Rock_Paper_Scissors&#34;&gt;Rock Paper Scissors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;57&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Frogger&#34;&gt;Frogger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;58&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SusanStorm/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Not_morethan5&#34;&gt;!morethan5 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;59&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Unruly_Tower&#34;&gt;Unruly Tower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;60&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/MazeGame&#34;&gt;Maze Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;61&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Connect4&#34;&gt;Connect4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;62&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Spelling_Bee&#34;&gt;Spelling_Bee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;63&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/2048&#34;&gt;2048&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Spin_the_wheel&#34;&gt;Spin the Wheel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;65&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Breakout&#34;&gt;Breakout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;66&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Tower_Blocks&#34;&gt;Tower Blocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;67&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Platform_Game&#34;&gt;Platform_Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;68&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Red_Light_Green_Light&#34;&gt;Red_Light_Green_Light&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;69&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Squashing_your_Enemy&#34;&gt;Squash your Enemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;70&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Avax_gods&#34;&gt;Avax Gods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;71&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Flip_Card_Game&#34;&gt;Flip Card Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;72&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Bingo_Game&#34;&gt;Bingo Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;73&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Fifteen_Puzzle_Game&#34;&gt;Fifteen Puzzle Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;74&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/tree/main/Games/Stack_Game&#34;&gt;Stack_Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA; &lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;/center&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Objects/Page%20with%20Curl.png&#34; alt=&#34;Page with Curl&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Contributing Guideline &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- contributing guideline detail --&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kunjgit/GameZone/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING_GUIDELINE.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING GUIDELINE&lt;/a&gt; to get all details about contributing to &lt;strong&gt;GameZone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Learn all about development process and all information you need to contribute to our project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are having the basic queries make sure you checkout resources there&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- code of conduct --&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Hand%20gestures/Handshake.png&#34; alt=&#34;Handshake&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Code of Conduct &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please note that this project is released with &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kunjgit/GameZone/main/.github/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;CODE OF CONDUCT&lt;/a&gt;. By participating in this project you agree to abide by its terms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- mentors --&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/People%20with%20professions/Man%20Teacher%20Light%20Skin%20Tone.png&#34; alt=&#34;Robot&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Mentors&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/girlscript/gssoc-assets/main/Logos/GS_logo_White.png&#34; alt=&#34;GSSoC23&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;table&gt; &#xA;  &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;Arun G Nayak&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;RAJU KUMAR&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/84305637?v=4&amp;amp;s=150&#34; alt=&#34;Mentor 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/97028776?v=4&amp;amp;s=150&#34; alt=&#34;Mentor 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/arun-g-nayak&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Arun9739/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajukumar101/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/raju-kumar21&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA; &lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- a big thanks to all the contributors --&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tarikul-Islam-Anik/Animated-Fluent-Emojis/master/Emojis/Smilies/Red%20Heart.png&#34; alt=&#34;Red Heart&#34; width=&#34;40&#34; height=&#34;40&#34;&gt; Contributors &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This project thanking all the contributors for having your valuable contribution to our project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure you show some love by giving  to our repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;center&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kunjgit/GameZone/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=kunjgit/GameZone&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;/center&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>songquanpeng/one-api</title>
    <updated>2023-06-06T01:40:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-06:/songquanpeng/one-api</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;All in one  OpenAI  API  Azure OpenAI API key OpenAI API  Docker &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/songquanpeng/one-api/main/web/public/logo.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; alt=&#34;one-api logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;One API&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; All in one  OpenAI  API &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/songquanpeng/one-api/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/songquanpeng/one-api?color=brightgreen&#34; alt=&#34;license&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/releases/latest&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/songquanpeng/one-api?color=brightgreen&amp;amp;include_prereleases&#34; alt=&#34;release&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/repository/docker/justsong/one-api&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/justsong/one-api?color=brightgreen&#34; alt=&#34;docker pull&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/releases/latest&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/songquanpeng/one-api/total?color=brightgreen&amp;amp;include_prereleases&#34; alt=&#34;release&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/songquanpeng/one-api&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/songquanpeng/one-api&#34; alt=&#34;GoReportCard&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api#&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api#&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.justsong.cn/&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api#&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;v0.2&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;code&gt;v0.3&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/songquanpeng/one-api/main/bin/migration_v0.2-v0.3.sql&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; API  PR  issue  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; OpenAI &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Azure OpenAI API&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://api2d.com/r/197971&#34;&gt;API2D&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aigptx.top?aff=uFpUl2Kf&#34;&gt;OhMyGPT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aiproxy.io/?i=OneAPI&#34;&gt;AI Proxy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;OneAPI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.ls&#34;&gt;AI.LS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://openaimax.com&#34;&gt;OpenAI Max&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai-sb.com&#34;&gt;OpenAI-SB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://console.openai-asia.com/r/2412&#34;&gt;CloseAI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt;  OpenAI &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;stream &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/songquanpeng/one-api/main/#%E5%A4%9A%E6%9C%BA%E9%83%A8%E7%BD%B2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;logo &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; HTML &amp;amp; Markdown  iframe &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/settings/applications/new&#34;&gt;GitHub &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/wechat-server&#34;&gt;WeChat Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; API  API &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt; Docker &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -d --restart always -p 3000:3000 -v /home/ubuntu/data/one-api:/data justsong/one-api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-p 3000:3000&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;code&gt;3000&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;code&gt;/home/ubuntu/data/one-api&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nginx &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;server{&#xA;   server_name openai.justsong.cn;  # &#xA;   &#xA;   location / {&#xA;          client_max_body_size  64m;&#xA;          proxy_http_version 1.1;&#xA;          proxy_pass http://localhost:3000;  # &#xA;          proxy_set_header Host $host;&#xA;          proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $remote_addr;&#xA;          proxy_cache_bypass $http_upgrade;&#xA;          proxy_set_header Accept-Encoding gzip;&#xA;   }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; Let&#39;s Encrypt  certbot  HTTPS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Ubuntu  certbot&#xA;sudo snap install --classic certbot&#xA;sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot&#xA;#  &amp;amp;  Nginx &#xA;sudo certbot --nginx&#xA;# &#xA;#  Nginx&#xA;sudo service nginx restart&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/releases/latest&#34;&gt;GitHub Releases&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api.git&#xA;&#xA;# &#xA;cd one-api/web&#xA;npm install&#xA;npm run build&#xA;&#xA;# &#xA;cd ..&#xA;go mod download&#xA;go build -ldflags &#34;-s -w&#34; -o one-api&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;chmod u+x one-api&#xA;./one-api --port 3000 --log-dir ./logs&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;123456&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://iamazing.cn/page/how-to-deploy-a-website&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;code&gt;SESSION_SECRET&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;code&gt;SQL_DSN&lt;/code&gt; MySQL  SQLite&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;code&gt;SYNC_FREQUENCY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;code&gt;FRONTEND_BASE_URL&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/songquanpeng/one-api/main/#%E7%8E%AF%E5%A2%83%E5%8F%98%E9%87%8F&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt; API Key&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; One API  &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/introduction&#34;&gt;OpenAI API&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; ID &lt;code&gt;Authorization: Bearer ONE_API_KEY-CHANNEL_ID&lt;/code&gt;  ID&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;REDIS_CONN_STRING&lt;/code&gt; Redis  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;REDIS_CONN_STRING=redis://default:redispw@localhost:49153&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SESSION_SECRET&lt;/code&gt; cookie  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SESSION_SECRET=random_string&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SQL_DSN&lt;/code&gt; SQLite &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SQL_DSN=root:123456@tcp(localhost:3306)/one-api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;FRONTEND_BASE_URL&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;FRONTEND_BASE_URL=https://openai.justsong.cn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SYNC_FREQUENCY&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SYNC_FREQUENCY=60&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--port &amp;lt;port_number&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;:  &lt;code&gt;3000&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--port 3000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--log-dir &amp;lt;log_dir&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;:  &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--log-dir ./logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;--help&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.justsong.cn&#34;&gt;https://openai.justsong.cn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/39998050/233837954-ae6683aa-5c4f-429f-a949-6645a83c9490.png&#34; alt=&#34;channel&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/39998050/233837971-dab488b7-6d96-43af-b640-a168e8d1c9bf.png&#34; alt=&#34;token&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/songquanpeng/one-api/issues/97&#34;&gt;#97&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>