<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-28T01:37:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>LaniJ/invoice-dragon</title>
    <updated>2023-07-28T01:37:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-28:/LaniJ/invoice-dragon</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LaniJ/invoice-dragon" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Invoice Dragon&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Generate invoices and receipts simply by filling a form.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Invoice Dragon is a lightning-fast application that simplifies the process of generating professional Invoices and Receipts for your business needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply fill a form, select a template and generate your document! Visit the website at &lt;a href=&#34;https://invoicedragon.com&#34;&gt;https://invoicedragon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed and Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Invoice Dragon is designed to streamline the invoicing process, ensuring that you can create invoices quickly and efficiently. It focuses solely on generating invoices in the most time-effective manner.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed and Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Invoice Dragon is time efficient. You only need to fill your details into a form, and we automate the rest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customization Options:&lt;/strong&gt; Offers 4 different templates to choose from. More templates coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export your invoices as PDF:&lt;/strong&gt; Easily share invoices with clients and colleagues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start using Invoice Dragon, simply visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.invoicedragon.com&#34;&gt;Invoice Dragon.com&lt;/a&gt; . You can begin generating invoices immediately.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why did I build this?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years I&#39;ve run a couple of businesses where I&#39;d typically have to make invoices and receipts. I&#39;ve recently found the process of creating and editing invoice templates to be quite cumbersome, particularly when I have to make invoices for a good number of clients. The process of editing and ensuring everything is as I want it to be usually takes up too much time. So I decided to build this app to ensure invoices and receipts can be built, reviewed and saved as PDF... all at lighting-fast speed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes please! Contributions are welcome! If you have any ideas, bug fixes, or enhancements, feel free to submit a PR :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Invoice Dragon is a free software application released under the MIT License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for choosing Invoice Dragon! We hope this application simplifies your invoicing process and saves you valuable time. If you have any further questions or need assistance, please don&#39;t hesitate to reach out. Happy invoicing!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>