<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-22T01:38:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T01:38:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-22:/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Completely revolutionizes the Spotify Lyrics Experience by introducing Live Lyrics, Dynamic Backgrounds, and Immersive Views&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Beautiful Lyrics&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟 Starring the project helps this extension get seen by more people - which means more Beautiful Lyrics!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics&#34; alt=&#34;Github Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;Github Stars badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics/main/previews/thumbnail.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Thumbnail&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Completely REVAMPS the Spotify Lyrics Experience&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The background has been given a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic&lt;/em&gt; Color Background&lt;/strong&gt; that blends through the colors of the Cover-Art beautifully.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lyrics have also been completely revamped to provide an entirely new and better Lyrics experience!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;Cinema and Page Lyric Views&lt;/strong&gt; have been added to replace Spotifys own versions! &lt;strong&gt;Page view&lt;/strong&gt; replaces the main-page and &lt;strong&gt;Cinema view&lt;/strong&gt; gives you an &lt;strong&gt;immersive Lyrics experience&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you know &lt;em&gt;Spotify doesn&#39;t give its fullscreen mode to non-premium users&lt;/em&gt;? With Beautiful Lyrics &lt;strong&gt;EVERYBODY&lt;/strong&gt; gets an extremely beautiful &lt;strong&gt;Fullscreen Mode&lt;/strong&gt; with all the great features that the other views give!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re a fan of &lt;strong&gt;Chinese, Japanese, or Korean songs&lt;/strong&gt; but want to see the lyrics phonetically spelled than just toggle the &lt;strong&gt;Romanization&lt;/strong&gt; feature! The toggle is &lt;em&gt;per supported language&lt;/em&gt; so you can &lt;strong&gt;pick and choose which ones are romanized&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Never worry about Updating ever! &lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Lyrics is ALWAYS Up-to-Date because it Auto-Updates as &lt;em&gt;SOON&lt;/em&gt; as an update is available!&lt;/strong&gt; This means that if you make an issue/suggestion - it could be added and working for you (and everyone else) minutes later!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;None of the Lyrics are Showing Up/The visuals are off - what do I do?&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you aren&#39;t using a theme follow these steps: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Make sure that your Spicetify AND Spotify are updated to the most recent versions. Update Spicetify using these &lt;a href=&#34;https://spicetify.app/docs/getting-started/#updating&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;. You can update Spotify IF - when you click your Profile Picture - there is an option to do so: usually there is a little blue circle on your profile-picture indicating that you can update.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If this still doesn&#39;t work - try reinstalling Spotify. &lt;em&gt;MAKE SURE&lt;/em&gt; that you are &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; using the Windows Store version as this version is &lt;strong&gt;known to cause issues&lt;/strong&gt;. Download Spotify from the Spotify website directly and run the installation from there.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If you are on the latest version of the extension and none of this fixes it than it must be an issue with Beautiful-Lyrics: so make an issue on GitHub! You can find a button to do that at the &lt;strong&gt;bottom&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you are using a theme: then make an issue on GitHub that has a title similar to this &#34;Theme THEME_NAME Issues&#34;. Make sure to &lt;strong&gt;include a screenshot of what is specifically wrong&lt;/strong&gt; and also - again - &lt;strong&gt;leave the name of the theme you are using&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Usually&lt;/em&gt; these will be fixed very quickly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have the extension but not the Right Side-Card! How do I get it?&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The right side-card is not a part of the extension - it&#39;s actually a built-in Spotify feature they haven&#39;t released! This is how you enable it: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Click your Profile Picture and click the &#34;Expiremental Features&#34; tab&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Type into the search bar &#34;&lt;strong&gt;side&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Click the checkmark for: &#xA;      &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;       &lt;li&gt;&#34;&lt;strong&gt;Enable the view on the right sidebar&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;       &lt;li&gt;&#34;&lt;strong&gt;Extract background color based on artwork images&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;       &lt;li&gt;&#34;&lt;strong&gt;Enable Panel Size Coordination&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;      &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you don&#39;t see any of the items listed above when you search &#34;side&#34; &lt;strong&gt;reinstall Spotify using the instructions above&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The extension isn&#39;t working at all!&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you are in the country of Egypt (or any country that puts restrictions on popular sites) and you are not using a VPN it&#39;s possible that Spicetify is being blocked from getting the extensions and running them. You&#39;ll notice this for other extensions as well. Your best bet in this scenario is to simply download the extension and install it locally. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If you want to install it locally - all you need to do is go to the dist directory on the website and to the javascript file located in it. Copy the code there and create a new file somewhere on your computer and paste the code in it. Then follow these steps on how to actually use/install it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://spicetify.app/docs/advanced-usage/extensions&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Have an issue/idea? Go ahead and send them!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/surfbryce/beautiful-lyrics/bug&#34; alt=&#34;Github Bug badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>timpaul/form-extractor-prototype</title>
    <updated>2024-04-22T01:38:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-22:/timpaul/form-extractor-prototype</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/timpaul/form-extractor-prototype" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Form Extractor Prototype&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool extracts the structure from an image of a form.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://claude.ai&#34;&gt;Claude 3 LLM&lt;/a&gt; model by Anthropic.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A single extraction of an A4 form costs about 10p.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It replicates the form structue in JSON, following the schema used by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.forms.service.gov.uk/&#34;&gt;GOV.UK Forms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It then uses that to generate a multi-page web form in the GOV.UK style.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Run locally&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll need an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/api&#34;&gt;Anthropic API key&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add the key as a local environment variable called ANTHROPIC_API_KEY.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the app locally with &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start the app with &lt;code&gt;npm start&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;ll be available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current limitations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;it can only process images of forms, not documents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;it only knows about certain kinds of question types&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;you can&#39;t provide your own API key via the UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;you can&#39;t browse previous form extractions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;like a lot of Gen AI, it can be unpredictable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This is a prototype and I am not a developer ;-).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main UI is in &lt;code&gt;app/views/index.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional CSS styles are in &lt;code&gt;public/assets/style.css&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The form in &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; is intercepted by the script in &lt;code&gt;public/assets/scripts.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It sends the image at the URL provided by the user to the Claude API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It does this via the &#39;SendToClaude&#39; function in &lt;code&gt;server.js&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The function makes use of the &#39;tools&#39; feature of Claude.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That allows you to specify a JSON schema that you&#39;d like it&#39;s response to conform to.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The results are saved as files in subfolders in &lt;code&gt;app/views/results&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those files are then loaded by &lt;code&gt;scripts.js&lt;/code&gt; into iframes in &lt;code&gt;app/views/index.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;To do&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;switch from saving files to better use of routes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;let users add an API key via the UI, so I can host the app somewhere&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;add more question types - eg. radio and checkbox lists&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>