<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-05-03T01:32:19Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ubuntu/gnome-shell-extension-appindicator</title>
    <updated>2025-05-03T01:32:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-05-03:/ubuntu/gnome-shell-extension-appindicator</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ubuntu/gnome-shell-extension-appindicator" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adds KStatusNotifierItem support to the Shell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AppIndicator/KStatusNotifierItem support for GNOME Shell&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This extension integrates Ubuntu AppIndicators and KStatusNotifierItems (KDE&#39;s blessed successor of the systray) into GNOME Shell. Including support for legacy tray icons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/615/appindicator-support/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/andyholmes/gnome-shell-extensions-badge/master/get-it-on-ego.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show indicator icons in the panel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reveal indicator menus upon click.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Double clicking an icon will activate the application window (if implemented by the indicator).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Legacy tray icons&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Middle mouse click an icon to send a &#39;SecondaryActivate&#39; event to the application. Support needs to be implemented in the application. &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/unity/+bug/812933&#34;&gt;Info 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.ubuntu.com/api/devel/ubuntu-13.10/c/AppIndicator3-0.1.html&#34;&gt;Info 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Missing features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tooltips: Not implemented in &lt;code&gt;libappindicator&lt;/code&gt; nor in Unity and I&#39;ve yet to see any indicator using it for anything relevant (KDE ones maybe?). Also, the GNOME designers decided not to have tooltips in the shell and I&#39;d like to honor that decision.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ClassicMenu Indicator takes ages to load and has been reported to freeze the shell forever. This is probably caused by the insane amount of embedded PNG icons. Try at your own risk.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normal users are recommended to get the extension from &lt;a href=&#34;https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/615/appindicator-support/&#34;&gt;extensions.gnome.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can check out a version from git, compile the language files, and symlink &lt;code&gt;~/.local/share/gnome-shell/extensions/appindicatorsupport@rgcjonas.gmail.com&lt;/code&gt; to your clone:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/ubuntu/gnome-shell-extension-appindicator.git&#xA;meson gnome-shell-extension-appindicator /tmp/g-s-appindicators-build&#xA;ninja -C /tmp/g-s-appindicators-build install&#xA;gnome-extensions enable appindicatorsupport@rgcjonas.gmail.com&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Under X11, you may need to restart GNOME Shell (&lt;kbd&gt;Alt&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;F2&lt;/kbd&gt;, &lt;kbd&gt;r&lt;/kbd&gt;, &lt;kbd&gt;⏎&lt;/kbd&gt;) after that. Under Wayland you need to logout and login again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Applications dependencies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many applications support indicators via &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/libappindicator&#34;&gt;libappindicator&lt;/a&gt;, (that is quite often dynamically loaded, as it happens in Electron apps), so without having this library installed in your system no icon will be shown.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Guidelines for bug reports&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this extension is not completely bug free and will probably never be. In order to successfully resolve remaining issues, you need to provide some data:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your distribution, Shell version and extension version (something like &#34;latest git&#34; or &#34;latest from extensions.gnome.org&#34; is sufficient).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The indicator that caused the bug (if applicable).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Instructions how to reproduce it. &lt;strong&gt;This is the single most important point&lt;/strong&gt;. Bugs which &lt;a href=&#34;http://xkcd.com/583/&#34;&gt;cannot be reproduced&lt;/a&gt; cannot be fixed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bug reports which do not provide the necessary information may be closed as &#34;invalid&#34; without prior notice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release process&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section serves as reminder for the current maintainer and as instruction set for an eventual sucessor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The maintainer decides when to release a new version.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Versions are tagged (and signed). Version numbers sould be kept in sync with the versions submitted to &lt;code&gt;extensions.gnome.org&lt;/code&gt;. This implies that version numbers are integers which will be incremented with each release.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The maintainer will tag a new version, update the meson version and generate a zip file using &lt;code&gt;ninja -C &amp;lt;build-dir&amp;gt; zip-file&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The zip file will be tested to ensure that nothing was missed when packaging it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Only if it passed, it is uploaded to &lt;code&gt;extensions.gnome.org&lt;/code&gt; and the tag is pushed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This release process has been in place since v41.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>