<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-07T01:32:38Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol</title>
    <updated>2025-06-07T01:32:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-07:/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🏝️ A CLI tool to replace and automate your daily web browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Beachpatrol: Browser&#39;s End-user Automation CLI Hub. Potentialize All Tasks Regarding Online Life.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/assets/88276600/49fbdf4f-eeec-42f8-a0aa-dd1c1c6c1617&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Essential software should be fully automatable. Web browsers aren&#39;t. Let&#39;s change that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beachpatrol is a CLI tool to replace and automate your everyday web browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/assets/88276600/bc3bf9e8-28e2-48ef-a1f4-8754b4918916&#34;&gt;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/assets/88276600/bc3bf9e8-28e2-48ef-a1f4-8754b4918916&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt; to launch a Chromium or Firefox browser which can be controlled externally through &lt;a href=&#34;https://playwright.dev/&#34;&gt;Playwright&lt;/a&gt; scripts. You can use it as your daily driver; it works like a regular browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use also &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol --profile &amp;lt;profile-name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to launch a specific profile, or &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol --incognito&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To automate it, create a custom Playwright script in the &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol/commands&lt;/code&gt; folder. Then, run &lt;code&gt;beachmsg &amp;lt;script-name&amp;gt; [&amp;lt;argument&amp;gt;...]&lt;/code&gt;. It will run your script by default on the currently focused tab, but you can use the Playwright API to move to an existing tab, open a new one, or use a headless tab instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t want to go back and forth to the CLI to automate your browser, you can install the &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol-browser-extension&lt;/code&gt;. Its UI allows you to select a command and call it with arguments. It will call &lt;code&gt;beachmsg&lt;/code&gt; itself through the browser extension&#39;s Native Messaging feature. Also, the UI will highlight commands which are meant to run on the current URL, will provide GUI elements for common situations (such as pagination and dropdowns), and will support hotkeys:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/assets/88276600/751aec3f-284d-4563-ac0f-09bfa52034e2&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What can you automate with Beachpatrol? The sky is the limit:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check your email.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check your bank transactions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download a file from a website.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dump the text from the current tab into a file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fill an online form.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check for messages in your social media or work communication platform.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integrate with your OS: Add browser task to your Bash/Python scripts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All of this right there on your everyday browser!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linux (Wayland or X11) or macOS &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Windows support is WIP. You can try &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/pull/4&#34;&gt;this branch&lt;/a&gt; which should be working properly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Node.js and NPM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chromium or Firefox (installed automatically by Playwright)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repo: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Move to the folder: &lt;code&gt;cd beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; to install dependencies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; to install symlinks to the executables (in &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt; by default, which should be in your &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Launch a browser with &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optionally launch it in the background with &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol &amp;amp;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use it as your regular browser. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Install browser extensions if you want.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you close it. Run &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt; again and you should still be logged-in to all your sites.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you want a different profile, use &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol --profile new-profile-name&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Note: Due to a Chromium&#39;s limitation, it is not possible to use the in-browser&#39;s profile features to switch profiles. However, this might be fixed in the future.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;beachmsg smoke-test&lt;/code&gt; to run the pre-installed test command, which performs the classic &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.selenium.dev/documentation/webdriver/getting_started/first_script/&#34;&gt;Selenium smoke test&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If it reads &#34;Form submitted&#34;, it worked correctly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Now create your own automation scripts!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Technical details&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt; contains a customized Playwright script to launch your browser. It passes arguments which closely recreate the experience of using a non-automated browser. For example, it does not set a fixed viewport (which is, otherwise, a sensible default for Playwright&#39;s main use-case of automated testing.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beachpatrol also installs and loads the packages &lt;code&gt;patchright&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;playwright-extra&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;puppeteer-extra-plugin-stealth&lt;/code&gt;. This is needed to hide the fact that the browser is automated, which in turn is needed for basic features such as Google Sign-in.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the above packages are tangentially related to a cat-and-mouse game between web-scrapers and web-masters. As such, they might stop working at any time. Beachpatrol guarantees to find new automation-hiding techniques if that happens. Beachpatrol also encourages users to respect every website&#39;s terms and conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;patchright&lt;/code&gt; is currently one of the best tools for this task. However, it doesn&#39;t support Firefox. We use &lt;code&gt;puppeteer-extra-plugin-stealth&lt;/code&gt; for Firefox, which might encounter some issues such as Cloudflare&#39;s false positives, and extra Google captchas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the browser is launched, it listens on a UNIX socket, &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol.sock&lt;/code&gt;, for messages by &lt;code&gt;beachmsg&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;Usage: beachpatrol [--profile &amp;lt;profile_name&amp;gt;] [--incognito] [--headless]&#xA;&#xA;Launches a browser with the specified profile.&#xA;Opens a socket to listen for commands. Commands can be sent with&#xA;the &#39;beachmsg&#39; command.&#xA;&#xA;Options:&#xA;  --profile &amp;lt;profile_name&amp;gt;  Use the specified profile. Default: default&#xA;  --browser &amp;lt;browser_name&amp;gt;  Use the specified browser. Default: chromium&#xA;      Supported browsers: chromium, firefox&#xA;  --incognito               Launch browser in incognito mode&#xA;  --headless                Launch browser in headless mode&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;Usage: beachmsg &amp;lt;command&amp;gt; [&amp;lt;arg&amp;gt;...]&#xA;&#xA;Send commands to beachpatrol. The provided command must exist&#xA;in the commands directory of beachpatrol.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;F.A.Q.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Isn&#39;t the claim that web browsers aren&#39;t automatable a bit far-fetched?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we say that web browsers aren&#39;t automatable, we&#39;re thinking more along the lines of the depth of automation available with tools like Bash, Vim or Emacs (where virtually every interaction can be scripted and interwoven into custom workflows without much resistance.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, we acknowledge there are existing ways to automate browser tasks like autofill, mouse and keyboard macros, bookmarklets, extensions, and of course various tools like Playwright.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beachpatrol aspires to bring a new spin to the state-of-the-art, re-imagining automation tools not as a one-time task, but integrated into your daily browser. Just as your favorite shell or extendable text editor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short, our aim is to take existing automation tools (currently designed for testing or scraping) and tweak them for everyday browsing, while also providing a UI which is both simple and power-user friendly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;But what’s the point? Isn’t Beachpatrol just a wrapper around a Playwright browser?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;True, but it offers several value-added features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automation Detection Evasion&lt;/strong&gt;: Beachpatrol carefully selects Playwright options and plugins to mirror the activity of a regular browser, helping to avoid detection mechanisms that websites use to identify and block automated browsers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client/Server Architecture&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol&lt;/code&gt; launches a browser and listens on a socket. The separate client &lt;code&gt;beachmsg&lt;/code&gt; can then be used to transmit Playwright commands to the controlled browser. This separation allows for greater flexibility and integration with other tools and scripts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browser Extension&lt;/strong&gt;: An accompanying browser extension is designed to also communicate with the socket and send commands. The extension provides a user-friendly graphical interface and contextual tools.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why Playwright instead of Selenium?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initial browser launch benchmarks suggested us to prioritize Playwright.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Browser&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Launch time&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Playwright Chrome&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;1.7s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Selenium Node Chrome&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;1.8s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Selenium Java Chrome&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;4s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Playwright Firefox&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;4.3s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Selenium Java Firefox&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;6s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Selenium Node Firefox&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;9s&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why JavaScript/Node.js instead of Python?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Python is a popular language for web automation, we decided for JavaScript to enable code sharing with the browser extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why use an external automation tool (Playwright) instead of a browser extension?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar functionality can indeed be achieved with Userscript managers, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/violentmonkey/violentmonkey&#34;&gt;Violentmonkey&lt;/a&gt; browser extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;But, while Beachpatrol allows us to control the browser from both the OS and a browser extension, our priority is the OS. Also, there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sitepoint.com/community/t/tampermonkey-access-local-files-and-commands/299771&#34;&gt;limitations&lt;/a&gt; on how much you can interact with the OS from a browser extension. Therefore, something like Playwright was the natural choice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, while controlling the browser from an extension is possible, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/develop/migrate/improve-security&#34;&gt;Manifest v3 removed the ability to execute third-party strings of code&lt;/a&gt;. Popular automation extensions like Greasemonkey and Tampermonkey could also be affected by Manifest v3. The alternative is to embed the code into the extension, but that would require re-bundling the extensions after every change. Other tricks do exist to make this approach work, and there is some hope for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/w3c/webextensions/issues/279&#34;&gt;future Manifest v3 solutions&lt;/a&gt;, but this path is certainly tricky.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is more likely that Selenium and related tools will continue to work in the foreseeable future given the business demand for traditional browser testing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How does Beachpatrol compare to bookmarklets for quick tasks?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bookmarklets are handy for executing scripts with a click, but they are limited to user-triggered actions and may not handle complex workflows, such as automation based on specific timing or interaction with operating system features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plus, there&#39;s a personal preference factor. For those who like to have finer control, keeping automation scripts within their file system feels cleaner and less bound to a particular browser ecosystem. However, we recognize that bookmarklets have their place and can be the preferred choice for many users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Writing Playwright scripts for every task takes too long.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.chrome.com/docs/devtools/recorder/reference&#34;&gt;Chromium DevDool&#39;s Recorder tab&lt;/a&gt; to record actions and export them as Puppeteer scripts, which use the same API as Playwright. Or, you can use the Playwright &lt;a href=&#34;https://playwright.dev/docs/codegen&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;codegen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, given Playwright&#39;s popularity, you can describe your task in natural language to an AI and ask for it as a Playwright script. With some practice, this should get you halfway to a working script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is in &lt;strong&gt;alpha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The API is subject to change.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Currently Linux and macOS are supported. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Windows support is WIP. You can try &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebastiancarlos/beachpatrol/pull/4&#34;&gt;this branch&lt;/a&gt; which should be working properly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Currently only Chromium and Firefox are supported.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The ability to run a command when a new URL matches a pattern will be added soon.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;beachpatrol-browser-extension&lt;/code&gt; is in early-testing and &lt;strong&gt;not publicly released.&lt;/strong&gt; It is expected to launch in a fully-functional state by the next release.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contributions welcome!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Due to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/playwright/issues/35415&#34;&gt;known limitation of Playwright&lt;/a&gt;, the in-browser download manager shows UUIDs for downloaded file names. However, the download functionality itself should work as expected: all downloaded files should correctly appear in to the expected folder with the originally suggested file name.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The state-of-the-art stealth plugins are currently only available for Chromium. Firefox users might encounter some issues such as Cloudflare&#39;s false positives, and extra Google captchas.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;You might also like&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/osnr/TabFS&#34;&gt;TabFS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/violentmonkey/violentmonkey&#34;&gt;Violentmonkey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MIT&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions of all kinds. If you have a suggestion or fix, please feel free to open an issue or pull request.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>