<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-06T01:38:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>bobangajicsm/react-portfolio-website</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T01:38:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-06:/bobangajicsm/react-portfolio-website</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/bobangajicsm/react-portfolio-website" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;YouTube Tutorial on how I built this portfolio =&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ESHaail1eGc&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/ESHaail1eGc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Getting Started with Create React App&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project was bootstrapped with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/create-react-app&#34;&gt;Create React App&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Available Scripts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the project directory, you can run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Runs the app in the development mode.&lt;br&gt; Open &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000&lt;/a&gt; to view it in your browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The page will reload when you make changes.&lt;br&gt; You may also see any lint errors in the console.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm test&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Launches the test runner in the interactive watch mode.&lt;br&gt; See the section about &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/running-tests&#34;&gt;running tests&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Builds the app for production to the &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;br&gt; It correctly bundles React in production mode and optimizes the build for the best performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The build is minified and the filenames include the hashes.&lt;br&gt; Your app is ready to be deployed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the section about &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/deployment&#34;&gt;deployment&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run eject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: this is a one-way operation. Once you &lt;code&gt;eject&lt;/code&gt;, you can&#39;t go back!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you aren&#39;t satisfied with the build tool and configuration choices, you can &lt;code&gt;eject&lt;/code&gt; at any time. This command will remove the single build dependency from your project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, it will copy all the configuration files and the transitive dependencies (webpack, Babel, ESLint, etc) right into your project so you have full control over them. All of the commands except &lt;code&gt;eject&lt;/code&gt; will still work, but they will point to the copied scripts so you can tweak them. At this point you&#39;re on your own.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You don&#39;t have to ever use &lt;code&gt;eject&lt;/code&gt;. The curated feature set is suitable for small and middle deployments, and you shouldn&#39;t feel obligated to use this feature. However we understand that this tool wouldn&#39;t be useful if you couldn&#39;t customize it when you are ready for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn More&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can learn more in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/getting-started&#34;&gt;Create React App documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn React, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/&#34;&gt;React documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Code Splitting&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/code-splitting&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/code-splitting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Analyzing the Bundle Size&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/analyzing-the-bundle-size&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/analyzing-the-bundle-size&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Making a Progressive Web App&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/making-a-progressive-web-app&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/making-a-progressive-web-app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Advanced Configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/advanced-configuration&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/advanced-configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Deployment&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/deployment&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm run build&lt;/code&gt; fails to minify&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section has moved here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/troubleshooting#npm-run-build-fails-to-minify&#34;&gt;https://facebook.github.io/create-react-app/docs/troubleshooting#npm-run-build-fails-to-minify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ayaka14732/ChatGPTAPIFree</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T01:38:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-06:/ayaka14732/ChatGPTAPIFree</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ayaka14732/ChatGPTAPIFree" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A simple and open-source proxy API that allows you to access OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT API for free!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ChatGPT API Free&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the ChatGPT API Free project, a simple and open-source proxy API that allows you to access OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT API for free.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023-03-04&lt;/strong&gt;: Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://freechatgpt.chat/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT Free App&lt;/a&gt;, an amazing open-source web application that allows you to interact with OpenAI&#39;s ChatGPT API for free. It is built on top of this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use ChatGPT API Free, simply send a POST request to the following endpoint:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://chatgpt-api.shn.hk/v1/&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, to generate a response to the prompt &#34;Hello, how are you?&#34; using the &lt;code&gt;gpt-3.5-turbo&lt;/code&gt; model, send the following &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;curl https://chatgpt-api.shn.hk/v1/ \&#xA;  -H &#39;Content-Type: application/json&#39; \&#xA;  -d &#39;{&#xA;  &#34;model&#34;: &#34;gpt-3.5-turbo&#34;,&#xA;  &#34;messages&#34;: [{&#34;role&#34;: &#34;user&#34;, &#34;content&#34;: &#34;Hello, how are you?&#34;}]&#xA;}&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can view the full API documentation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/api-reference/chat/create&#34;&gt;OpenAI official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT is a world-renowned conversational AI model developed by OpenAI, known for generating human-like responses to various prompts and queries. With its cutting-edge capabilities, ChatGPT is a valuable asset for chatbots, virtual assistants, and other natural language processing applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ChatGPT API is a powerful tool that allows developers to integrate the ChatGPT model into their own applications. However, to use this API, users need to have an OpenAI API key and pay for usage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT API Free believes that everyone should have access to the latest AI technology without the financial burden of paying for an API key. This open-source proxy API allows you to access the ChatGPT API without a key, promoting accessibility and innovation for all.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What does ChatGPT API Free do?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This simple proxy API acts as a bridge between you and the OpenAI ChatGPT API. You can send requests to the ChatGPT API Free endpoint using the same format as the original API. This proxy API then forwards the request to the OpenAI API with an API key provided by this project, and the response from the OpenAI API is returned to you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Significance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ChatGPT API Free project is a game-changer for the AI development community. With the proxy API, anyone can access the state-of-the-art ChatGPT model without needing a key. This accessibility fosters creativity, innovation, and collaboration among developers, and could potentially lead to groundbreaking advancements in AI technology.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, other successful projects such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://freechatgpt.chat/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT Free App&lt;/a&gt; build on top of this API, showing the vast potential of this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Privacy Statement&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project highly values privacy and is committed to safeguarding the privacy of its users. This project does not collect, record, or store any text entered by users or returned by the OpenAI server in any manner. This project does not provide any information to OpenAI or any third parties about the identity of API callers, including but not limited to IP addresses and user-agent strings. The source code of this project is available for inspection to verify this statement.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the OpenAI API does retain data for 30 days in accordance with its &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/docs/data-usage-policies&#34;&gt;data usage policies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Host Your Own Instance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to run your own instance of ChatGPT API Free, you can easily do so by following these steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup OpenAI&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create an OpenAI account (if you don&#39;t have one already)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Obtain an OpenAI API Key from &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys&#34;&gt;OpenAI API Keys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup Cloudflare&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a Cloudflare account (if you don&#39;t have one already)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a Cloudflare Worker named &#34;chatgpt-api&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally, you can add custom domains for your Cloudflare worker by following the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/workers/platform/triggers/custom-domains/#build-a-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Build a Custom Domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the KV page of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dash.cloudflare.com/?to=/:account/workers/kv/namespaces&#34;&gt;Workers dashboard&lt;/a&gt;, create a Workers KV named &#34;chatgpi-api&#34;, then record its Workers KV ID for later use&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the Cloudflare Worker, add an environment variable &lt;code&gt;API_KEYS&lt;/code&gt; using the dashboard, which should be a JSON list of strings that contains at least one OpenAI API Key. For more information on adding environment variables, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/workers/platform/environment-variables/#adding-environment-variables-via-the-dashboard&#34;&gt;Adding Environment Variables via the Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the Cloudflare Worker, add an environment variable &lt;code&gt;SECRET_KEY&lt;/code&gt; using the dashboard, which should be a long-enough random string&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a Cloudflare API token by following the instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.cloudflare.com/workers/wrangler/ci-cd/#create-a-cloudflare-api-token&#34;&gt;Create a Cloudflare API token&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup GitHub&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a GitHub account (if you don&#39;t have one already)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork this repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modify &lt;code&gt;wrangler.toml&lt;/code&gt;, change the &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;kv_namespaces&lt;/code&gt; to the Workers KV ID above&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In your forked repository, create an encrypted secret named &lt;code&gt;CF_API_TOKEN&lt;/code&gt;, which should contain your Cloudflare API token. For more information on creating encrypted secrets, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/actions/security-guides/encrypted-secrets#creating-encrypted-secrets-for-a-repository&#34;&gt;Creating Encrypted Secrets for a Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the Deploy action to deploy your changes to Cloudflare&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait for the action to complete and you&#39;re done! Share your API endpoint with others&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Improve this project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is always seeking ways to improve and welcomes feedback and contributions from its users. If you have any suggestions or ideas, please feel free to create an issue or submit a pull request on the GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sponsor me!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find ChatGPT API Free useful, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/ayaka14732&#34;&gt;sponsoring the author&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub to support ongoing development and maintenance. Your support would help her maintain this project and continue to make AI technology accessible for all. Thank you for your support!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>adrianhajdin/project_3D_developer_portfolio</title>
    <updated>2023-03-06T01:38:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-06:/adrianhajdin/project_3D_developer_portfolio</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/adrianhajdin/project_3D_developer_portfolio" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Build and Deploy a Fantastic 3D Portfolio Website with Three.js and React.js&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/9ykhLtM/Thumbnail.png&#34; alt=&#34;3D Portfolio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most impressive websites in the world use 3D graphics and animations to bring their content to life. Learn how to build your own ThreeJS 3D Developer Portfolio today!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you&#39;ll learn the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ThreeJS - a powerful 3D graphics library for rendering and animating the 3D model&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;React Three Fiber - a popular library for creating 3D graphics with ThreeJS in React&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TailwindCSS - a popular utility-first CSS styling framework&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Framer Motion - the most popular library used to bring your React website to life with animations You&#39;ll also learn how to:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Load, create and customize stunning 3D models and geometries with various lights, as well as understand the 3D world with a camera and positioning of an object in space.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make your code reusable and scalable using Higher Order Components (HOCs) and other industry-standard best practices&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Implement sending emails through a form on the website&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure responsiveness across all devices and improve your site&#39;s performance using Suspense and Preload.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Stay up to date with new projects&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;New major projects coming soon, subscribe to the mailing list to stay up to date &lt;a href=&#34;https://jsmastery.pro&#34;&gt;https://jsmastery.pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>