<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-14T01:28:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lulu5239/view-loggers</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T01:28:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-14:/lulu5239/view-loggers</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lulu5239/view-loggers" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Setting up&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vercel.com/new/clone?repository-url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Flulu5239%2Fview-loggers&amp;amp;env=WEBHOOK_URL&amp;amp;envDescription=Paste%20your%20Discord%2FGuilded%20Webhook%20URL&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vercel.com/button&#34; alt=&#34;Deploy with Vercel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make an account on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vercel.com/&#34;&gt;Vercel&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;code&gt;Deploy&lt;/code&gt; button above to create the project on Vercel;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a webhook and copy its URL;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Put your &lt;code&gt;WEBHOOK_URL&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;Enviroment Variables&lt;/code&gt; dropdown shown during the deployment: &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Zaid-maker/view-loggers/assets/53424436/b0f1dbb6-304c-4719-a4e6-2adbba8a67ba&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deploy the project (it takes around 40 seconds).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vercel should trigger the view-logger a few times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You won&#39;t need to edit the files to enter your webhook URL, because you should have already entered it at step 4. &lt;em&gt;If needed, you can still edit it in the project settings in Vercel, as explained &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lulu5239/view-loggers/issues/10#issuecomment-1995980025&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send on Discord or Guilded the link to your subdomain (it can be any page, you can choose a page to recognize the view-logger);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your webhook should send something whenever someone sees the view-logger. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Discord, view-loggers seems to not trigger on every platform, it does for the Android mobile app but not the browser version for example. You may also need a bit of spacing between the invisible image of the view-logger and the bottom of the conversation, by adding a reaction on your message for example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Guilded, view-loggers can only trigger once every 4 hours.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can hide the link by using Markdown (like &lt;code&gt;[.](https://viewlog.lublox.xyz)&lt;/code&gt;), but the invisible image has to be loaded/visible.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This feature has been available since June 2023 on &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/api/oauth2/authorize?client_id=760184483659251753&amp;amp;permissions=0&amp;amp;scope=applications.commands%20bot&#34;&gt;Lulu5239&#39;s bots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>obsidianmd/jsoncanvas</title>
    <updated>2024-03-14T01:28:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-14:/obsidianmd/jsoncanvas</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/obsidianmd/jsoncanvas" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open file format for infinite canvas data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;An open file format for infinite canvas data.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Infinite canvas tools are a way to view and organize information spatially, like a digital whiteboard. Infinite canvases encourage freedom and exploration, and have become a popular interface pattern across many apps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The JSON Canvas format was created to provide longevity, readability, interoperability, and extensibility to data created with infinite canvas apps. The format is designed to be easy to parse and give users &lt;a href=&#34;https://stephango.com/file-over-app&#34;&gt;ownership over their data&lt;/a&gt;. JSON Canvas files use the &lt;code&gt;.canvas&lt;/code&gt; extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;JSON Canvas was originally created for &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/blog/json-canvas/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. JSON Canvas can be implemented freely as an import, export, and storage format for any app or tool. This site, and all the resources associated with JSON Canvas are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/obsidianmd/jsoncanvas&#34;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt; under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>