<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-09-04T01:34:04Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>iam-veeramalla/observability-zero-to-hero</title>
    <updated>2024-09-04T01:34:04Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-09-04:/iam-veeramalla/observability-zero-to-hero</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/iam-veeramalla/observability-zero-to-hero" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[WIP]: Repo for learning observability&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;📚 7-Day Observability Tutorial Series&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the 5-Day Observability Tutorial Series! This repository contains the code and detailed explanations for setting up and understanding observability in Kubernetes using Prometheus, Grafana, Elasticsearch, Fluentbit, and Kibana.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📅 Overview of Each Day&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 1: Introduction to Observability&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Observability, Monitoring, Logging, and Tracing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The difference between Monitoring and Observability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Tools available for Monitoring and Observability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Comparison between monitoring and observing in Bare-Metal Servers vs. Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Understand the fundamental concepts of observability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Learn why monitoring and observability are crucial in modern IT environments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 2: Prometheus - Setting Up Monitoring&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Prometheus and its architecture.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Setup and configuration of Prometheus in an EKS cluster.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Installation of kube-prometheus-stack with Helm and integrating it with Grafana.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Basic queries and setup for monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Get hands-on experience with Prometheus and Grafana.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Learn to install and configure Prometheus on Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 3: Metrics and PromQL in Prometheus&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Understanding different types of metrics in Prometheus: Counter, Gauge, Histogram, and Summary.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to PromQL and basic querying techniques.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Aggregation and functions in PromQL to analyze metrics data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Master the Prometheus Query Language (PromQL) for querying and analyzing metrics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Understand how to work with different types of metrics in Prometheus.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 4: Instrumentation and Custom Metrics&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Instrumentation for adding monitoring capabilities to applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Writing custom metrics in a Node.js application using the &lt;code&gt;prom-client&lt;/code&gt; library.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dockerizing the application and deploying it on Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Setting up Alertmanager for alerting based on custom metrics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Learn how to instrument applications to expose custom metrics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Configure alerts in Alertmanager to monitor application performance.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 5: Logging with EFK Stack&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to logging in distributed systems and Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Setting up the EFK stack (Elasticsearch, Fluentbit, Kibana) on Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detailed setup and configuration for collecting and visualizing logs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Cleaning up the Kubernetes cluster and resources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Understand the importance of logging and how to set up&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day 6: Distributed Tracing with Jaeger&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concepts Covered&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Jaeger and its architecture for distributed tracing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Setting up Jaeger in a Kubernetes cluster using Helm.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Instrumenting services using OpenTelemetry to enable tracing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Viewing and analyzing traces in the Jaeger UI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Cleaning up the environment after setting up Jaeger.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Learning&lt;/strong&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Gain insights into distributed tracing and how it helps in debugging and performance optimization.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Learn how to set up and configure Jaeger for tracing in a microservices architecture.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>