<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-03T01:31:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>software-mansion/radon-ide</title>
    <updated>2024-10-03T01:31:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-03:/software-mansion/radon-ide</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/software-mansion/radon-ide" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;VSCode extension that turns your editor into a fully fledged IDE for React Native and Expo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Radon IDE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/14fd4413-c518-4ead-915a-2020c4f4f981&#34; alt=&#34;RadonIDE banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to Radon IDE Beta 🎉&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radon IDE is an extension for VSCode and Cursor that turns the code editor into a fully fledged IDE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;✨ What does it do&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radon IDE is a VSCode and Cursor extension that aims to streamline development of React Native and Expo applications. The current version supports developing on macOS for Android and iOS platforms with the current list of features available:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Managing iOS and Android simulator (for now only iPhone Pro and Pixel 7 skins are available)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically build and launch your project (keeping track of native or javascript updates automatically)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integrated debugger always available – when running the project you can set breakpoints in the editor and don&#39;t need to bother with any additional configuration to get your application to stop at those breakpoints&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Element inspector that jumps to component code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integrated console log output panel that links to file/line with the log statement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Preview package that allows for working on components in isolation (render single component instead of the whole app)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Expo Router integration with browser-like URL toolbar&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easy access to device settings for text size and light/dark mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;💽 Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For installation instructions head to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ide.swmansion.com/docs/installation&#34;&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;💻 Usage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://ide.swmansion.com/docs/usage&#34;&gt;USAGE&lt;/a&gt; guide on how to get started after installing the extension. You can also visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://ide.swmansion.com&#34;&gt;Radon IDE&lt;/a&gt; website where we highlight the most important features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For troubleshooting and guide on reporting issues head to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ide.swmansion.com/docs/troubleshooting&#34;&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;⚒️ Extension Development&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to develop the extension and contribute updates head to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ide.swmansion.com/docs/development&#34;&gt;DEVELOPMENT&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>