<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-19T01:31:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>fossology/fossology</title>
    <updated>2025-03-19T01:31:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-19:/fossology/fossology</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/fossology/fossology" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FOSSology is an open source license compliance software system and toolkit. As a toolkit you can run license, copyright and export control scans from the command line. As a system, a database and web ui are provided to give you a compliance workflow. License, copyright and export scanners are tools used in the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;FOSSology&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/fossology/fossology&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Gitpod-ready--to--code-blue?logo=gitpod&#34; alt=&#34;Gitpod ready-to-code&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fossology/fossology/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/fossology/fossology&#34; alt=&#34;GPL-2.0&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/2395&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/2395/badge&#34; alt=&#34;CII Best Practices&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveralls.io/github/fossology/fossology?branch=master&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/fossology/fossology/badge.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://join.slack.com/t/fossology/shared_invite/enQtNzI0OTEzMTk0MjYzLTYyZWQxNDc0N2JiZGU2YmI3YmI1NjE4NDVjOGYxMTVjNGY3Y2MzZmM1OGZmMWI5NTRjMzJlNjExZGU2N2I5NGY&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/slack-fossology-blue.svg?longCache=true&amp;amp;logo=slack&#34; alt=&#34;Slack Channel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/releases/latest&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/fossology/fossology&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub release (latest by date)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZGPJnQZVnEPQWxOuNamLpw&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/youtube-FOSSology-red.svg?&amp;amp;logo=youtube&amp;amp;link=https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZGPJnQZVnEPQWxOuNamLpw&#34; alt=&#34;YouTube Channel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.reuse.software/info/github.com/fossology/fossology&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.reuse.software/badge/github.com/fossology/fossology&#34; alt=&#34;REUSE status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology is an open source license compliance software system and toolkit. As a toolkit, you can run license, copyright, and export control scans from the command line. As a system, a database and web UI are provided to give you a compliance workflow. In one click you can generate an SPDX file or a ReadMe with all the copyrights notices from your software. FOSSology deduplication means that you can scan an entire distro, rescan a new version, and only the changed files will get rescanned. This is a big time saver for large projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fossology.org&#34;&gt;Check out Who Uses FOSSology!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology does not give legal advice. &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossology.org/&#34;&gt;https://fossology.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PHP versions 7.3 and later are supported to work for FOSSology. FOSSology requires Postgresql as the database server and apache httpd 2.6 as the web server. These and more dependencies are installed by &lt;code&gt;utils/fo-installdeps&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install Python dependencies, run &lt;code&gt;install/fo-install-pythondeps&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology should work with many Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/releases&lt;/a&gt; for source code download of the releases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For installation instructions see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/wiki/Install-from-Source&#34;&gt;Install from Source&lt;/a&gt; page in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/wiki&#34;&gt;Github Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Docker&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology comes with a Dockerfile allowing the containerized execution both as a single instance or in combination with an external PostgreSQL database. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; It is strongly recommended to use an external database for production use since the standalone image does not take care of data persistency.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A pre-built Docker image is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/r/fossology/fossology/&#34;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt; and can be run using the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;docker run -p 8081:80 fossology/fossology&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The docker image can then be used using http://IP_OF_DOCKER_HOST:8081/repo user fossy password fossy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to run Fossology with an external database container, you can use Docker Compose, via the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;docker-compose up&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker Compose is a tool that allows you to define and run multi-container applications using a YAML file. FOSSology provides a docker-compose.yml file that defines three services: scheduler, web, and db.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scheduler service runs the FOSSology scheduler daemon, which handles the analysis tasks. The web service runs the FOSSology web server, which provides the web interface. The db service runs a PostgreSQL database server, which stores the FOSSology data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;docker-compose up&lt;/code&gt; command starts all the three services at once.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FOSSology web service allows you to configure its database connection using some environment variables. These variables are defined in the docker-compose.yml file under the environment key.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSSOLOGY_DB_HOST:&lt;/strong&gt; Hostname of the PostgreSQL database server. An integrated PostgreSQL instance is used if not defined or set to &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSSOLOGY_DB_NAME:&lt;/strong&gt; Name of the PostgreSQL database. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;fossology&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSSOLOGY_DB_USER:&lt;/strong&gt; User to be used for PostgreSQL connection. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;fossy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOSSOLOGY_DB_PASSWORD:&lt;/strong&gt; Password to be used for PostgreSQL connection. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;fossy&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can change them if you want to use a different database server or credentials.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Vagrant&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology comes with a VagrantFile that can be used to create an isolated environment for FOSSology and its dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-requisites:&lt;/strong&gt; Vagrant &amp;gt;= 2.x and Virtualbox &amp;gt;= 5.2.x&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/fossology/fossology&#xA;cd fossology/&#xA;vagrant up&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The server must be ready at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8081/repo/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8081/repo/&lt;/a&gt;. The login credentials are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;user: fossy&#xA;pass: fossy&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Test Instance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For trying out FOSSology quickly, a test instance is also available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossology.osuosl.org/&#34;&gt;https://fossology.osuosl.org/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;This instance can be deleted or reinstalled at any time, thus it is not suitable for serving as your productive version&lt;/strong&gt;. The login credentials are as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Username: fossy&#xA;Password: fossy&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The test instance is not up to date with the latest release. The instance will reset every night at 2 am UTC and all the user uploaded data will be lost.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick dev prototype with GitPod.io&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology is ready to be coded on GitPod.io. To use it, you would need to setup an account. You can directly use the following button to launch the project on GitPod.io: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitpod.io/#https://github.com/fossology/fossology&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gitpod.io/button/open-in-gitpod.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Link to Gitpod&#34; title=&#34;Open in Gitpod&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once in, you should see 2 terminals, one running FOSSology scheduler and one running the installation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Handy scripts/aliases&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the ease of usability, following aliases/scripts have been defined and can be used:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;conffoss&lt;/code&gt;: This will reconfigure cmake with all variables&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;buildfoss&lt;/code&gt;: This will build the FOSSology using cmake&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;installfoss&lt;/code&gt;: This will install FOSSology&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fossrun&lt;/code&gt;: Run the FOSSology scheduler&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pg_stop&lt;/code&gt;: Stop PostgreSQL server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;pg_start&lt;/code&gt;: Start PostgreSQL server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are currently migrating our documentation to Github. At this stage, you can find general documentation at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fossology.org/get-started/basic-workflow/&#34;&gt;https://www.fossology.org/get-started/basic-workflow/&lt;/a&gt; and developer docs on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fossology/fossology/wiki&#34;&gt;Github Wiki&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://fossology.github.io/&#34;&gt;https://fossology.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mailing lists, FAQs, Release Notes, and other useful info are available by clicking the documentation tab on the project website. We encourage all users to join the mailing list and participate in discussions. There is also a #fossology IRC channel on the freenode IRC network if you&#39;d like to talk to other FOSSology users and developers. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fossology.org/about/contact/&#34;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We really like contributions in several forms, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fossology/fossology/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original FOSSology source code and associated documentation including these web pages are Copyright (C) 2007-2012 HP Development Company, L.P. In the past years, other contributors added source code and documentation to the project, see the NOTICES file or the referring files for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any modifications or additions to source code or documentation contributed to the FOSSology project are Copyright (C) the contributor, and should be noted as such in the comments section of the modified file(s).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSSology is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldrlegal.com/license/gnu-general-public-license-v2&#34;&gt;GPL-2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify&#xA;it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by&#xA;the Free Software Foundation; version 2 of the License&#xA;&#xA;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the&#xA;GNU General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along&#xA;with this program; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc.,&#xA;51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301 USA.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exception:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the FOSSology source code is licensed under the terms of the GNU General Public License version 2, with the following exceptions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;libfossdb and libfossrepo libraries are licensed under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License version 2.1, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tldrlegal.com/license/gnu-lesser-general-public-license-v2.1-(lgpl-2.1)&#34;&gt;LGPL-2.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or&#xA;modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either&#xA;version 2.1 of the License.&#xA;&#xA;This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU&#xA;Lesser General Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public&#xA;License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software&#xA;Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA&#xA;02110-1301  USA&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the LICENSE file included with this software for the full texts of these licenses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>