<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-11T01:32:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lowcoder-org/lowcoder</title>
    <updated>2025-06-11T01:32:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-11:/lowcoder-org/lowcoder</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lowcoder-org/lowcoder" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🔥 🔥 🔥 The Open Source Retool, Tooljet and Appsmith Alternative&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Lowcoder continues from the abandoned Openblocks project. For more information &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lowcoder-org/lowcoder/main/MANIFESTO.md&#34;&gt;read our manifesto&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1 style=&#34;border-bottom: none; margin-bottom: 0&#34;&gt;Lowcoder&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3 style=&#34;margin-top: 0&#34;&gt;This is the only Platform, which closes the gap between App Development, Website Development, interactive Slides/Presentations and Collaboration Tools!&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt; Create software applications (internal and customer-facing!) and Meeting/Collaboration tools for your Company and your Customers with minimal coding experience. &lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3 style=&#34;margin-top: 0&#34;&gt;We think, Lowcoder is simply better than Retool, Appsmith Tooljet, Outsystems or Mendix.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; --- &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🎥 Lowcoder Intro Video&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AQo0iFWUWiU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.youtube.com/vi/AQo0iFWUWiU/maxresdefault.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lowcoder Intro Video&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Click the image above to watch the video on YouTube&lt;/i&gt; 📺&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📢 Use Lowcoder in 3 steps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect to any data sources or APIs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build flexible and responsive UI with 120+ components and free layout / design possibilities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Share with colleagues and customers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💡 Why Lowcoder&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One platform for everything instead so many different softwares. (like Website Builders, CMS, CRM, POS, ERP, Dashboards &amp;amp; Data Story Visualization, Collaboration Tools).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s cumbersome to create a single app. You had to design user interfaces, write code in multiple languages and frameworks, and understand how all of that code works together.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NewGen Lowcode Platforms like Retool and others are great for their simplicity and flexibility - like Lowcoder too, but they can also be limited in different ways, especially when it comes to &#34;external&#34; applications for everyone - because their pricing focusses to internal apps and &#34;pay per User&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Lowcoder we did a step forward. More specifically, Lowcoder is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An all-in-one IDE to create internal or customer-facing (external) apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A place to create, build and share building blocks of web applications and whole websites.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The tool and community to support your business, and lower the cost and time to develop interactive applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The only platform to embed Lowcode Apps natively in Websites (no iFrame!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The only platform where you can build your own Meeting Tool - like Teams, Zoom or Google Meets, - just in the Lowcode way.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The only platform which has extensibility plugin architecture &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/search?q=lowcoder-comp&#34;&gt;Check Community Contributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🪄 Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual UI builder&lt;/strong&gt; with 120+ built-in components. Save 90% of time to build apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modules&lt;/strong&gt; for reusable (!) embedable component sets in the UI builder.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed Lowcoder Apps as native parts of any Website&lt;/strong&gt; instead of iFrame (!). &lt;a href=&#34;http://demo-lowcoder.42web.io/ecommerce/&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/lowcoder-extension/native-embed-sdk&#34;&gt;Docu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video Meeting Components&lt;/strong&gt; to create your own individual Web-Meeting tool.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query Library&lt;/strong&gt; for reusable data queries of your data sources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom components&lt;/strong&gt; to develop own components and use them in the UI builder.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Native Data connections&lt;/strong&gt; to PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, REST API, SMTP, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stream Data connections&lt;/strong&gt; to Websockets for realtime data updates &amp;amp; collaboration! &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/connect-your-data/data-sources-in-lowcoder/websocket-datasource&#34;&gt;Docu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JavaScript supported everywhere&lt;/strong&gt; to transform data, control components, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Role-based access control (RBAC)&lt;/strong&gt; for granular permission management. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/workspaces-and-teamwork/members-and-groups&#34;&gt;Docu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto-saved and restorable history&lt;/strong&gt; for release and version control.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App Themes and Theme Editor&lt;/strong&gt; to precisely align with your company&#39;s brand guidelines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self Hosting&lt;/strong&gt; to use Lowcoder in your internal company network, even behind the firewall. &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/setup-and-run/self-hosting&#34;&gt;Docu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free Community Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; to start within a minute and build your first Apps. &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.lowcoder.cloud&#34;&gt;Start here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🏆 Comparisons&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs Teams, Google Meets, Zoom&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;build a Meeting tool with peace in mind. Blue buttons - ok. Red corners or circle Videostream - ok too.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;embedd applications in your Video-Meetings, so attendees can enjoy collaborative &#34;anything&#34;. From shopping to working and gaming...&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs Powerapps&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;build a apps way faster than in Power Apps. Save up to 50&amp;amp; of the time and costs at least.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use self-hosting to keep all apps and data under your control for example at the own baremetals.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs Retool&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder is open-source. You don&#39;t need to worry about vendor lock-in or being stuck with an outdated version of the software.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In Lowcoder, developers can build truly responsive apps - not as cumbersome as the &#34;Desktop / Mobile switch&#34; in Retool&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder is free and you can contribute!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;With Lowcoder you can design better Apps. More Layout &amp;amp; Design Components as also better support for powerful Data &amp;amp; Admin Dashboards.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The EE Version of Lowcoder comes with a much better pricing model, so you have no &#34;per-user costs&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs Appsmith, Tooljet&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder has more components and richer configuration than Appsmith and Tooljet.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In Lowcoder, you can choose auto-height or fixed-height mode for your components, while Appsmith supports fixed-height mode only.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In Lowcoder, you can reuse common structures when building apps with modules and query library features.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs Mendix, Outsystems, Pega&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder is modern. The codebase is fresh and uses modern standards.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder Apps do not need a compile and deployment. Just publish and use. Within seconds!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder Apps can get embedded natively in websites and apps, even in mobile apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Lowcoder vs internal Tool platforms&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lowcoder supports internal tools like admin panels perfectly, but also customer-facing apps can get developed and published.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Lowcoder UI builder is straightforward and better to use than Bubble.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;App release cycles and updates can be done nearly daily without service downtimes for customers and users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;👐 Support and Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us or share them with our community. Our team is here ready to help. And we mean it... Day by day!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📮 Best way is to chat with us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/qMG9uTmAx2&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📑 Search for solutions in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🔎 Submit an issue here on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lowcoder-org/lowcoder/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💻 Deployment Options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deploy.stitch.tech/lowcoder/lowcoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/deploy_with-Stitch-%23E369F7?logo=amazonaws&amp;amp;color=%23E369F7&#34; alt=&#34;Deploy to AWS using Stitch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://elest.io/open-source/lowcoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Deploy_to-Elestio-%23E369F7?color=orange&#34; alt=&#34;Deploy to Elestio&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can access Lowcoder from &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.lowcoder.cloud/&#34;&gt;cloud-hosted version&lt;/a&gt; at any time, or use the following resources for self-host Lowcoder on different platforms:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/setup-and-run/self-hosting&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💪 Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Language support: If you have experience with a language that isn&#39;t currently supported by our product, send us a pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create and share components or demos: If you&#39;ve created something that might be useful to others, add the link here.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.lowcoder.cloud/lowcoder-documentation/lowcoder-extension/opensource-contribution&#34;&gt;Contributing guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special tanks goes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sjhoeksma&#34;&gt;@sjhoeksma&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mousheng&#34;&gt;@mousheng&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mat02&#34;&gt;@mat02&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jomedya&#34;&gt;@jomedya&lt;/a&gt; and many other contributors!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🥇 Sponsors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accelerate the growth of Lowcoder and unleash its potential with your Sponsorship – together, we&#39;re shaping the future of Lowcode for everyone! &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/lowcoder-org&#34;&gt;Be a Sponsor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like ... &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Darkjamin&#34;&gt;@Darkjamin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spacegoats-io&#34;&gt;@spacegoats-io&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Jomedya&#34;&gt;@Jomedya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CHSchuepfer&#34;&gt;@CHSchuepfer&lt;/a&gt;, Thank you very much!!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>