<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-13T01:31:34Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tc39/proposal-import-attributes</title>
    <updated>2024-10-13T01:31:34Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-13:/tc39/proposal-import-attributes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Proposal for syntax to import ES modules with assertions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Import Attributes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Champions: Sven Sauleau (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xtuc&#34;&gt;@xtuc&lt;/a&gt;), Daniel Ehrenberg (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/littledan&#34;&gt;@littledan&lt;/a&gt;), Myles Borins (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MylesBorins&#34;&gt;@MylesBorins&lt;/a&gt;), Dan Clark (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dandclark&#34;&gt;@dandclark&lt;/a&gt;), and Nicolò Ribaudo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicolo-ribaudo&#34;&gt;@nicolo-ribaudo&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Status: Stage 3&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;⚠️ The specification in this proposal might be out of date. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/ecma262/pull/3057&#34;&gt;tc39/ecma262#3057&lt;/a&gt; is the latest version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Some of the changes present in the current specification have not been presented to committee yet: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/142&#34;&gt;#142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please leave any feedback you have in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Import Attributes proposal, formerly known as Import Assertions, adds an inline syntax for module import statements to pass on more information alongside the module specifier. The initial application for such attributes will be to support additional types of modules in a common way across JavaScript environments, starting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/tc39/proposal-json-modules&#34;&gt;JSON modules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The syntax will be as follows (shown here is the proposed method for importing a JSON module):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;import json from &#34;./foo.json&#34; with { type: &#34;json&#34; };&#xA;import(&#34;foo.json&#34;, { with: { type: &#34;json&#34; } });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The specification of JSON modules was originally part of this proposal, but it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/master/meetings/2020-07/july-21.md#import-conditions-for-stage-3&#34;&gt;resolved&lt;/a&gt; during the July 2020 meeting to split JSON modules out into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/tc39/proposal-json-modules&#34;&gt;separate Stage 3 proposal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Standards-track JSON ES modules were &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/w3c/webcomponents/issues/770&#34;&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; to allow JavaScript modules to easily import JSON data files, similarly to how they are supported in many nonstandard JavaScript module systems. This idea quickly got broad support from web developers and browsers, and was merged into HTML, with an implementation for V8/Chromium created by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/w3c/webcomponents/issues/839&#34;&gt;an issue&lt;/a&gt;, Ryosuke Niwa (Apple) and Anne van Kesteren (Mozilla) proposed that security would be improved if some syntactic marker were required when importing JSON modules and similar module types which cannot execute code, to prevent a scenario where the responding server unexpectedly provides a different MIME type, causing code to be unexpectedly executed. The solution was to somehow indicate that a module was JSON, or in general, not to be executed, somewhere in addition to the MIME type.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some developers have the intuition that the file extension could be used to determine the module type, as it is in many existing non-standard module systems. However, it&#39;s a deep web architectural principle that the suffix of the URL (which you might think of as the &#34;file extension&#34; outside of the web) does not lead to semantics of how the page is interpreted. In practice, on the web, there is a widespread &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/master/content-type-vs-file-extension.md&#34;&gt;mismatch between file extension and the HTTP Content Type header&lt;/a&gt;. All of this sums up to it being infeasible to depend on file extensions/suffixes included in the module specifier to be the basis for this checking.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are other possible pieces of metadata which could be associated with modules, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/8&#34;&gt;#8&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-reflection/issues/18&#34;&gt;tc39/proposal-import-reflection#18&lt;/a&gt; for further discussion.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proposed ES module types that are blocked by this security concern, in addition to JSON modules, include &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/whatwg/html/pull/4898&#34;&gt;CSS modules&lt;/a&gt; and potentially &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/whatwg/html/pull/4505&#34;&gt;HTML modules&lt;/a&gt; if the HTML module proposal is restricted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/w3c/webcomponents/issues/805&#34;&gt;not allow script&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Rationale&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three places where this data could be provided:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;As part of the module specifier (e.g., as a pseudo-scheme) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Challenges: Adds complexity to URLs or other module specifier syntaxes, and risks being confusing to developers (further discussion: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/11&#34;&gt;#11&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;webpack supports this sort of construct (&lt;a href=&#34;https://webpack.js.org/concepts/loaders/#inline&#34;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt;). &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Demand from users for similar behavior in Parcel, with pushback from some maintainers (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/parcel-bundler/parcel/issues/3477&#34;&gt;#3477&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Separately, out of band (e.g., a separate resource file) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Challenges: How to load that resource file; what should the format be; unergonomic to have to jump between files during development (further discussion: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/13&#34;&gt;#13&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the JavaScript source text &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Challenges: Requires a change at the JavaScript language level (this proposal)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This proposal pursues the third option, as we expect it to lead to the best developer experience, and are hopeful that language design/standardization issues can be resolved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Proposed syntax&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Import attributes have to be made available in several different contexts. They use a key-value syntax is used preceded by the &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; keyword, with the key &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; used as an example indicating the module type. Such key-value syntax can be used in various different contexts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;import statements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ImportDeclaration would allow any arbitrary attributes after the &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; keyword.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; attribute could be used to indicate a module type, for example importing a JSON module with the following syntax.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;import json from &#34;./foo.json&#34; with { type: &#34;json&#34; };&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; syntax in the &lt;code&gt;ImportDeclaration&lt;/code&gt; statement uses curly braces, for the following reasons (as discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/5&#34;&gt;#5&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;JavaScript developers are already used to the Object literal syntax and since it allows a trailing comma copy/pasting attributes will be easy.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;it clearly indicates the end of the attributes list when splitting them across multiple lines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;re-export statements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similar to import statements, the ExportDeclaration, when re-exporting from another module, would allow any arbitrary attributes after the &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; keyword.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;export { val } from &#39;./foo.js&#39; with { type: &#34;javascript&#34; };&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;dynamic import()&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;import()&lt;/code&gt; pseudo-function would allow import attributes to be indicated in an options bag in the second argument.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;import(&#34;foo.json&#34;, { with: { type: &#34;json&#34; } })&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second parameter to &lt;code&gt;import()&lt;/code&gt; is an options bag, with the only option currently defined to be &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;: the value here is an object containing the import attributes. There are other proposals for entries to put in the options bag: for example, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-reflection&#34;&gt;Module Source Imports&lt;/a&gt; proposal introduces a &lt;code&gt;phase&lt;/code&gt; property.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Integration of modules into environments&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Host environments (e.g., the Web platform, Node.js) often provide various different ways of loading modules. The analogous string could be passed through these ways of loading other kinds of modules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Worker instantiation&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;new Worker(&#34;foo.wasm&#34;, { type: &#34;module&#34;, with: { type: &#34;webassembly&#34; } });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sidebar about WebAssembly module types and the web: it&#39;s still uncertain whether importing WebAssembly modules would need to be marked specially, or would be imported just like JavaScript. Further discussion in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/19&#34;&gt;#19&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;HTML&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although changes to HTML won&#39;t be specified by TC39, an idea here would be that each import attribute, preceded by &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;, becomes an HTML attribute which could be used in script tags.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&#34;foo.wasm&#34; type=&#34;module&#34; withtype=&#34;webassembly&#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(See the caveat about WebAssembly above.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;WebAssembly&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the context of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/webassembly/esm-integration&#34;&gt;WebAssembly/ESM integration proposal&lt;/a&gt;: for imports of other module types from within a WebAssembly module, this proposal would introduce a new custom section (named &lt;code&gt;importattributes&lt;/code&gt;) that will annotate with attributes each imported module (which is listed in the import section).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Proposed semantics and interoperability&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This proposal does not specify behavior for any particular attribute key or value. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-json-modules&#34;&gt;JSON modules proposal&lt;/a&gt; will specify that &lt;code&gt;type: &#34;json&#34;&lt;/code&gt; must be interpreted as a JSON module, and will specify common semantics for doing so. It is expected the &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; attribute will be leveraged to support additional module types in future TC39 proposals as well as by hosts. HTML and CSS modules are under consideration, and these may use similar explicit &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; syntax when imported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Attributes in addition than &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; may also be introduced for purposes not yet foreseen.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;JavaScript implementations are encouraged to reject attributes and type values which are not implemented in their environment (rather than ignoring them). This is to allow for maximal flexibility in the design space in the future--in particular, it enables new import attributes to be defined which change the interpretation of a module, without breaking backwards-compatibility.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why not out of band?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why not both? The champions of this proposal think that exploring both an in- and out of band solutions to various kinds of metadata. While we prefer in-band metadata for module types, we are happy to see the development of various out-of-band manifests of modules being proposed and implemented in certain JS environments:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WICG/import-maps&#34;&gt;import maps&lt;/a&gt; to map module specifiers to URLs/paths&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/api/policy.html&#34;&gt;Node.js policy files&lt;/a&gt;, e.g., to perform integrity checks on modules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This proposal does not exclude out-of-band metadata being used for module types. And it definitely doesn&#39;t argue that all metadata should be in-band. For example, integrity hashes simply don&#39;t work in-band, both because module circularities make them impossible to calculate, and because of the need for a &#34;cascading&#34; update when a deep dependency changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out-of-band solutions face certain downsides; these are not necessarily fatal, but are interesting to take into account when considering the solution space and making tradeoffs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By-hand authoring experience&lt;/strong&gt;: While an in-band solution is somewhat verbose, it is also more straightforward for developers to adopt when writing code without much tooling. For smaller projects developers do not need to create an extra file by hand.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tooling complexity for large projects&lt;/strong&gt;: For large project with many dependencies, developers will not have to worry about creating a large manifest by compiling the metadata of all of their dependencies. Module authors will also not have to worry about shipping a manifest in order for consumers to be able to run their modules.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance tradeoffs&lt;/strong&gt;: The experience in Node.js&#39;s experimental, out-of-band policy files is that they can carry significant startup cost, due to certain aspects of loading and parsing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How is common behavior ensured across JavaScript environments?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A central goal of this proposal is to share as much syntax and behavior across JavaScript environments as possible. To the same end, we also &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-json-modules&#34;&gt;propose&lt;/a&gt; a standardization of JSON modules to the extent that this is possible (omitting just the contents of the redundant type check, which necessarily differs between environments, in addition to the pre-existing host-defined parts such as interpreting the module specifier and fetching the module).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, at the same time, behavior of modules in general, and the set of module types specifically, is expected to differ across JavaScript environments. For example, WebAssembly, HTML and CSS modules may not make sense in certain minimal embedded JavaScript environments. We hope that environments can experiment and collaborate where it makes sense for them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We see the management of compatibility issues across environments as similar, independent of whether metadata is held in-band or out-of-band. An out of band solution would also suffer from the risk of inconsistent implementation or support across host environments if some kind of coordination does not occur.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The topic of attribute divergence is further discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/34&#34;&gt;#34&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How would this proposal work with caching?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Attributes are part of the module cache key and can affect how a module is loaded: the cache key is extended from &lt;em&gt;(referrer, specifier)&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;(referrer, specifier, attributes)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why not use more terse syntax to indicate module types, like &lt;code&gt;import json from &#34;./foo.json&#34; as &#34;json&#34;&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another option considered and not selected has been to use a single string as the attribute, indicating the type. This option is not selected due to its implication that any particular attribute is special; even though this proposal only specifies the &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; attribute, the intention is to be open to more attributes in the future. (discussion in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/12&#34;&gt;#12&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Should more than just strings be supported as attribute values?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We could permit import attributes to have more complex values than simply strings, for example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;import value from &#34;module&#34; with { attr: { key1: &#34;value1&#34;, key2: [1, 2, 3] } };&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would allow import attributes to scale to support a larger variety of metadata.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We propose to omit this generalization in the initial proposal, as a key/value list of strings already affords significant flexibility to start, but we&#39;re open to a follow-on proposal providing this kind of generalization.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What are you open to changing? When do we have to settle down on the details?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are planning to make descisions and reach consensus during specific stages of this proposal. Here&#39;s our plan.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;&lt;em&gt;Original plan before Stage 2 and Stage 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;h4&gt;Before stage 2&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;We have achieved consensus on the following core decisions as part of Stage 2, including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The attribute form; key-value or single string (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/12&#34;&gt;#12&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;// Not selected&#xA;import value from &#34;module&#34; as &#34;json&#34;;&#xA;&#xA;// Not selected&#xA;import value from &#34;module&#34; with type: &#34;json&#34;;&#xA;&#xA;// Proposal that was approved from Stage 2 to Stage 3 the first time&#xA;import value from &#34;module&#34; assert { type: &#34;json&#34; };&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA; &lt;h4&gt;Before stage 3&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;After Stage 2 and before Stage 3, we&#39;re open to settling on some less core details, such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Considering alternatives for the &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt; keywords (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/3&#34;&gt;#3&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;import value from &#34;module&#34; when { type: &#39;json&#39; };&#xA;import value from &#34;module&#34; given { type: &#39;json&#39; };&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;How dynamic import would accept import attributes:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;import(&#34;foo.wasm&#34;, { with: { type: &#34;webassembly&#34; } });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;For consistency the &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt; key is used for both dynamic and static imports.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;An alternative would be to remove the &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt; nesting in the object:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;import(&#34;foo.wasm&#34;, { type: &#34;webassembly&#34; });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;However, that&#39;s not possible with the &lt;code&gt;Worker&lt;/code&gt; API since it already uses an object with a &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; key as the second parameter. Which would make the APIs inconsistent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Before Stage 4&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The integration of import attributes into various host environments. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For example, in the Web Platform, how import attributes would be enabled when launching a worker (if that is supported in the initial version to be shipped on the Web) or included in a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mjs&#34;&gt;new Worker(&#34;foo.wasm&#34;, { type: &#34;module&#34;, with: { type: &#34;webassembly&#34; } });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Standardization here would consist of building consensus not just in TC39 but also in WHATWG HTML as well as the Node.js ESM effort and a general audit of semantic requirements across various host environments (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/10&#34;&gt;#10&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/24&#34;&gt;#24&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-import-attributes/issues/25&#34;&gt;#25&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2019-12&lt;/strong&gt;: The proposal, named &lt;em&gt;module attributes&lt;/em&gt; is approved for Stage 1 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2019-12/december-5.md#module-attributes-for-stage-1&#34;&gt;notes part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2019-12/december-5.md#module-attributes-continuation-of-earlier-discussion&#34;&gt;notes part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1pyRtuOjnaTV_wr3a7sOZEt3PVxrbhgy_JCXovm0Dklk&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;) to explore metadata for module imports, and to explore guarantees about modules with no code execution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020-06&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Module attributes&lt;/em&gt; advances to Stage 2 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2020-06/june-3.md#module-attributes-for-stage-2&#34;&gt;notes part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2020-06/june-4.md#continuation-module-attributes-for-stage-2&#34;&gt;notes part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1MOVBh0gw7-tqEx-maEvS2HsgwXd5X5pcwL80V67xCIg&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;), with consensus based on the restriction that import attributes cannot be part of the cache key in the modules map. The proposed syntax is &lt;code&gt;import { x } from &#34;./mod&#34; with type: &#34;json&#34;, something: &#34;else&#34;;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2020-09&lt;/strong&gt;: The proposal, renamed to &lt;em&gt;import assertions&lt;/em&gt;, advances to Stage 3 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2020-09/sept-22.md#import-assertions-for-stage-3&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1RuWMkNAatIZ6lhcdslD8cUD-zntioptqH1-hTbVlhzg&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;). The rename better describes the agreed assert-only semantics, and the keyword changes from &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt;. However, the proposal relaxes the caching restriction so that HTML can still include the module type as part of the cache key, while still respecting the &#34;spirit&#34; of the proposal.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2021-05&lt;/strong&gt;–&lt;strong&gt;2022-02&lt;/strong&gt;: The proposal, with the &lt;code&gt;import { x } from &#34;./mod&#34; assert { type: &#34;json&#34; };&lt;/code&gt; syntax, is implemented and shipped in Chrome, Node.js and Deno. They all support the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/proposal-json-modules&#34;&gt;JSON modules&lt;/a&gt; proposal.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023-01&lt;/strong&gt;: Due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/whatwg/html/issues/7233&#34;&gt;incompatibility&lt;/a&gt; with the semantics needed by HTML for non-JavaScript modules, specifically regarding HTTP fetching and CSPs, the proposal is demoted back to Stage 2 (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2023-01/jan-31.md#problems-with-import-assertions-for-module-types-and-a-possible-general-solution--downgrade-to-stage-2&#34;&gt;notes part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tc39/notes/raw/c7fa95d3f2d0af68eaba9d388d5f79f2e166a4cc/meetings/2023-01/feb-02.md#import-assertions&#34;&gt;notes part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1HbWhyo4tSnpv4vMZqCa2YQvi_mKdpDi4JWWBtSUQqQY&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;) to investigate a solution to the web platform&#39;s needs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2023-03&lt;/strong&gt;: The proposal is renamed to &lt;em&gt;Import attributes&lt;/em&gt; and moves back to Stage 3 (TODO: notes, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Abdr54Iflz_4sah2_yX2qS3K09qDJGV84qIZ6pHAqIk&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;). The restriction on the cache key is completely removed, and the keyword changes back from &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;import { x } from &#34;./mod&#34; with { type: &#34;json&#34; };&lt;/code&gt;. For compatibility with existing implementations, the &lt;code&gt;assert&lt;/code&gt; keyword will still be supported until it&#39;s safe to remove it, if it will ever be.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Specification&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tc39.es/proposal-import-attributes/&#34;&gt;Specification Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/whatwg/html/pull/5658&#34;&gt;Pull Request for HTML spec integration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>