<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-12-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>vishaltewatia/code</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-30:/vishaltewatia/code</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/vishaltewatia/code" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;code&lt;/h1&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>uiverse-io/galaxy</title>
    <updated>2023-12-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-30:/uiverse-io/galaxy</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/uiverse-io/galaxy" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🚀 3500+ UI elements! Community-made and free to use. Made with either CSS or Tailwind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/uiverse-io/.github/main/cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Galaxy&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;code&gt;galaxy&lt;/code&gt;, a collection of over 3000 unique UI elements from &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every single UI element you find in here is sourced from our main platform, &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt;. As designers and enthusiasts share their creations on our website, we automatically curate and upload them here for ease of access and implementation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Browsing the Collection&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While this repository provides an archive of all the UI elements, the best way to browse is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt;. There, you can search and interact with all the elements while having a visual overview.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interested in growing this universe of UI components? Contribution is simple:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create &amp;amp; Submit&lt;/strong&gt;: Craft your unique UI element and submit it to &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approval&lt;/strong&gt;: Once your submission is reviewed and approved on our platform, it will automatically be uploaded to this repo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;: Direct contributions or pull requests to this repository will be ignored. The &lt;code&gt;galaxy&lt;/code&gt; is exclusively managed through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt; platform to ensure consistency and quality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing and Attribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All UI elements in this repository are available under the &lt;strong&gt;MIT License&lt;/strong&gt;, granting you the freedom to use, modify, and distribute them as you please. However, while not mandatory, we deeply value and appreciate attribution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When implementing a UI element from this collection, kindly consider giving credit to both the original creator and &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiverse.io/&#34;&gt;Uiverse.io&lt;/a&gt;. This simple act promotes the ethos of sharing, acknowledges the designer&#39;s effort, and celebrates the community spirit.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>