<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-31T01:38:28Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>henryhu712/technote</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T01:38:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-31:/henryhu712/technote</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/henryhu712/technote" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;编程笔记&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Node.js 常用模块&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;模块名&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;功能&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;适用&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;url&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;axios&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;HTTP客户端&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;浏览器、Node&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/axios/axios&#34;&gt;https://github.com/axios/axios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;formiable&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;处理表单，尤其是文件&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Node&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>hexagonkt/codecv</title>
    <updated>2023-01-31T01:38:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-31:/hexagonkt/codecv</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hexagonkt/codecv" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Manage your resume as structured data: CV format specification and tools to manage CV documents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/master/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;CodeCV&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manage your resume as structured data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has two sides:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CV format specification and documentation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reference tool to cover the basis of CV maintenance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here you can see a &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/t4aOSJibuzs&#34;&gt;3 min quick demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤔 Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The format was developed and evolved with the simple requirement to store and maintain my own CV.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main driver for this development was to separate content from presentation. Also using open standards that prevented the need to keep documents updated upon new Word Processor versions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years my CV has become big and the need to split it in different files and provide different versions has arisen (i.e.: a brief version and a full one, one with partial education and other only with finished degrees, etc.). So a modular approach has been implemented to fulfill this requirement.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🎯 Goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Readable CVs in code form&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Leverage existing editors features (use a JSON schema version widely supported)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allow documents to be imported and exported easily from/to other sites&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create documents in a flexible way. Composing files to make your CV modular.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Not only state your career&#39;s details, but also record details of what happened (i.e.: why you quit a job, etc.). You can think of it as a professional diary&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Batteries included: provide a reference tool to manage and maintain CV documents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;♻️ Differences with other CV formats&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allow to compose CVs in a modular way (including different files to create profiles) creating different views from the data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It is field compatible with other formats as &lt;a href=&#34;https://jsonresume.org&#34;&gt;JSON Resume&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://eures.ec.europa.eu/index_en&#34;&gt;Eures&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getmanfred/mac&#34;&gt;Manfred MAC&lt;/a&gt; (import/export functionality pending)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📄 CV Format Schema&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CV JSON schema is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/master/cv.schema.json&#34;&gt;/cv.schema.json&lt;/a&gt;. The URL to use on the CVs will be: &lt;code&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;/cv.schema.json&lt;/code&gt;. Being &lt;code&gt;version&lt;/code&gt; the schema version (&lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; can be used to link to the latest published version).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The schema can be used to validate documents in different formats (YAML, JSON and TOML at the moment).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The format allows the use of the &lt;code&gt;$schema&lt;/code&gt; key to reference the schema URL (this key is used by some editors to attach a schema to a file).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some formats (YAML and TOML) allow the use of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix)&#34;&gt;&#39;shebang&#39;&lt;/a&gt; to make them &#34;executable&#34; and launch the CV server automatically upon execution. Check the examples for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🧰 Examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can check some CV examples (in different formats) on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/master/examples&#34;&gt;/examples&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some modular CVs definitions in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/master/examples/modular&#34;&gt;/examples/modular&lt;/a&gt; directory. These CV files use the &lt;code&gt;Resources&lt;/code&gt; key to include different files in different cv documents, allowing to have different documents with different data each one.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🎨 Templates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The templates are attached to documents with the &lt;code&gt;Templates&lt;/code&gt; key (each document can get a different template).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sample template is provided as an example and a reference to create different ones. The template engine used to render it is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pebbletemplates.io&#34;&gt;Pebble Template Engine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤖 Reference Tool&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compiling this project you will get an application with the following features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change a CV file data format (among JSON and YAML)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check the schema documentation in HTML&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Render a CV to a Web page (allowing it to be printed)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To compile this tool you will need a JDK 16+. After installing it, executing &lt;code&gt;gradlew build&lt;/code&gt; on the project root directory will create a binary on &lt;code&gt;/build/codecv/bin/codecv&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use the tool in CVs&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shebang_(Unix)&#34;&gt;shebangs&lt;/a&gt; you need to copy or link the binary to a directory in the &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt; variable. On Unix systems you can do so with (assuming &lt;code&gt;~/.local/bin&lt;/code&gt; is in the path): &lt;code&gt;ln -s &#34;$(pwd)/build/codecv/bin/codecv&#34; &#34;$HOME/.local/bin/cv&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🎚️️ Editor Settings&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;JSON schemas are assigned to files based on patterns registered on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.schemastore.org/json&#34;&gt;central repository&lt;/a&gt;. As the CodeCV format is not registered there yet, you may have to register it on your editor of choice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, some editors (most notably Visual Studio Code) support schema binding via the &lt;code&gt;$schema&lt;/code&gt; key on the documents, if your editor support this convention, you won&#39;t need to change its settings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤝 Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is Open Source under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hexagonkt/codecv/master/license.md&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;. If you want to propose an improvement, file a bug or resolve a usage doubt, you are absolutely encouraged to do so! Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hexagonkt/codecv/contribute&#34;&gt;contributing guide&lt;/a&gt; for details on how to proceed on each case.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to contribute a new feature on the tool or a change on the schema. You can also do so by creating an issue and filing a PR. Please read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hexagonkt/codecv/contribute&#34;&gt;contributing guide&lt;/a&gt; before doing so.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;❤️ Support the Project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to see more progress on this project, and see more developer targeted tools, spread the word on social networks! and don&#39;t forget to give it a ⭐!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be notified on updates or new tools developed within the Hexagon organization. Follow the Twitter account (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hexagon_kt&#34;&gt;@hexagon_tk&lt;/a&gt;) and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hexagonkt&#34;&gt;GitHub organization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your support!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>