<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-29T01:38:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>cure53/HTTPLeaks</title>
    <updated>2023-06-29T01:38:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-29:/cure53/HTTPLeaks</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cure53/HTTPLeaks" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HTTPLeaks - All possible ways, a website can leak HTTP requests&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HTTPLeaks&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project aims to enumerate all possible ways, a website can leak HTTP requests. In one single HTML file. See the file &lt;code&gt;leak.html&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cure53/HTTPLeaks/main/leak.html&#34;&gt;raw text version&lt;/a&gt;) in the root of this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is it for?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use this to test your browser for &lt;em&gt;CSP leaks&lt;/em&gt;, your web-mailer for &lt;em&gt;HTTP leaks&lt;/em&gt; and everything else that is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; supposed to send HTTP requests to where the sun won&#39;t shine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With &#34;HTTP Leak&#34;, we are essentially referring to a situation, where a certain combination of HTML elements and attributes cause a request to an external resource to be fired - when it should not. Think, for example, of the body of an HTML mail where a HTTP Leak would tell someone out there that you just read that mail. Not always bad - but almost never good.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or think about web proxies. Those tools try to show you a website from a different domain to offer what they call &#34;anonymity&#34;. Of course they have to also rewrite all HTML elements and attributes that fetch resources via HTTP (or alike) and if they forget something, the so called &#34;anonymity&#34; is gone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And, since no one really knows anymore what elements and attributes can request external resources, we decided to create this project to keep track on that.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;And now?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The HTML will be extended as soon as we learn about a new leak, pull requests with additional exotic sources for HTTP leaks are very welcome! Further welcome are ideas of how else this content could be presented (JSON, HTML, XML, ...).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hasegawayosuke&#34;&gt;@hasegawayosuke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/masa141421356&#34;&gt;@masa141421356&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mramydnei&#34;&gt;@mramydnei&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/avlidienbrunn&#34;&gt;@avlidienbrunn &lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/orenhafif&#34;&gt;@orenhafif&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/freddyb&#34;&gt;@freddyb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tehjh&#34;&gt;@tehjh&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/webtonull&#34;&gt;@webtonull&lt;/a&gt;, @intchloe, @Boldewyn and many others for adding content and smaller fixes here and there!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>duckduckgo/iOS</title>
    <updated>2023-06-29T01:38:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-29:/duckduckgo/iOS</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/duckduckgo/iOS" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo iOS Application&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;DuckDuckGo iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to engage the community in development!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;We are hiring!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo is growing fast and we continue to expand our fully distributed team. We embrace diverse perspectives, and seek out passionate, self-motivated people, committed to our shared vision of raising the standard of trust online. If you are a senior software engineer capable in either iOS or Android, visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/hiring/#open&#34;&gt;careers&lt;/a&gt; page to find out more about our openings!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Submodules&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use submodules, so you will need to bring them into the project in order to build and run it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;git submodule update --init --recursive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Developer details&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not part of the DuckDuckGo team, you should provide your Apple developer account id, app id, and group id prefix in an &lt;code&gt;ExternalDeveloper.xcconfig&lt;/code&gt; file. To do that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;cp Configuration/DuckDuckGoDeveloper.xcconfig Configuration/ExternalDeveloper.xcconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;Configuration/ExternalDeveloper.xcconfig&lt;/code&gt; and change the values of all fields&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clean and rebuild the project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use Swift Package Manager for dependency management, which shouldn&#39;t require any additional set up.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;SwiftLint&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/realm/SwiftLint&#34;&gt;SwifLint&lt;/a&gt; for enforcing Swift style and conventions, so you&#39;ll need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/realm/SwiftLint#installation&#34;&gt;install it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Debugging&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instruments&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have Custom Instruments tool to help visualize and track events that happen during runtime.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to run it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build a Debug version and install it on Simulator/Device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select Instruments target and run it on a Mac. A New instance of Instruments app will be run that has a grayed out icon indicating that it works in debug mode with custom instruments attached.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &#39;DDG Trace&#39; template or set up a custom one by importing &#39;DDG Timeline&#39; instrument from Library.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start recording.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.apple.com/instruments/developer/mac/current/&#34;&gt;Instruments Developer Help&lt;/a&gt; for reference how to create custom instruments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Terminology&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have taken steps to update our terminology and remove words with problematic racial connotations, most notably the change to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branches, &lt;code&gt;allow lists&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;blocklists&lt;/code&gt;. Closed issues or PRs may contain deprecated terminology that should not be used going forward.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/duckduckgo/iOS/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Discuss&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contact us at &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/feedback&#34;&gt;https://duckduckgo.com/feedback&lt;/a&gt; if you have feedback, questions or want to chat. You can also use the feedback form embedded within our Mobile App - to do so please navigate to Settings and select &#34;Send Feedback&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DuckDuckGo is distributed under the Apache 2.0 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/duckduckgo/ios/raw/master/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>