<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-28T01:33:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Shivraj-Chavan/DigitalAnalogCLock</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T01:33:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/Shivraj-Chavan/DigitalAnalogCLock</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Shivraj-Chavan/DigitalAnalogCLock" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T01:33:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repo for my &#39;Learning JavaScript Design Patterns&#39; book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gruntjs.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.gruntjs.com/builtwith.png&#34; alt=&#34;Built with Grunt&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns.png&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Learning JavaScript Design Patterns&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.github.com/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns/master/cover/cover.jpg&#34; width=&#34;350px&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the source code for Learning JavaScript Design Patterns. It is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-Share Alike 3.0 license. I hope you enjoy it, I hope it helps you learn, and I hope you&#39;ll support O&#39;Reilly and me by purchasing a print copy of the book at &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920025832.do&#34;&gt;O&#39;Reilly.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Design patterns are reusable solutions to commonly occurring problems in software development and are a very useful tool to have at your disposal. You can read the latest version &lt;a href=&#34;http://addyosmani.com/resources/essentialjsdesignpatterns/book/&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; for free at any time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Why is this book needed?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this book as I felt that patterns were an area a lot of new and intermediate JavaScript developers may not have had a chance to explore just yet and I&#39;m hopeful my book will encourage you to check them out as they can be quite powerful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing and Errata&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m always welcome to feedback on how the book can be improved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Pull requests&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help improve the project, please feel free to send over a pull request. Some useful notes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All changes should be made against the master branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The source of the book is currently in &lt;code&gt;book/index.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Atomic commits make it easier to review changes. If you can separate changes out in this form, it&#39;ll save us time when trying to land.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please review the version of the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://addyosmani.com/resources/essentialjsdesignpatterns/book/&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; before requesting a change. It is updated more frequently than the physical version of the book but we do bring changes back in every few months.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Building the project&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install dependencies : &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; Build the project: &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; Preview: &lt;code&gt;grunt serve&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Additional formats&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project is currently authored in HTML, however we do plan on introducing builds for other formats (PDF, ePub) shortly. In the mean time, official releases for other formats can be obtained via O&#39;Reilly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Translations&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get involved with translating this project to another language, please open up a new issue. O&#39;Reilly have a process for handling translations to ensure that they go through the same review process that the English version goes through.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, we&#39;ve successfully had the book translated to Japanese. You can find that version on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.co.jp/books/9784873116181/&#34;&gt;O&#39;Reilly Japan&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is released under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial- No Derivative Works 3.0 United States License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;What this means it that the project is free to read and use, but the license does not permit commercial use of the material (i.e you can freely print out the book for your own use, but you can&#39;t sell it). I&#39;m trying to best to publish all of my books in a free + purchased (if you would like to support these projects) form so I would greatly appreciate it if you would respect these terms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright Addy Osmani, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>vidio-boy/Eaglercraft1.8.8</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T01:33:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/vidio-boy/Eaglercraft1.8.8</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/vidio-boy/Eaglercraft1.8.8" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eaglercraft 1.8.8 javascript runtime. Multiplayer worlds available. Customizable profile, skins, settings, and controls. Game modes including creative, survival, peaceful, and more! Villages, mine shafts, dungeons, caves, ravines, many different biomes, and other things can spawn. The Nether and End are also available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Eaglercraft 1.8.8 Browser&lt;/h1&gt;  &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Eaglercraft 1.8.8 javascript runtime.&lt;/b&gt; Multiplayer worlds available. Customizable profile, skins, settings, and controls. Game modes including creative, survival, peaceful, and more! Villages, mine shafts, dungeons, caves, ravines, many different biomes, and other things can spawn. The Nether and End are also available. Commands are the same as the real Minecraft. &lt;b&gt;If you want to play singleplayer, you will have to download my Eaglercraft 1.5.2, as this version only has multiplayer.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;   &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to launch game in browser:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;1. Download the zip file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2. Open the zip in your files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;3. Find the eaglercraft.1.8.8.html file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;4. Open the file and let it load.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Servers&lt;/h1&gt; Go to &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1PhUJSb0ojMyhv1Fs8bmVqwANBkySOgdyfRinJto3xnE/edit&#34; &lt;a&gt;this doc&lt;/a&gt; to get &#xA;&lt;b&gt;a list of Multiplayer Server Adresses.&lt;/b&gt; I do not own it or edit it in any way. &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;IMPORTANT!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; When you create a new world, it will be a black screen, or you may have spawned underground. &lt;b&gt;ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS WAIT 1–5 MINUTES!&lt;/b&gt; It will fix on its own. It will also be laggy at first, but it will smooth out after 5–10 minutes. &lt;b&gt;Keep in mind that this is an old version of Minecraft and that not everything in the real current Minecraft will be avialable.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div&gt; &#xA; &lt;footer&gt;&#xA;  &lt;small&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/b&gt; I do not own Eaglercraft, and I am not associated with it in any way, this is just a way for people to access it fullscreen on browser.&lt;small&gt;&#xA;    &lt;footer&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&#xA; &lt;/footer&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>