<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-18T01:30:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>nuejs/www</title>
    <updated>2023-09-18T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-18:/nuejs/www</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/nuejs/www" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Content for nuejs.org&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Nue website&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the source code for &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nuejs.org&#34;&gt;nuejs.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The site is generated with &lt;strong&gt;Nuekit&lt;/strong&gt;, which is part of the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nuejs.org/ecosystem/&#34;&gt;Nue ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s currently developed in a private GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All content is written with &lt;strong&gt;Nuemark&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a Markdown dialect with Nue JS component support. Also developed privately ATM.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvements to content are highly welcome.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SpecterOps/TierZeroTable</title>
    <updated>2023-09-18T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-18:/SpecterOps/TierZeroTable</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SpecterOps/TierZeroTable" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About Table of AD and Azure assets and whether they belong to Tier Zero&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;TierZeroTable&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Table of AD and Azure assets and whether they belong to Tier Zero.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;View the table here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://specterops.github.io/TierZeroTable/&#34;&gt;https://specterops.github.io/TierZeroTable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Blog posts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://posts.specterops.io/what-is-tier-zero-part-1-e0da9b7cdfca&#34;&gt;What is Tier Zero - Part 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://posts.specterops.io/what-is-tier-zero-part-2-6e1d14fddcaf&#34;&gt;What is Tier Zero - Part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Webinars:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://specterops.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_hOwvqBQ3Q7-9dGS-urDj9w&#34;&gt;Defining the Undefined: What is Tier Zero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://specterops.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_aROefO96TZqgOUM2bqVE7A&#34;&gt;Defining the Undefined: What is Tier Zero Part II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER: The table does not include all Tier Zero assets yet.&lt;/strong&gt; We will add assets to the table throughout the webinar series. So if you think we are missing something, then you are completely right. But feel free to make a pull request or open an issue with the asset you think we should add. All contributions are appreciated. Also if you disagree on something in the table :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Table columns&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Name&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Common name of the asset.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Type&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Type of the asset.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD computer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD container&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD GPO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD group&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AD user&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Computer host&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DC group&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;IdP&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Identity Provider of the asset.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Active Directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Identification&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;How the asset can be identified. E.g., SID of AD object.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Description&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description of the asset, i.e., its purpose of existence. This will be copied from Microsoft documentation if available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Known Tier Zero compromise by default configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether a publicly known abuse technique exists that allows compromise of Tier Zero assets using this asset. The abuse technique must work in an environment with default configurations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a publicly known abuse technique exists it will be described in the &lt;em&gt;Reasoning&lt;/em&gt; column and links will be provided in the &lt;em&gt;External links&lt;/em&gt; column.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES - Takeover - A publicly known abuse technique to takeover one or more Tier Zero assets exists and works in environments with default configurations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES - Disruption - A publicly known abuse technique to disrupt the operations of Tier Zero assets exists and works in environments with default configurations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NO - No publicly known abuse technique to compromise Tier Zero assets in an environment with default configurations exists.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Known Tier Zero compromise by common (mis)configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether a publicly known abuse technique exists that allows compromise of Tier Zero assets using this asset, which is enabled do to a common non-default (mis)configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a publicly known abuse technique exists it will be described in the &lt;em&gt;Reasoning&lt;/em&gt; column and links will be provided in the &lt;em&gt;External links&lt;/em&gt; column.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES - Takeover - A publicly known abuse technique to takeover one or more Tier Zero assets exists and works in environments with a common non-default (mis)configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES - Disruption - A publicly known abuse technique to disrupt the operations of Tier Zero assets exists and works in environments with a common non-default (mis)configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NO - No publicly known abuse technique to compromise Tier Zero assets in an environment with common non-default (mis)configurations exists.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;N/A - Compromise by default - A publicly known abuse technique to compromise Tier Zero assets exists and works in environments with default configurations, hence it does not require any special configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Is Tier Zero&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the asset should be considered Tier Zero based on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JonasBK/TierZeroTable/tree/main#definition-of-tier-zero&#34;&gt;Definition of Tier Zero&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Reasoning&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The explanation of why the asset is/isn&#39;t Tier Zero, including an abuse summary and if the asset is a security dependency for Tier Zero.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Microsoft: Privileged access security roles&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether the asset is included in Microsoft&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/security/privileged-access-workstations/privileged-access-security-levels&#34;&gt;Privileged access security roles&lt;/a&gt; list.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;AdminSDHolder protected&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether the asset is part of the default &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-server/identity/ad-ds/plan/security-best-practices/appendix-c--protected-accounts-and-groups-in-active-directory&#34;&gt;Protected Accounts and Groups in Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;, which are protected with the AdminSDHolder security descriptor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;YES&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Not applicable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is Tier Zero episode&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In which episode of the &lt;em&gt;What is Tier Zero&lt;/em&gt; series was this asset discussed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;External links&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Links to documentation for the asset, abuse information, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>polarsys/b612</title>
    <updated>2023-09-18T01:30:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-18:/polarsys/b612</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/polarsys/b612" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eclipse B612&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PolarSys B612 font family&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;B612 is an highly legible open source font family designed and tested to be used on aircraft cockpit screens.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Main characteristics are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maximize the distance between the forms of the characters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Respect the primitives of the different letters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Harmonize the forms and their spacing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The genesis of PolarSys B612&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2010, Airbus initiated a research collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enac.fr&#34;&gt;ENAC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.univ-tlse3.fr/&#34;&gt;Université de Toulouse III&lt;/a&gt; on a prospective study to define and validate an “Aeronautical Font”: the challenge was to improve the display of information on the cockpit screens, in particular in terms of legibility and comfort of reading, and to optimize the overall homogeneity of the cockpit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2 years later, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.airbus.com&#34;&gt;Airbus&lt;/a&gt; came to find &lt;a href=&#34;https://intactile.com&#34;&gt;Intactile DESIGN&lt;/a&gt; to work on the design of the eight typographic variants of the font. This one, baptized B612 in reference to the imaginary asteroid of the aviator Saint‑Exupéry, benefited from a complete hinting on all the characters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Releasing a new version of the font&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update the version number in the font info of the source files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make a copy of the source files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the copies in Fontlab&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the merge intersection command on each file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generate the ttf files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the build script from the scripts folder to fix digital signature&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2012, AIRBUS (airbus-group.com). All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program and the accompanying materials are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v2.0 and Eclipse Distribution License v1.0 and the SIL Open Font License v1.1 which accompanies this distribution. The Eclipse Public License is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v20.html&#34;&gt;https://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v20.html&lt;/a&gt; and the Eclipse Distribution License is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eclipse.org/org/documents/edl-v10.php&#34;&gt;https://www.eclipse.org/org/documents/edl-v10.php&lt;/a&gt;. The SIL Open Font License v1.1 is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://scripts.sil.org/OFL&#34;&gt;https://scripts.sil.org/OFL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>