<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-08-08T01:30:37Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>DataDog/documentation</title>
    <updated>2024-08-08T01:30:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-08-08:/DataDog/documentation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/DataDog/documentation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The source for Datadog&#39;s documentation site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Documentation site for Datadog&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Datadog documentation repository. The markdown stored in this repo is published to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.datadoghq.com&#34;&gt;Datadog documentation site&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a static website generation tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute to the docs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are encouraged! If you notice something on one of the pages that needs an edit, open a pull request in this repo for the documentation team to review&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most pages on the documentation site feature an &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; button that sends you to the source file in this repo. You can make an edit straight from the GitHub website!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DataDog/documentation/master/static/images/edit_link.png&#34; alt=&#34;The edit button on a docs page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information on contributing, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/DataDog/documentation/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contribution guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Working on Docs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Datadog Staff&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Always branch off of master; never commit directly to master.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Name your branch &lt;code&gt;slack_username/branch_name&lt;/code&gt;. If you don&#39;t include the forward slash (&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;), the Gitlab pipeline won&#39;t run and you won&#39;t get a branch preview. Getting a branch preview makes it easier for us to check for any issues with your PR, such as broken links. Using a Slack username ensures you get build notifications in Slack.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Consult our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DataDog/documentation/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When you&#39;re ready to commit, create a new pull request to master from your branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use GitHub&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.blog/2019-02-14-introducing-draft-pull-requests/&#34;&gt;draft pull request&lt;/a&gt; feature and appropriate labels such as &#34;Do Not Merge&#34; or &#34;Work in Progress&#34; until your PR is ready to be merged and live on production.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;ve named your branch correctly, a GitHub bot posts a link to the docs preview website for your PR. After the preview build completes, you can use the link to preview your changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Running the build locally is optional. If you followed the branch naming conventions above, your pull request should generate a preview. For information on local builds, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datadoghq.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/docs4docs/pages/3960766866/Build+setup+guide&#34;&gt;Build setup guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Outside Contributors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the master branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Consult our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DataDog/documentation/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When you&#39;re ready to finalize your changes, commit them and make a pull request back to &lt;code&gt;DataDog/master&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A Datadog technical writer might change your PR title with a DOCS ticket number, such as &#34;[DOCS-9000],&#34; which means it has been added to the team&#39;s internal Jira queue to triage and review. No action is necessary from you if we change the title of your PR.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;A note about markdown&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yuin/goldmark&#34;&gt;Goldmark&lt;/a&gt; for markdown, which is compliant with &lt;a href=&#34;https://spec.commonmark.org/0.29/&#34;&gt;CommonMark 0.29&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you include ANY Markdown in a file, give it a &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make sure all files are lowercase. Macs are case-insensitive when creating links to images and pages, but our build server is not, so tests may work locally, but the site will fail in production.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Releasing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within 10 minutes of merging to master, it deploys automatically.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to add a new integration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.datadoghq.com/developers/integrations&#34;&gt;See the dedicated doc page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>