<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-04T01:35:37Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ahmadbilaldev/langui</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T01:35:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-04:/ahmadbilaldev/langui</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UI for your AI. Open Source Tailwind components tailored for your GPT, generative AI, and LLM projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.LangUI.dev&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/public/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;LangUI Logo&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;The perfect UI for your AI&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahmadbilaldev/LangUI/stargazers&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/ahmadbilaldev/LangUI.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Stars&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.LangUI.dev&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://vercelbadge.vercel.app/api/ahmadbilaldev/langui&#34; alt=&#34;Vercel Deployment&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.LangUI.dev&#34;&gt;LangUI&lt;/a&gt; is an Open Source Tailwind library with free components tailored for your AI and GPT projects. It offers a collection of beautiful, ready-to-use components to enhance the user interface of your AI applications, allowing you to focus on building the next best project while leaving the UI to LangUI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;⭐️ LangUI is Open Source and its 60+ components are completely free. Please star it to show your support!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For documentation and components, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.langui.dev/&#34;&gt;LangUI.dev&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;LangUI components are ready-to-use, meaning you don&#39;t need to install or configure anything.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Browse &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.langui.dev/&#34;&gt;LangUI.dev&lt;/a&gt; and select a comopnent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Copy the desired component&#39;s code in HTML or JSX from the LangUI documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paste the code into your project&#39;s HTML or React/Vue/Angular components. Done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy &amp;amp; Paste Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Zero installations or dependencies! Simply choose your desired component, copy, and paste it into your project.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source &amp;amp; Free&lt;/strong&gt;: LangUI is MIT licensed, making it suitable for both personal and commercial projects. Feel free to contribute and support us by starring LangUI on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark &amp;amp; Light Modes&lt;/strong&gt;: All LangUI components support light &amp;amp; dark modes and are carefully designed to look the best across both modes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fully Responsive&lt;/strong&gt;: LangUI components are responsive, ensuring they look fantastic on any screen size or device.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Customization&lt;/strong&gt;: LangUI uses a two-color-only pallete. The two color pallete - slate and blue - allows for effortless customization into your brand&#39;s colors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/screenshots/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;LangUI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/screenshots/2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Components&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/screenshots/3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Preview Component&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Request a Component&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Have an idea for a new component? We&#39;d love to hear from you! Simply head over to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahmadbilaldev/LangUI&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; and submit your component request. Let&#39;s collaborate and cook up something spicy together!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to LangUI are highly welcome! Whether it&#39;s bug fixes, new components, or improvements, we appreciate your support in making this library better for the AI community. Please read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contribution guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LangUI is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ahmadbilaldev/langui/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Uses&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shadesofpurple.pro/&#34;&gt;Shades of Purple Theme&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ahmadawais.com/&#34;&gt;Ahmad Awais&lt;/a&gt; for syntax highlighting&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tabler-icons.io/&#34;&gt;Tabler Icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy using LangUI to build stunning UIs for your AI and GPT projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🌟 If you find it helpful, don&#39;t forget to give it a star on GitHub! Stars are like little virtual hugs that keep us going! We appreciate every single one we receive.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any queries or issues, feel free to open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahmadbilaldev/LangUI/issues&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; on the repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy coding! 😊&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>arm-university/VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit</title>
    <updated>2023-08-04T01:35:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-04:/arm-university/VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/arm-university/VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gain an understanding of the fundamentals of Very Large-Scale Integration (VLSI), including how the theories and concepts can be applied in the design of simple logic circuits and in the physical implementation of a simplified microprocessor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our VLSI Fundamentals: A Practical Approach Education Kit!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arm-university/VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit/archive/refs/heads/main.zip&#34;&gt;Download the EdKit here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our flagship offering to universities worldwide is the Arm University Program Education Kit series.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These self-contained educational materials are offered exclusively and at no cost to academics and teaching staff worldwide. They’re designed to support your day-to-day teaching on core electronic engineering and computer science subjects. You have the freedom to choose which modules to teach – you can use all the modules in the Education Kit or only those that are most appropriate to your teaching outcomes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;VLSI Fundamentals: A Practical Approach Education Kit covers the fundamentals of Very Large-Scale Integration (VLSI) design, including how the theories and concepts can be applied in the design of simple logic circuits and in the physical implementation of a simplified microprocessor. A full description of the education kit can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arm.com/resources/education/education-kits/vlsi-fundamentals-a-practical-approach&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Kit specification:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A full set of 20 modules with lecture slides and lab exercises (in selected modules) ready for use in a typical 10-12-week undergraduate course (full syllabus below).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lab manuals include additional libraries for lab exercises and solutions for faculty.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt; Students are required to have an understanding of digital electronics and the basics of hardware description language (Verilog).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Aim&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To produce students with solid introductory knowledge on VLSI concepts and application of these concepts in simulation, verification, and physical implementation of a simplified microprocessor using standard industry tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tools Used&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cadence Virtuoso for schematic capture and layout editing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cadence NCSim (Incisive) for simulation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Synopsys Design Compiler for Synthesis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cadence SoC Encounter for PnR.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note, the Cadence Innovus tool can be used instead of the older tool Cadence SoC Encounter for PnR.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An all Cadence tools version of this course can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cadence.com/en_US/home/company/cadence-academic-network/educators/vlsi-fundamentals.html?utm_source=arm&amp;amp;utm_medium=armweb&amp;amp;utm_campaign=vlsikit&amp;amp;utm_content=10_21%20VLSI%20Fundamentals&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Circuits and Layout&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Simple Processor Example&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CMOS Transistor Theory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nonideal Transistor Theory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DC &amp;amp; Transient Response&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logical Effort&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Power&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scaling&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SPICE Simulation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Combinational Circuit Design&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sequential Circuit Design&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wires&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adders&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Datapath Functional Units&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SRAM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clocking&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Variation and Reliability&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Test&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Packaging, I/O &amp;amp; Power Distribution&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are free to fork or clone this material. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arm-university/VLSI-Fundamentals-A-Practical-Approach-Education-Kit/raw/main/License/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;LICENSE.md&lt;/a&gt; for the complete license. All relevant lab files are provided and used with permission from the following authors:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prof. David Harris&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prof. Erik Brunvand&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Inclusive Language Commitment&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arm is committed to making the language we use inclusive, meaningful, and respectful. Our goal is to remove and replace non-inclusive language from our vocabulary to reflect our values and represent our global ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arm is working actively with our partners, standards bodies, and the wider ecosystem to adopt a consistent approach to the use of inclusive language and to eradicate and replace offensive terms. We recognise that this will take time. This course has been updated to replace references to non-inclusive language. We recognise that some of you will be accustomed to using the previous terms and may not immediately recognise their replacements. Please refer to the following example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When introducing edge-triggered Flip-Flops, we will use the term ‘JK Flip-flop’ instead of ‘master-slave flip-flop’.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course may still contain other references to non-inclusive language; it will be updated with newer terms as those terms are agreed and ratified with the wider community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contact us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:education@arm.com&#34;&gt;education@arm.com&lt;/a&gt; with questions or comments about this course. You can also report non-inclusive and offensive terminology usage in Arm content at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:terms@arm.com&#34;&gt;terms@arm.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>