<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Scala Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-28T01:40:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Scala in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>23fa-cpsc490/canyough</title>
    <updated>2023-08-28T01:40:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-28:/23fa-cpsc490/canyough</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/23fa-cpsc490/canyough" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s try again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;#This is the change I made. This is another change that was made - Justin Sohn&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;canyough&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s try again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;UPDATED ASST&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Do a PR&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;15 points&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DM me your Github username (in Zoom chat). Or canvas it to me Or sms it. or email it.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Accept the invite&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Fork canyough&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(and then clone it to your pc)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Make a change. Employ humor.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Create a pull request for your change. It must be for a branch from your fork&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CHANGE - READ THIS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Before you create your PR, visit the canyough repo.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Handle at least one OPEN PR (if present). &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;review the change.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make sure it doesn&#39;t have conflicts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make sure it follows the instructions/configuration below. (from THEIR named branch into canyough&#39;s MAIN branch).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;if it does have conflicts or is not correct, comment so the owner sees them &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Assuming no conflicts, MERGE IT.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;THEN create your PR.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(this should have the effect of keeping the conflicts and merge problems low)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Due: 8/27 11:59 PM&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Upload the link to the PR.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This has been fun (HHOS). Here are some basic instructions.:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;you might wonder how i Gone &amp;amp; Produced These...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Filing a Pull Request on GitHub: A Step-by-Step Guide&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Fork the Repository:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to the GitHub repository provided by the professor. Click on the &#34;Fork&#34; button in the top-right corner to create your personal copy of the repository. Clone the Forked Repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;On your GitHub profile, navigate to the forked repository.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click on the &#34;Code&#34; button and copy the repository&#39;s URL. Open a terminal on your computer and use the git clone command followed by the copied URL to clone the repository. Create a New Branch:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Navigate to the repository directory in your terminal using cd repository-name.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a new branch for your changes using the git checkout -b branch-name command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Make a Single Change:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open the project files using your preferred code editor. Make a single coding change, such as fixing a bug or adding a new feature.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Commit and Push Changes:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Save the changes in your code editor. In the terminal, use the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add . (to stage your changes)&#xA;&#xA;git commit -m &#34;Brief description of your change&#34; (to commit your changes)&#xA;&#xA;git push origin branch-name (to push your changes to your forked repository)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Open a Pull Request:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigate to your forked repository on GitHub. You should see a notification banner suggesting to create a pull request for the recent branch you&#39;ve pushed. Click on &#34;Compare &amp;amp; pull request.&#34; Review Pull Request Details:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the &#34;base&#34; branch is the original repository&#39;s main branch (usually &#34;main&#34; or &#34;master&#34;). The &#34;compare&#34; branch should be your created branch with the changes. Provide a descriptive title and detailed comment about your changes. Submit the Pull Request:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Review your pull request changes in the &#34;Files Changed&#34; tab. If everything looks good, click the &#34;Create pull request&#34; button. Address Feedback (if any):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Collaborators may provide feedback or request changes. Make the necessary adjustments by committing and pushing new changes to the same branch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;List Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To list contributors, use the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;./contributors.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>