<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-17T01:34:13Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>67272-App-Design-Dev/PATS_v1</title>
    <updated>2024-02-17T01:34:13Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-17:/67272-App-Design-Dev/PATS_v1</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/67272-App-Design-Dev/PATS_v1" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A first version of PATS using Rails 7&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;67272_PATS_v1_sqlite&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a basic Rails app that was built as a class demonstration in the spring of 2018 and revised in Spring 2022. This first version of the project is designed help students become more familiar with the basics of the Rails 5.2.6 framework; future versions will add in additional features like searching (straight|phonetic|full-text), polymorphic associations, and interactive javascript interfaces.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The class is Application Design &amp;amp; Development (67-272) and is for students in Information Systems at Carnegie Mellon University. We have posted this code on github in a public directory so that (a) it is readily accessible to students and (b) that students will get a little familiarity with github.com.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project does require the use of several gems to work properly. Check the Gemfile to see which gems are used. This project also assumes the user is running Ruby 2.6.9 since that is what is used in the course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version of the project requires only a sqlite3 database. After cloning this repo, install all gems with the &lt;code&gt;bundle install&lt;/code&gt; on the command line. To set up the database and populate it with realistic sample records, run on the command line &lt;code&gt;rake db:populate&lt;/code&gt;. The populate script will remove any old databases, create new development and test databases, run all the migrations to set up the structure, and then create 240 owners with over 450 pets and several thousand visits. (Every run will generate a different set of data and because of the large numbers and the callbacks used, it will take a few minutes.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To verify the model and controller tests are functioning, simply run &lt;code&gt;rails test&lt;/code&gt; on the command line. The SimpleCov gem will create a coverage directory with an index.html file in it; open this file in a web browser to see the coverage provided.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The populate script will also create a vet user to login into the system. The username is &#39;vet&#39; and the password is &#39;yodel&#39; -- a tribute to VeggieTales&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bUkpE16b56g&#34;&gt;The Yodeling Veterinarian of the Alps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to load the testing context into the development database, you can do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;if you have previously populated the database, drop it and rerun &lt;code&gt;rails db:migrate&lt;/code&gt; to recreate a blank db.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;open &lt;code&gt;rails console&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;type &lt;code&gt;require &#39;factory_bot_rails&#39;&lt;/code&gt; (it will say &#39;false&#39;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;type &lt;code&gt;require &#39;./test/contexts&#39;&lt;/code&gt; (it will say &#39;true&#39;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;type &lt;code&gt;include Contexts&lt;/code&gt; (it will say &#39;Object&#39;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;type in whatever context building method you wish (e.g., &lt;code&gt;create_animals&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;But of course, even easier than this would be to just run &lt;code&gt;rake db:contexts&lt;/code&gt; and it will drop the existing database, rebuild the schema, and then run the &lt;code&gt;create_all&lt;/code&gt; method in the context.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>