<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-18T01:32:42Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Digital-Forensics-Discord-Server/TheHitchhikersGuidetoDFIRExperiencesFromBeginnersandExperts</title>
    <updated>2022-08-18T01:32:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-18:/Digital-Forensics-Discord-Server/TheHitchhikersGuidetoDFIRExperiencesFromBeginnersandExperts</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Digital-Forensics-Discord-Server/TheHitchhikersGuidetoDFIRExperiencesFromBeginnersandExperts" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The official repo for a project involving a crowdsourced DFIR book. The main purpose of this book is to give anyone interested an opportunity to write a chapter of a book to get their name out there, get a publication on their resume with an actual ISBN number, and ideally lower the bar for people to contribute something back to the DFIR Communi…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Hitchhikers Guide to DFIR: Experiences From Beginners and Experts&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Digital-Forensics-Discord-Server/TheHitchhikersGuidetoDFIRExperiencesFromBeginnersandExperts/main/manuscript/resources/BookCover.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the book on &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/TheHitchhikersGuidetoDFIRExperiencesFromBeginnersandExperts&#34;&gt;Leanpub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookwire.com/book/USA/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-dfir-9798986335902-andrew-rathbun-85169559&#34;&gt;Bookwire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A DFIR book:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Being written on GitHub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Being edited on GitHub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Being self published through Leanpub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Being written by multiple co-authors collaboratively&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a proof of concept and a great first step for providing a different method of knowledge sharing within the DFIR space.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;When will it be done?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.0 is live!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, the writing and editing process has been fully transparent to the public! Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Digital-Forensics-Discord-Server/CrowdsourcedDFIRBook/milestones&#34;&gt;Milestones&lt;/a&gt; to see where we&#39;re at. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;ISBN Numbers&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;ISBN&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;PDF&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;979-8-9863359-0-2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;ePub&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;979-8-9863359-3-3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of July 2022, Amazon (and therefore Leanpub) no longer supports &lt;code&gt;Send to Kindle&lt;/code&gt; for MOBI files, so there no longer will be a MOBI version generated as of July 25, 2022, for this book or any Leanpub books.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>helpyio/helpy</title>
    <updated>2022-08-18T01:32:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-18:/helpyio/helpy</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/helpyio/helpy" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Helpy is a modern, open source helpdesk customer support application. Features include knowledgebase, community discussions and support tickets integrated with email.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Helpy: A Modern Helpdesk Platform&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy is a modern help desk platform written in Ruby on Rails and released under the MIT license. The goal of Helpy is to power your support email and ticketing, integrate seamlessly with your app, and run an amazing customer helpcenter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/helpyio/helpy&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/travis/helpyio/helpy/master.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeclimate.com/github/helpyio/helpy&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codeclimate.com/github/helpyio/helpy/badges/gpa.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Code Climate&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://helpy.io/images/github-main-image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Sponsor/Support Helpy&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy is licensed under the MIT license, and is an open-core project. This means that the core functionality is 100% open source and fully hackable or even re-sellable under the MIT license. See the features comparison below to understand what is included.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy is a large system and cannot exist purely as a hobby project. If you use it in a money generating capacity, it makes good sense to support the project financially or by becoming an official sponsor or supporter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/helpyio&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/helpyio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Open Source Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy is an integrated support solution- combining and leveraging synergies between support ticketing, Knowledgebase and a public community. Each feature is optional however, and can be easily disabled.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multichannel ticketing:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrated with inbound email via Sendgrid, Mandrill, Mailgun, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledgebase:&lt;/strong&gt; Full text searchable and SEO optimized to help users answer questions before they contact you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile-friendly:&lt;/strong&gt; Support requests come at all times, and Helpy works on all devices out of the box so you can delight customers with prompt answers, from anywhere and at anytime!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Support Forums:&lt;/strong&gt; Customers and Agents can both answer questions in a publicly accessible forum, and vote both threads and replies up or down accordingly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed Widget:&lt;/strong&gt; Helpy Includes a lightweight javascript widget that allows your users to contact you from just about anywhere.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-lingual:&lt;/strong&gt; Helpy is fully multi-lingual and can provide support in multiple languages at the same time. Currently the app includes translations for 19 languages and is easy to translate.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Themeable:&lt;/strong&gt; Customize the look and functionality of your Helpy without disturbing the underlying system that makes it all work. Helpy comes with two additional themes, and we hope to add more and get more from the community as time goes on.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sends HTML email:&lt;/strong&gt; Responses to customers can include html, emojis and attachments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable:&lt;/strong&gt; Set colors to match your brand both on the helpcenter, and in the ticketing UI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GDPR Compliant:&lt;/strong&gt; Comply with GDPR right to be forgotten requests by deleting users and their history, or by anonymizing them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Pro Version&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also offer a pro version with additional features designed to make your helpcenter even more awesome. This is available as either a turn-key SaaS or AWS/Azure marketplace product. Both spin up in seconds. Proceeds go directly towards supporting the continued development of the project. Some of the things found in the pro version:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Triggers:&lt;/strong&gt; Insert events at any point in the ticket lifecycle. This includes an outbound JSON API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notifications:&lt;/strong&gt; Browser notifications when new tickets are received, you are assigned to a ticket, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real time UI:&lt;/strong&gt; When tickets arrive, they are automatically added to the UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Views:&lt;/strong&gt; Add additional Ticketing queues to highlight just the tickets you need to see&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; A suite of additional reports on the performance of your ticketing and helpcenter knowledgebase&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced search:&lt;/strong&gt; Easily filter and find tickets or customers when you have thousands&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable Request Forms:&lt;/strong&gt; Easily Add questions to the ticket creation forms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Support Chatbot:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a chatbot for your website to answer up 90% of tier one questions autonomously&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Getting Started:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helpy Pro - 30 Second one-click install via DigitalOcean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can launch the free tier of Helpy Pro using the DigitalOcean Marketplace. This &#34;one click&#34; marketplace image spins up a dedicated VM within 30 seconds, running Ubuntu. &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.digitalocean.com/apps/helpy-pro?refcode=1368cfa70df6&#34;&gt;Launch DigitalOcean Marketplace Image&lt;/a&gt;. Use of all features requires either a trial or paid license code, available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.helpy.io/orders&#34;&gt;Helpy License Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Helpy via Docker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker is the recommended way to quickly test or run Helpy in production.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://get.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and docker-compose&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create config file from template &lt;code&gt;cp docker/.env.sample docker/.env&lt;/code&gt; and edit &lt;code&gt;docker/.env&lt;/code&gt; to match your needs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;docker/Caddyfile&lt;/code&gt; to include your URL or turn on SSL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build Helpy from local git checkout &lt;code&gt;docker-compose build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;docker-compose up -d&lt;/code&gt; to start all of the services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Install Helpy on your Local System&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although not required, installing locally is highly recommended and will make it easier for you to customize things like settings, colors and logos to match your site identity. To begin, clone Helpy from the official repo to your local system:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/helpyio/helpy.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure Basic Settings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a settings option in the admin panel to set up things like i18n, system names, colors, the embeddable widget, etc. There is a full guide to getting set up at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.helpy.io/en/knowledgebase/11-Installing-Helpy/docs/22-Configuring-your-Helpy-Settings&#34;&gt;Configuring Your Helpy Settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support Multiple Languages (optional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy includes support for Multilingual help sites, and multi-language knowledgebase articles. This page explains how to enable Helpy&#39;s international capabilities and provides an overview of what functionality this adds to Helpy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.helpy.io/en/knowledgebase/12-Using-Helpy/docs/9-How-to-set-up-a-multilingual-Helpy-support-knowledgebase&#34;&gt;How To Set Up A Multilingual Helpy Support Knowledgebase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up your Helpy to send and receive email (optional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy has the ability to receive email at your support email addresses and import the messages as tickets in the web interface. Whenever you or the user replies to the email thread, Helpy captures the discussion and sends out messages accordingly. Follow the tutorial on &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.helpy.io/en/knowledgebase/11-Installing-Helpy/docs/14-Setting-up-your-Helpy-installation-to-send-and-receive-email&#34;&gt;Setting Up Your Helpy Installation To Send And Receive Email&lt;/a&gt; to set this up.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configure oAuth (optional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy supports Omniauth login capabilities. This means you can allow your support users to sign in with a single click via any Omniauth provider- ie. Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, or many others. Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helpyio/helpy/wiki/SSO--Configuring-OAUTH&#34;&gt;Setting Up Oauth For Your Helpy&lt;/a&gt; to see how.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Live Demo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also a live demo with fake data available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.helpy.io&#34;&gt;http://demo.helpy.io&lt;/a&gt; Admin User: &lt;code&gt;admin@test.com&lt;/code&gt; and password: &lt;code&gt;12345678&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy was designed to run on modern cloud providers, although it should work on any linux based system. There is a full guide to installing Helpy in the wiki: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helpyio/helpy/wiki&#34;&gt;https://github.com/helpyio/helpy/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Requirements are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ruby 2.4+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rails 4.2.x&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Postgres&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A server like Unicorn, Puma or Passenger&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Helpy leverages two external services to help out:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;an email provider like Sendgrid&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Google Analytics for stats (optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contributing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome, and thanks for contributing to Helpy. Together we are building the best customer support platform in the world. Here are some of the ways you can contribute:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Report or fix Bugs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Refactoring&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve test coverage- As with any large and growing codebase, test coverage is not always as good as it could be. Help improving test coverage is always welcome and will help you learn how Helpy works. We use Minitest exclusively.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Translate the project- The community has already translated Helpy into 18 languages, but there are many more waiting. We need help getting Helpy translated into as many locales as possible! &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helpyio/helpy/wiki/How-to-translate-Helpy-into-your-language&#34;&gt;Please see the guide to translation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build new features. There is a backlog of new features that we’d like to see built. Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/b/NuiWsdmK/helpy&#34;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; for more insight on this, and if you would like to take one on, please get in touch with us to make sure someone is not already working on it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Guidelines:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Join us on Slack. Let me know you wish to contribute. &lt;a href=&#34;https://helpyioslackin.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://helpyioslackin.herokuapp.com/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Slack Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make your PRs granular. They should only include one piece of functionality per PR.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check the roadmap: &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/b/NuiWsdmK/helpy&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; If you want to build a feature, contact us to make sure no one else is already working on it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must provide passing test coverage. We use minitest, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubypigeon.com/posts/minitest-cheat-sheet/?utm_source=rubyweekly&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&#34;&gt;http://www.rubypigeon.com/posts/minitest-cheat-sheet/?utm_source=rubyweekly&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You also must expose functionality to the API. We use Grape. API methods should be tested as well.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If your feature/bug fix/enhancement adds or changes text in the project, please create i18n strings in &lt;code&gt;en.yml&lt;/code&gt; and any other locales you can.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We are hugely concerned with user experience, and a nice UI. Oftentimes that means we may take what you have contributed and “dress it up” or ask you to do the same.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Security Issues&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have found a vulnerability or other security problem in Helpy, please &lt;em&gt;do not open an issue&lt;/em&gt; on GitHub. Instead, contact [&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@helpy.io&#34;&gt;hello@helpy.io&lt;/a&gt;](mailto: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@helpy.io&#34;&gt;hello@helpy.io&lt;/a&gt;) directly by email. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/helpyio/helpy/master/SECURITY.md&#34;&gt;SECURITY&lt;/a&gt; guide to learn more and see a hall of fame of security reporters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-2021, Helpy.io, LLC, Scott Miller and Contributors. Helpy Core is released under the MIT open source license. Please contribute back any enhancements you make. Also, I would appreciate if you kept the &#34;powered by Helpy&#34; blurb in the footer. This helps me keep track of how many are using Helpy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/igrigorik/ga-beacon&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ga-beacon.appspot.com/UA-50151-28/helpy/readme?pixel&#34; alt=&#34;Analytics&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>