<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-07T01:45:39Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>github/brasil</title>
    <updated>2023-05-07T01:45:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-07:/github/brasil</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/github/brasil" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recursos e informações do GitHub para a comunidade de desenvolvedores no Brasil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/assets/br.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Read in English&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;Welcome to GitHub Brasil 🇧🇷&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;In this repo, you can find resources and information for the developer community in Brasil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#--open-source&#34;&gt;Open Source&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;   &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#octocat--developers&#34;&gt;Developers&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;   &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#meetups&#34;&gt;Meetups &amp;amp; GitTogethers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#github-stars&#34;&gt;GitHub Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#the-readme-project&#34;&gt;The ReadME Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-students&#34;&gt;Students&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;   &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#campus-program&#34;&gt;Campus Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#student-developer-pack&#34;&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#campus-experts&#34;&gt;Campus Experts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-startups&#34;&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;   &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#github-for-startups&#34;&gt;GitHub for startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-events&#34;&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-lets-connect&#34;&gt;Let&#39;s connect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#%EF%B8%8Fcontributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;🧑‍💻 Open Source&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;The open source movement in Brasil has gained significant momentum in recent years, with a growing number of developers and organizations adopting open source technologies and contributing to the open source community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Projects and Maintainers from Brasil&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;There are many open-source projects that we might be using frequently, but unaware that it&#39;s a project that was created in or receiving significant contributions from Brasil. We have collated some of the projects and maintainers from Brasil on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubbrasil.com&#34;&gt;githubbrasil.com website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you know of any other projects or maintainers from Brasil, feel free to make a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contribution.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you are looking to make your first contribution to open source, or even an experienced maintainer looking for ways to grow your community — we have resources to help you! Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.guide/pt/&#34;&gt;Open Source Guide&lt;/a&gt; which has many resources on how to start an open-source project, build communities, best practices for maintainers, and a lot more!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;octocat&#34; src=&#34;https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/octocat.png?v8&#34;&gt;) Developers&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;GitHub is the platform where millions of developers and companies build, ship and maintain their software. We help developers with the resources they need and showcase their awesome work to the rest of the community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Meetups&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;GitHub Brasil Virtual Meetup group is for developers in Brasil, by developers in Brszil, and fuelled by the love for Open Source! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/githubbrasil/&#34;&gt;Join us on the Meetup group&lt;/a&gt; and come check out the latest on GitHub, learn about new open source projects, and meet maintainers &amp;amp; GitHub staff from Brasil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;GitHub Stars&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;The GitHub Stars program thanks GitHub’s most influential developers and gives them a platform to showcase their work, reach more people, and shape the future of GitHub. Say hello 👋🏼 to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stars.github.com/profiles/?country=Brazil&#34;&gt;GitHub Stars from Brasil!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you know an inspiring community leader, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stars.github.com/nominate/&#34;&gt;we want to hear about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;The ReadME Project&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;The ReadME Project is part of GitHub’s ongoing effort to amplify the voices of the developer community. It’s an evolving space to engage with the community and explore the stories, challenges, technology, and culture that surround the world of open source.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Check out the stories of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/stories/felipe-de-morais&#34;&gt;Felipe De Morais&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/stories/pedro-nauck&#34;&gt;Pedro Nauck&lt;/a&gt; from Brazil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;We’re always on the lookout for inspiring developers who passionately dedicate themselves to their communities. Know somebody whose story deserves to be told? &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/nominate&#34;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt;, and they could end up being featured on The ReadME Project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;🧑‍🎓 Students&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;GitHub Education helps students, teachers, and schools access the tools and events they need to shape the next generation of software development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Campus Program&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;With the GitHub Campus Program, your school will get a package of technical tools, training for faculty members, and support to grow technical communities on campus. Learn more and enroll your school in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.github.com/schools&#34;&gt;GitHub Campus Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;There&#39;s no substitute for hands-on experience. But for most students, real-world tools can be cost-prohibitive. That&#39;s why we created the GitHub Student Developer Pack with some of our partners and friends: to give students free access to the best developer tools in one place so they can learn by doing. Check out the tools and get your &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.github.com/pack&#34;&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Campus Experts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Campus Experts are student leaders that strive to build diverse and inclusive spaces to learn skills, share their experiences, and build projects together. They can be found across the globe leading in-person and online conferences, meetups, and hackathons, and maintaining open source projects. Explore and connect with &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubcampus.expert/experts&#34;&gt;Campus Experts from Brasil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;📈 Startups&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Brasil has a vibrant tech startup community, with many entrepreneurs choosing GitHub to enable innovation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;GitHub for Startups&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;GitHub for Startups program helps startups go from idea to IPO on the world’s best software development platform with free access to GitHub Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;For details about the program, &lt;a href=&#34;https://startups.github.com&#34;&gt;check out startups.github.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;📢 Events&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Connect with the GitHub community through conferences, meetups and hackathons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;💬 Let&#39;s connect&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Stay tuned to what&#39;s happening with GitHub Brasil by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GitHubBrasil&#34;&gt;following us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;You are also welcome to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/brazil/discussions/categories/general&#34;&gt;GitHub Discussions&lt;/a&gt; on this repository. Please respect the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; and be awesome to each other!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Contributions are welcome to certain parts of this repository. For getting started, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/brasil/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.MD&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;📜 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Content is released under CC0-1.0. Code is released under MIT License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;When using the GitHub logos, be sure to follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/logos&#34;&gt;GitHub logo guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Boas vindas ao GitHub Brasil 🇧🇷&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neste repositório, você pode encontrar recursos e informações para a comunidade de pessoas desenvolvedoras no Brasil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#--open-source&#34;&gt;Código Aberto&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#recursos&#34;&gt;Recursos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#octocat--desenvolvedores&#34;&gt;Devs&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#meetups&#34;&gt;Meetups &amp;amp; GitTogethers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#github-stars&#34;&gt;GitHub Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#the-readme-project&#34;&gt;Projeto ReadME&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-estudantes&#34;&gt;Estudantes&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#campus-program&#34;&gt;Programa Campus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#student-developer-pack&#34;&gt;GitHub Student Pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#campus-experts&#34;&gt;Campus Experts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-startups&#34;&gt;Startups&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#github-for-startups&#34;&gt;GitHub para Startups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-eventos&#34;&gt;Eventos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-vamos-nos-conectar&#34;&gt;Vamos nos conectar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#%EF%B8%8Fcontribuindo&#34;&gt;Contribuindo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/#-licen%C3%A7a&#34;&gt;Licença&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🧑‍💻 Código Aberto&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O movimento de código aberto no Brasil tem ganhado impulso significativo nos últimos anos, com um número crescente de pessoas desenvolvedoras e organizações adotando tecnologias de código aberto e contribuindo para a comunidade.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Projetos e Pessoas Mantenedoras do Brasil&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Existem muitos projetos de código aberto que podemos estar usando frequentemente, mas sem saber que é um projeto criado ou recebendo contribuições significativas do Brasil. Nós reunimos alguns dos projetos e pessoas do Brasil no site &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubbrasil.com&#34;&gt;githubbrasil.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Se você conhece outros projetos ou pessoa mantenedoras do Brasil, sinta-se à vontade para fazer uma &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/brasil/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.MD&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Recursos&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Se você está procurando fazer sua primeira contribuição para o código aberto, ou é uma pessoa mantenedora experiente procurando maneiras de aumentar sua comunidade - temos recursos para ajudá-lo! Confira o &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.guide/pt/&#34;&gt;Guia de Código Aberto&lt;/a&gt; que possui muitos recursos sobre como iniciar um projeto de código aberto, construir comunidades, melhores práticas para manter projetos e muito mais!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;octocat&#34; src=&#34;https://github.githubassets.com/images/icons/emoji/octocat.png?v8&#34;&gt;) Devs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O GitHub é a plataforma onde milhões de pessoas desenvolvedoras e empresas constroem, entregam e mantêm seu software. Ajudamos essas pessoas com os recursos necessários e exibimos seu trabalho incrível para o restante da comunidade.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Meetups&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O grupo de Meetup virtual do GitHub Brasil é para devs no Brasil, por devs no Brasil, e alimentado pelo amor pelo Código Aberto! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/githubbrasil/&#34;&gt;Junte-se a nós no grupo Meetup&lt;/a&gt; e venha conferir as últimas novidades do GitHub, conhecer novos projetos de código aberto e encontrar pessoas mantenedoras e funcionários do GitHub do Brasil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;GitHub Stars&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O programa Estrelas do GitHub agradece a pessoas desenvolvedoras mais influentes do GitHub e lhes dá uma plataforma para exibir seu trabalho, alcançar mais pessoas e moldar o futuro do GitHub. Dê um olá 👋🏼 às &lt;a href=&#34;https://stars.github.com/profiles/?country=Brazil&#34;&gt;Estrelas do GitHub do Brasil!&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Se você conhece uma pessoa líder comunitário inspiradora e que te ensinou algo sobre Git, GitHub ou Open Source no geral, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stars.github.com/nominate/&#34;&gt;queremos saber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;O Projeto ReadME&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Projeto ReadME faz parte do esforço contínuo do GitHub para amplificar as vozes da comunidade É um espaço em constante evolução para se engajar com a comunidade e explorar as histórias, desafios, tecnologia e cultura que cercam o mundo do código aberto.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confira as histórias de &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/stories/felipe-de-morais&#34;&gt;Felipe De Morais&lt;/a&gt; e &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/stories/pedro-nauck&#34;&gt;Pedro Nauck&lt;/a&gt; do Brasil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estamos sempre procurando por pessoas inspiradoras que se dediquem apaixonadamente às suas comunidades. Conhece alguém cuja história merece ser contada? &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/readme/nominate&#34;&gt;Nos conte&lt;/a&gt;, e elas podem acabar sendo apresentadas no Projeto ReadME.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🧑‍🎓 Estudantes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O GitHub Education ajuda estudantes, professores e escolas a acessar as ferramentas e eventos de que precisam para moldar a próxima geração de desenvolvimento de software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Programa Campus&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Com o Programa Campus do GitHub, sua escola receberá um pacote de ferramentas técnicas, treinamento para membros do corpo docente e suporte para crescer comunidades técnicas no campus. Saiba mais e inscreva sua escola no &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.github.com/schools&#34;&gt;Programa Campus do GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Não há substituto para a experiência prática. Mas, para a maioria dos estudantes, as ferramentas do mundo real podem ser proibitivas em termos de custo. É por isso que criamos o Student Developer Pack (Pacote de Desenvolvimento para Estudantes) do GitHub com alguns de nossos parceiros e amigos: para dar aos estudantes acesso gratuito às melhores ferramentas de desenvolvimento em um só lugar, para que possam aprender fazendo. Confira as ferramentas e obtenha seu &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.github.com/pack&#34;&gt;Student Developer Pack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Campus Experts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Campus Experts são líderes estudantis que se esforçam para construir espaços diversos e inclusivos para aprender habilidades, compartilhar suas experiências e construir projetos juntos. Podem ser encontrados em todo o mundo liderando conferências, meetups e hackathons presenciais e online, e mantendo projetos de código aberto. Explore e conecte-se com &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubcampus.expert/experts&#34;&gt;Campus Experts do Brasil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📈 Startups&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O Brasil possui uma grande comunidade de startups de tecnologia, com muitos empreendedores escolhendo o GitHub para permitir a inovação.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;GitHub para Startups&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O programa GitHub for Startups ajuda as startups a ir da ideia ao IPO na melhor plataforma de desenvolvimento de software do mundo com acesso gratuito ao GitHub Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Para obter detalhes sobre o programa, &lt;a href=&#34;https://startups.github.com&#34;&gt;confira startups.github.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📢 Eventos&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Conecte-se com a comunidade do GitHub por meio de conferências, meetups e hackathons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💬 Vamos nos conectar&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fique por dentro do que está acontecendo com o GitHub Brasil &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GitHubBrasil&#34;&gt;nos seguindo no Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Você também é bem-vindo para participar das &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/brazil/discussions/categories/general&#34;&gt;Discussões do GitHub&lt;/a&gt; neste repositório. Por favor, respeite o &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/github/brasil/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;código de conduta&lt;/a&gt; e seja incrível com os outros!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribuindo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contribuições são bem-vindas para certas partes deste repositório. Para começar, confira For contributing to the content, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/brasil/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.MD&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📜 Licença&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O conteúdo é liberado sob CC0-1.0. O código é liberado sob a Licença MIT.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ao usar os logotipos do GitHub, certifique-se de seguir as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/logos&#34;&gt;diretrizes de logotipo do GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>wix-incubator/homebrew-brew</title>
    <updated>2023-05-07T01:45:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-07:/wix-incubator/homebrew-brew</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/wix-incubator/homebrew-brew" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Homebrew tap for formulae for software developed by Wix&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Wix Homebrew Tap&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; tap for formulae for software developed by Wix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using these formulae requires Homebrew, which in turn requires Xcode. If you have not yet installed Homebrew, a quick summary is at the end of this document.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once homebrew is installed, simply run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;brew tap wix/brew&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install software, just use &lt;code&gt;brew install&lt;/code&gt; with the name of the formula. You may wish to run &lt;code&gt;brew update&lt;/code&gt; before hand to get the latest version of the formulae. For example, to install the latest version of the Apple simulator utilities:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;brew tap wix/brew&#xA;brew update&#xA;brew install wix/applesimutils&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To upgrade software:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;brew update&#xA;# update just applesimutils&#xA;brew upgrade applesimutils&#xA;# or,&#xA;# upgrade all software installed with Homebrew&#xA;brew upgrade&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In case an installation fails, make sure to update your command line tools in the System Update system prefernce pane of your Mac&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If Homebrew complains about a conflict in the &lt;code&gt;wix/brew&lt;/code&gt; tap, run &lt;code&gt;brew untap wix/brew &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew tap wix/brew&lt;/code&gt; and try installing again&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If installation still fails, &lt;strong&gt;run &lt;code&gt;brew doctor&lt;/code&gt; and fix all issues &amp;amp; warnings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please file bug reports and/or enhancement requests as GitHub issues of the individual projects, not this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew help&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;man brew&lt;/code&gt;, or the Homebrew &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Homebrew/brew/raw/master/docs/README.md&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tomtt/flocklocal</title>
    <updated>2023-05-07T01:45:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-07:/tomtt/flocklocal</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tomtt/flocklocal" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;do good.fast&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;== Welcome to Rails&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rails is a web-application and persistence framework that includes everything needed to create database-backed web-applications according to the Model-View-Control pattern of separation. This pattern splits the view (also called the presentation) into &#34;dumb&#34; templates that are primarily responsible for inserting pre-built data in between HTML tags. The model contains the &#34;smart&#34; domain objects (such as Account, Product, Person, Post) that holds all the business logic and knows how to persist themselves to a database. The controller handles the incoming requests (such as Save New Account, Update Product, Show Post) by manipulating the model and directing data to the view.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Rails, the model is handled by what&#39;s called an object-relational mapping layer entitled Active Record. This layer allows you to present the data from database rows as objects and embellish these data objects with business logic methods. You can read more about Active Record in link:files/vendor/rails/activerecord/README.html.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The controller and view are handled by the Action Pack, which handles both layers by its two parts: Action View and Action Controller. These two layers are bundled in a single package due to their heavy interdependence. This is unlike the relationship between the Active Record and Action Pack that is much more separate. Each of these packages can be used independently outside of Rails. You can read more about Action Pack in link:files/vendor/rails/actionpack/README.html.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Getting Started&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;At the command prompt, start a new Rails application using the &lt;tt&gt;rails&lt;/tt&gt; command and your application name. Ex: rails myapp (If you&#39;ve downloaded Rails in a complete tgz or zip, this step is already done)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change directory into myapp and start the web server: &lt;tt&gt;script/server&lt;/tt&gt; (run with --help for options)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/a&gt; and get &#34;Welcome aboard: You’re riding the Rails!&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the guidelines to start developing your application&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Web Servers&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, Rails will try to use Mongrel and lighttpd if they are installed, otherwise Rails will use WEBrick, the webserver that ships with Ruby. When you run script/server, Rails will check if Mongrel exists, then lighttpd and finally fall back to WEBrick. This ensures that you can always get up and running quickly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mongrel is a Ruby-based webserver with a C component (which requires compilation) that is suitable for development and deployment of Rails applications. If you have Ruby Gems installed, getting up and running with mongrel is as easy as: &lt;tt&gt;gem install mongrel&lt;/tt&gt;. More info at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://mongrel.rubyforge.org&#34;&gt;http://mongrel.rubyforge.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If Mongrel is not installed, Rails will look for lighttpd. It&#39;s considerably faster than Mongrel and WEBrick and also suited for production use, but requires additional installation and currently only works well on OS X/Unix (Windows users are encouraged to start with Mongrel). We recommend version 1.4.11 and higher. You can download it from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lighttpd.net&#34;&gt;http://www.lighttpd.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And finally, if neither Mongrel or lighttpd are installed, Rails will use the built-in Ruby web server, WEBrick. WEBrick is a small Ruby web server suitable for development, but not for production.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;But of course its also possible to run Rails on any platform that supports FCGI. Apache, LiteSpeed, IIS are just a few. For more information on FCGI, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/pages/FastCGI&#34;&gt;http://wiki.rubyonrails.com/rails/pages/FastCGI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Debugging Rails&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes your application goes wrong. Fortunately there are a lot of tools that will help you debug it and get it back on the rails.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First area to check is the application log files. Have &#34;tail -f&#34; commands running on the server.log and development.log. Rails will automatically display debugging and runtime information to these files. Debugging info will also be shown in the browser on requests from 127.0.0.1.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also log your own messages directly into the log file from your code using the Ruby logger class from inside your controllers. Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;class WeblogController &amp;lt; ActionController::Base def destroy @weblog = Weblog.find(params[:id]) @weblog.destroy logger.info(&#34;#{Time.now} Destroyed Weblog ID ##{@weblog.id}!&#34;) end end&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The result will be a message in your log file along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mon Oct 08 14:22:29 +1000 2007 Destroyed Weblog ID #1&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;More information on how to use the logger is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-doc.org/core/&#34;&gt;http://www.ruby-doc.org/core/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, Ruby documentation can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.ruby-lang.org/&lt;/a&gt; including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Learning Ruby (Pickaxe) Book: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-doc.org/docs/ProgrammingRuby/&#34;&gt;http://www.ruby-doc.org/docs/ProgrammingRuby/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Learn to Program: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pine.fm/LearnToProgram/&#34;&gt;http://pine.fm/LearnToProgram/&lt;/a&gt; (a beginners guide)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These two online (and free) books will bring you up to speed on the Ruby language and also on programming in general.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Debugger&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debugger support is available through the debugger command when you start your Mongrel or Webrick server with --debugger. This means that you can break out of execution at any point in the code, investigate and change the model, AND then resume execution! Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;class WeblogController &amp;lt; ActionController::Base def index @posts = Post.find(:all) debugger end end&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the controller will accept the action, run the first line, then present you with a IRB prompt in the server window. Here you can do things like:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;@posts.inspect =&amp;gt; &#34;[#&amp;lt;Post:0x14a6be8 @attributes={&#34;title&#34;=&amp;gt;nil, &#34;body&#34;=&amp;gt;nil, &#34;id&#34;=&amp;gt;&#34;1&#34;}&amp;gt;, #&amp;lt;Post:0x14a6620 @attributes={&#34;title&#34;=&amp;gt;&#34;Rails you know!&#34;, &#34;body&#34;=&amp;gt;&#34;Only ten..&#34;, &#34;id&#34;=&amp;gt;&#34;2&#34;}&amp;gt;]&#34; @posts.first.title = &#34;hello from a debugger&#34; =&amp;gt; &#34;hello from a debugger&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;...and even better is that you can examine how your runtime objects actually work:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;f = @posts.first =&amp;gt; #&amp;lt;Post:0x13630c4 @attributes={&#34;title&#34;=&amp;gt;nil, &#34;body&#34;=&amp;gt;nil, &#34;id&#34;=&amp;gt;&#34;1&#34;}&amp;gt; f. Display all 152 possibilities? (y or n)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, when you&#39;re ready to resume execution, you enter &#34;cont&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Console&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can interact with the domain model by starting the console through &lt;tt&gt;script/console&lt;/tt&gt;. Here you&#39;ll have all parts of the application configured, just like it is when the application is running. You can inspect domain models, change values, and save to the database. Starting the script without arguments will launch it in the development environment. Passing an argument will specify a different environment, like &lt;tt&gt;script/console production&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To reload your controllers and models after launching the console run &lt;tt&gt;reload!&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Description of Contents&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app Holds all the code that&#39;s specific to this particular application.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app/controllers Holds controllers that should be named like weblogs_controller.rb for automated URL mapping. All controllers should descend from ApplicationController which itself descends from ActionController::Base.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app/models Holds models that should be named like post.rb. Most models will descend from ActiveRecord::Base.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app/views Holds the template files for the view that should be named like weblogs/index.erb for the WeblogsController#index action. All views use eRuby syntax.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app/views/layouts Holds the template files for layouts to be used with views. This models the common header/footer method of wrapping views. In your views, define a layout using the &lt;tt&gt;layout :default&lt;/tt&gt; and create a file named default.erb. Inside default.erb, call &amp;lt;% yield %&amp;gt; to render the view using this layout.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;app/helpers Holds view helpers that should be named like weblogs_helper.rb. These are generated for you automatically when using script/generate for controllers. Helpers can be used to wrap functionality for your views into methods.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;config Configuration files for the Rails environment, the routing map, the database, and other dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;db Contains the database schema in schema.rb. db/migrate contains all the sequence of Migrations for your schema.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;doc This directory is where your application documentation will be stored when generated using &lt;tt&gt;rake doc:app&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;lib Application specific libraries. Basically, any kind of custom code that doesn&#39;t belong under controllers, models, or helpers. This directory is in the load path.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;public The directory available for the web server. Contains subdirectories for images, stylesheets, and javascripts. Also contains the dispatchers and the default HTML files. This should be set as the DOCUMENT_ROOT of your web server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;script Helper scripts for automation and generation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;test Unit and functional tests along with fixtures. When using the script/generate scripts, template test files will be generated for you and placed in this directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;vendor External libraries that the application depends on. Also includes the plugins subdirectory. This directory is in the load path.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== This change should show up using cap:deploy&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>