<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub F# Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-30T01:40:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of F# in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>fsharp/fslang-design</title>
    <updated>2022-06-30T01:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-30:/fsharp/fslang-design</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-design" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RFCs and docs related to the F# language design process, see https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-suggestions to submit ideas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;F# Language Design RFCs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;RFCs (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Request_for_Comments&#34;&gt;Request for Comments&lt;/a&gt;) and docs related to the F# language design process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All open RFCs that have not been released live under &lt;code&gt;/RFCs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All RFCs that have been implemented in a preview of F# live under &lt;code&gt;/preview&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All release language and FSharp.Core RFCs live under a folder with their respective release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All tooling RFCs (typically for cross-cutting, cross-editor tooling) live under &lt;code&gt;/tooling&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Process:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-suggestions&#34;&gt;F# Language Suggestions&lt;/a&gt; to submit ideas, vote on them and discuss them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ideas which get &#34;approved in principle&#34; get an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-design/tree/master/RFCs&#34;&gt;RFC entry&lt;/a&gt; based on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-design/raw/master/RFC_template.md&#34;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt;, and a corresponding &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-design/issues&#34;&gt;RFC discussion thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is currently a backlog of approved ideas. If an idea has been approved and you&#39;d like to accelerate the creation of an RFC, send a PR creating the RFC document for any approved-in-principle issue.&lt;br&gt; First in first served. To &#34;grab the token&#34; send a PR doing nothing but creating or naming the RFC file, and then fill in the further details with additional commits to the PR.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;to pick the RFC numbered identifier, you can run &lt;code&gt;dotnet fsi find.next.id.fsx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;to name the file, tooling RFCs are prefixed with &lt;code&gt;FST-&lt;/code&gt;, language RFC are prefixed with &lt;code&gt;FS-&lt;/code&gt;, use &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; and lower casing (relaxed for code identifiers), giving descriptive name&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;the file location is always under RFCs and get moved by owners of the repository when it ships in a preview or a release.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Implementations and testing are submitted to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dotnet/fsharp&#34;&gt;dotnet/fsharp repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When RFCs are implemented and a version of F# is revved, the RFCs which correspond to the F# version they were implemented in are archived under the appropriate folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Language Update Release Trains&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Delivery of language features is via RFCs plus implementations submitted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dotnet/fsharp&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dotnet/fsharp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;New features that meet our quality bar are then merged and placed beyond a preview flag in the F# compiler and FSharp.Core.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When we have a handful of 100% “ready, tested and completed” FSharp.Core and F# Language features in preview that aren&#39;t &#34;too minor&#34;, then we will bump the language version and begin tactical work to release them in a few months.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;New releases of F# typically align with a .NET and/or Visual Studio version.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Roadmap and Areas of Priority Work&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any or all of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-suggestions/labels/approved-in-principle&#34;&gt;approved-in-principle&lt;/a&gt; items are eligible to catch a release train. That is as good as it gets for a &#34;roadmap&#34; for the language design.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The BDFL (@dsyme) has put together a list of &#34;proposed priority&#34; approved language design items which he plans to focus on or which other people have taken past RFC stage. This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a roadmap, because other people will choose to prioritize other approved items (e.g. match! - which is not a priority item for me), and is also subject to change and edit.. It is an informal list. You can find that list here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-suggestions/labels/proposed-priority&#34;&gt;https://github.com/fsharp/fslang-suggestions/labels/proposed-priority&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Style Guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The F# style guide is hosted as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/dotnet/fsharp/style-guide/&#34;&gt;.NET docs for F#&lt;/a&gt; and by default &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fsprojects/fantomas&#34;&gt;Fantomas&lt;/a&gt; aims to implement this style guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The design process for raising issues arising about this style guide is managed via issues in this repository. Issues are noted by &lt;code&gt;[style-guide]&lt;/code&gt; in the title.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The style guide itself is adjusted via PRs to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dotnet/docs/raw/main/docs/fsharp/style-guide/formatting.md&#34;&gt;the style guide doc&lt;/a&gt; however discussion should happen here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adjustments to the style guide should generally only be made with consideration about their implementability in Fantomas, and if an adjustment is approved you should be prepared to contribute a matching pull request to Fantomas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The decision maker for the style guide is @dsyme, with input/veto from @nojaf (current maintainer of Fantomas) and input from all interested parties.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is governed by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.contributor-covenant.org/&#34;&gt;Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We pledge to be overt in our openness, welcoming all people to contribute, and pledging in return to value them as whole human beings and to foster an atmosphere of kindness, cooperation, and understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RyushiAok/Tetris</title>
    <updated>2022-06-30T01:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-30:/RyushiAok/Tetris</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/RyushiAok/Tetris" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Tetris&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/55625375/137788918-202b78b3-86fa-48a2-998f-a1dfea28b002.gif&#34; alt=&#34;dthou&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>