<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-15T01:45:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>adambard/learnxinyminutes-docs</title>
    <updated>2024-12-15T01:45:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-15:/adambard/learnxinyminutes-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/adambard/learnxinyminutes-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code documentation written as code! How novel and totally my idea!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learnxinyminutes.com&#34;&gt;Learn X in Y minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whirlwind tours of (several, hopefully many someday) popular and ought-to-be-more-popular programming languages, presented as valid, commented code and explained as they go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;We need YOU!...&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;... to write more inline code tutorials. Just grab an existing file from this repo and copy the formatting (don&#39;t worry, it&#39;s all very simple). Make a new file, send a pull request, and if it passes muster I&#39;ll get it up pronto. Remember to fill in the &#34;contributors&#34; fields so you get credited properly!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All contributions are welcome, from the tiniest typo to a brand new article. Translations in all languages are welcome (or, for that matter, original articles in any language). Send a pull request or open an issue any time of day or night.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please prepend the tag &lt;code&gt;[language/lang-code]&lt;/code&gt; to your issues and pull requests.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, &lt;code&gt;[python/en]&lt;/code&gt; for English Python. This will help everyone pick out things they care about.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re happy for any contribution in any form, but if you&#39;re making more than one major change (i.e. translations for two different languages) it would be super cool of you to make a separate pull request for each one so that someone can review them more effectively and/or individually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a detailed style guide, please review the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/adambard/learnxinyminutes-docs/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; guidelines.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributors retain copyright to their work, and can request removal at any time. By uploading a doc here, you agree to publish your work under the default &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.en_US&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported&lt;/a&gt; licensing included on each doc page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anything not covered by the above -- basically, this README -- you can use as you wish, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>