<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-27T02:04:20Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ftp27/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt</title>
    <updated>2023-08-27T02:04:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-27:/ftp27/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ftp27/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A fastlane plugin that provides an action to translate text using OpenAI API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ftp27/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt/master/images/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;translate-gpt plugin&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rubygems.org/gems/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://rawcdn.githack.com/fastlane/fastlane/master/fastlane/assets/plugin-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;fastlane Plugin Badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://badge.fury.io/rb/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badge.fury.io/rb/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Gem Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane&#34;&gt;fastlane&lt;/a&gt; plugin. To get started with &lt;code&gt;fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt&lt;/code&gt;, add it to your project by running:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;fastlane add_plugin translate_gpt&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About translate-gpt&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt; is a fastlane plugin that allows you to easily translate your iOS and Android app&#39;s strings using the OpenAI GPT API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically detects the source language and translates to the desired target language.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can take contextual information, such as comments in your code, into account to improve translation accuracy.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can automatically skip strings that are already translated, improving performance and reducing costs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following example demonstrates how to use &lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt; in a &lt;code&gt;Fastfile&lt;/code&gt; to translate an app&#39;s strings from English to French:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;lane :translate_strings do&#xA;  translate_gpt(&#xA;    api_key: &#39;YOUR_API_KEY&#39;,&#xA;    target_language: &#39;fr&#39;&#xA;  )&#xA;end&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following options are available for &lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Key&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Environment Variable&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;api_key&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The API key for your OpenAI GPT account.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;model_name&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Name of the ChatGPT model to use&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_MODEL_NAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;temperature&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;What sampling temperature to use, between 0 and 2. Higher values like 0.8 will make the output more random, while lower values like 0.2 will make it more focused and deterministic. Defaults to 0.5&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_TEMPERATURE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;request_timeout&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Timeout for the request in seconds. Defaults to 30 seconds&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_REQUEST_TIMEOUT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;skip_translated&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Whether to skip strings that have already been translated. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_SKIP_TRANSLATED&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;source_language&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The source language of the strings to be translated. Defaults to auto-detection.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_SOURCE_LANGUAGE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;target_language&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The target language of the translated strings. Required.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_TARGET_LANGUAGE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;source_file&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The path to the &lt;code&gt;Localizable.strings&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;strings.xml&lt;/code&gt; file to be translated.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_SOURCE_FILE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;target_file&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The path to the output file for the translated strings.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_TARGET_FILE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;context&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Common context for the translation&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_COMMON_CONTEXT&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;bunch_size&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Number of strings to translate in a single request.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;GPT_BUNCH_SIZE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;I advise using &lt;code&gt;bunch_size&lt;/code&gt;. It will reduce the number of API requests and translations will be more accurate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Providing context&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;TranslateGptAction&lt;/code&gt; allows you to provide additional context for your translation requests in two ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. Using a common context&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can provide a common context for your project that will be used in all translation requests. This can be done by setting the &lt;code&gt;common&lt;/code&gt; property when calling the &lt;code&gt;TranslateGptAction&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;common&lt;/code&gt; property should be a string that describes the context of your project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;translate_gpt(&#xA;  target_language: &#39;fr&#39;,&#xA;  common: &#34;This is a mobile app for ordering food online&#34;&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;2. Adding comments for specific keys&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also add comments to your Localizable.strings file for specific keys. These comments will be included in the translation request for that key. To add a comment for a specific key, simply include a comment before the key in your Localizable.strings file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;/* This is a comment for KEY1 */&#xA;&#34;KEY1&#34; = &#34;Value for KEY1&#34;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you run the &lt;code&gt;TranslateGptAction&lt;/code&gt;, the comment will be included in the translation request for &lt;code&gt;KEY1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Authentication&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt; supports multiple authentication methods for the OpenAI GPT API:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;API Key&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can provide your API key directly as an option to &lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;translate-gpt(&#xA;  api_key: &#39;YOUR_API_KEY&#39;,&#xA;  target_language: &#39;fr&#39;&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Environment Variable&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can set the &lt;code&gt;GPT_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt; environment variable with your API key:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;export GPT_API_KEY=&#39;YOUR_API_KEY&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then call &lt;code&gt;translate-gpt&lt;/code&gt; without specifying an API key:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;translate-gpt(&#xA;  target_language: &#39;fr&#39;&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Issues and Feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have trouble using plugins, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fastlane.tools/plugins/plugins-troubleshooting/&#34;&gt;Plugins Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; guide. For any other issues and feedback about this plugin, please submit it to this repository or contact the maintainers on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ftp27host&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; Plugins&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information about how the &lt;code&gt;fastlane&lt;/code&gt; plugin system works, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fastlane.tools/plugins/create-plugin/&#34;&gt;Plugins documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About &lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;fastlane&lt;/em&gt; is the easiest way to automate beta deployments and releases for your iOS and Android apps. To learn more, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://fastlane.tools&#34;&gt;fastlane.tools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to contribute to this plugin, please fork the repository and make your changes. When you&#39;re ready, submit a pull request explaining your changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This action is released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ftp27/fastlane-plugin-translate_gpt/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>basecamp/kamal</title>
    <updated>2023-08-27T02:04:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-27:/basecamp/kamal</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/basecamp/kamal" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deploy web apps anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Kamal: Deploy web apps anywhere&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From bare metal to cloud VMs using Docker, deploy web apps anywhere with zero downtime. Kamal uses the dynamic reverse-proxy Traefik to hold requests, while the new app container is started and the old one is stopped — working seamlessly across multiple hosts, using SSHKit to execute commands. Originally built for Rails apps, Kamal will work with any type of web app that can be containerized with Docker.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;➡️ See &lt;a href=&#34;https://kamal-deploy.org&#34;&gt;kamal-deploy.org&lt;/a&gt; for documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kamal-deploy.org/docs/installation&#34;&gt;installation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kamal-deploy.org/docs/configuration&#34;&gt;configuration&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://kamal-deploy.org/docs/commands&#34;&gt;commands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing to the documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please help us improve Kamal&#39;s documentation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/basecamp/kamal-site&#34;&gt;the basecamp/kamal-site repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kamal is released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ubicloud/ubicloud</title>
    <updated>2023-08-27T02:04:20Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-27:/ubicloud/ubicloud</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open, free, and portable cloud. Elastic compute, block storage (non replicated), and virtual networking services in public alpha.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/assets/2545443/45d2b775-dacf-45e8-93c4-ba16d312396a&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Ubicloud &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/actions/workflows/ci.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;CI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/actions/workflows/build.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ubicloud is an open, free, and portable cloud. Think of it as an open alternative to cloud providers, like what Linux is to proprietary operating systems.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ubicloud provides IaaS cloud features on bare metal providers, such as Hetzner, OVH, and AWS Bare Metal. You can set it up yourself on these providers or you can use our managed service. We&#39;re currently in public alpha.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Managed platform&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use Ubicloud without installing anything. When you do this, we pass along the underlying provider&#39;s benefits to you, such as price or location.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://console.ubicloud.com&#34;&gt;https://console.ubicloud.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Build your own cloud&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also build your own cloud. To do this, start up Ubicloud&#39;s control plane and connect to its cloud console.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:ubicloud/ubicloud.git&#xA;&#xA;# Generate secrets for demo&#xA;./demo/generate_env&#xA;&#xA;# Run containers: db-migrator, app (web &amp;amp; respirate), postgresql&#xA;docker-compose -f demo/docker-compose.yml up&#xA;&#xA;# Visit localhost:3000&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The control plane is responsible for cloudifying bare metal Linux machines. The easiest way to build your own cloud is to lease instances from one of those providers. For example: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hetzner.com/sb&#34;&gt;https://www.hetzner.com/sb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you lease instance(s), run the following script for each instance to cloudify the instance. By default, the script cloudifies bare metal instances leased from Hetzner. After you cloudify your instances, you can provision and manage cloud resources on these machines.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Enter hostname/IP and provider, and install SSH key as instructed by script&#xA;docker exec -it ubicloud-app ./demo/cloudify_server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Later when you create VMs, Ubicloud will assign them IPv6 addresses. If your ISP doesn&#39;t support IPv6, please use a VPN or tunnel broker such Mullvad or Hurricane Electric&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://tunnelbroker.net/&#34;&gt;https://tunnelbroker.net/&lt;/a&gt; to connect. Alternatively, you could lease IPv4 addresses from your provider and add them to your control plane.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why use it&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Public cloud providers like AWS, Azure, and Google Cloud made life easier for start-ups and enterprises. But they are closed source, have you rent computers at a huge premium, and lock you in. Ubicloud offers an open alternative, reduces your costs, and returns control of your infrastructure back to you. All without sacrificing the cloud&#39;s convenience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today, AWS offers about two hundred cloud services. Ultimately, we will implement 10% of the cloud services that make up 80% of that consumption.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example workloads and reasons to use Ubicloud today include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You have an ephemeral workload like a CI/CD pipeline (we&#39;re integrating with GitHub Actions), or you&#39;d like to run compute/memory heavy tests. Our managed cloud is ~3x cheaper than AWS, so you save on costs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You want a portable and simple app deployment service like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrsked/mrsk&#34;&gt;MRSK&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;re moving Ubicloud&#39;s control plane from Heroku to MRSK; and we want to provide open and portable services for MRSK&#39;s dependencies in the process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You have bare metal machines sitting somewhere. You&#39;d like to build your own cloud for portability, security, or compliance reasons.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ubicloud is in public alpha. You can provide us your feedback, get help, or ask us to support your network environment in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/discussions&#34;&gt;Community Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We follow an established architectural pattern in building public cloud services. A control plane manages a data plane, where the data plane leverages open source software. You can find our current cloud components / services below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elastic Compute&lt;/strong&gt;: Our control plane communicates with Linux bare metal servers using SSH. We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cloud-hypervisor/cloud-hypervisor&#34;&gt;Cloud Hypervisor&lt;/a&gt; as our virtual machine monitor (VMM); and each instance of the VMM is contained within Linux namespaces for further isolation / security.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Virtual Networking&lt;/strong&gt;: We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPsec&#34;&gt;IPsec&lt;/a&gt; tunneling to establish an encrypted and private network environment. We support IPv4 and IPv6 in a dual-stack setup and provide both public and private networking. For security, each customer’s VMs operate in their own networking namespace. Everything in virtual networking is layer 3 and up.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block Storage, non replicated&lt;/strong&gt;: We use Storage Performance Development Toolkit (&lt;a href=&#34;https://spdk.io&#34;&gt;SPDK&lt;/a&gt;) to provide virtualized block storage to VMs. SPDK enables us to add enterprise features such as snapshot and replication in the future. We follow security best practices and encrypt the data encryption key itself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attribute-Based Access Control (ABAC)&lt;/strong&gt;: With ABAC, you can define attributes, roles, and permissions for users and give them fine-grained access to resources. You can read more about our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/main/doc/authorization.md&#34;&gt;ABAC design here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&#39;s Next?&lt;/strong&gt;: We&#39;re planning to work on the elastic load balancer or simple storage service next. If you have a workload that would benefit from a specific cloud service, please get in touch with us through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/discussions&#34;&gt;Community Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Control plane: Manages data plane services and resources. This is a Ruby program that stores its data in Postgres. We use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roda.jeremyevans.net/&#34;&gt;Roda&lt;/a&gt; framework to serve HTTP requests and &lt;a href=&#34;http://sequel.jeremyevans.net/&#34;&gt;Sequel&lt;/a&gt; to access the database. We manage web authentication with &lt;a href=&#34;http://rodauth.jeremyevans.net/&#34;&gt;RodAuth&lt;/a&gt;. We communicate with data plane servers using SSH, via the library &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/net-ssh/net-ssh&#34;&gt;net-ssh&lt;/a&gt;. For our tests, we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://rspec.info/&#34;&gt;RSpec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cloud console: Server-side web app served by the Roda framework. For the visual design, we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://tailwindcss.com&#34;&gt;Tailwind CSS&lt;/a&gt; with components from &lt;a href=&#34;https://tailwindui.com&#34;&gt;Tailwind UI&lt;/a&gt;. We also use jQuery for interactivity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to start hacking with Ubicloud, any method of obtaining Ruby and Postgres versions is acceptable. If you have no opinion on this, our development team uses &lt;code&gt;asdf-vm&lt;/code&gt; as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ubicloud/ubicloud/main/DEVELOPERS.md&#34;&gt;documented here in detail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Do you have any experience with building this sort of thing?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our founding team comes from Azure; and worked at Amazon and Heroku before that. We also have start-up experience. We were co-founders and founding team members at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/citusdata/citus&#34;&gt;Citus Data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18990469&#34;&gt;which got acquired by Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How is this different than OpenStack?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We see three differences. First, Ubicloud is available as a managed service (vs boxed software). This way, you can get started in minutes rather than weeks. Since Ubicloud is designed for multi-tenancy, it comes with built-in with features such as encryption at rest and in transit, virtual networking, secrets rotation, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Second, we&#39;re initially targeting developers. This -we hope- will give us fast feedback cycles and enable us to have 6 key services in GA form in the next two years. OpenStack is still primarily used for 3 cloud services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last, we&#39;re designing for simplicity. With OpenStack, you pick between 10 hypervisors, 10 S3 implementations, and 5 block storage implementations. The software needs to work in a way where all of these implementations are compatible with each other. That leads to consultant-ware. We&#39;ll take a more opinionated approach with Ubicloud.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>