<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Ruby Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-12T01:55:50Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Ruby in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>TheOdinProject/ruby-exercises</title>
    <updated>2023-11-12T01:55:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-12:/TheOdinProject/ruby-exercises</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TheOdinProject/ruby-exercises" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Odin Project Ruby Exercises&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is a complement to the Ruby course for The Odin Project. It contains a series of Ruby exercises alongside pre-written tests that will help guide the student towards a solution, providing a Test Driven Development experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each set of exercises should only be done &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; being directed to do so in the assignment of the corresponding Ruby lesson. I.e. if you just finished the Basic Data Types lesson you should &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; do the exercises in the &lt;code&gt;1_data_types&lt;/code&gt; folder for now.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Cloning and installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone this repository to your local machine. To do this, click on the green &#34;Code&#34; button at the top right of list of files and copy the link in the prompt. Then, run the following command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone &amp;lt;link&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will create a folder called &#39;ruby-exercises&#39; inside the directory you ran the command in.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CD into that folder:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ruby-exercises&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now before beginning work on the exercises, you&#39;ll want to install a gem called RSpec. RSpec is a popular Ruby testing framework that is used in this repository to provide you with tests that check your solutions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install RSpec, run the following command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install rspec&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should see a message that says something along the lines of &#34;6 gems installed&#34; in your terminal. Verify that the installation was successful by simply running the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rspec&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which should print a few lines about not finding any examples. This is ok and means it&#39;s working!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your shell reports that it cannot find the rspec binary, it may be necessary to run the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rbenv rehash&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each directory contains a read me with instructions for the exercises within them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>