<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-21T01:47:41Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>StanfordBDHG/HealthGPT</title>
    <updated>2023-04-21T01:47:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-21:/StanfordBDHG/HealthGPT</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/HealthGPT" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Query your Apple Health data with natural language 💬 🩺&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HealthGPT&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StanfordBDHG/HealthGPT/main/Figures/Example.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example Conversation&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HealthGPT is an experimental iOS app that allows users to interact with their health data stored in the Apple Health app using natural language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Built on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/CardinalKit&#34;&gt;CardinalKit&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/CardinalKitTemplateApplication/&#34;&gt;CardinalKitTemplateApplication&lt;/a&gt; and OpenAI. HealthGPT offers an easy-to-extend solution for those looking to make large language model powered apps within the Apple Health ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chat-style interface for user-friendly health data interaction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integration with the Apple Health app to ensure seamless first-party data usage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extensible architecture built on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/CardinalKit&#34;&gt;CardinalKit&lt;/a&gt; for easy customization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GPT-3.5 + GPT-4 access through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MacPaw/OpenAI&#34;&gt;OpenAI&lt;/a&gt; Swift module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Out of the box support for querying sleep, step count, active energy, exercise minutes, heart rate, and body mass.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HealthGPT is provided for general informational purposes only and is not intended as a substitute for professional medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment. Large language models, such as those provided by OpenAI, are known to hallucinate and at times return false information. The use of HealthGPT is at your own risk. Always consult a qualified healthcare provider for personalized advice regarding your health and well-being. Aggregated HealthKit data for the past 14 days will be uploaded to OpenAI. Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/policies/privacy-policy&#34;&gt;OpenAI privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Set Up&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;HealthGPT.xcodeproj&lt;/code&gt; in Xcode. Wait for all dependencies to install and indexing to finish.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Replace the OpenAI API key placeholder in &lt;code&gt;Supporting Files/OpenAI-Info.plist&lt;/code&gt; with your own from OpenAI&#39;s dashboard. You can also paste your key into the app during onboarding.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the app (on device or in the simulator) and play with HealthGPT on your own data 🚀&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: if you&#39;re using the simulator, you will need to manually add data in the Health app. Otherwise, all of your results will read zero.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can add queries for additional &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/healthkit&#34;&gt;HealthKit&lt;/a&gt; quantities and categories as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;HealthGPT/HealthGPT/HealthDataFetcher.swift&lt;/code&gt; to create an appropriate query for your data type.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update the prompt in &lt;code&gt;HealthGPT/HealthGPT/MessageInputView.swift&lt;/code&gt; to pass the newly acquired data to the OpenAI API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any other quick changes (such as adding an onboarding flow), refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/CardinalKitTemplateApplication/&#34;&gt;CardinalKitTemplateApplication&lt;/a&gt; repo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to this project are welcome. Please make sure to read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/.github/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contribution guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StanfordBDHG/.github/raw/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;contributor covenant code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StanfordBDHG/.github/main/assets/biodesign-footer-light.png#gh-light-mode-only&#34; alt=&#34;Stanford Byers Center for Biodesign Logo&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/StanfordBDHG/.github/main/assets/biodesign-footer-dark.png#gh-dark-mode-only&#34; alt=&#34;Stanford Byers Center for Biodesign Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>shaunnarayan/cytev2</title>
    <updated>2023-04-21T01:47:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-21:/shaunnarayan/cytev2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/shaunnarayan/cytev2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MacOS background screen recorder/reader for easy history search&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;🧐 Cyte&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shaunnarayan/cytev2/actions/workflows/swift-xcode.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/shaunnarayan/cytev2/actions/workflows/swift-xcode.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Xcode - Build and Analyze&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-yellow.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License: MIT&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cataddict42&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/url/https/twitter.com/cataddict42.svg?style=social&amp;amp;label=%20%40CatAddict42&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Work in progress - this is beta software, use with care&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A background screen recorder for easy history search. If you choose to supply an OpenAI key, or a local language model like LLaMA, it can act as a knowledge base. Be aware that transcriptions will be sent to OpenAI when you chat if you provide an OpenAI API key.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shaunnarayan/cytev2/main/assets/images/cyte.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Cyte Screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Uses&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;🧠 Train-of-thought recovery&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Autosave isn’t always an option, in those cases you can easily recover your train of thought, a screenshot to use as a stencil, or extracted copy from memories recorded.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;🌏 Search across applications&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of research involves collating information from multiple sources; internal tools like confluence, websites like wikipedia, pdf and doc files etc; When searching for something we don’t always remember the source (or it&#39;s at the tip of your tongue)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;When no OpenAI key is supplied, and browser context awareness is disabled, Cyte is completely private, data is stored on disk only, no outside connections are made&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Pause/Restart recording easily&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Set applications that are not to be recorded (while taking keystrokes)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Chat your data; ask questions about work you&#39;ve done&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy to accept PRs related to any of the following&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Issues&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;App sandbox is disabled to allow file tracking; &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/70972475&#34;&gt;instead should request document permissions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Timeline slider not updating while video playing (timeJumped notification not sent until pause)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build process fails on Github (Needs signing cert installed to sign embedded content?)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Should not &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/avkit/avplayerview/3986556-allowsvideoframeanalysis&#34;&gt;perform video analysis&lt;/a&gt; on feed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Some results from searching fail to highlight the result snippet&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keyboard navigation events: Return to open selected episode, escape to pop timeline view&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fallback to object recognition&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Encryption e.g. Filevault?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these great open source projects:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/diff-match-patch&#34;&gt;DiffMatchPatch&lt;/a&gt;: Used to differentiate unchanged and changed text from OCR&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmandry/AXSwift&#34;&gt;AXSwift&lt;/a&gt;: Used for browser context awareness&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evgenyneu/keychain-swift&#34;&gt;KeychainSwift&lt;/a&gt;: Used to securely store API keys in the Apple Keychain Manager&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stephencelis/SQLite.swift&#34;&gt;SQLite.swift&lt;/a&gt;: Used for the text search functionality&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DaveWoodCom/XCGLogger&#34;&gt;XCGLogger&lt;/a&gt;: Used to save debug logs to disk&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ggerganov/llama.cpp&#34;&gt;llama.cpp&lt;/a&gt;: Used to load and run LLMs for chat when a local model is provided&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MacPaw/OpenAI&#34;&gt;MacPaw OpenAI&lt;/a&gt;: Used to run LLMs for chat when OpenAI API enabled&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>