<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-27T01:40:33Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>sourcelocation/AirTroller</title>
    <updated>2022-11-27T01:40:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-27:/sourcelocation/AirTroller</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sourcelocation/AirTroller" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AirDrop spammer / flooder to troll friends&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AirTroller&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AirDrop spammer / flooder to troll friends&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/52459150/203855388-0ca5b060-fb64-4181-affc-68bfa917b230.png&#34; alt=&#34;Artboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join my Discord server &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/VyVcNjRMeg&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/VyVcNjRMeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s the difference between TrollDrop and AirTroller?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TrollDrop is also an AirDrop spammer, but broke on iOS 12-13, when Apple started introducing &#34;auto-decline&#34; techniques. AirTroller utilises a different method: sending a request and then canceling it right as target receives it, tested on iOS 14-15.7.1 target devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Wasn&#39;t it meant to be a $4.99 tweak?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I planned AirTroller to be a paid tweak / app. I spent so much time on this project, so much effort, that it was awfuly painful to just give away my hard work for free. Why have I decided so? Well, iOS 16 significantly improved AirDrop &#34;auto decline&#34;, which AirTroller was abusing - a big deal for a tweak centered around trolling your friends. It does work on iOS 15 though. I honestly don&#39;t know what to do with this tweak, because on one side it&#39;s a fun project I was working on for around a month I wanted to sell and finally replace my fried GPU, but on the other, it gets more and more useless every day, destroying it&#39;s whole purpose. I highly appreciate if you decide to donate :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What devices does AirTroller support?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Troller: iOS 14 and above, TrollStore and Jailbreak Victim: See above, it&#39;s important&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I, the creator, am not responsible for any actions, and or damages, caused by this software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You bear the full responsibility of your actions and acknowledge that this software was created for educational purposes only.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software&#39;s main purpose is NOT to be used maliciously, or targeting other&#39;s devices, or have the right to use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By using this software, you automatically agree to the above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Credits:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/midnightchip/trolldrop&#34;&gt;https://github.com/midnightchip/trolldrop&lt;/a&gt; - MIT&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>