<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-27T01:37:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>huggingface/chat-macOS</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T01:37:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-27:/huggingface/chat-macOS</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/huggingface/chat-macOS" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Making the community&#39;s best AI chat models available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/huggingface/chat-macOS/main/assets/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;HuggingChat macOS Banner&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;margin-top: 0;&#34;&gt;HuggingChat macOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache-orange&#34; alt=&#34;Static Badge&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apple/swift&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Swift-6.0-brightgreen.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;swift-version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apple/swift&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Platform-macOS_14.0-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;platform&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HuggingChat macOS is a native chat interface designed specifically for macOS users, leveraging the power of open-source language models. It brings the capabilities of advanced AI conversation right to your desktop, offering a seamless and intuitive experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Demo&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/dacc87b2-2242-4ef5-84d5-9f9aae50c453&#34;&gt;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/dacc87b2-2242-4ef5-84d5-9f9aae50c453&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/huggingface/chat-macOS/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; section of this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the latest &lt;code&gt;HuggingChat-macOS.zip&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unzip the downloaded file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drag the &lt;code&gt;HuggingChat.app&lt;/code&gt; to your Applications folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Homebrew&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HuggingChat is also available via Homebrew. Simply run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew install --cask huggingchat&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it! You can now launch HuggingChat from your Applications folder or using the dedicated keyboard shortcut: &lt;code&gt;⌘ + Shift + Return&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;VSCode Integration&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to use HuggingChat in VSCode, you&#39;ll need to install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cyrilzakka/huggingchat-helper&#34;&gt;HuggingChat Extension&lt;/a&gt;. After downloading it, add it to VSCode by navigating to the Extensions tab and selecting &#34;Install from VSIX&#34;. Choose the downloaded file and restart VSCode. HuggingChat can now use context from your code editor to provide more accurate responses.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Development Setup&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Xcode 16.0 or later&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;macOS 14.0 or later&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Building the Project&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/huggingface/chat-macOS.git&#xA;cd HuggingChat-macOS&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;HuggingChat-macOS.xcodeproj&lt;/code&gt; in Xcode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select your development team in the project settings if you plan to run on a physical device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build and run the project (⌘ + R)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Making Contributions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;1. Choose or Create an Issue&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check existing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/huggingface/chat-macOS/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; for something you&#39;d like to work on&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new issue if you have a bug fix or feature proposal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Comment on the issue to let maintainers know you&#39;re working on it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;2. Fork and Branch&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the repository to your GitHub account&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new branch for your work: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git checkout -b feature/your-feature-name&#xA;# or&#xA;git checkout -b fix/your-bug-fix&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;3. Code Style Guidelines&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow Apple&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/documentation/api-design-guidelines/&#34;&gt;Swift API Design Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use SwiftLint rules defined in the project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maintain consistent spacing and formatting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Write meaningful commit messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add comments for complex logic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We value your input! If you have any suggestions, encounter issues, or want to share your experience, please feel free to reach out:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/strong&gt;: For bug reports or feature requests, please create an issue in this repository. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Provide a clear title and description of your feedback&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Include steps to reproduce the issue (for bugs) or detailed explanation (for feature requests)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Include the app version number and macOS version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Submit the issue&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback helps improve HuggingChat macOS for everyone. Thank you for your support!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>swiftlang/swift-foundation</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T01:37:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-27:/swiftlang/swift-foundation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/swiftlang/swift-foundation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Foundation project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Foundation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation provides a base layer of functionality useful in many applications, including fundamental types for numbers, data, collections, and dates, as well as functions for task management, file system access, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is designed with these goals in mind:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Provide a small set of basic utility types&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable a level of platform independence, to enhance portability&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Demonstrate useful conventions that can be widely adopted by the Swift ecosystem&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support internationalization and localization to make software accessible around the world&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project, &lt;code&gt;swift-foundation&lt;/code&gt;, provides a shared implementation of key Foundation API for all platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On macOS, iOS, and other Apple platforms, apps should use the Foundation that comes with the operating system. The Foundation framework includes this code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On all other Swift platforms, &lt;code&gt;swift-foundation&lt;/code&gt; is available as part of the toolchain. Simply &lt;code&gt;import FoundationEssentials&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;import FoundationInternationalization&lt;/code&gt; to use its API. It is also re-exported from &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/apple/swift-corelibs-foundation&#34;&gt;swift-corelibs-foundation&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;code&gt;Foundation&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;FoundationXML&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;FoundationNetworking&lt;/code&gt; modules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building and Testing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] Building swift-foundation requires the in-development Swift 6.0 toolchain. You can download the Swift 6.0 nightly toolchain from &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/install&#34;&gt;the Swift website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before building Foundation, first ensure that you have a Swift toolchain installed. Next, check out the &lt;em&gt;Getting Started&lt;/em&gt; section of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/swift-foundation/main/Foundation_Build_Process.md#getting-started&#34;&gt;Foundation Build Process&lt;/a&gt; guide for detailed steps on building and testing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Navigator&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation builds in different configurations and is composed of several projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;  graph TD;&#xA;      FF[Foundation.framework]--&amp;gt;SF&#xA;      subgraph GitHub&#xA;        SCLF[swift-corelibs-foundation]--&amp;gt;SF&#xA;        SF[swift-foundation]--&amp;gt;FICU[swift-foundation-icu]&#xA;        SF--&amp;gt;SC[swift-collections]&#xA;      end   &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Swift Foundation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shared library shipped in the Swift toolchain, written in Swift. It provides the core implementation of many key types, including &lt;code&gt;URL&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Data&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;JSONDecoder&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Locale&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Calendar&lt;/code&gt;, and more in the &lt;code&gt;FoundationEssentials&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FoundationInternationalization&lt;/code&gt; modules. Its source code is shared across all platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;swift-foundation&lt;/em&gt; depends on a limited set of packages, primarily &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/apple/swift-collections&#34;&gt;swift-collections&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/swiftlang/swift-syntax&#34;&gt;swift-syntax&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Swift Corelibs Foundation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A shared library shipped in the Swift toolchain. It provides compatibility API for clients that need pre-Swift API from Foundation. It is written in Swift and C. It provides, among other types, &lt;code&gt;NSObject&lt;/code&gt;, class-based data structures, &lt;code&gt;NSFormatter&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;NSKeyedArchiver&lt;/code&gt;. It re-exports the &lt;code&gt;FoundationEssentials&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FoundationInternationalization&lt;/code&gt; modules, allowing compatibility for source written before the introduction of the &lt;em&gt;swift-foundation&lt;/em&gt; project. As these implementations are distinct from those written in Objective-C, the compatibility is best-effort only.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/apple/swift-corelibs-foundation&#34;&gt;swift-corelibs-foundation&lt;/a&gt; builds for non-Darwin platforms only. It installs the &lt;code&gt;Foundation&lt;/code&gt; umbrella module, &lt;code&gt;FoundationXML&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;FoundationNetworking&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Foundation ICU&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A private library for Foundation, wrapping ICU. Using a standard version of ICU provides stability in the behavior of our internationalization API, and consistency with the latest releases on Darwin platforms. It is imported from the &lt;code&gt;FoundationInternationalization&lt;/code&gt; module only. Clients that do not need API that relies upon the data provided by ICU can import &lt;code&gt;FoundationEssentials&lt;/code&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Foundation Framework&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/MacOSX/Conceptual/BPFrameworks/Frameworks.html&#34;&gt;framework&lt;/a&gt; built into macOS, iOS, and all other Darwin platforms. It is written in a combination of C, Objective-C, and Swift. The Foundation framework compiles the sources from &lt;em&gt;swift-foundation&lt;/em&gt; into its binary and provides one &lt;code&gt;Foundation&lt;/code&gt; module that contains all features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Governance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation&#39;s goal is to create the best fundamental data types and internationalization features, and make them available to Swift developers everywhere. It takes advantage of emerging features in the language as they are added, and enables library and app authors to build higher level API with confidence.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is part of the overall &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org&#34;&gt;Swift project&lt;/a&gt;. It has a workgroup to (a) oversee &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/swift-foundation/main/Evolution.md&#34;&gt;community API proposals&lt;/a&gt; and (b) to closely coordinate with developments in the Swift project and Apple platforms. The workgroup meets regularly to review proposals, look at emerging trends in the Swift ecosystem, and discuss how the library should evolve.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Foundation welcomes contributions from the community, including bug fixes, tests, documentation, and ports to new platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.swift.org/c/related-projects/foundation/99&#34;&gt;Swift forums for discussion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apple/swift-foundation/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt; for tracking bugs, feature requests, and other work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apple/swift-foundation/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; document for more information, including the process for accepting community contributions for new API in Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>