<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-12T01:47:13Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>hotwired/turbo-ios</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T01:47:13Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-12:/hotwired/turbo-ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hotwired/turbo-ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;iOS framework for making Turbo native apps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Turbo Native for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The Hotwire frameworks are presented in beta form. We&#39;re using them all in production with HEY, but expect that significant changes might be made in response to early feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build high-fidelity hybrid apps with native navigation and a single shared web view.&lt;/strong&gt; Turbo Native for iOS provides the tooling to wrap your &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hotwired/turbo&#34;&gt;Turbo 7&lt;/a&gt;-enabled web app in a native iOS shell. It manages a single WKWebView instance across multiple view controllers, giving you native navigation UI with all the client-side performance benefits of Turbo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliver fast, efficient hybrid apps.&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid reloading JavaScript and CSS. Save memory by sharing one WKWebView.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reuse mobile web views across platforms.&lt;/strong&gt; Create your views once, on the server, in HTML. Deploy them to iOS, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hotwired/turbo-android&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;, and mobile browsers simultaneously. Ship new features without waiting on App Store approval.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhance web views with native UI.&lt;/strong&gt; Navigate web views using native patterns. Augment web UI with native controls.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Produce large apps with small teams.&lt;/strong&gt; Achieve baseline HTML coverage for free. Upgrade to native views as needed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turbo iOS is written in Swift 5.3 and requires iOS 12 or higher, but we&#39;ll most likely drop iOS 12 in the near future. It supports web apps using either Turbo 7 or Turbolinks 5. The Turbo iOS framework has no dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You should understand how Turbo works with web applications in the browser before attempting to use Turbo iOS. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hotwired/turbo&#34;&gt;Turbo 7 documentation&lt;/a&gt; for details. Ensure that your web app sets the &lt;code&gt;window.Turbo&lt;/code&gt; global variable as it&#39;s required by the native apps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;import { Turbo } from &#34;@hotwired/turbo-rails&#34;&#xA;window.Turbo = Turbo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to get started with Turbo iOS to try out the demo app first to get familiar with the framework. The demo app walks you through all the basic Turbo flows as well as some advanced features. To run the demo, clone this repo and open &lt;code&gt;Demo/Demo.xcworkspace&lt;/code&gt; in Xcode and run the Demo target. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Demo/README.md&#34;&gt;Demo/README.md&lt;/a&gt; for more details about the demo. When you’re ready to start your own application, read through the rest of the documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/Installation.md&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/QuickStartGuide.md&#34;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/Overview.md&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/Authentication.md&#34;&gt;Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/PathConfiguration.md&#34;&gt;Path Configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/Migration.md&#34;&gt;Migration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/Docs/Advanced.md&#34;&gt;Advanced&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turbo iOS is open-source software, freely distributable under the terms of an &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT-style license&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hotwired/turbo-ios&#34;&gt;source code is hosted on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Development is sponsored by &lt;a href=&#34;https://basecamp.com/&#34;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions in the form of bug reports, pull requests, or thoughtful discussions in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that this project is released with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/hotwired/turbo-ios/main/CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Contributor Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. By participating in this project you agree to abide by its terms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;© 2020 Basecamp, LLC&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>