<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-08T01:44:07Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>leetcode-mafia/cheetah</title>
    <updated>2023-04-08T01:44:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-08:/leetcode-mafia/cheetah</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/leetcode-mafia/cheetah" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whisper &amp; GPT-based app for passing remote SWE interviews&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Cheetah&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cheetah is an AI-powered macOS app designed to assist users during remote software engineering interviews by providing real-time, discreet coaching and live coding platform integration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/106342593/229961889-489e2b36-f3e6-453a-9784-f160bc1c4f8d.mp4&#34; alt=&#34;Quick demo video (1:28)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/leetcode-mafia/cheetah/raw/91cc5b89864fe28476a7e2062ede2c8322c17896/cheetah.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Cheetah, you can improve your interview performance and increase your chances of landing that $300k SWE job, without spending your weekends cramming leetcode challenges and memorizing algorithms you&#39;ll never use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cheetah leverages Whisper for real-time audio transcription and GPT-4 for generating hints and solutions. You need to have your own OpenAI API key to use the app. If you don&#39;t have access to GPT-4, gpt-3.5-turbo may be used as an alternative.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whisper runs locally on your system, utilizing Georgi Gerganov&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ggerganov/whisper.cpp&#34;&gt;whisper.cpp&lt;/a&gt;. A recent M1 or M2 Mac is required for optimal performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Audio driver setup&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the best results, ensure the audio input captures both sides of the conversation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When using a video chat app like Zoom or Google Meet, you can achieve this with &lt;a href=&#34;https://existential.audio/blackhole/&#34;&gt;BlackHole&lt;/a&gt;, a free audio loopback driver. Follow the instructions for setting up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ExistentialAudio/BlackHole/wiki/Multi-Output-Device&#34;&gt;Multi-Output Device&lt;/a&gt;, and remember not to use the loopback device as input for the video chat app.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;App overview&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open the app and select an audio input to start live transcription. A snippet of the transcription will be displayed under the audio input selector.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; running the app in debug mode will result in very slow audio transcription performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UI features three buttons:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Answer:&lt;/strong&gt; Generates an answer for the interviewer&#39;s question.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refine:&lt;/strong&gt; Updates the existing answer, useful for when the interviewer provides additional constraints or clarification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze:&lt;/strong&gt; Analyzes code and logs from the live coding environment in your web browser. Requires the browser extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also select (highlight) a portion of a generated answer and click Refine to get more detail.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installing the browser extension&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, only Firefox is supported. Follow these steps to install the extension:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the domain of the live coding platform to &lt;code&gt;matches&lt;/code&gt; in ./extension/manifest.json&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://firefox-source-docs.mozilla.org/devtools-user/about_colon_debugging/index.html&#34;&gt;about:debugging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click &#34;This Firefox&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click &#34;Load Temporary Add-on&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select ./extension/manifest.json&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cheetah is a satirical art project and is not intended for use in real-world settings. It may generate incorrect or inappropriate solutions. Users should exercise caution and take responsibility for the information provided by the app.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>