<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-02T01:45:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>FelixKrueger/TrimGalore</title>
    <updated>2022-10-02T01:45:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-02:/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A wrapper around Cutadapt and FastQC to consistently apply adapter and quality trimming to FastQ files, with extra functionality for RRBS data&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Trim Galore&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trim Galore&lt;/em&gt; is a wrapper around &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marcelm/cutadapt&#34;&gt;Cutadapt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bioinformatics.babraham.ac.uk/projects/fastqc/&#34;&gt;FastQC&lt;/a&gt; to consistently apply adapter and quality trimming to FastQ files, with extra functionality for RRBS data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/62039322&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/62039322.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bioconda.github.io/recipes/trim-galore/README.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/install%20with-bioconda-brightgreen.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;install with bioconda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://quay.io/repository/biocontainers/trim-galore&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://quay.io/repository/biocontainers/trim-galore/status&#34; alt=&#34;container ready&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trim Galore&lt;/em&gt; is a a Perl wrapper around two tools: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marcelm/cutadapt&#34;&gt;Cutadapt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bioinformatics.babraham.ac.uk/projects/fastqc/&#34;&gt;FastQC&lt;/a&gt;. To use, ensure that these two pieces of software are available and copy the &lt;code&gt;trim_galore&lt;/code&gt; script to a location available on the &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Check that cutadapt is installed&#xA;cutadapt --version&#xA;# Check that FastQC is installed&#xA;fastqc -v&#xA;# Install Trim Galore&#xA;curl -fsSL https://github.com/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore/archive/0.6.6.tar.gz -o trim_galore.tar.gz&#xA;tar xvzf trim_galore.tar.gz&#xA;# Run Trim Galore&#xA;~/TrimGalore-0.6.6/trim_galore&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instructions on how to use &lt;em&gt;Trim Galore&lt;/em&gt;, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FelixKrueger/TrimGalore/master/Docs/Trim_Galore_User_Guide.md&#34;&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trim Galore&lt;/em&gt; was developed at The Babraham Institute by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FelixKrueger/&#34;&gt;@FelixKrueger&lt;/a&gt;. You can find it&#39;s project page here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bioinformatics.babraham.ac.uk/projects/trim_galore/&#34;&gt;bioinformatics.babraham.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Logitech/slimserver</title>
    <updated>2022-10-02T01:45:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-02:/Logitech/slimserver</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Logitech/slimserver" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Server for Logitech Squeezebox players. This server is also called Logitech Media Server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Logitech Media Server&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logitech Media Server (aka. LMS, fka. SlimServer, SqueezeCenter, SqueezeboxServer, SliMP3) is the server software that powers audio players from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logi.com&#34;&gt;Logitech&lt;/a&gt; (formerly known as SlimDevices), including &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.slimdevices.com/index.php/Squeezebox_Family_Overview&#34;&gt;Squeezebox 3rd Generation, Squeezebox Boom, Squeezebox Receiver, Transporter, Squeezebox2, Squeezebox and SLIMP3&lt;/a&gt;, and many software emulators like &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/lmsclients/files/&#34;&gt;Squeezelite and SqueezePlay&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the help of many plugins, Logitech Media Server can stream not only your local music collection, but content from many music services and internet radio stations to your players.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logitech Media Server is written in Perl. It runs on pretty much any platform that Perl runs on, including Linux, Mac OSX, Solaris and Windows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SB Radio, SB Touch, SB Controller and Logitech Media Server 8+&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the latest Squeezebox Radio/Touch/Controller firmwares (7.x) come with a bug which causes some irritation connecting to Logitech Media Server 8+. The version string comparison function fails to recognize 8.0.0 as more recent than 7.7.3. While the bug has been fixed years ago, the fixed firmware never got released. There&#39;s a workaround built in to Logitech Media Server 8+ now, but you might still get warnings in the log file or on the device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this point in time we&#39;re unfortunately not able to build an official, fixed firmware for distribution. &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.slimdevices.com/showthread.php?113479-Announce-Community-Firmware-for-Squeezebox-Radio-Touch-Controller-and-LMS-8&#34;&gt;The Squeezebox Community has come up with a custom firmware&lt;/a&gt; which, among other bugs, fixes this issue. If you feel confident enough, you can install that 3rd party provided firmware on your device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer not to replace the full firmware of your Squeezebox &lt;em&gt;Radio&lt;/em&gt; (only!), there&#39;s a patch available which you can easily install:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;On the Squeezebox go to Settings/Advanced/Applet Installer. Make sure &#34;Recommended Applets Only&#34; is unchecked, then install the Patch Installer. The device will re-boot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once it&#39;s back, go to Settings/Advanced/Patch Installer and install the &#34;Version Comparison Fix&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the music on your Squeezebox!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Perl/perl5</title>
    <updated>2022-10-02T01:45:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-02:/Perl/perl5</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Perl/perl5" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🐫 The Perl programming language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Perl is Copyright (C) 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, 1998, 1999, 2000,&#xA;2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, 2005, 2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012,&#xA;2013, 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, 2022&#xA;by Larry Wall and others.&#xA;All rights reserved.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ABOUT PERL&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perl is a general-purpose programming language originally developed for text manipulation and now used for a wide range of tasks including system administration, web development, network programming, GUI development, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language is intended to be practical (easy to use, efficient, complete) rather than beautiful (tiny, elegant, minimal). Its major features are that it&#39;s easy to use, supports both procedural and object-oriented (OO) programming, has powerful built-in support for text processing, and has one of the world&#39;s most impressive collections of third-party modules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For an introduction to the language&#39;s features, see pod/perlintro.pod.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a discussion of the important changes in this release, see pod/perldelta.pod.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are also many Perl books available, covering a wide variety of topics, from various publishers. See pod/perlbook.pod for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re using a relatively modern operating system and want to install this version of Perl locally, run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./Configure -des -Dprefix=$HOME/localperl&#xA;make test&#xA;make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will configure and compile perl for your platform, run the regression tests, and install perl in a subdirectory &#34;localperl&#34; of your home directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you run into any trouble whatsoever or you need to install a customized version of Perl, you should read the detailed instructions in the &#34;INSTALL&#34; file that came with this distribution. Additionally, there are a number of &#34;README&#34; files with hints and tips about building and using Perl on a wide variety of platforms, some more common than others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have Perl installed, a wealth of documentation is available to you through the &#39;perldoc&#39; tool. To get started, run this command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perldoc perl&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;IF YOU RUN INTO TROUBLE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perl is a large and complex system that&#39;s used for everything from knitting to rocket science. If you run into trouble, it&#39;s quite likely that someone else has already solved the problem you&#39;re facing. Once you&#39;ve exhausted the documentation, please report bugs to us at the GitHub issue tracker at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Perl/perl5/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While it was current when we made it available, Perl is constantly evolving and there may be a more recent version that fixes bugs you&#39;ve run into or adds new features that you might find useful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can always find the latest version of perl on a CPAN (Comprehensive Perl Archive Network) site near you at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cpan.org/src/&#34;&gt;https://www.cpan.org/src/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to submit a simple patch to the perl source, see the &#34;SUPER QUICK PATCH GUIDE&#34; in pod/perlhack.pod.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a personal note: I want you to know that I create nice things like this because it pleases the Author of my story. If this bothers you, then your notion of Authorship needs some revision. But you can use perl anyway. :-)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;LICENSING&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify&#xA;it under the terms of either:&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;a) the GNU General Public License as published by the Free&#xA;&#x9;Software Foundation; either version 1, or (at your option) any&#xA;&#x9;later version, or&#xA;&#xA;&#x9;b) the &#34;Artistic License&#34; which comes with this Kit.&#xA;&#xA;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,&#xA;but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See either&#xA;the GNU General Public License or the Artistic License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the Artistic License with this&#xA;Kit, in the file named &#34;Artistic&#34;.  If not, I&#39;ll be glad to provide one.&#xA;&#xA;You should also have received a copy of the GNU General Public License&#xA;along with this program in the file named &#34;Copying&#34;. If not, write to the&#xA;Free Software Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor,&#xA;Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA or visit their web page on the internet at&#xA;https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/gpl.html.&#xA;&#xA;For those of you that choose to use the GNU General Public License,&#xA;my interpretation of the GNU General Public License is that no Perl&#xA;script falls under the terms of the GPL unless you explicitly put&#xA;said script under the terms of the GPL yourself.  Furthermore, any&#xA;object code linked with perl does not automatically fall under the&#xA;terms of the GPL, provided such object code only adds definitions&#xA;of subroutines and variables, and does not otherwise impair the&#xA;resulting interpreter from executing any standard Perl script.  I&#xA;consider linking in C subroutines in this manner to be the moral&#xA;equivalent of defining subroutines in the Perl language itself.  You&#xA;may sell such an object file as proprietary provided that you provide&#xA;or offer to provide the Perl source, as specified by the GNU General&#xA;Public License.  (This is merely an alternate way of specifying input&#xA;to the program.)  You may also sell a binary produced by the dumping of&#xA;a running Perl script that belongs to you, provided that you provide or&#xA;offer to provide the Perl source as specified by the GPL.  (The&#xA;fact that a Perl interpreter and your code are in the same binary file&#xA;is, in this case, a form of mere aggregation.)  This is my interpretation&#xA;of the GPL.  If you still have concerns or difficulties understanding&#xA;my intent, feel free to contact me.  Of course, the Artistic License&#xA;spells all this out for your protection, so you may prefer to use that.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>