<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-17T01:56:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mcsaucy/Shazbot</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:56:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/mcsaucy/Shazbot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mcsaucy/Shazbot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Perl IRC bot that accepts Wikipedia, Wolfram|Alpha, and Bit.ly queries and responds accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>IanMulvany/connotea-public</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:56:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/IanMulvany/connotea-public</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/IanMulvany/connotea-public" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;public snapshot of current connotea code under GIT revision control&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;NAME Connotea Code&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;COPYRIGHT AND LICENSE (c) Copyright 2005-2007 Nature Publishing Group.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it&#xA;under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the&#xA;Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at your&#xA;option) any later version.&#xA;&#xA;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but&#xA;WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of&#xA;MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General&#xA;Public License for more details.&#xA;&#xA;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along&#xA;with this program; if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc.,&#xA;59 Temple Place - Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.&#xA;&#xA;Some portions regarding RDF are originally from RDF::Core, derived from&#xA;works Copyright (C) 2001 Ginger Alliance Ltd., and carry their own&#xA;copyright and GPL notices.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NAMING You will the see the names Connotea, Bibliotech and Connotea Code used. To eliminate any confusion, we&#39;ll clarify the meaning of those names here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Connotea is the name of the online reference management service created&#xA;and run by Nature Publishing Group (NPG). Bibliotech was the initial&#xA;project name used at NPG while the service was being developed, and&#xA;hence this name is used for some class and variable names in the code.&#xA;The release of the underlying technology for Connotea is known as&#xA;Connotea Code. The purpose of this page and the SourceForge project is&#xA;to make the code that runs this site publicly available for review and&#xA;re-use.&#xA;&#xA;Therefore, it makes sense to refer to Connotea the service, or to the&#xA;Connotea Code. However, Connotea is a trademark of Nature Publishing&#xA;Group, so if you use the code to create your own bookmarking service, we&#xA;ask that you don&#39;t brand it as Connotea. We also ask that you include&#xA;the following footer on your site:&#xA;&#xA;  This site is powered by&#xA;  &amp;lt;a href=&#34;http://sf.net/projects/connotea&#34;&amp;gt;Connotea Code&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;,&#xA;  the open source software behind&#xA;  &amp;lt;a href=&#34;http://www.connotea.org/&#34;&amp;gt;Connotea&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&#xA;&#xA;The Connotea logo, the site guide and related documentation, other image&#xA;files and stylesheets are copyrighted by NPG and are not released under&#xA;the GPL.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ABOUT THE CODE Connotea Code runs a social bookmarking web site for users to save and share links, which can have citation data automatically retrieved from authoritative sources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Connotea Code is written in Perl, and uses MySQL as the data store. It&#xA;runs as a mod_perl handler in Apache2, and uses templates for page&#xA;presentation.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DOWNLOAD Download the tarball from the connotea SourceForge project area at &lt;a href=&#34;http://sf.net/projects/connotea&#34;&gt;http://sf.net/projects/connotea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The current stable release is version 1.8.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPGRADING NEW FEATURES FROM 1.7.1 TO 1.8 * Web API in regular use. * Template Toolkit based templates in regular use. * More optimized SQL queries for common requests. * Greater use of transactions in MySQL. * Greater flexbility for citation source modules. * New citation source modules, plus improvements to existing modules. * Blog component to create news page from external blog. * Wiki component to create custom wiki. * Admin component with user search. * Integration with Bibutils library for BibTeX and MODS output. * Antispam system with captcha and quarantine responses. * Click tracker for all posts. * Alpha-version proxy module system to handle known proxied post URL&#39;s. * Alpha-version stand-alone citation server capability. * Additional tools such as command-line post by API, user recovery, and test suite launch. * Automated deployment scripts, now supporting Darcs instead of CVS. * Updated code to support newer versions of CPAN modules. * More test suite scripts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEW FEATURES FROM 1.5.0 TO 1.7.1 * Many bugs fixed. * Alpha-version Web API. * Alpha-version Template Toolkit based output framework. * Full text searching feature. * Better cache control and throttling. * Better bookmarklets. * Better URI validation. * Better XML encoding for fringe cases. * Better character set decoding of downloaded documents for citations. * Exception email notification. * More support for two instances on same server. * More support for split web/database servers for one instance. * More comprehensive User Agent support for citation modules. * Method to switch from one citation module to another. * Optimized SQL for counting totals and some other operations. * Added methods for profiling code and dumping SQL statements. * Loosen some grammar restrictions, e.g. ok to name a tag &#34;tag&#34;. * Tighten some grammar restrictions, e.g. num &amp;amp; start must be numeric. * Better RIS import based on real-world file examples. * New citation modules:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * Blackwell&#xA;    * PMC&#xA;    * Wiley&#xA;    * ePrints&#xA;&#xA;* Several optional administrator utilities:&#xA;&#xA;    * retro: script to update citation data rectroactively.&#xA;    * bibwatch: load monitoring utility.&#xA;    * bibpreempt: preempting and testing utility.&#xA;    * resendreg: utility to resend registration details.&#xA;    * deluser: utility to delete users.&#xA;    * memcache_wrapper: init.d script to keep memcached running.&#xA;&#xA;* Several developer testing utilities:&#xA;&#xA;    * import: test import modules&#xA;    * citation_source_test.pl: test citation modules&#xA;    * get_test_urls.pl: retrieve URLs from Yahoo for testing citation&#xA;    modules&#xA;    * htmlise.pl: convert citation module test results to clickable HTML&#xA;    for review in a browser&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPGRADING FROM 1.7.1 TO 1.8 See sql/schema_alter.sql for commands to patch your database. Other elements of the upgrade should be optional; that is, you can turn them on later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPGRADING FROM 1.5.0 TO 1.7.1 The biggest difference between 1.5.0 and 1.7.1 is that 1.7.1 uses two databases at once.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;In order to support fulltext matching, a new feature, we use a MyISAM&#xA;database in MySQL with FULLTEXT keys (see&#xA;&amp;lt;http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/4.1/en/fulltext-search.html&amp;gt;).&#xA;&#xA;However, InnoDB is still faster for JOIN&#39;s and offers referential&#xA;integrity, so as a compromise we run two databases and keep them&#xA;synchronized with MySQL replication (see&#xA;&amp;lt;http://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/4.1/en/replication.html&amp;gt;).&#xA;&#xA;If you are upgrading from Connotea Code 1.5.0, please see the section&#xA;below on database setup for the secondary search database. To upgrade,&#xA;you will need to:&#xA;&#xA;* Create a mysql dump that does not mention schema, just data, as in:&#xA;     $ mysqldump -c -t -u bibliotech -p bibliotech &amp;gt; /tmp/dump&#xA;&#xA;* Create the MyISAM search database as described below.&#xA;* Setup replication and restart MySQL as described below.&#xA;* Run sql/wipe.sql to remove all data from your database:&#xA;     $ echo &#39;source sql/wipe.sql&#39; | mysql -u bibliotech -p bibliotech&#xA;&#xA;* Reimport your dump back into your main InnoDB database, from where it&#xA;will flow to the search database because of replication:&#xA;     $ echo &#39;source /tmp/dump&#39; | mysql -u bibliotech -p bibliotech&#xA;&#xA;Except for the addition of a MyISAM database, there are no intradatabase&#xA;schema changes between 1.5.0 and 1.7.1.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPGRADING FROM VERSIONS PRIOR TO 1.5.0 TO 1.7.1 To upgrade from versions prior to 1.5.0, please edit sql/schema_alter.sql to contain only the statements necessary to alter the database schema from your version to the current schema. There are no schema changes between 1.5.0 and 1.7.1.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ $EDITOR schema_alter.sql&#xA; $ echo &#39;source schema_alter.sql&#39; | mysql -u root -p bibliotech&#xA;&#xA;Then follow the directions above for upgrading from 1.5.0.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACQUIRING SOURCE FOR SPECIALIZED PROGRAMMING CREATING A CITATION MODULE Connotea&#39;s ability to import bibliographic information from third-party websites is enabled by a series of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you downloaded this source code with the intent of creating a&#xA;citation module, see the comments and code in the file&#xA;Bibliotech/CitationSource.pm which will explain the base class from&#xA;which your citation source module should be derived.&#xA;&#xA;In previous releases testing your citation module required a full&#xA;instance of Connotea Code. In this release, a script named&#xA;test_util/citation_source_test.pl provides a way to test your module&#39;s&#xA;return values without an instance. Your module file should be placed in&#xA;the Bibliotech/CitationSource directory to be recognized by this script.&#xA;&#xA;You may also test by creating a fully installed instance, which gives&#xA;the added benefit of letting you test via a web browser and ensure that&#xA;citation data is saved properly in MySQL.&#xA;&#xA;If you create a new citation plug-in, please consider releasing it back&#xA;to the Connotea community.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CREATING AN IMPORT MODULE Connotea&#39;s ability to import a batch of links or references depends on a series of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you downloaded this source code with the intent of creating an import&#xA;module, see the comments and code in the file Bibliotech/Import.pm which&#xA;will explain the base class from which your import module should be&#xA;derived.&#xA;&#xA;In previous releases testing your citation module required a full&#xA;instance of Connotea Code. In this release, a script named&#xA;test_util/import provides a way to test your module&#39;s return values&#xA;without an instance. Your module file should be placed in the&#xA;Bibliotech/Import directory to be recognized by this script.&#xA;&#xA;You may also test by creating a fully installed instance, which gives&#xA;the added benefit of letting you test via a web browser and ensure that&#xA;imported data is saved properly in MySQL.&#xA;&#xA;If you create a new import plug-in, please consider releasing it back to&#xA;the Connotea community.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CREATING A PROXY MODULE Connotea&#39;s ability to provide proxy translation for specific types of URI&#39;s depends on a series of plug-ins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you downloaded this source code with the intent of creating a proxy&#xA;module, see the comments and code in the file Bibliotech/Proxy.pm which&#xA;will explain the base class from which your import module should be&#xA;derived.&#xA;&#xA;You may test by creating a fully installed instance.&#xA;&#xA;If you create a new proxy plug-in, please consider releasing it back to&#xA;the Connotea community.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ADDING A STATIC WEB PAGE Any Connotea Code instance that contains the &#34;Inc&#34; component has the ability to deliver static pages through the template system. A URL path that is not recognized by &#34;Bibliotech::Parser&#34; will be tested as a filename under the document root with an extension of &#34;.inc&#34; appended. The contents of this file should be XHTML. If found, the contents will be served within inc.tt or default.tt according to the rules of the template system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ADDING A DYNAMIC WEB PAGE To create a new component for your Connotea Code instance that serves dynamic web content requires at least the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;In Bibliotech/Parser.pm you must find the grammar definition and add a&#xA;subrule to the page production which will designate the URL path that&#xA;will activate your component. Keep in mind that a path name that is a&#xA;shortened version of another path name will always eclipse the longer&#xA;one if it appears first, so you should add it after (e.g. &#34;urilabel&#34;&#xA;must come before &#34;uri&#34; or &#34;uri&#34; would always match for either).&#xA;&#xA;In Bibliotech/Page/Standard.pm add a package based on &#34;Bibliotech::Page&#34;&#xA;like the others defined in that file. The name should be&#xA;&#34;Bibliotech::Page::x&#34; where &#34;x&#34; is your path name with a single capital&#xA;letter at the beginning even if it is more than one word (e.g.&#xA;&#34;Bibliotech::Page::Reportspam&#34; for a path of &#34;/reportspam&#34;). Include a&#xA;&#34;main_component()&#34; method that returns a string of the last part of the&#xA;class name of the main component, a &#34;Bibliotech::Component&#34;-derived&#xA;class (e.g. &#39;ReportSpam&#39; for &#34;Bibliotech::Component::ReportSpam&#34;).&#xA;&#xA;In the Bibliotech/Component directory create a module based on&#xA;Bibliotech::Component. Use the others that appear in that diectory as&#xA;examples and refer directly to the source code in&#xA;Bibliotech/Component.pm, particularly the comments, for descriptions of&#xA;expected methods and their expected return values. For an HTML&#xA;compontent be sure to include &#34;last_updated_basis()&#34; and&#xA;&#34;html_content()&#34;. In particular, html_content() should return a&#xA;&#34;Bibliotech::Page::HTML_Content&#34; object; that class is defined in&#xA;Bibliotech/Page.pm.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SPEAKING TO THE WEB API FROM YOUR APPLICATION The Connotea Web API allows communication with an instance, either the Connotea web site at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.connotea.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.connotea.org/&lt;/a&gt; or your own private instance, using a predefined set of commands to access structured data and accomplish normal user actions in a programmatic manner.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Your software may be written in any language you choose - the basic&#xA;requirements are the ability to create and parse XML and communicate&#xA;using the HTTP protocol. The ability to interpret the XML as RDF and use&#xA;object orientation to model the objects serialized as RDF may prove&#xA;helpful. Libraries and sample code are available.&#xA;&#xA;See &amp;lt;http://www.connotea.org/wiki/WebAPI&amp;gt; for Web API documentation.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MINIMUM REQUIREMENTS This code requires, or has been best tested on:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Linux/UNIX operating system (tested on Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 -&#xA;see &amp;lt;http://www.redhat.com/&amp;gt;)&#xA;* Perl 5.8.0 (see &amp;lt;http://www.perl.org/&amp;gt;)&#xA;* Perl CPAN modules as identified on the list below (see&#xA;&amp;lt;http://cpan.perl.org/&amp;gt;)&#xA;* Apache 2.0.40 (see &amp;lt;http://httpd.apache.org/&amp;gt;)&#xA;* MySQL 5.0.17 (see &amp;lt;http://www.mysql.com/&amp;gt;)&#xA;* Memcached 1.1.12 (see &amp;lt;http://www.danga.com/memcached/&amp;gt;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CPAN You will need to have the following modules installed from CPAN.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;On all Perl systems you can type:&#xA;&#xA;  $ LANG=C cpan&#xA;&#xA;...or...&#xA;&#xA;  $ LANG=C perl -MCPAN -e shell&#xA;&#xA;...to get a CPAN shell prompt, and then type:&#xA;&#xA;  cpan&amp;gt; install XXX::YYY&#xA;&#xA;..or...&#xA;&#xA;  cpan&amp;gt; force install XXX::YYY&#xA;&#xA;...to install a module.&#xA;&#xA;The &#34;LANG=C&#34; portion of the command line above is highly recommended as&#xA;many modern Linux distributions set your default &#34;LANG&#34; to a&#xA;locale-based setting and this often interferes with Perl module&#xA;compilations. When it does, the error messages will be very misleading&#xA;and never mention the &#34;LANG&#34; variable.&#xA;&#xA;Before you embark on what will probably be a long install-fest, it is&#xA;also recommended that you type:&#xA;&#xA; cpan&amp;gt; install Bundle::CPAN&#xA;&#xA;...inside the CPAN shell and then restart it. This will ensure that you&#xA;are using the latest version of the CPAN code. Some things will go more&#xA;smoothly.&#xA;&#xA;When asked whether to follow dependencies, answer yes. When asked about&#xA;optional utilities and scripts that can be installed to /bin or&#xA;/usr/bin, answer however you like, as none are necessary for this code.&#xA;&#xA;You do not necessarily need the latest version of every module, although&#xA;in one or two cases you do. In general, if your Perl is at least 5.8.0,&#xA;just install the version that a non-force install will give you at the&#xA;CPAN prompt. If you are lower than 5.8.0, upgrade your base Perl&#xA;installation first.&#xA;&#xA;The list:&#xA;&#xA;On Red Hat and some other distros, the following are provided in vendor&#xA;packages, and you&#39;re better off using those.&#xA;&#xA;* Apache2&#xA;* Apache::Const&#xA;* Apache::File&#xA;&#xA;...but install these from CPAN so you get new versions:&#xA;&#xA;* IO::String (for Bio::Biblio::IO, better to preinstall)&#xA;* XML::Writer (for Bio::Biblio::IO, better to preinstall)&#xA;* XML::Twig (for Bio::Biblio::IO, better to preinstall)&#xA;* SOAP::Lite (for Bio::Biblio::IO, better to preinstall)&#xA;* Pod::Man (for DateTime, better to preinstall)&#xA;* Bio::Biblio (may need to be forced)&#xA;* Cache::Memcached&#xA;* CGI&#xA;* Class::DBI&#xA;* Config::Scoped&#xA;* Data::Dumper (not just for debugging, actually used in production)&#xA;* Date::Parse&#xA;* DateTime (you may need to force installation of DateTime::Set if your&#xA;timezone is not UTC)&#xA;* DateTime::Format::ISO8601&#xA;* DateTime::Format::MySQL&#xA;* DateTime::Incomplete&#xA;* Digest::MD5&#xA;* Encode (you may need to force installation of Encode if some&#xA;non-English tests fail)&#xA;* Fcntl&#xA;* File::Temp&#xA;* File::Touch&#xA;* FindBin&#xA;* HTML::Entities&#xA;* HTML::Sanitizer (you may need to force installation of HTML::Sanitizer&#xA;due to some year-old bugs already filed on CPAN)&#xA;* HTTP::OAI&#xA;* IO::File&#xA;* JSON&#xA;* LWP::UserAgent&#xA;* List::MoreUtils&#xA;* List::Util (you may need to force installation of List::Util unless&#xA;you have a very new version of Perl)&#xA;* Net::Daemon::Log (you may need to force installation of&#xA;Net::Daemon::Log for failing a fork test - not used by us)&#xA;* Netscape::Bookmarks&#xA;* Parse::RecDescent&#xA;* RDF::Core&#xA;* SQL::Abstract&#xA;* Set::Array&#xA;* Storable&#xA;* Template&#xA;* Test::Exception&#xA;* Time::HiRes&#xA;* URI&#xA;* URI::Escape&#xA;* URI::Heuristic&#xA;* URI::OpenURL&#xA;* URI::QueryParam&#xA;* Want&#xA;* Wiki::Toolkit&#xA;* Wiki::Toolkit::Plugin::Diff&#xA;* XML::Element&#xA;* XML::Feed&#xA;* XML::LibXML&#xA;* XML::RSS&#xA;* YAML (you may need to force installation of Test::Simple which is a&#xA;dependency of YAML, for an unknown reason)&#xA;* Apache::Emulator (not required for core web service service)&#xA;* Text::BibTeX (not required for core web service service)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SETUP MYSQL Two databases for user posts need to be created. See sql/schema.sql for the database schema which needs to be created in MySQL. The first database will be created using InnoDB tables to enforce foreign keys and constraints and for table joining speed. A second database then should be created with a _search suffix using MyISAM tables that have FULLTEXT indexes which are queried when searching for words. (FULLTEXT indexes are not available for InnoDB yet.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The second schema is generated from the first by running:&#xA;&#xA;  $ cd sql&#xA;  $ perl mkschema_search &amp;lt; schema.sql &amp;gt; schema_search.sql&#xA;&#xA;MySQL relication can be used to make the MyISAM database a slave of the&#xA;InnoDB database, even on the same machine. This is a suggested&#xA;configuration for /etc/my.cnf that will do just that:&#xA;&#xA;  [mysqld]&#xA;  # local replication of bibliotech to bibliotech_search:&#xA;  server-id=1&#xA;  log-bin=mysql-bin&#xA;  binlog-do-db=bibliotech&#xA;  replicate-same-server-id=1&#xA;  replicate-rewrite-db=bibliotech-&amp;gt;bibliotech_search&#xA;  replicate-do-db=bibliotech_search&#xA;  master-host=localhost&#xA;  master-user=search_repl&#xA;  master-password=pass&#xA;  # change stopwords in support of bibliotech freematch feature:&#xA;  #ft_stopword_file=/etc/mysql_stopwords.txt&#xA;  ft_min_word_len=2&#xA;  ft_max_word_len=255&#xA;  # allow packing of queries&#xA;  group_concat_max_len=8192&#xA;&#xA;Change the master-password line! Also change the database names if you&#xA;are not using &#34;bibliotech&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;You will probably find the MySQL stopwords to be too restrictive in&#xA;practice. The list can be viewed at&#xA;&amp;lt;http://dev.mysql.com/doc/mysql/en/fulltext-stopwords.html&amp;gt;. We&#xA;recommend that you pare down this list to a more suitable one, and use&#xA;the ft_stopword_file keyword to tell MySQL to use your list instead.&#xA;&#xA;In any case, if you want the search feature to behave predictably, you&#xA;must specify an external text file stopword list to MySQL. The search&#xA;handler will query MySQL to find out the stopword list file being used,&#xA;and read it as well, so it can anticipate MySQL reporting no matches for&#xA;words that otherwise should match.&#xA;&#xA;You&#39;ll need to execute a grant statement similar to this one:&#xA;&#xA; GRANT REPLICATION SLAVE, REPLICATION CLIENT ON *.* TO&#xA; search_repl@&#39;localhost.localdomain&#39; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;pass&#39;;&#xA;&#xA;Two notes on the replication grant statement:&#xA;&#xA;* MySQL seems to consider &#34;localhost.localdomain&#34; different from&#xA;&#34;localhost&#34; and while the shorter version normally works, for&#xA;replication it seems that the longer one is needed. If you have&#xA;problems, try both.&#xA;* You must have the updated privilege table structure. If you have had&#xA;MySQL installed since the 3.x series, your mysql.user table lacks the&#xA;privilege fields mentioned above; check your docs about a script called&#xA;&#39;mysql_fix_privilege_tables&#39;. On many systems this will be a shell&#xA;script in /usr/bin that you can run as root with a &#34;--password=xxx&#34;&#xA;parameter (to specify the MySQL root user password, not the Unix root&#xA;user password).&#xA;&#xA;The MySQL username used by the Perl handler must have access to both&#xA;databases (username and password as in /etc/bibliotech.conf):&#xA;&#xA;  GRANT SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE ON bibliotech.* TO&#xA;  user@localhost IDENTIFIED BY &#39;secret&#39;;&#xA;  GRANT SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE ON bibliotech_search.* TO&#xA;  user@localhost IDENTIFIED BY &#39;secret&#39;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WIKI::TOOLKIT You also need to setup Wiki::Toolkit so that a wiki is available. This is required. You should create a blank database, grant a user rights to it, and run the provided setup script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  CREATE DATABASE conwiki;&#xA;  GRANT ALL ON conwiki.* TO conwiki@localhost IDENTIFIED BY &#39;secret&#39;;&#xA;&#xA;  $ /usr/bin/wiki-toolkit-setupdb --type mysql \&#xA;                                  --name conwiki \&#xA;                                  --user conwiki \&#xA;                                  --pass secret \&#xA;                                  --host localhost&#xA;&#xA;Remember to populate the &#34;COMPONENT WIKI&#34; block of your configuration&#xA;file with the wiki database details.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;APACHE Everything under the site/default subdirectory should be placed or linked into an Apache-accessible location, and a location handler should be added to httpd.conf (or elsewhere in the Apache configuration) such as the following one.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Update the values to match your IP, domain, and file paths:&#xA;&#xA;  &amp;lt;VirtualHost 1.2.3.4:80&amp;gt;&#xA;    ServerName www.yourdomain.com&#xA;    ServerAlias yourdomain.com&#xA;    ServerAdmin you@yourdomain.com&#xA;    DocumentRoot /var/www/perl/connotea_code/site/default&#xA;    PerlOptions +Parent&#xA;    PerlSwitches -I/var/www/perl/connotea_code&#xA;    PerlModule Bibliotech::Apache&#xA;    PerlModule Bibliotech::AuthCookie&#xA;    &amp;lt;Location /&amp;gt;&#xA;      SetHandler perl-script&#xA;      PerlHandler Bibliotech::Apache&#xA;      PerlAuthenHandler Bibliotech::AuthCookie::authen_handler&#xA;      AuthName Bibliotech&#xA;      AuthType basic&#xA;      require valid-user&#xA;      #ErrorDocument 503 /paused.html&#xA;      #ErrorDocument 503 /readonly.html&#xA;      ErrorDocument 503 /unavailable.html&#xA;    &amp;lt;/Location&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;/VirtualHost&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;The 503 lines allow a custom page to be displayed when your site is&#xA;under heavy load (unavailable.html) or when you deliberately pause&#xA;service (paused.html) or make it read-only (readonly.html); you must&#xA;edit your Apache configuration and switch which line is commented for&#xA;the latter two modes.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MEMCACHED Memcached is required, and the code is written to assume that a memcache is running. Database timestamps, cached HTML, and uploaded files are all stored temporarily in this cache.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CONFIGURATION See config for a configuration that should be copied to /etc/bibliotech.conf and edited to suit your needs. Particularly, be sure to change *_SECRET and *_PASSWORD variables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Default configuration:&#xA;&#xA;  (((config)))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CUSTOMIZATION The look and feel of your Connotea Code installation can be modified by creating a new stylesheet and new templates. The template system is Template Toolkit documented at the web site at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.template-toolkit.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.template-toolkit.org/&lt;/a&gt;. We refer to this system as TT for short.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE LOCATION Templates are located by default in site/default. This is controlled by options in the configuration. It is recommended that templates have a .tt extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE SELECTION The template used to service a particular request is determined by the page requested and the available template filenames.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Individual templates can be defined for individual pages; for example,&#xA;to override the template for the add form, create a template called&#xA;add.tt.&#xA;&#xA;For general bookmark listing queries (e.g. &#34;/tag/tagname&#34;), templates&#xA;beginning with recent can be used. recent.tt will be used for queries&#xA;with no user or tag parameters - recent_user.tt, recent_tag.tt and&#xA;recent_user_tag.tt can be created to specify the behaviour is there is a&#xA;user query, a tag query, or both respectively.&#xA;&#xA;Unless overridden by a specific template, default.tt is used.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE EXAMPLES Templates should not contain the full HTML for the page you want to construct, but only that which should appear between the &#34;&#34; and &#34;&#34; tags.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This is an example default.tt:&#xA;&#xA;  [% prepare_component_begin() %]&#xA;  [% prepare_component(&#39;main&#39;,undef,&#39;main,verbose&#39;) %]&#xA;  [% prepare_component_end() %]&#xA;  &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;[% main_title %]&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&#xA;  [% rss_link %]&#xA;  [% component_javascript_block_if_needed %]&#xA;  &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;body[% component_javascript_onload_if_needed %]&amp;gt;&#xA;  [% component_html(&#39;main&#39;,undef,&#39;main,verbose&#39;) %]&#xA;  &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;The syntax is from Template Toolkit documented at the web site at&#xA;&amp;lt;http://www.template-toolkit.org/&amp;gt;. We refer to TT for short.&#xA;&#xA;A Connotea web page is a series of components that are combined&#xA;together, contributing HTML which can be organized in separately-placed&#xA;parts calculated at once, or as one block, and also sometimes Javascript&#xA;to be placed in a &#34;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&#34; block in the &#34;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&#34; or in the &#34;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&#34;&#xA;&#34;onload&#34; attribute. The components are controlled by the template&#xA;selected to represent the HTTP query, and each component running can&#xA;access the current command, the posts that result from the SQL engine&#xA;processing the query of the command, and a variety of support services.&#xA;&#xA;Several functions are provided to TT by the calling instance.&#xA;&#34;prepare_component_begin()&#34; is called before anything happens, and this&#xA;prepares some internal data structures; then &#34;prepare_component()&#34; is&#xA;called with the base name of the component (e.g. &#34;Blah&#34; corresponds to&#xA;&#34;Bibliotech::Component::Blah&#34;) or the special word &#34;main&#34; which does a&#xA;lookup for the main component of a page described in&#xA;Bibliotech/Parser.pm and Bibliotech/Page/Standard.pm, which allows some&#xA;templates to be reused. The second argument is a comma-separated list of&#xA;parts, which is a mechanism used by some components such as&#xA;&#34;ListOfTags&#34;, and the third argument is a comma-separated list of&#xA;options to the components, of which the universal ones are &#34;main&#34; and&#xA;&#34;verbose&#34; which should be set to true for the main component (the format&#xA;is key=value but ommiting the value is the same as =1 which is true).&#xA;Later in the template, a call to &#34;component_html()&#34; with the same&#xA;arguments inserts the HTML (if you specified multiple part names in the&#xA;prepare call, you should have multiple calls to insert HTML each with&#xA;one part mentioned).&#xA;&#xA;Individual templates can be defined for individual requests. For&#xA;example, to override the template for the add form, create a template&#xA;called add.tt. For general bookmark listing queries (e.g.&#xA;&#34;/tag/tagname&#34;), templates beginning with recent can be used. recent.tt&#xA;will be used for queries with no user or tag parameters -&#xA;recent_user.tt, recent_tag.tt and recent_user_tag.tt can be created to&#xA;specify the behaviour is there is a user query, a tag query, or both&#xA;respectively.&#xA;&#xA;A more realistic example for default.tt would make calls to a&#xA;normalprep.tt and a normal.tt wrapper:&#xA;&#xA;  [% prepare_component_begin() %]&#xA;  [% INCLUDE normalprep.tt %]&#xA;  [% prepare_component(&#39;main&#39;,undef,&#39;main,verbose&#39;) %]&#xA;  [% prepare_component_end() %]&#xA;  [% WRAPPER normal.tt %]&#xA;  [% component_html(&#39;main&#39;,undef,&#39;main,verbose&#39;) %]&#xA;  [% END %]&#xA;&#xA;In this case, normal.tt would contain a basic look for the web site that&#xA;can be used by many other templates.&#xA;&#xA;A set of working templates is furnished with this distribution.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATES AND COMPONENTS A Connotea web page is a series of components that are combined together, contributing HTML which can be organized in separately-placed parts calculated at once, or as one block, and also sometimes Javascript to be placed in a &#34;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&#34; block in the &#34;&#34; or in the &#34;&#34; &#34;onload&#34; attribute. The components are controlled by the template selected to represent the HTTP query, and each component running can access the current command, the posts that result from the SQL engine processing the query of the command, and a variety of support services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Several functions are provided to TT by the calling instance. Some&#xA;functions are general, and are available in all templates, even small&#xA;snippet templates used by components (conventionally named with a comp&#xA;prefix). Some functions are page-level utilities that largely control&#xA;component insertion.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE PAGE LEVEL FUNCTIONS * &#34;prepare_component_begin()&#34; Declare the beginning of &#34;prepare_component()&#34; calls.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* &#34;prepare_component(module, parts, options)&#34;&#xA;    Prepare a component.&#xA;&#xA;    * module&#xA;        The base name of the desired component (e.g. &#34;Blah&#34; corresponds&#xA;        to &#34;Bibliotech::Component::Blah&#34;) or the special word &#34;main&#34;&#xA;        which does a lookup for the main component of a page described&#xA;        in Bibliotech/Parser.pm and Bibliotech/Page/Standard.pm, which&#xA;        allows some templates to be reused.&#xA;&#xA;    * parts&#xA;        For most components, use &#34;undef&#34; for one block of HTML output.&#xA;        For components that can return multiple parts of HTML, this&#xA;        option is a comma-separated list of part names to prepare in one&#xA;        calculation for efficiency. Components with parts: &#34;ListOfTags&#34;,&#xA;        &#34;ListOfUsers&#34;, and &#34;ListOfGangs&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;    * options&#xA;        A comma-separated list of options to the component, of which the&#xA;        universal ones are &#34;main&#34; and &#34;verbose&#34; which should be set to&#xA;        true for the main component (the format is key=value but&#xA;        ommiting the value is the same as =1 which is true).&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;prepare_component_end()&#34;&#xA;    Declare the end of &#34;prepare_component()&#34; calls.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;component_html(module, part, options)&#34;&#xA;    The arguments are the same as &#34;prepare_component()&#34;, except that the&#xA;    part should be at most one part, not more than one.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;component_javascript_onload()&#34;&#xA;    Insert the Javascript addressed at the &#34;onload&#34; handler.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;component_javascript_onload_if_needed&#34;&#xA;    Insert the Javascript addressed at the &#34;onload&#34; handler, but wrap it&#xA;    a space followed by the actual attribute itself, as in, &#34;&#xA;    onload=&#34;blah&#34;&#34;, or if there is no Javascript, insert nothing.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;component_javascript_block()&#34;&#xA;    Insert the Javascript addressed at the &#34;head&#34; of the HTML document.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;component_javascript_block_if_needed()&#34;&#xA;    Insert the Javascript addressed at the &#34;head&#34; of the HTML document,&#xA;    but wrap it in a &#34;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&#34; block, or if there is no Javascript,&#xA;    insert nothing.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;main_title&#34;&#xA;    The HTML document title recommended by the main component, or&#xA;    failing that, a default constructed from the site name and page&#xA;    name.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;main_heading&#34;&#xA;    The HTML document heading (&#34;H1&#34;) recommended by the main component.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;main_description&#34;&#xA;    The description recommended by the main component; used in RSS, etc.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;css_link&#34;&#xA;    Insert a &#34;&amp;lt;link&amp;gt;&#34; representing the CSS files dictated by&#xA;    &#34;HOME_CSS_FILE&#34; for the home page or &#34;GLOBAL_CSS_FILE&#34; otherwise&#xA;    (configuration options).&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;rss_link&#34;&#xA;    Insert a &#34;&amp;lt;link&amp;gt;&#34; representing the RSS format output for the&#xA;    currently viewed page.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE GENERAL FUNCTIONS * &#34;location&#34; Base URL for the web site, which can be directly prepended to page names, as in:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;      &amp;lt;a href=&#34;[% location %]news&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;sitename&#34;&#xA;    The name of the web site as defined in the configuration.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;siteemail&#34;&#xA;    The email address of the administrator of the web site as defined in&#xA;    the configuration.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;user&#34;&#xA;    User object of the current user looking at the web page, e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      [% IF user %][% user.username %][% ELSE %]Visitor[% END %]&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;is_browser_safari&#34;, &#34;is_browser_firefox&#34;, &#34;is_browser_ie&#34;,&#xA;&#34;is_browser_other&#34;&#xA;    Can be used in an IF test - true if the user&#39;s browser is the type&#xA;    indicated.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;browser_redirect(url)&#34;&#xA;    Immediately abort and issue a Location header to a new URL. The URL&#xA;    can be relative to the root of the web site in which case &#34;location&#34;&#xA;    is prepended.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;is_virgin&#34;&#xA;    Can be used in an IF test - true if the user is a first-time&#xA;    visitor.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;canonical_uri&#34;&#xA;    Canonical URI for the current page.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;canonical_location&#34;&#xA;    Canonical URI using &#34;location&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;object_location&#34;&#xA;    Canonical URI using &#34;location&#34; and setting format to HTML.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;no_num(url)&#34;&#xA;    Remove the num=x parameter from a URL.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;encode_xml_utf8(str)&#34;&#xA;    Escape ampersand, less- and greater-than symbols, normalize HTML&#xA;    entities to XML entities, and remove unusual control characters.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;encode_xhtml_utf8(str)&#34;&#xA;    Encode characters as XML entities where needed and remove unusual&#xA;    control characters.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;now&#34;&#xA;    The current date and time, as a &#34;Bibliotech::DateTime&#34; object, e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      [% now.label %]&#xA;      [% now.ymd %]&#xA;      [% now.ymdhm %]&#xA;      [% now.iso8601 %]&#xA;      [% now.iso8601_utc %]&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;time&#34;&#xA;    The current date and time, as a Unix timestamp.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;join(joinstr, ...)&#34;&#xA;    Perl&#39;s join command.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;speech_join(jointype, ...)&#34;&#xA;    Join several elements as in speech. Argument &#34;jointype&#34; is &#34;and&#34; or&#xA;    &#34;or&#34;. This function will combine with commas, spaces, and the&#xA;    jointype operator (if at least three items), e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      speech_join(&#39;and&#39;, &#39;bob&#39;) -&amp;gt; &#39;bob&#39;&#xA;      speech_join(&#39;and&#39;, &#39;bob&#39;, &#39;alice&#39;) -&amp;gt; &#39;bob and alice&#39;&#xA;      speech_join(&#39;and&#39;, &#39;bob&#39;, &#39;alice&#39;, &#39;tom&#39;) -&amp;gt; &#39;bob, alice, and tom&#39;&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;plural(amount, singular, plural, no_space)&#34;&#xA;    Join a number with the appropriate singular or plural noun, e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      plural(6, &#39;second&#39;, &#39;seconds&#39;) -&amp;gt; &#39;6 seconds&#39;&#xA;      plural(1, &#39;second&#39;, &#39;seconds&#39;) -&amp;gt; &#39;1 second&#39;&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;commas(num)&#34;&#xA;    Decorate a number with commas every three digits (thousands) per the&#xA;    American style, e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      commas(5000000) -&amp;gt; &#39;5,000,000&#39;&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;divide(a, b, places, multiplier)&#34;&#xA;    Divide two numbers, but avoid a division by zero error by returning&#xA;    zero. Return a number formatted to the number of decimals indicated&#xA;    in &#34;places&#34; (default 1 if omitted), and multiplied by &#34;multiplier&#34;&#xA;    (default 1 if omitted), e.g.:&#xA;&#xA;      divide(10, 0) -&amp;gt; 0&#xA;      divide(10, 2) -&amp;gt; 5&#xA;      divide(10, 4, 2) -&amp;gt; 2.50&#xA;      divide(10, 4, 2, 100) -&amp;gt; 250&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;percent(a, b, places)&#34;&#xA;    Same as &#34;divide&#34; but multiplier is 100 and a percent sign is&#xA;    appended.&#xA;&#xA;      percent(1, 2) -&amp;gt; 50.0%&#xA;      percent(4, 100) -&amp;gt; 4.0%&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;bookmarklets&#34;&#xA;    Insert all the bookmarklets.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;bookmarklet(page, popup)&#34;&#xA;    Insert a bookmarklet. Argument &#34;page&#34; should be &#34;add&#34;, &#34;addcomment&#34;,&#xA;    or &#34;comments&#34;. Argument &#34;popup&#34; should be &#34;direct&#34; or &#34;popup&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;bookmarklet_js(page, popup)&#34;&#xA;    Same as &#34;bookmarklet&#34; but only insert the Javascript.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;user_in_own_library&#34;&#xA;    Can be used in an IF test - true if the user is looking at a page&#xA;    that has a current filter of &#34;/user&#34; with their username.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;user_in_another_library&#34;&#xA;    Can be used in an IF test - true if the user is looking at a page&#xA;    that has a current filter of &#34;/user&#34; with a username other than&#xA;    their own.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;click_counter_onclick(url, new_window)&#34;&#xA;    Insert a hyperlink run through the click counter, to the URL&#xA;    provided, optionally in a new window if &#34;new_window&#34; is true.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TEMPLATE COMPONENT SNIPPET FUNCTIONS * &#34;sticky(parameter)&#34; Used primarily inside the &#34;value&#34; attributes of HTML &#34;ipnut&#34; tags, this function allows the form to remember values between refreshes, so if a message must be displayed to the user causing the form to be redisplayed, the user&#39;s form responses are not lost.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* &#34;has_validation_error&#34;&#xA;    True if the form is redisplayed with an active error.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;has_validation_error_for(field)&#34;&#xA;    True if the form is redisplayed with an active error concerning the&#xA;    field specified. Note that some errors are not tied to a field.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;validation_error_field&#34;&#xA;    If the form is redisplayed with an active error, the field name that&#xA;    gave rise to the error. Note that some errors are not tied to a&#xA;    field.&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;validation_error&#34;&#xA;    If the form is redisplayed with an active error, the error message.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LOGROTATE A log file will be created at the place specified in &#34;LOG_FILE&#34; in the configuration. This file can grow quickly so you may like to configure logrotate to deal with it on a weekly basis. This is the contents of a suggested /etc/logrotate.d/bibliotech file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  /var/log/bibliotech.log {&#xA;          create 644 apache root&#xA;          notifempty&#xA;          weekly&#xA;          rotate 5&#xA;          compress&#xA;      postrotate&#xA;          /bin/kill -HUP `cat /var/run/httpd.pid 2&amp;gt;/dev/null` 2&amp;gt; /dev/null || true&#xA;      endscript&#xA;  } &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SUPPORT To subscribe to the Connotea Code development mailing list, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/connotea-code-devel&#34;&gt;https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/connotea-code-devel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;This list is for the discussion of the core code and citation and import&#xA;plug-ins. It is intended for use by people who are installing their own&#xA;instance of Connotea Code, or who are reviewing the code to see how&#xA;Connotea handles their data, or who would like to help enable the&#xA;importing of bibliographic information from more sources.&#xA;&#xA;There is a separate list, connotea-discuss, for discussion of Connotea&#xA;itself - i.e. for discussion of &amp;lt;http://www.connotea.org/&amp;gt;. That list is&#xA;the appropriate place for questions about how to use the site, or&#xA;requests or suggestions for new features.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WEBCITE The Connotea Code has a module called WebCite which can be employed separately as a simple web service providing citation information using the Connotea Code citation modules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;A WebCite instance requires the full codebase to be present, as well as&#xA;the CPAN module dependencies, and a compatible version of Apache, just&#xA;as you might setup for Connotea Code proper. However, MySQL, Memcache,&#xA;and Wiki::Toolkit are not required.&#xA;&#xA;You should create a configuration file as directed for Connotea Code,&#xA;but only the WEBCITE section and sections for your active citation&#xA;modules are required.&#xA;&#xA;WebCite provides caching not with memcached but via the filesystem, so&#xA;the results survive Apache restarts.&#xA;&#xA;WebCite can be turned on inside a normal Connotea Code deployment, but&#xA;will perform its duties separately from the main codebase.&#xA;&#xA;The main page for WebCite simply presents a form with two fields:&#xA;&#xA;* &#34;uri&#34; - text field for the URL&#xA;* &#34;fmt&#34; - select field for the format:&#xA;&#xA;    * &#34;ris&#34;&#xA;    * &#34;mods&#34;&#xA;    * &#34;json&#34;&#xA;&#xA;A submit button is provided for human users but the value is ignored.&#xA;&#xA;The form can be called by programs by performing an HTTP POST to the&#xA;installed location with &#34;uri&#34; and &#34;fmt&#34; parameters.&#xA;&#xA;Programs should evaluate the HTTP status code first.&#xA;&#xA;* 200 - citation data returned&#xA;* 404 - no citation data found&#xA;* 500 - internal error&#xA;&#xA;In the case of a 404 code, a brief message such as &#34;No citation&#34; may be&#xA;displayed, but programs should not expect this value, and should rely&#xA;exclusively on the HTTP status code to determine this condition.&#xA;&#xA;In the case of a 200 code, the &#34;Content-Type&#34; header should be&#xA;appropriate for the format requested, and the data payload should&#xA;present the citation data in the format requested.&#xA;&#xA;A 500 code will occur if an exception is thrown retrieving the citation&#xA;data, and the data payload will be plain text giving the error message.&#xA;&#xA;All transactions are separate. There is no concept of sessions.&#xA;&#xA;There are no authentication checks in the WebCite code, although the&#xA;system administrator is free to add restrictions in the Apache&#xA;configuration.&#xA;&#xA;Subsequent requests within 90 days for the same URL will return data&#xA;cached from the original request. Data is cached in an internal&#xA;structure form so the same cache entry can produce all output formats.&#xA;&#xA;The Apache configuration block for WebCite is as follows:&#xA;&#xA;  PerlSwitches -I/var/www/perl/...&#xA;  &amp;lt;Location /bibliotech&amp;gt;&#xA;    SetHandler perl-script&#xA;    PerlHandler Bibliotech::WebCite&#xA;  &amp;lt;/Location&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;The PerlSwitches line should point to the directory that contains the&#xA;Bibliotech directory.&#xA;&#xA;This may or may not appear in the same Apache configuration as Connotea&#xA;Code proper.&#xA;&#xA;A suggested configuration for /etc/bibliotech.conf is as follows:&#xA;&#xA;  WEBCITE {&#xA;    CACHE_ENABLED = true&#xA;    CACHE_PATH = &#39;/var/cache/webcite&#39;&#xA;    CACHE_TIMEOUT = 7776000&#xA;    LOG_ENABLED = true&#xA;    LOG_FILE = &#39;/var/log/webcite.log&#39;&#xA;  }&#xA;&#xA;Again this may be a file exclusively for WebCite or a file with&#xA;intermixed configuration for Connotea Code proper.&#xA;&#xA;You should create the cache directory and log file and give the Apache&#xA;user write access before starting Apache.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACKNOWLEDGMENTS The look, structure, documentation and source code of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.connotea.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.connotea.org/&lt;/a&gt; are the collective work of Martin Flack, Ben Lund, Timo Hannay, Joanna Scott, Stefania Bojano, Grant Farrelly, Euan Adie, and Ian Mulvany. The vast majority of the programming was done by Martin Flack of NeoReality, Inc., &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neoreality.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.neoreality.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The materials available from &amp;lt;http://sf.net/projects/connotea&amp;gt; are&#xA;released under the GNU General Public License; reuse of all other&#xA;materials requires the express written permission of Nature Publishing&#xA;Group.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MORE INFORMATION Please visit this URL for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.connotea.org/code&#34;&gt;http://www.connotea.org/code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;If you have questions, email us or try our mailing lists:&#xA;&amp;lt;http://www.connotea.org/contact&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>takuji31/p5-qpsmtpd-plugin-jobqueue</title>
    <updated>2023-09-17T01:56:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-17:/takuji31/p5-qpsmtpd-plugin-jobqueue</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/takuji31/p5-qpsmtpd-plugin-jobqueue" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Qpsmtpd JobQueue plugin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Perl module Qpsmtpd::Plugin::JobQueue.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qpsmtpd::Plugin::JobQueue installation is straightforward. If your CPAN shell is set up, you should just be able to do&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% cpan Qpsmtpd::Plugin::JobQueue&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download it, unpack it, then build it as per the usual:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% perl Makefile.PL&#xA;% make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make test&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then install it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DOCUMENTATION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qpsmtpd::Plugin::JobQueue documentation is available as in POD. So you can do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;% perldoc Qpsmtpd::Plugin::JobQueue&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;to read the documentation online with your favorite pager.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nishibayashi Takuji&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>