<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-12T01:42:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>holzschu/a-shell</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:42:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/holzschu/a-shell</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/holzschu/a-shell" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A terminal for iOS, with multiple windows&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;a-shell: A terminal for iOS, with multiple windows&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Platform-iOS%2014.0+-lightgrey.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Platform: iOS&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/a_Shell_iOS&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Twitter-@a__Shell__iOS-blue.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/cvYnZm69Gy&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/935519150305050644?color=5865f2&amp;amp;label=Discord&amp;amp;style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal in this project is to provide a simple Unix-like terminal on iOS. It uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/holzschu/ios_system/&#34;&gt;ios_system&lt;/a&gt; for command interpretation, and includes all commands from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/holzschu/ios_system/&#34;&gt;ios_system&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem (nslookup, whois, python3, lua, pdflatex, lualatex...)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project uses iPadOS 13 ability to create and manage multiple windows. Each window has its own context, appearance, command history and current directory. &lt;code&gt;newWindow&lt;/code&gt; opens a new window, &lt;code&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt; closes the current window.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For help, type &lt;code&gt;help&lt;/code&gt; in the command line. &lt;code&gt;help -l&lt;/code&gt; lists all the available commands. &lt;code&gt;help -l | grep command&lt;/code&gt; will tell you if your favorite command is already installed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can change the appearance of a-Shell using &lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt;. It lets you change the font, the font size, the background color, the text color and the cursor color and shape. Each window can have its own appearance. &lt;code&gt;config -p&lt;/code&gt; will make the settings for the current window permanent, that is used for all future windows. With &lt;code&gt;config -t&lt;/code&gt; you can also configure the toolbar.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When opening a new window, a-Shell executes the file &lt;code&gt;.profile&lt;/code&gt; if it exists. You can use this mechanism to customize further, e.g. have custom environment variables or cleanup temporary files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more tips on how to use a-Shell, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://bianshen00009.gitbook.io/a-guide-to-a-shell/&#34;&gt;the document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AppStore&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;a-Shell is now &lt;a href=&#34;https://holzschu.github.io/a-Shell_iOS/&#34;&gt;available on the AppStore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to compile it?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to compile the project yourself, you will need the following steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;download the entire project and its sub-modules: &lt;code&gt;git submodule update --init --recursive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;download all the xcFrameworks: &lt;code&gt;downloadFrameworks.sh&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;this will download the standard Apple frameworks (in &lt;code&gt;xcfs/.build/artefacts/xcfs&lt;/code&gt;, with checksum control).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There are too many Python frameworks (more than 2000) for automatic download. You can either remove them from the &#34;Embed&#34; step in the project, or compile them: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;You&#39;ll need the Xcode command line tools, if you don&#39;t already have them: &lt;code&gt;sudo xcode-select --install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;You also need the OpenSSL libraries (libssl and libcrypto), XQuartz (freetype), and Node.js (npm) for macOS (we provide the versions for iOS and simulator).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;change directory to &lt;code&gt;cpython&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;cd cpython&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;build Python 3.11 and all the associated libraries / frameworks: &lt;code&gt;sh ./downloadAndCompile.sh&lt;/code&gt; (this step takes several hours on a 2GHz i5 MBP, YMMV).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;a-Shell now runs on the devices. a-Shell mini can run on the devices and the simulator.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because Python 3.x uses functions that are only available on the iOS 14 SDK, I&#39;ve set the minimum iOS version to 14.0. It also reduces the size of the binaries, so &lt;code&gt;ios_system&lt;/code&gt; and the other frameworks have the same settings. If you need to run it on an iOS 13 device, you&#39;ll have to recompile most frameworks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Home directory&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In iOS, you cannot write in the &lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; directory, only in &lt;code&gt;~/Documents/&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/Library/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;~/tmp&lt;/code&gt;. Most Unix programs assume the configuration files are in &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So a-Shell changes several environment variables so that they point to &lt;code&gt;~/Documents&lt;/code&gt;. Type &lt;code&gt;env&lt;/code&gt; to see them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most configuration files (Python packages, TeX files, Clang SDK...) are in &lt;code&gt;~/Library&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sandbox and Bookmarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;a-Shell uses iOS 13 ability to access directories in other Apps sandbox. Type &lt;code&gt;pickFolder&lt;/code&gt; to access a directory inside another App. Once you have selected a directory, you can do pretty much anything you want here, so be careful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the directories you access with &lt;code&gt;pickFolder&lt;/code&gt; are bookmarked, so you can return to them later without &lt;code&gt;pickFolder&lt;/code&gt;. You can also bookmark the current directory with &lt;code&gt;bookmark&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;showmarks&lt;/code&gt; will list all the existing bookmarks, &lt;code&gt;jump mark&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;cd ~mark&lt;/code&gt; will change the current directory to this specific bookmark, &lt;code&gt;renamemark&lt;/code&gt; will let you change the name of a specific bookmark and &lt;code&gt;deletemark&lt;/code&gt; will delete a bookmark.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A user-configurable option in Settings lets you use the commands &lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;g&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; instead or as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are lost, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; will always bring you back to &lt;code&gt;~/Documents/&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;cd -&lt;/code&gt; will change to the previous directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;a-Shell is compatible with Apple Shortcuts, giving users full control of the Shell. You can write complex Shortcuts to download, process and release files using a-Shell commands. There are three shortcuts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Execute Command&lt;/code&gt;, which takes a list of commands and executes them in order. The input can also be a file or a text node, in which case the commands inside the node are executed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Put File&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Get File&lt;/code&gt; are used to transfer files to and from a-Shell.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shortcuts can be executed either &#34;In Extension&#34; or &#34;In App&#34;. &#34;In Extension&#34; means the shortcut runs in a lightweight version of the App, without no graphical user interface. It is good for light commands that do not require configuration files or system libraries (mkdir, nslookup, whois, touch, cat, echo...). &#34;In App&#34; opens the main application to execute the shortcut. It has access to all the commands, but will take longer. Once a shortcut has opened the App, you can return to the Shortcuts app by calling the command &lt;code&gt;open shortcuts://&lt;/code&gt;. The default behaviour is to try to run the commands &#34;in Extension&#34; as much as possible, based on the content of the commands. You can force a specific shortcut to run &#34;in App&#34; or &#34;in Extension&#34;, with the warning that it won&#39;t always work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both kind of shortcuts run by default in the same specific directory, &lt;code&gt;$SHORTCUTS&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~shortcuts&lt;/code&gt;. Of course, since you can run the commands &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;jump&lt;/code&gt; in a shortcut, you can pretty much go anywhere.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Programming / add more commands:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;a-Shell has several programming languages installed: Python, Lua, JS, C, C++ and TeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For C and C++, you compile your programs with &lt;code&gt;clang program.c&lt;/code&gt; and it produces a webAssembly file. You can then execute it with &lt;code&gt;wasm a.out&lt;/code&gt;. You can also link multiple object files together, make a static library with &lt;code&gt;ar&lt;/code&gt;, etc. Once you are satisfied with your program, if you move it to a directory in the &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt; (e.g. &lt;code&gt;~/Documents/bin&lt;/code&gt;) and rename it &lt;code&gt;program.wasm&lt;/code&gt;, it will be executed if you type &lt;code&gt;program&lt;/code&gt; on the command line.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also cross-compile programs on your main computer using our specific &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/holzschu/wasi-sdk&#34;&gt;WASI-sdk&lt;/a&gt;, and transfer the WebAssembly file to your iPad or iPhone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Precompiled WebAssembly commands specific for a-Shell are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/holzschu/a-Shell-commands&#34;&gt;https://github.com/holzschu/a-Shell-commands&lt;/a&gt; These include &lt;code&gt;zip&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;unzip&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xz&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt;... You install them on your iPad by downloading them and placing them in the &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have the limitations of WebAssembly: no sockets, no forks, no interactive user input (piping input from other commands with &lt;code&gt;command | wasm program.wasm&lt;/code&gt; works fine).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Python, you can install more packages with &lt;code&gt;pip install packagename&lt;/code&gt;, but only if they are pure Python. The C compiler is not yet able to produce dynamic libraries that could be used by Python.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TeX files are not installed by default. Type any TeX command and the system will prompt you to download them. Same with LuaTeX files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;VoiceOver&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you enable VoiceOver in Settings, a-Shell will work with VoiceOver: reading commands as you type them, reading the result, letting you read the screen with your finger...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HexaCluster/pgdsat</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:42:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/HexaCluster/pgdsat</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HexaCluster/pgdsat" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL Database Security Assessment Tool&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;NAME&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pgdsat - PostgreSQL Database Security Assessment Tool&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PGDSAT is a security assessment tool that checks around 70 PostgreSQL security controls of your PostgreSQL clusters including all recommendations from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cisecurity.org/cis-benchmarks/&#34;&gt;CIS compliance benchmark&lt;/a&gt; but not only.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool is a single command that must be run on the PostgreSQL server to collect all necessaries system and PostgreSQL information to compute a security assessment report. A report consist in a summary of all tests status and a second part with all detailed information. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.darold.net/sample_pgdsat/report.html&#34;&gt;sample report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This PostgreSQL Security Assessment Tool allow assessments to be carried out in an automated manner to verify the security policies established inside the company. It also gives understanding of the security issued that your cluster can be faced.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the default text output format can be read directly from a terminal the use of the HTML output format is recommended for better reading as you can see in the sample report above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SECURITY CHECKS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All checks recommended by the CIS Benchmark for PostgreSQL 16 are implemented but not only. Some additional tests not part of the CIS document are marked with the &#34;(*)&#34; mention in the description.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the list all checks performed on a PostgreSQL cluster. Some must be checked manually but most of them are check automatically by the tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    1 - Installation and Patches&#xA;      1.1 - Ensure packages are obtained from authorized repositories =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        1.1.1 - PostgreSQL packages installed. (Manual)&#xA;        1.1.2 - Ensure packages are obtained from PGDG =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      1.2 - Ensure systemd Service Files Are Enabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      1.3 - Ensure Data Cluster Initialized Successfully =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        1.3.1 - Check initialization of the PGDATA =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        1.3.2 - Check version in PGDATA =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        1.3.3 - Ensure Data Cluster have checksum enabled =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        1.3.4 - Ensure WALs and temporary files are not on the same partition as the PGDATA =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        1.3.5 - Ensure that the PGDATA partition is encrypted (Manual)&#xA;      1.4 - Ensure PostgreSQL versions are up-to-date =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      1.5 - Ensure unused PostgreSQL extensions are removed (Manual)&#xA;    2 - Directory and File Permissions&#xA;      2.1 - Ensure the file permissions mask is correct =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      2.2 - Check permissions of PGDATA =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      2.3 - List content of PGDATA to check unwanted files and symlinks (Manual)&#xA;      2.4 - Check permissions of pg_hba.conf =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      2.5 - Check permissions on Unix Socket =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;    3 - Logging And Auditing&#xA;      3.1 - PostgreSQL Logging =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.1 - Logging Rationale =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.2 - Ensure the log destinations are set correctly =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.3 - Ensure the logging collector is enabled =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.4 - Ensure the log file destination directory is set correctly =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.5 - Ensure the filename pattern for log files is set correctly (Manual)&#xA;        3.1.6 - Ensure the log file permissions are set correctly =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.7 - Ensure &#39;log_truncate_on_rotation&#39; is enabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.8 - Ensure the maximum log file lifetime is set correctly (Manual)&#xA;        3.1.9 - Ensure the maximum log file size is set correctly (Manual)&#xA;        3.1.10 - Ensure the correct syslog facility is selected (Manual)&#xA;        3.1.11 - Ensure syslog messages are not suppressed =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.12 - Ensure syslog messages are not lost due to size =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.13 - Ensure the program name for PostgreSQL syslog messages is correct (Manual)&#xA;        3.1.14 - Ensure the correct messages are written to the server log =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.15 - Ensure the correct SQL statements generating errors are recorded =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.16 - Ensure &#39;debug_print_parse&#39; is disabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.17 - Ensure &#39;debug_print_rewritten&#39; is disabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.18 - Ensure &#39;debug_print_plan&#39; is disabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.19 - Ensure &#39;debug_pretty_print&#39; is enabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.20 - Ensure &#39;log_connections&#39; is enabled =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.21 - Ensure &#39;log_disconnections&#39; is enabled =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.22 - Ensure &#39;log_error_verbosity&#39; is set correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.23 - Ensure &#39;log_hostname&#39; is set correctly =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;        3.1.24 - Ensure &#39;log_line_prefix&#39; is set correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.25 - Ensure &#39;log_statement&#39; is set correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.26 - Ensure &#39;log_timezone&#39; is set correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;        3.1.27 - Ensure that log_directory is outside the PGDATA =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      3.2 - Ensure the PostgreSQL Audit Extension (pgAudit) is enabled =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;    4 - User Access and Authorization&#xA;      4.1 - Ensure sudo is configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      4.2 - Ensure excessive administrative privileges are revoked =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      4.3 - Ensure excessive function privileges are revoked (Manual)&#xA;      4.4 - Ensure excessive DML privileges are revoked (Manual)&#xA;      4.5 - Ensure Row Level Security (RLS) is configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      4.6 - Ensure the set_user extension is installed (Manual) =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      4.7 - Make use of predefined roles (Manual)&#xA;      4.8 - Ensuse the public schema is protected&#xA;    5 - Connection and Login&#xA;      5.1 - Ensure login via &#34;local&#34; UNIX Domain Socket is configured correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      5.2 - Ensure login via &#34;host&#34; TCP/IP Socket is configured correctly =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      5.3 - Ensure Password Complexity is configured =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      5.4 - Ensure authentication timeout and delay are well configured =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      5.5 - Ensure SSL is used for client connection =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      5.6 - Ensure authorized Ip addresses ranges are not too large =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      5.7 - Ensure specific database and users are used =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      5.8 - Ensure superusers are not allowed to connect remotely =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      5.9 - Ensure that &#39;password_encryption&#39; is correctly set =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;    6 - PostgreSQL Settings&#xA;      6.1 - Understanding attack vectors and runtime parameters&#xA;      6.2 - Ensure &#39;backend&#39; runtime parameters are configured correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      6.3 - Ensure &#39;Postmaster&#39; runtime parameters are configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      6.4 - Ensure &#39;SIGHUP&#39; runtime parameters are configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      6.5 - Ensure &#39;Superuser&#39; runtime parameters are configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      6.6 - Ensure &#39;User&#39; runtime parameters are configured correctly (Manual)&#xA;      6.7 - Ensure FIPS 140-2 OpenSSL cryptography is used =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      6.8 - Ensure TLS is enabled and configured correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      6.9 - Ensure a cryptographic extension is installed =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;    7 - Replication&#xA;      7.1 - Ensure a replication-only user is created and used for streaming replication =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      7.2 - Ensure logging of replication commands is configured =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      7.3 - Ensure base backups are configured and functional =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      7.4 - Ensure WAL archiving is configured and functional =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      7.5 - Ensure streaming replication parameters are configured correctly =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;    8 - Special Configuration Considerations&#xA;      8.1 - Ensure PostgreSQL subdirectory locations are outside the data cluster =&amp;gt; SUCCESS&#xA;      8.2 - Ensure the backup and restore tool, &#39;pgBackRest&#39;, is installed and configured =&amp;gt; FAILURE&#xA;      8.3 - Ensure miscellaneous configuration settings are correct (Manual)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;REQUIREMENT&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PGDSAT is a standalone program that can be run on any Linux server, it doesn&#39;t require any additional package installation except if your system do not have the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure that PostgreSQL binaries are reachable from the &#39;$PATH&#39; environment variable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure PostgreSQL &amp;gt;= 10.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure that &#39;PGHOST&#39;, &#39;PGUSER&#39;, &#39;PGPASSWORD&#39; and &#39;PGDATA&#39; environment variables are defined or use the dedicated command line options (except for &#39;PGPASSWORD&#39;). Or set a &#39;.pgpass&#39; file in the postgres system account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure &#39;sudo apt install crypto-policies&#39; have been run for the FIPS test.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure the Perl bignum module is installed &#39;perl -e &#34;use bignum&#34;&#39;, if the command fail, install it using &#39;dnf install perl-bignum perl-Math-BigRat&#39;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure the &#39;curl&#39; command is available and the server have access to Internet. It is used to check the PostgreSQL version online. If this is not possible, use command line option --no-pg-version-check to disable this check.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To view the HTML report you also need an Internet access to obtain the FontAwesome icons used in the Summary Table of security checks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PostgreSQL command psql is used to query the PostgreSQL cluster.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install PGDSAT:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    perl Makefile.PL&#xA;    make&#xA;    sudo make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t want to install PGDSAT on your system but just want to execute it from the source directory, follow the instruction at end of next chapter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some Linux RPM based distributions do not provide the bignum Perl module by default, you will need to install it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    dnf install perl-bignum perl-Math-BigRat&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;USAGE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PGSAT use commands to look at the system and especially to the PostgreSQL installation. It means that it requires the privilege of owner of these repository to be executed. Run it as postgres system user.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usage: pgdsat [options]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PostgreSQL Database Security Assessment Tool.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;-a | --allow   : database to include into the report in parts 4.3 to 4.5.&#xA;                 Can be used multiple time and regexp are supported.&#xA;-d | --database: name of the database to connect to PostgreSQL.&#xA;-D | --pgdata  : path to the PostgreSQL cluster PGDATA to analyze.&#xA;-e | --exclude : database to exclude from the report in parts 4.3 to 4.5.&#xA;                 Can be used multiple time and regexp are supported.&#xA;-f | --format  : output format, can be: text or html. Default: html.&#xA;-h | --host    : PostgreSQL serveur ip address if not listening on localhost&#xA;-l | --lang    : language used for the output (en_US, fr_FR). Default: en_US&#xA;-o | --output  : output file where to write the report. Default stdout.&#xA;-p | --port    : port where PostgreSQL is listening, default: 5432.&#xA;-P | --psql    : full path to the psql command if not found in PATH.&#xA;-T | --title   : set title to use to differentiate the reports. Default is&#xA;                 to use &#34;on `hostname`&#34;.&#xA;-U | --user    : PostgreSQL user to use with the psql command.&#xA;-v | --version : show version of pgdsat and exist.&#xA;-V | --cluster : PostgreSQL Cluster version, ex: 15.4.&#xA;--help         : show usage and exit.&#xA;&#xA;--no-pg-version-check : disable check for PostgreSQL minor versions. Useful&#xA;                 when connecting to Internet is not permitted.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pgdsat -U postgres -h localhost -d postgres -o report.html&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;or pgdsat -U postgres -h localhost -d postgres -f html &amp;gt; report.html&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have several PostgreSQL cluster installed you must give the running version that you want to test:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pgdsat -U postgres -h localhost -d postgres -f html -V 15.4 &amp;gt; report.html&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To execute the pgdsat command locally without installation, use:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo perl -I ./lib ./pgdsat ...&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AUTHORS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gilles Darold.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pgdsat is free software distributed under the GPLv3 license. See LICENCE file for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2024 HexaCluster Corp&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some parts are copied from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cisecurity.org/cis-benchmarks&#34;&gt;CIS Benchmark&lt;/a&gt; licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;Creative Common Version 4.0&lt;/a&gt; terms of use.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>dimuls/texts-classifier</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:42:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/dimuls/texts-classifier</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/dimuls/texts-classifier" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Neural network classifier for natural language texts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;texts-classifier&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neural network classifier for natural language texts&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>