<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-03T02:19:14Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ko-ichi-h/khcoder</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T02:19:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/ko-ichi-h/khcoder</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ko-ichi-h/khcoder" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;KH Coder: for Quantitative Content Analysis or Text Mining&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;KH Coder: for Quantitative Content Analysis or Text Mining&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Web&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japanese: &lt;a href=&#34;http://khcoder.net&#34;&gt;http://khcoder.net&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; English: &lt;a href=&#34;http://khcoder.net/en&#34;&gt;http://khcoder.net/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;KH Coder is a free software for &lt;strong&gt;quantitative content analysis&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;text mining&lt;/strong&gt;. It is also utilized for computational linguistics. You can analyze Catalan, Chinese (simplified), Dutch, English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Portuguese, Russian, Slovenian and Spanish text with KH Coder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Screenshots: &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/photos/ixn1sTM3jm8o11bP8&#34;&gt;https://goo.gl/photos/ixn1sTM3jm8o11bP8&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; Official book (in Japanese): &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3LdRHMJ&#34;&gt;https://amzn.to/3LdRHMJ&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/2wHFxKg&#34;&gt;http://amzn.to/2wHFxKg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!--&#xA;Changelog:&#xA;https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=en&amp;sl=ja&amp;tl=en&amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fkhcoder.net%2Fversions.html&amp;sandbox=1&#xA;--&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to run source code of KH Coder on Windows&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download &amp;amp; install Perl: &lt;a href=&#34;http://strawberryperl.com/&#34;&gt;http://strawberryperl.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Fork and) clone this repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download released *.exe file (Winzip self-extractor) of KH Coder 3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unzip the downloaded file into the clone directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open command prompt window and go to the clone directory, type &#34;perl kh_coder.pl&#34;, and hit &#34;Enter&#34; key&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you get errors like &#34;Can&#39;t locate &lt;strong&gt;Jcode&lt;/strong&gt;.pm in @INC&#34;, you need to install Perl module called &#34;&lt;strong&gt;Jcode&lt;/strong&gt;&#34;. To install it, type &#34;cpanm &lt;strong&gt;Jcode&lt;/strong&gt;&#34; and hit &#34;Enter&#34; key on your command prompt window.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Above procedure is for people who want to develop or modify KH Coder. If you want to just try or use KH Coder, you don&#39;t need Perl. Please just download and unzip released *.exe file, then double click extracted &#34;kh_coder.exe&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;On Linux or other Un*x like system&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MySQL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Perl (and some Perl modules)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;R (and some R packages)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Morphological Analysis and POS Tagging software &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;ChaSen or MeCab for analyzing Japanese text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FreeLing or Stanford POS Tagger for analyzing English text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FreeLing for analyzing Catalan, French, German, Italian, Portuguese, Russian or Spanish text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MeCab and HanDic for analyzing Korean text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Stanford Word Segmenter and Stanford POS Tagger for analyzing Chinese text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ko-ichi-h/khcoder/issues/91&#34;&gt;issue #91&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ko-ichi-h/khcoder/raw/master/doc_contrib/Vagrantfile&#34;&gt;doc_contrib/Vagrantfile&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ko-ichi-h/khcoder/raw/master/doc_contrib/FedoraInstallation.md&#34;&gt;doc_contrib/FedoraInstallation.md&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU GPL version 2 or later&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SpiderLabs/ModSecurity-nginx</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T02:19:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity-nginx</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity-nginx" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ModSecurity v3 Nginx Connector&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity/raw/v3/master/others/modsec.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity-nginx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity-nginx.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://zenhub.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ZenHubIO/support/master/zenhub-badge.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ModSecurity-nginx connector is the connection point between nginx and libmodsecurity (ModSecurity v3). Said another way, this project provides a communication channel between nginx and libmodsecurity. This connector is required to use LibModSecurity with nginx.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ModSecurity-nginx connector takes the form of an nginx module. The module simply serves as a layer of communication between nginx and ModSecurity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notice that this project depends on libmodsecurity rather than ModSecurity (version 2.9 or less).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is the difference between this project and the old ModSecurity add-on for nginx?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old version uses ModSecurity standalone, which is a wrapper for Apache internals to link ModSecurity to nginx. This current version is closer to nginx, consuming the new libmodsecurity which is no longer dependent on Apache. As a result, this current version has less dependencies, fewer bugs, and is faster. In addition, some new functionality is also provided - such as the possibility of use of global rules configuration with per directory/location customizations (e.g. SecRuleRemoveById).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Compilation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before compile this software make sure that you have libmodsecurity installed. You can download it from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SpiderLabs/ModSecurity&#34;&gt;ModSecurity git repository&lt;/a&gt;. For information pertaining to the compilation and installation of libmodsecurity please consult the documentation provided along with it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With libmodsecurity installed, you can proceed with the installation of the ModSecurity-nginx connector, which follows the nginx third-party module installation procedure. From the nginx source directory:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --add-module=/path/to/ModSecurity-nginx&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or, to build a dynamic module:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --add-dynamic-module=/path/to/ModSecurity-nginx --with-compat&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that when building a dynamic module, your nginx source version needs to match the version of nginx you&#39;re compiling this for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Further information about nginx third-party add-ons support are available here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.nginx.org/3rdPartyModules&#34;&gt;http://wiki.nginx.org/3rdPartyModules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ModSecurity for nginx extends your nginx configuration directives. It adds four new directives and they are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;modsecurity&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;modsecurity on | off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;context:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;http, server, location&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;default:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Turns on or off ModSecurity functionality. Note that this configuration directive is no longer related to the SecRule state. Instead, it now serves solely as an nginx flag to enable or disable the module.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;modsecurity_rules_file&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;modsecurity_rules_file &amp;lt;path to rules file&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;context:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;http, server, location&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;default:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifies the location of the modsecurity configuration file, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nginx&#34;&gt;server {&#xA;    modsecurity on;&#xA;    location / {&#xA;        root /var/www/html;&#xA;        modsecurity_rules_file /etc/my_modsecurity_rules.conf;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;modsecurity_rules_remote&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;modsecurity_rules_remote &amp;lt;key&amp;gt; &amp;lt;URL to rules&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;context:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;http, server, location&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;default:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifies from where (on the internet) a modsecurity configuration file will be downloaded. It also specifies the key that will be used to authenticate to that server:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nginx&#34;&gt;server {&#xA;    modsecurity on;&#xA;    location / {&#xA;        root /var/www/html;&#xA;        modsecurity_rules_remote my-server-key https://my-own-server/rules/download;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;modsecurity_rules&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;modsecurity_rules &amp;lt;modsecurity rule&amp;gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;context:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;http, server, location&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;default:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allows for the direct inclusion of a ModSecurity rule into the nginx configuration. The following example is loading rules from a file and injecting specific configurations per directory/alias:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nginx&#34;&gt;server {&#xA;    modsecurity on;&#xA;    location / {&#xA;        root /var/www/html;&#xA;        modsecurity_rules_file /etc/my_modsecurity_rules.conf;&#xA;    }&#xA;    location /ops {&#xA;        root /var/www/html/opts;&#xA;        modsecurity_rules &#39;&#xA;          SecRuleEngine On&#xA;          SecDebugLog /tmp/modsec_debug.log&#xA;          SecDebugLogLevel 9&#xA;          SecRuleRemoveById 10&#xA;        &#39;;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;modsecurity_transaction_id&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syntax:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;modsecurity_transaction_id string&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;context:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;http, server, location&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;default:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allows to pass transaction ID from nginx instead of generating it in the library. This can be useful for tracing purposes, e.g. consider this configuration:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-nginx&#34;&gt;log_format extended &#39;$remote_addr - $remote_user [$time_local] &#39;&#xA;                    &#39;&#34;$request&#34; $status $body_bytes_sent &#39;&#xA;                    &#39;&#34;$http_referer&#34; &#34;$http_user_agent&#34; $request_id&#39;;&#xA;&#xA;server {&#xA;    server_name host1;&#xA;    modsecurity on;&#xA;    modsecurity_transaction_id &#34;host1-$request_id&#34;;&#xA;    access_log logs/host1-access.log extended;&#xA;    error_log logs/host1-error.log;&#xA;    location / {&#xA;        ...&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;server {&#xA;    server_name host2;&#xA;    modsecurity on;&#xA;    modsecurity_transaction_id &#34;host2-$request_id&#34;;&#xA;    access_log logs/host2-access.log extended;&#xA;    error_log logs/host2-error.log;&#xA;    location / {&#xA;        ...&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a combination of log_format and modsecurity_transaction_id you will be able to find correlations between access log and error log entries using the same unique identificator.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;String can contain variables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contributing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As an open source project we invite (and encourage) anyone from the community to contribute to our project. This may take the form of: new functionality, bug fixes, bug reports, beginners user support, and anything else that you are willing to help with. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Providing Patches&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We prefer to have your patch within the GitHub infrastructure to facilitate our review work, and our QA integration. GitHub provides an excellent documentation on how to perform “Pull Requests”. More information available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests/&#34;&gt;https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please respect the coding style in use. Pull requests can include various commits, so provide one fix or one functionality per commit. Do not change anything outside the scope of your target work (e.g. coding style in a function that you have passed by).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Don’t know where to start?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within our code there are various items marked as TODO or FIXME that may need your attention. Check the list of items by performing a grep:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /path/to/modsecurity-nginx&#xA;$ egrep -Rin &#34;TODO|FIXME&#34; -R *&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may also take a look at recent bug reports and open issues to get an idea of what kind of help we are looking for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Testing your patch&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Along with the manual testing, we strongly recommend that you to use the nginx test utility to make sure that you patch does not adversely affect the behavior or performance of nginx.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The nginx tests are available on: &lt;a href=&#34;http://hg.nginx.org/nginx-tests/&#34;&gt;http://hg.nginx.org/nginx-tests/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use those tests, make sure you have the Perl utility prove (part of Perl 5) and proceed with the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cp /path/to/ModSecurity-nginx/tests/* /path/to/nginx/test/repository&#xA;$ cd /path/to/nginx/test/repository&#xA;$ TEST_NGINX_BINARY=/path/to/your/nginx prove .&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are facing problems getting your added functionality to pass all the nginx tests, feel free to contact us or the nginx mailing list at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://nginx.org/en/support.html&#34;&gt;http://nginx.org/en/support.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Debugging&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We respect the nginx debugging schema. By using the configuration option &#34;--with-debug&#34; during the nginx configuration you will also be enabling the connector&#39;s debug messages. Core dumps and crashes are expected to be debugged in the same fashion that is used to debug nginx. For further information, please check the nginx debugging information: &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.nginx.org/Debugging&#34;&gt;http://wiki.nginx.org/Debugging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are facing a configuration issue or if something is not working as you expect it to be, please use ModSecurity user’s mailing list. Issues on GitHub are also welcome, but we prefer to have users question on the mailing list first, where you can reach an entire community. Also don’t forget to look for an existing issue before opening a new one.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, If you are planning to open an issue on GitHub, please don’t forget to tell us the version of your libmodsecurity and the version of the nginx connector you are running.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Security issue&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please do not publicly report any security issue. Instead, contact us at: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@modsecurity.org&#34;&gt;security@modsecurity.org&lt;/a&gt; to report the issue. Once the problem is fixed we will provide you with credit for the discovery.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature Request&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We would love to discuss any ideas that you may have for a new feature. Please keep in mind this is a community driven project so be sure to contact the community via the mailing list to get feedback first. Alternatively, feel free to open GitHub issues requesting for new features. Before opening a new issue, please check if there is an existing feature request for the desired functionality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having our packages in distros on time is something we highly desire. Let us know if there is anything we can do to facilitate your work as a packager.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>get-iplayer/get_iplayer</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T02:19:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/get-iplayer/get_iplayer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A utility for downloading TV and radio programmes from BBC iPlayer and BBC Sounds&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;get_iplayer: BBC iPlayer/BBC Sounds Indexing Tool and PVR&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Downloads TV and radio programmes from BBC iPlayer/BBC Sounds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows multiple programmes to be downloaded using a single command&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Indexing of most available iPlayer/Sounds catch-up programmes from previous 30 days (not Red Button, iPlayer Exclusive, or Podcast-only)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Caching of programme index with automatic updating&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regex search on programme name&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Regex search on programme description and episode title&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Filter search results by channel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Direct download via programme ID or URL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PVR capability (may be used with cron or Task Scheduler)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HTTP proxy support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Perl 5.16+ required, plus LWP, LWP::Protocol::https, XML::LibXML, Mojolicious, and CGI modules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Requires ffmpeg for conversion to MP4 and AtomicParsley for metadata tagging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runs on Linux/BSD (Ubuntu, Fedora, OpenBSD and others), macOS (10.10+), Windows (7/8/10)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;get_iplayer can only search for programmes that were scheduled for broadcast on BBC linear services within the previous 30 days, even if some are available for more than 30 days on the iPlayer/Sounds sites. Red button programmes, iPlayer box sets, web-only content, and BBC podcasts are not searchable. Programmes that are still available after 30 days must be located on the iPlayer/Sounds sites and downloaded directly via PID or URL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;get_iplayer does not support downloading news/sport videos, other embedded media, archive programmes, special collections, educational material, programme clips or any content other than whole episodes of programmes scheduled for broadcast on BBC linear services within the previous 30 days. However, it is generally possible to download other content such as red button programmes, iPlayer box sets, or podcasts directly via PID or URL. get_iplayer DOES NOT support live recording from BBC channels.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer/wiki&#34;&gt;https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer/wiki/installation&#34;&gt;https://github.com/get-iplayer/get_iplayer/wiki/installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --help&#xA;get_iplayer --basic-help&#xA;get_iplayer --long-help&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all TV programmes (&lt;code&gt;--type=tv&lt;/code&gt; set by default):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer &#34;.*&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Search output appears in this format:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ...&#xA;  208:  Doctor Who: Series 7 Part 2 - 1. The Bells of Saint John, BBC One, b01rryzz&#xA;  209:  Doctor Who: Series 7 Part 2 - 2. The Rings Of Akhaten, BBC One, b01rx0lj&#xA;  210:  Doctor Who: Series 7 Part 2 - 3. Cold War, BBC One, b01s1cz7&#xA;  ...&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Format = &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;index&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; - &amp;lt;episode&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;channel&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;pid&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all TV programmes with long descriptions:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --long &#34;.*&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all radio programmes:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --type=radio &#34;.*&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all TV programmes with &#34;doctor who&#34; in the name (matching is case-insensitive):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer &#34;doctor who&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all TV and radio programmes with &#34;doctor who&#34; in the name:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --type tv,radio &#34;doctor who&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List all BBC One programmes:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --channel=&#34;BBC One&#34; &#34;.*&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List Radio 4 and Radio 4 Extra programmes with &#34;Book at Bedtime&#34; in the title:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --type=radio --channel=&#34;Radio 4&#34; &#34;Book at Bedtime&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;List only Radio 4 programmes with &#34;Book at Bedtime&#34; in the title:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --type=radio --channel=&#34;Radio 4$&#34; &#34;Book at Bedtime&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(The &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; regular expression metacharacter matches &#34;Radio 4&#34; only at the end of the channel name, thus avoiding matches against &#34;Radio 4 Extra&#34;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record TV programme number 208 (index from search results) in HD, with fallback to lower quality if not available:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --get 208&lt;/code&gt; [default setting]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --get 208 --tv-quality=hd,sd,web,mobile&lt;/code&gt; [explicit setting]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record TV programme number 208 in lower resolution only (704x396@50):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --get 208 --tv-quality=web&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record TV programme number 208 and download subtitles in SubRip (SRT) format:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --get 208 --subtitles&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record multiple TV programmes (using index numbers from search results):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --get 208 209 210&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record a TV programme using its iPlayer URL:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer https://www.bbc.co.uk/iplayer/episode/b01sc0wf/Doctors_Series_15_Perfect/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record a TV programme using the PID (b01sc0wf) from its iPlayer URL:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b01sc0wf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record a radio programme using its Sounds URL:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/b07gcv34&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record a radio programme using the PID (b07gcv34) from its Sounds URL in high quality (320k), with fallback to lower quality if not available (default setting):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b07gcv34&lt;/code&gt; [default setting]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b07gcv34 --radio-quality=high,std,med,low&lt;/code&gt; [explicit setting]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record a radio programme using the PID (b07gcv34) from its Sounds URL with lower bit rate only (96k):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b07gcv34 --radio-quality=med&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Record multiple radio programmes (using PIDs from Sounds URLs):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b07gcv34,b07h60ld&lt;/code&gt; [comma-separated list]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_iplayer --pid=b07gcv34 --pid=b07h60ld&lt;/code&gt; [multiple arguments]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Sometimes you may not be able to download a listed programme immediately after broadcast (usually available within 24hrs of airing). Some BBC programmes may not be available from iPlayer/Sounds.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>