<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-04T01:32:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PAIR-code/facets</title>
    <updated>2024-01-04T01:32:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-04:/PAIR-code/facets</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PAIR-code/facets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visualizations for machine learning datasets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The facets project contains two visualizations for understanding and analyzing machine learning datasets: Facets Overview and Facets Dive.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The visualizations are implemented as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polymer-project.org&#34;&gt;Polymer&lt;/a&gt; web components, backed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typescriptlang.org&#34;&gt;Typescript&lt;/a&gt; code and can be easily embedded into Jupyter notebooks or webpages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Live demos of the visualizations can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pair-code.github.io/facets/&#34;&gt;Facets project description page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Facets Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/facets/master/img/overview-census.png&#34; alt=&#34;Overview visualization of UCI census data&#34; title=&#34;Overview visualization of UCI census data -  Lichman, M. (2013). UCI Machine Learning Repository [http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Census+Income]. Irvine, CA: University of California, School of Information and Computer Science&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview gives a high-level view of one or more data sets. It produces a visual feature-by-feature statistical analysis, and can also be used to compare statistics across two or more data sets. The tool can process both numeric and string features, including multiple instances of a number or string per feature.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview can help uncover issues with datasets, including the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unexpected feature values&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Missing feature values for a large number of examples&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Training/serving skew&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Training/test/validation set skew&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key aspects of the visualization are outlier detection and distribution comparison across multiple datasets. Interesting values (such as a high proportion of missing data, or very different distributions of a feature across multiple datasets) are highlighted in red. Features can be sorted by values of interest such as the number of missing values or the skew between the different datasets.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The python code to generate the statistics for visualization can be installed through &lt;code&gt;pip install facets-overview&lt;/code&gt;. As of version 1.1.0, the &lt;code&gt;facets-overview&lt;/code&gt; package requires a version of &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; at version 3.20.0 or later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Details about Overview usage can be found in its &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/facets/master/facets_overview/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Facets Dive&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/facets/master/img/dive-census.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dive visualization of UCI census data&#34; title=&#34;Dive visualization of UCI census data -  Lichman, M. (2013). UCI Machine Learning Repository [http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Census+Income]. Irvine, CA: University of California, School of Information and Computer Science&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dive is a tool for interactively exploring up to tens of thousands of multidimensional data points, allowing users to seamlessly switch between a high-level overview and low-level details. Each example is a represented as single item in the visualization and the points can be positioned by faceting/bucketing in multiple dimensions by their feature values. Combining smooth animation and zooming with faceting and filtering, Dive makes it easy to spot patterns and outliers in complex data sets.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Details about Dive usage can be found in its &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/facets/master/facets_dive/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage in Google Colabratory/Jupyter Notebooks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Facets in &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com&#34;&gt;Google Colabratory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://jupyter.org&#34;&gt;Jupyter&lt;/a&gt; notebooks can be seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/github/PAIR-code/facets/blob/master/colab_facets.ipynb&#34;&gt;in this notebook&lt;/a&gt;. These notebooks work without the need to first download/install this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both Facets visualizations make use of HTML imports. So in order to use them, you must first load the appropriate polyfill, through &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&#34;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/webcomponentsjs/1.3.3/webcomponents-lite.js&#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, as shown in the demo notebooks in this repo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that for using Facets Overview in a Jupyter notebook, there are two considerations:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the notebook, you will need to change the path that the Facets Overview python code is loaded from to the correct path given where your notebook kernel is run from.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must also have the Protocol Buffers python runtime library installed: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/protobuf/tree/master/python&#34;&gt;https://github.com/google/protobuf/tree/master/python&lt;/a&gt;. If you used pip or anaconda to install Jupyter, you can use the same tool to install the runtime library.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When visualizing a large amount of data in Dive in a Juypter notebook, as is done in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/facets/master/facets_dive/Dive_demo.ipynb&#34;&gt;Dive demo Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt;, you will need to start the notebook server with an increased IOPub data rate. This can be done with the command &lt;code&gt;jupyter notebook --NotebookApp.iopub_data_rate_limit=10000000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/PAIR-code/facets&#xA;cd facets&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building the Visualizations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you make code changes to the visualization and would like to rebuild them, follow these directions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install bazel: &lt;a href=&#34;https://bazel.build/&#34;&gt;https://bazel.build/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build the visualizations: &lt;code&gt;bazel build facets:facets_jupyter&lt;/code&gt; (run from the facets top-level directory)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using the rebuilt Visualizations in a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use the visualizations you built locally in a Jupyter notebook, follow these directions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Move the resulting vulcanized html file from the build step into the facets-dist directory: &lt;code&gt;cp -f bazel-bin/facets/facets-jupyter.html facets-dist/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the visualizations into Jupyter as an nbextension.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If jupyter was installed with pip, you can use &lt;code&gt;jupyter nbextension install facets-dist/ &lt;/code&gt; if jupyter was installed system-wide or &lt;code&gt;jupyter nbextension install facets-dist/ --user&lt;/code&gt; if installed per-user (run from the facets top-level directory). You do not need to run any follow-up &lt;code&gt;jupyter nbextension enable&lt;/code&gt; command for this extension.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can manually install the nbextension by finding your jupyter installation&#39;s &lt;code&gt;share/jupyter/nbextensions&lt;/code&gt; folder and copying the facets-dist directory into it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the notebook cell&#39;s HTML link tag that loads the built facets html, load from &lt;code&gt;/nbextensions/facets-dist/facets-jupyter.html&lt;/code&gt;, which is the locally installed facets distribution. from the previous step.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Facets visualizations currently work only in Chrome - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PAIR-code/issues/9&#34;&gt;Issue 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer: This is not an official Google product&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>