<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-12T01:32:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>svpino/youtube-rag</title>
    <updated>2024-03-12T01:32:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-12:/svpino/youtube-rag</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/svpino/youtube-rag" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Building a RAG application from scratch&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a step-by-step guide to building a simple RAG (Retrieval-Augmented Generation) application using Pinecone and OpenAI&#39;s API. The application will allow you to ask questions about any YouTube video.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a virtual environment and install the required packages:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ python3 -m venv .venv&#xA;$ source .venv/bin/activate&#xA;$ pip install -r requirements.txt&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Create a free Pinecone account and get your API key from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pinecone.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Create a &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file with the following variables:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;OPENAI_API_KEY = [ENTER YOUR OPENAI API KEY HERE]&#xA;PINECONE_API_KEY = [ENTER YOUR PINECONE API KEY HERE]&#xA;PINECONE_API_ENV = [ENTER YOUR PINECONE API ENVIRONMENT HERE]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mithril-security/LaVague</title>
    <updated>2024-03-12T01:32:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-12:/mithril-security/LaVague</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mithril-security/LaVague" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Large Action Model framework to automate browser interaction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mithril-security/LaVague/main/static/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;LaVague Logo&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;🌊 Welcome to LaVague&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Redefining internet surfing by transforming natural language instructions into seamless browser interactions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/SDxn9KpqX9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/SDxn9KpqX9?compact=true&amp;amp;style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Join our Discord server!&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;See LaVague in Action&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Here are examples to show how LaVague can execute natural instructions on a browser to automate interactions with a website:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;figure&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mithril-security/LaVague/main/static/hf_lavague.gif&#34; alt=&#34;LaVague Interaction Example&#34; style=&#34;margin-right: 20px;&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;   LaVague interacting with Hugging Face&#39;s website.&#xA;  &lt;/figcaption&gt; &#xA; &lt;/figure&gt; &#xA; &lt;figure&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mithril-security/LaVague/main/static/irs_lavague.gif&#34; alt=&#34;LaVague Workflow Example&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;   LaVague interacting with the IRS&#39;s website.&#xA;  &lt;/figcaption&gt; &#xA; &lt;/figure&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaVague is designed to automate menial tasks on behalf of its users. Many of these tasks are repetitive, time-consuming, and require little to no cognitive effort. By automating these tasks, LaVague aims to free up time for more meaningful endeavors, allowing users to focus on what truly matters to them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By providing an engine turning natural language queries into Selenium code, LaVague is designed to make it easy for users or other AIs to automate easily express web workflows and execute them on a browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the key usages we see is to automate tasks that are personal to users and require them to be logged in, for instance automating the process of paying bills, filling out forms or pulling data from specific websites.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaVague is built on open-source projects and leverages open-sources models, either locally or remote, to ensure the transparency of the agent and ensures that it is aligned with users&#39; interests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/strong&gt;: Understands instructions in natural language to perform browser interactions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selenium Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Seamlessly integrates with Selenium for automating web browsers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-Source&lt;/strong&gt;: Built on open-source projects such as transformers and llama-index, and leverages open-source models, either locally or remote, to ensure the transparency of the agent and ensures that it is aligned with users&#39; interests.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local models for privacy and control&lt;/strong&gt;: Supports local models like &lt;code&gt;Gemma-7b&lt;/code&gt; so that users can fully control their AI assistant and have privacy guarantees.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced AI techniques&lt;/strong&gt;: Uses a local embedding (&lt;code&gt;bge-small-en-v1.5&lt;/code&gt;) first to perform RAG to extract the most relevant HTML pieces to feed the LLM answering the query, as directly dropping the full HTML code would not fit in context. Then leverages Few-shot learning and Chain of Thought to elicit the most relevant Selenium code to perform the action without having to finetune the LLM (&lt;code&gt;Nous-Hermes-2-Mixtral-8x7B-DPO&lt;/code&gt;) for code generation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can try LaVague in the following Colab notebook:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/github/dhuynh95/LaVague/blob/main/LaVague.ipynb&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Open In Colab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an early project but could grow to democratize transparent and aligned AI models to undertake actions for the sake of users on the internet. We see the following key areas to explore:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fine-tune local models like a &lt;code&gt;gemma-7b-it&lt;/code&gt; to be expert in Text2Action&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve retrieval to make sure only relevant pieces of code are used for code generation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support other browser engines (playwright) or even other automation frameworks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested by this project, want to ask questions, contribute, or have proposals, please come on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/SDxn9KpqX9&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; to chat!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>