<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-23T01:33:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ed-donner/agents</title>
    <updated>2025-06-23T01:33:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-23:/ed-donner/agents</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ed-donner/agents" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repo for the Complete Agentic AI Engineering Course&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Master AI Agentic Engineering - build autonomous AI Agents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;6 week journey to code and deploy AI Agents with OpenAI Agents SDK, CrewAI, LangGraph, AutoGen and MCP&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/assets/autonomy.png&#34; alt=&#34;Autonomous Agent&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&#39;re looking at this in Cursor, please right click on the filename in the Explorer on the left, and select &#34;Open preview&#34;, to view the formatted version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t be more excited to welcome you! This is the start of your 6 week adventure into the powerful, astonishing and often surreal world of Agentic AI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Before you begin&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m here to help you be most successful! Please do reach out if I can help, either in the platform or by emailing me direct (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ed@edwarddonner.com&#34;&gt;ed@edwarddonner.com&lt;/a&gt;). It&#39;s always great to connect with people on LinkedIn to build up the community - you&#39;ll find me here:&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eddonner/&#34;&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eddonner/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; And this is new to me, but I&#39;m also trying out X/Twitter at &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/edwarddonner&#34;&gt;@edwarddonner&lt;/a&gt; - if you&#39;re on X, please show me how it&#39;s done 😂&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The not-so-dreaded setup instructions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps famous last words: but I really, truly hope that I&#39;ve put together an environment that will be not too horrific to set up!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows people, your instructions are &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/setup/SETUP-PC.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mac people, yours are &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/setup/SETUP-mac.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linux people, yours are &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/setup/SETUP-linux.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any problems, please do contact me.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Important notes for CrewAI week (Week 3)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Windows PC users: you will need to have checked the &#34;gotcha #4&#34; at the top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/setup/SETUP-PC.md&#34;&gt;SETUP-PC&lt;/a&gt; instructions -- installing Microsoft Build Tools.&lt;br&gt; Then, you will need to run this command in a Cursor Terminal in the project root directory in order to run the Crew commands:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;uv tool install crewai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; And in case you&#39;ve used Crew before, it might be worth doing this to make sure you have the latest:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;uv tool upgrade crewai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then please keep in mind for Crew:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There are two ways that you can work on the CrewAI project in week 3. Either review the code for each project while I build it, and then do &lt;code&gt;crewai run&lt;/code&gt; to see it in action. Or if you prefer to be more hands-on, then create your own Crew project from scratch to mirror mine; for example, create &lt;code&gt;my_debate&lt;/code&gt; to go alongside &lt;code&gt;debate&lt;/code&gt;, and write the code alongside me. Either approach works!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows users: there&#39;s a new issue that was recently introduced by one of Crew&#39;s libraries. Until this is fixed, you might get a &#34;unicode&#34; error when you try to run &lt;code&gt;crewai create crew&lt;/code&gt;. If that happens, please try running this command in the Terminal first: &lt;code&gt;$env:PYTHONUTF8 = &#34;1&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Super useful resources&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The course &lt;a href=&#34;https://edwarddonner.com/2025/04/21/the-complete-agentic-ai-engineering-course/&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; with videos&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Many essential guides in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/guides/01_intro.ipynb&#34;&gt;guides&lt;/a&gt; section&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/setup/troubleshooting.ipynb&#34;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; notebook&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;API costs - please read me!&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course does involve making calls to OpenAI and other frontier models, requiring an API key and a small spend, which we set up in the SETUP instructions. If you&#39;d prefer not to spend on API calls, there are cheaper alternatives like DeepSeek and free alternatives like using Ollama!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Details are &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ed-donner/agents/main/guides/09_ai_apis_and_ollama.ipynb&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to monitor your API costs to ensure you are totally happy with any spend. For OpenAI, the dashboard is &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/usage&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;ABOVE ALL ELSE -&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Be sure to have fun with the course! You could not have picked a better time to be learning about Agentic AI. I hope you enjoy every single minute! And if you get stuck at any point - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/eddonner/&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>