<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-19T01:32:39Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kawalc1/kawalc1</title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T01:32:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-19:/kawalc1/kawalc1</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kawalc1/kawalc1" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Automatic verification of uploaded C1 forms through image processing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Kawal C1&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://kawalc1.org/static/img/logo-kotak.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a description of how this software was used to verify the results of the 2019 Indonesian elections, read the information at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kawalpemilu/upload.kawalpemilu.org&#34;&gt;Kawal Pemilu&lt;/a&gt;. Current updates are posted on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/c1kawal/&#34;&gt;facebook group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This video contains almost all tally forms from the 2019 presidential elections as they were digitized by our system:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_cgl1tMVcJ0&#34; title=&#34;800.000 Formulir&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.youtube.com/vi/_cgl1tMVcJ0/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMAGE ALT TEXT&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Verifikasi Otomatis Formulir Pemilu C1&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deskripsi Use Case:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pengguna mengunggah formulir C1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Aplikasi akan mencoba mengenali angka pada formulir&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Angka hasil pendeteksian akan ditampilkan beserta dengan hasil penjumlahannya&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Jika pengguna telah memverifikasi dan setuju dengan hasil pendeteksian, proses selesai.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Jika ditemukan hasil pendeteksian yang tidak sesuai, pengguna dapat melakukan koreksi secara manual.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Semua data akan disimpan di database dan digunakan untuk peningkatan akurasi dari algoritma yang digunakan.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Automatic Verification of C1 Election Forms&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use Case Description:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The user uploads a C1 form&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The application tries to recognize the numbers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The numbers that it has detected and whether they add up are displayed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the user agrees with what the computer has detected the process is finished.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the user doesn&#39;t agree with the computer, he/she has the opportunity to submit the correct numbers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All this data is stored in a database and can serve to improve the accuracy of the algorithms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development setup - python&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run unittests&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;copy the example.env file to pycharm.env&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;adjust the BASEDIR to point to your project location&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;install &lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.jetbrains.com/plugin/7861-envfile&#34;&gt;envfile&lt;/a&gt; plugin in PyCharm; follow the instructions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;run the unittests from the Run menu; they will fail, but you will have configuration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;edit the unittest configuration via the Run menu; point the unittest configuration to the pycharm.env file you just created&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;run the unittests again, they should now succeed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>huggingface/cookbook</title>
    <updated>2024-02-19T01:32:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-19:/huggingface/cookbook</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/huggingface/cookbook" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open-source AI cookbook&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open-Source AI Cookbook&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains community-driven practical examples of building AI applications and solving various tasks with AI using open-source tools and models.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing to the cookbook&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone is welcome to contribute, and we value everybody&#39;s contribution! There are several ways you can contribute to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/learn/cookbook/index&#34;&gt;Open-Source AI Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit an idea for a desired example/guide via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/huggingface/cookbook/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contribute a new notebook with a practical example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve existing examples by fixing issues/typos.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before contributing, check currently &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/huggingface/cookbook/issues&#34;&gt;open issues&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/huggingface/cookbook/pulls&#34;&gt;pull requests&lt;/a&gt; to avoid working on something that someone else is already working on.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What makes a good Cookbook notebook?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We believe that the Cookbook will be the most beneficial for everyone in the community if the Jupyter notebooks have the following qualities:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Practical&lt;/em&gt;: Your notebook should provide an illustration of an end-to-end project or a specific aspect of AI development. Aim for real-world applications, but try to avoid overcomplicating. Clearly explain the objectives, challenges and steps involved.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Build with open-source tools and models&lt;/em&gt;: Utilize open source libraries, datasets, and pre-trained models available under permissive licenses. Include links to all resources used within the notebook.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clearly written&lt;/em&gt;: Ensure your writing is clear, concise, and free from grammatical errors. Maintain a friendly and approachable tone throughout the notebook. Explain the steps you take to solve a problem, challenges, alternative approaches.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Executes without errors&lt;/em&gt;: Test your notebook to avoid runtime errors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adds to existing &#34;recipes&#34;&lt;/em&gt;: Before submitting, review existing notebooks to confirm that the subject hasn&#39;t been covered yet. We welcome diverse use cases, modalities, techniques, and approaches!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Creating a pull request&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When contributing a new example/guide, open a pull request and tag &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MKhalusova&#34;&gt;@MKhalusova&lt;/a&gt; for a review.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If using any images in the markdown, upload them to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/datasets/huggingface/cookbook-images&#34;&gt;huggingface/cookbook-images&lt;/a&gt; dataset. Then use the link to the image in your markdown, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![RAG diagram](https://huggingface.co/datasets/huggingface/cookbook-images/resolve/main/rag-diagram.png)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once your pull request is merged, the notebook will show up in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/huggingface/cookbook/main/hf.co/learn/cookbook&#34;&gt;Open-Source AI Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>