<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-14T01:31:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>UditGupta10/GPT-InvestAR</title>
    <updated>2023-09-14T01:31:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-14:/UditGupta10/GPT-InvestAR</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/UditGupta10/GPT-InvestAR" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Enhancing Stock Investment Strategies through Annual Report Analysis with Large Language Models&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;GPT-InvestAR&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enhancing Stock Investment Strategies through Annual Report Analysis with Large Language Models&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a set of tools and scripts designed to enhance stock investment strategies through the analysis of annual reports using Large Language Models. The components in this repository are organized as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;download_10k.py&lt;/strong&gt;: This Python script downloads 10-K filings of companies from the SEC website, which contain crucial financial information.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;convert_html_to_pdf.py&lt;/strong&gt;: Converts HTML files to PDF files. PDFs are preferred due to their token efficiency for further analysis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;make_targets.py&lt;/strong&gt;: Generates a DataFrame of stock tickers with target values of different time resolutions, which can be used as investment targets for a Machine Learning model.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;embeddings_save.py&lt;/strong&gt;: Generates embeddings of PDF files and saves them using Cromadb. These embeddings are numerical representations of the textual content in annual reports.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gpt_scores_as_features.py&lt;/strong&gt;: Utilizes saved embeddings to query all questions for each annual report using a Large Language Model (LLM) such as GPT-3.5, and uses the scores or answers as features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;modeling_and_return_estimation.ipynb&lt;/strong&gt;: This Jupyter Notebook contains the core modeling process. It uses machine learning techniques, specifically Linear Regression, to model the dataset and estimate returns. The goal is to create a portfolio of top-k predicted stocks and compare their returns with the S&amp;amp;P 500 index.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By following the sequence of these components, you can analyze annual reports, generate embeddings, and build predictive models to potentially enhance stock investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore each component for more details and usage instructions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jerryjliu/llama_index&#34;&gt;LLama Index&lt;/a&gt; (and related dependencies)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenBB-finance/OpenBBTerminal&#34;&gt;OpenBB&lt;/a&gt; (and related dependencies)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scikit-learn/scikit-learn&#34;&gt;Scikit-Learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JazzCore/python-pdfkit&#34;&gt;PDFKit&lt;/a&gt; (and related dependencies)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to install libraries 1 and 2 in separate virtual (conda) environments. The python scripts mentioned above do not require both these libraries to be installed in the same environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use the code or find this repository helpful, please consider citing the paper:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GPT-InvestAR&lt;/strong&gt;: Enhancing Stock Investment Strategies through Annual Report Analysis with Large Language Models&lt;br&gt; Udit Gupta&lt;br&gt; Published on arXiv: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.03079&#34;&gt;arXiv Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bibtex&#34;&gt;@article{GPT-InvestAR,&#xA;  author = {Udit Gupta},&#xA;  title = {GPT-InvestAR: Enhancing Stock Investment Strategies through Annual Report Analysis with Large Language Models},&#xA;  journal = {arXiv e-prints},&#xA;  year = {2023},&#xA;  eprint = {arXiv:2309.03079},&#xA;  url = {https://arxiv.org/abs/2309.03079},&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>