<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-14T01:29:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Recode-Hive/Stackoverflow-Analysis</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T01:29:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-14:/Recode-Hive/Stackoverflow-Analysis</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Recode-Hive/Stackoverflow-Analysis" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stack overflow is a professional community for developers. This repo analysis 3 years of developer Survey done by Stackoverflow and do visualization and predict the salary of Data Scientist in future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Stack Overflow Analysis Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;👨‍💻 Demo Video&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/30715153/168960157-e9448ea4-206c-44c0-bbd5-5e4770c0411f.mp4&#34;&gt;Watch the demo video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;👇 Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before installation, please ensure you have the following tools installed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; - Learn Git step-by-step by following the instructions provided &lt;a href=&#34;https://recodehive.com/how-to-install-git-git-tutorial/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anaconda.org/anaconda&#34;&gt;Anaconda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anaconda.org/anaconda/jupyter&#34;&gt;Jupyter Package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🛠️ Installation Steps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fork the project&lt;/strong&gt;: Fork the &lt;code&gt;sanjay-kv/Stackoverflow-Analysis&lt;/code&gt; repository. Follow these instructions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/articles/fork-a-repo&#34;&gt;how to fork a repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone the project&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:your-username/Stackoverflow-Analysis.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the original data&lt;/strong&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/13W20DfCW2W5GEeKTYTl7R6xV5hmPS2Do?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;drive link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Jupyter Notebook&lt;/strong&gt; and place the file in the project folder. Make sure you&#39;re selecting the correct path.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions from all levels of experience. If you think the community would benefit from being walked through the steps you&#39;re going through, please share! ❤️&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Finding Insights from Stack Overflow Developer Survey&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stack Overflow is a professional community for developers, conducting a survey annually. Analyzing the dataset professionally using modern tools can enable us to answer real-world questions effectively. The dataset covers 275 questions in total.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Project Goals:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Perform Analysis on the last 3 years&#39; Stack Overflow Dataset to extract insights.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Analyze the impact of higher education, experience, and responsibilities on salary and gender inequalities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Investigate participation rates based on ethnicity and differences in income between men and women.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Explore the popularity of programming languages and predict their growth based on survey responses.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Data Source and Background&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dataset comes from the annual Stack Overflow developer survey, covering responses from developers in 180 countries. The data are available in CSV format, ranging from 40 to 150 MB, with responses from 1.5 Lakh survey participants.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Data Format&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The data is in a CSV file format with 252,199 observations and 62 variables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Expected Work&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data wrangling tasks include handling null values and converting data for analysis. Techniques such as ML algorithms and data visualization will be employed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;👨‍💻 Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contributions are greatly appreciated. Check out our contribution guidelines (yet to be updated) for more information.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🛡️ License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Recode-Hive/Stackoverflow-Analysis/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💪 Thanks to all Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all contributors for helping this project grow! 🍻&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sanjay-kv/Stackoverflow-Analysis/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=sanjay-kv/Stackoverflow-Analysis&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🙏 Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t forget to leave a star ⭐️ for this project!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Crafted with ♥ by @sanjay-kv.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TAHIR0110/ThereForYou</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T01:29:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-14:/TAHIR0110/ThereForYou</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TAHIR0110/ThereForYou" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThereForYou: Your mental health ally. Kai, our AI assistant, offers compassionate support. Track your mood trends, find solace in a secure community, and access crisis resources swiftly. We&#39;re here to empower your journey towards improved well-being, leveraging technology for a brighter tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ThereForYou&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/63473496/213306239-9e8fc317-ce2f-4127-8bfe-17f5df06ee99.png#gh-light-mode-only&#34; alt=&#34;GSSoC Logo Light&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/63473496/213306279-338f7ce9-9a9f-4427-8c2a-3e344874498f.png#gh-dark-mode-only&#34; alt=&#34;GSSoC Logo Dark&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://socialify.git.ci/TAHIR0110/ThereForYou/image?language=1&amp;amp;name=1&amp;amp;pattern=Plus&amp;amp;theme=Auto&#34; alt=&#34;ThereForYou&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;320&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Enhanced Public Safety: ThereForYou&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ThereForYou&lt;/strong&gt; is a groundbreaking solution aimed at enhancing public safety, particularly focusing on mental health support and suicide prevention. Leveraging cutting-edge technologies such as artificial intelligence (AI), machine learning (ML), natural language processing (NLP), and blockchain, our project offers accessible and empathetic assistance to individuals facing mental health challenges.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Part 1: AI Psychologist&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dynamic Voice Adjustment: Our AI assistant dynamically adjusts its voice to match the user&#39;s gender, enhancing engagement and personalization.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Emotion Detection: Utilizing algorithms, the assistant detects signs of sadness or depression in user speech, securely storing this data using blockchain technology for potential future counseling sessions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Empathetic Support: In moments of distress, sadness, or depression, the AI psychologist offers empathetic support and practical advice to encourage users towards positive steps forward.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Part 2: Suicide Prevention Model&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choking Detection: We have developed an API powered by advanced machine learning models that can detect signs of choking in users. Upon detection, it immediately sends alerts with location data of the victim to nearby users and authorities, including police officers, ensuring prompt assistance in critical situations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reward System: Users who assist individuals in choking incidents are rewarded with HealthTokens, redeemable at hospitals. This incentivizes community involvement in assisting those in need.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Part 3: Voice-Activated Safety Alert System&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NLP-Based Danger Detection: Our advanced NLP model detects danger signals from user speech. Upon detection, nearby users and authorities such as police officers are alerted through push notifications about the location and condition of the victim.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reward Mechanism: Similar to Part 2, individuals who respond to safety alerts and assist those in danger are rewarded with HealthTokens.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Link to safety system =&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://vhelp.onrender.com/&#34;&gt;https://vhelp.onrender.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;App link could not be shared because of security reasons&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Videos:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PART 1:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/f8e68f17-ec9b-46f5-94c1-f09af9d5afa3&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/f8e68f17-ec9b-46f5-94c1-f09af9d5afa3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PART 2:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/8de7ae5d-30b6-48f8-a58c-c4c9c1ce8bf4&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/8de7ae5d-30b6-48f8-a58c-c4c9c1ce8bf4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PART 3 (MUST WATCH):&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/c13cde81-8ab2-4999-aa0c-916c5551d54d&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Atharv714/nationalhackathon/assets/142321494/c13cde81-8ab2-4999-aa0c-916c5551d54d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tech Stack&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Frontend&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HTML/CSS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;JavaScript&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flutter&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TensorFlow&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Natural language processing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SpaCy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NLTK&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenCV&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Backend&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flask&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenAPI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Google Web Speech API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PyAudio&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Node.js&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Firebase&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SrijanShovit/HealthLearning</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T01:29:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-14:/SrijanShovit/HealthLearning</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SrijanShovit/HealthLearning" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A repo comprising of various Machine Learning and Deep Learning projects in healthcare domain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Health Learning: ML and Deep Learning for Healthcare 🩺🧠&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Health Learning is an open-source project aimed at leveraging machine learning (ML) and deep learning techniques to address various healthcare challenges. By harnessing the power of data-driven approaches, our goal is to develop predictive models, diagnostic tools, and decision support systems to improve patient outcomes, optimize healthcare delivery, and advance medical research.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivation 🚀&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The field of healthcare is ripe for innovation, with vast amounts of data available from diverse sources such as electronic health records, medical imaging, wearable devices, and genetic sequencing. Health Learning seeks to harness this wealth of data to tackle a wide range of healthcare issues, including disease prediction, diagnosis, treatment optimization, and personalized medicine. By democratizing access to healthcare data and cutting-edge machine learning algorithms, we aim to empower researchers, clinicians, and healthcare professionals to make data-driven decisions and drive innovation in healthcare.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Datasets 📊&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Health Learning provides access to a curated collection of healthcare datasets sourced from various sources, including public repositories like Kaggle. These datasets cover a broad spectrum of health-related topics, including maternal health, diabetes classification, cardiovascular disease risk factors, stroke prediction, cancer imaging, and more. Researchers and developers can explore these datasets to develop and validate machine learning models for a wide range of healthcare applications. Individual projects have their datasets mentioned in respective README.md files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing 🤝&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Health Learning welcomes contributions from researchers, developers, healthcare professionals, and enthusiasts passionate about using machine learning and deep learning for healthcare. Whether you&#39;re interested in developing new models, improving existing algorithms, or curating datasets, there are plenty of opportunities to get involved. Check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SrijanShovit/HealthLearning/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribution Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to learn how you can contribute to the project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Health Learning is a community-driven initiative and is not affiliated with any specific healthcare organization or institution. We strive to promote collaboration, transparency, and open exchange of knowledge for the betterment of healthcare worldwide. Join us in our mission to revolutionize healthcare through machine learning and deep learning! 🌍💡&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>