<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Jupyter Notebook Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-08T01:30:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Jupyter Notebook in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mshumer/ai-researcher</title>
    <updated>2024-04-08T01:30:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-08:/mshumer/ai-researcher</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mshumer/ai-researcher" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ai-researcher&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mattshumer_&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/mattshumer_?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Follow&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1fn2Xisstp0d30_bAaLPA1y-0_svojLF3?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/assets/colab-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Open In Colab&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The AI Researcher is an AI agent that utilizes Claude 3 and SERPAPI to perform comprehensive research on a given topic. It breaks down the research process into subtopics, generates individual reports for each subtopic, and then combines them into a final comprehensive report.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generates a detailed checklist of subtopics to research for a given topic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Performs multiple rounds of searches and analysis for each subtopic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generates individual reports for each subtopic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Incorporates feedback from a &#34;boss&#34; persona to identify missing information and improve the reports&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Combines the subtopic reports into a comprehensive final report&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1fn2Xisstp0d30_bAaLPA1y-0_svojLF3?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Open the notebook in Google Colab&lt;/a&gt; or in a local Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Replace the placeholders &lt;code&gt;ANTHROPIC_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SERP_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt; in the script with your actual API keys.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run all the cells, and enter your topic to get started!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;After research + generation is complete, the report will be saved as &lt;code&gt;comprehensive_report.txt&lt;/code&gt; in the same directory as the script. Use a Markdown viewer to view the final report.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Customization&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can customize the behavior of the AI Research Assistant by modifying the following parameters in the script:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;model&lt;/code&gt;: The name of the Anthropic Claude AI model to use (default: &#34;claude-3-haiku-20240307&#34;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;max_tokens&lt;/code&gt;: The maximum number of tokens to generate in each AI response (default: 2000).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;temperature&lt;/code&gt;: The temperature value for controlling the randomness of the AI responses (default: 0.7).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The quality and accuracy of the generated reports depend on the performance of the Anthropic Claude AI and the relevance of the search results from SERPAPI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The script may take a considerable amount of time to execute, especially for complex topics with multiple subtopics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mshumer/ai-researcher/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The AI Research Assistant is an experimental tool and should be used for informational purposes only. The generated reports may contain inaccuracies or inconsistencies. Always verify the information obtained from the script with reliable sources before making any decisions based on it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to the AI Research Assistant are welcome! If you find any issues or have suggestions for improvements, please open an issue or submit a pull request on the GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/&#34;&gt;Anthropic&lt;/a&gt; for providing the Claude AI API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://serpapi.com/&#34;&gt;SERPAPI&lt;/a&gt; for providing the search API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matt Shumer - &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mattshumer_&#34;&gt;@mattshumer_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you want to try something even cooler than this, sign up for &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.hyperwriteai.com/personalassistant&#34;&gt;HyperWrite Personal Assistant&lt;/a&gt; (most of my time is spent on this). It&#39;s basically an AI with access to real-time information that a) is incredible at writing naturally, and b) can operate your web browser to complete tasks for you.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>City-Form-Lab/madina</title>
    <updated>2024-04-08T01:30:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-08:/City-Form-Lab/madina</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/City-Form-Lab/madina" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Python library modeling pedestrian and bicycle trips over networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Madina&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/City-Form-Lab/madina/main/docs/source/img/NYCFlows.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Example of trip flows generated for New York City&#34; title=&#34;Example of flows generated for New York CIty&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Madina &lt;em&gt;(Arabic for the word &#39;city&#39;)&lt;/em&gt; is a package of classes and functions to streamline the representation and analysis of urban networks. The package includes a python implemetation of the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Urban Network Analysis Toolbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://cityform.mit.edu/projects/una-rhino-toolbox&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://unatoolbox.notion.site/&#34;&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt;). More detailed documentation of the package is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://madinadocs.readthedocs.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To reference this package in your research, you can cite the paper available on SSRN:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alhassan, Abdulaziz and Sevtsuk, Andres, &lt;strong&gt;Madina Python Package: Scalable Urban Network Analysis for Modeling Pedestrian and Bicycle Trips in Cities.&lt;/strong&gt; Available at SSRN: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssrn.com/abstract=4748255&#34;&gt;https://ssrn.com/abstract=4748255&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4748255&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4748255&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{alhassan2024madina,&#xA;  title={Madina Python Package: Scalable Urban Network Analysis for Modeling Pedestrian and Bicycle Trips in Cities},&#xA;  author={Alhassan, Abdulaziz and Sevtsuk, Andres},&#xA;  journal={SSRN},&#xA;  year={2024},&#xA;  publisher={Elsevier}, &#xA;  doi={10.2139/ssrn.4748255},&#xA;  url={https://ssrn.com/abstract=4748255}&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Highlights&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Organization of data layers using &lt;a href=&#34;https://geopandas.org/en/stable&#34;&gt;Geopandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Creation of topological (Routable) networks from a geometric representaion. Networks are represented using &lt;a href=&#34;https://networkx.org/&#34;&gt;NetworkX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Insertion of origin and destination nodes from data layers into topological networks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Creating maps using &lt;a href=&#34;https://deck.gl/&#34;&gt;DeckGL&lt;/a&gt; with various streamlined styling options&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cityform.mit.edu/projects/una-rhino-toolbox&#34;&gt;UNA Tools&lt;/a&gt; that use multiprocessing and novel path generation algorithoms to enable effecient pedestrian accessibility and flow simulations on large-scale networks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added functionalities for UNA, including percieved segment costs that can account for segment quality attributes, elastic trip generation with respect to destination availability, KNN-Access metrics that allows WalkScore-type access calculations, turn penalties, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automated workflows for pedestrian flow simulation in urban environments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User-friendly workspace environment that requires minimal coding experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Pedestrain Flow Simulations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The package features a streamlined way to model pedestrian activity in urban areas between pairs of pre-specified origins and destinations. This can be done by following these steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prepare input data files for the network, and each origin and destination. Place all data in a folder called &lt;code&gt;Cities/city_name/Data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fill in the pairing table to specify origin-destination pairs, and specify specific parameters for each pair. Save the filled pairing table in the same &lt;code&gt;Cities/city_name/Data&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;run the simulation:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from madina.una.betweenness import betweenness_flow_simulation&#xA;&#xA;betweenness_flow_simulation(&#xA;    city_name=&#34;new_york&#34;&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Output would be saved in &lt;code&gt;Cities/city_name/Simulations&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More instructions on running a pedestrain flow simulation, preparing data and creating the pairing table are found in the documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://madinadocs.readthedocs.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, install geopandas through conda in a new environment&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda create -n madina_env -c conda-forge --strict-channel-priority geopandas&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Activate the newly created environment&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda activate madina_env&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install Madina through pip&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install -i https://test.pypi.org/simple/ --extra-index-url https://pypi.org/simple madina&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detailed instructions are available in the documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://madinadocs.readthedocs.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Library Structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Zonal&lt;/code&gt; class: This is the main class that the user interacts with. A user would create a Zonal object, populate it with data layers and calls functions to create a network object within a Zonal object.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Network&lt;/code&gt; Class: Created inside a Zonal ovject to represent a network of origins, destinations and &#39;street&#39; connections. This object is used internally as input to most network algorithms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;UNA&lt;/code&gt; Module: A set of functions implementing the UNA functionalities. Each function tales a &lt;code&gt;Zonal&lt;/code&gt; object as input.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Workflows&lt;/code&gt; module: A set of standarized workdlows that takes a set of structured inpurs. Examples for Pedesstrain flow simulartiob&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>