<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-05-26T01:31:39Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader</title>
    <updated>2025-05-26T01:31:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-05-26:/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Allows to download encrypted wiiu files from nintendo&#39;s official servers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;WiiUDownloader&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WiiUDownloader is a Golang program that allows you to download Wii U games from Nintendo&#39;s servers. It provides a user-friendly GUI built using GTK to browse and download Wii U titles directly to your local storage. Additionally, it supports decryption of downloaded contents for use on your Wii U console.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Browse and search for Wii U games, updates, DLC, demos, and more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download selected titles or queue multiple titles for batch download.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Decrypt downloaded contents for use on your Wii U console.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Delete encrypted contents after decryption (optional).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Filter titles based on name or title ID.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select regions (Japan, USA, and Europe) to filter available titles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install WiiUDownloader, download the appropriate binary for your operating system from the links below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader/releases/latest/download/WiiUDownloader-Linux-x86_64.AppImage&#34;&gt;WiiUDownloader-Linux-x86_64.AppImage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader/releases/latest/download/WiiUDownloader-macOS-Universal.dmg&#34;&gt;WiiUDownloader-macOS-Universal.dmg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader/releases/latest/download/WiiUDownloader-Windows.zip&#34;&gt;WiiUDownloader-Windows.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Linux, you may need to give execution permission to the downloaded binary:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;chmod +x WiiUDownloader-Linux-x86_64.AppImage   # For Linux&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Double-click the downloaded binary to launch WiiUDownloader.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The WiiUDownloader GUI window will appear, showing a list of available Wii U titles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the search bar to filter titles by name or title ID.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the category buttons to filter titles by type (Game, Update, DLC, Demo, All).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the checkboxes to select the desired region(s) for filtering (Japan, USA, Europe).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the &#34;Add to queue&#34; button to add selected titles to the download queue. The button label will change to &#34;Remove from queue&#34; if titles are already in the queue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the &#34;Download queue&#34; button to choose a location to save the downloaded games. The program will start downloading the queued titles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you enable &#34;Decrypt contents,&#34; the program will decrypt the downloaded files. You can also choose to delete encrypted contents after decryption (optional).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you already have downloaded files that aren&#39;t decrypted, you can go to Tools &amp;gt; Decrypt Contents and select the folder to decrypt.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Important Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WiiUDownloader provides access to Nintendo&#39;s servers for downloading titles. Please make sure to follow all legal and ethical guidelines when using this program.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Downloading and using copyrighted material without proper authorization may violate copyright laws in your country.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed under the GPLv3 License. For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Xpl0itU/WiiUDownloader/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WiiUDownloader uses several open-source libraries and dependencies to provide its functionality:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gotk3/gotk3&#34;&gt;github.com/gotk3/gotk3&lt;/a&gt;: Go bindings for GTK+3.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>