<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-30T01:30:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ekristen/aws-nuke</title>
    <updated>2025-01-30T01:30:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-30:/ekristen/aws-nuke</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Remove all the resources from an AWS account&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;aws-nuke&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/ekristen/aws-nuke.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;license&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/release/ekristen/aws-nuke.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;release&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke&#34; alt=&#34;Go Report Card&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeclimate.com/github/ekristen/aws-nuke/maintainability&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.codeclimate.com/v1/badges/bf05fb12c69f1ea7f257/maintainability&#34; alt=&#34;Maintainability&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/ekristen/aws-nuke/total&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Downloads (all assets, all releases)&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/ekristen/aws-nuke/latest/total&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Downloads (all assets, latest release)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remove all resources from an AWS account.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;aws-nuke&lt;/em&gt; is stable, but it is likely that not all AWS resources are covered by it. Be encouraged to add missing resources and create a Pull Request or to create an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/aws-nuke/issues/new&#34;&gt;Issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s New in Version 3&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 3 is a rewrite of this tool using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/libnuke&#34;&gt;libnuke&lt;/a&gt; with a focus on improving a number of the outstanding things that I couldn&#39;t get done with the original project without separating out the core code into a library. See Goals below for more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not a comprehensive list, but here are some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Feature: Signed Darwin Binaries for macOS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Feature: Published Homebrew Tap (ekristen/tap/aws-nuke@3)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Feature: Global Filters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Feature: Run Against All Enabled Regions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Feature: Explain Account and Explain Config Commands&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upcoming Feature: Filter Groups (&lt;strong&gt;in progress&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Breaking Change: &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; command no longer triggers the run, must use subcommand &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt; (alias: &lt;code&gt;nuke&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Breaking Change: CloudFormation Stacks now support a hold and wait for parent deletion process&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Breaking Change: Nested CloudFormation Stacks are now eligible for deletion and no longer omitted&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Completely rewrote the core of the tool as a dedicated library &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/libnuke&#34;&gt;libnuke&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This library has over 95% test coverage which makes iteration and new features easier to implement.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Semantic Releases with notifications on issues / pull requests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Context is passed throughout the entire library now, including the listing function and the removal function &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This is in preparation for supporting AWS SDK Go v2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New Resources&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Broke away from rebuy-de/aws-nuke project as a fork for reasons outlined in the history section&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Goals&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Easier maintainability and bug fixing, see go report and code climate badges above&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Adding additional tests around the core library&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Adding more tests around specific resource types&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Adding additional resources and tooling to make adding resources easier&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Adding documentation for adding resources and using the tool&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Consider adding DAG for dependencies between resource types and individual resources&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Support for AWS SDK Go v2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All documentation is in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ekristen/aws-nuke/main/docs&#34;&gt;docs/&lt;/a&gt; directory and is built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://squidfunk.github.io/mkdocs-material/&#34;&gt;Material for Mkdocs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ekristen.github.io/aws-nuke/&#34;&gt;https://ekristen.github.io/aws-nuke/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;History of this Fork&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; this is a full fork of the original tool written by the folks over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rebuy-de&#34;&gt;rebuy-de&lt;/a&gt;. This fork became necessary after attempting to make contributions and respond to issues to learn that the current maintainers only have time to work on the project about once a month and while receptive to bringing in other people to help maintain, made it clear it would take time. Considering the feedback cycle was already weeks on initial communications, I had to make the hard decision to fork and maintain it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;libnuke&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also needed a version of this tool for Azure and GCP, and initially I just copied and altered the code I needed for Azure, but I didn&#39;t want to have to maintain multiple copies of the same code, so I decided to create &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/libnuke&#34;&gt;libnuke&lt;/a&gt; to abstract all the code that was common between the two tools and write proper unit tests for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Attribution, License, and Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rewrite of this tool to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/libnuke&#34;&gt;libnuke&lt;/a&gt; would not have been possible without the hard work that came before me on the original tool by the team and contributors over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rebuy-de&#34;&gt;rebuy-de&lt;/a&gt; and their original work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rebuy-de/aws-nuke&#34;&gt;rebuy-de/aws-nuke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool is licensed under the MIT license. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ekristen/aws-nuke/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for more information. The bulk of this tool was rewritten to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ekristen/libnuke&#34;&gt;libnuke&lt;/a&gt; which was in part originally sourced from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rebuy-de/aws-nuke&#34;&gt;rebuy-de/aws-nuke&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can contribute to &lt;em&gt;aws-nuke&lt;/em&gt; by forking this repository, making your changes and creating a Pull Request against this repository. If you are unsure how to solve a problem or have other questions about a contributions, please create a GitHub issue.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>