<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-31T01:31:19Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>centrifugal/centrifugo</title>
    <updated>2025-01-31T01:31:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-31:/centrifugal/centrifugo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/centrifugal/centrifugo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scalable real-time messaging server in a language-agnostic way. Self-hosted alternative to Pubnub, Pusher, Ably. Set up once and forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centrifugo is an open-source scalable real-time messaging server. Centrifugo can instantly deliver messages to application online users connected over supported transports (WebSocket, HTTP-streaming, SSE/EventSource, GRPC, WebTransport). Centrifugo has the concept of channel subscriptions – so it&#39;s a user-facing PUB/SUB server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Centrifugo is language-agnostic and can be used to build chat apps, live comments, multiplayer games, real-time data visualizations, collaborative tools, etc. in combination with any backend. It is well suited for modern architectures and allows decoupling the business logic from the real-time transport layer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several official client SDKs for browser and mobile development wrap the bidirectional protocol. In addition, Centrifugo supports a unidirectional approach for simple use cases with no SDK dependency.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev&#34;&gt;Centrifugo official documentation site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/docs/getting-started/installation&#34;&gt;Installation instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/docs/getting-started/quickstart&#34;&gt;Getting started tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/docs/getting-started/design&#34;&gt;Design overview and idiomatic usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/docs/tutorial/intro&#34;&gt;Build a WebSocket chat/messenger app with Centrifugo&lt;/a&gt; tutorial&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/blog&#34;&gt;Centrifugal blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/docs/faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Join community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/joinchat/ABFVWBE0AhkyyhREoaboXQ&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/tYgADKx&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/centrifugalabs&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why Centrifugo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core idea of Centrifugo is simple – it&#39;s a PUB/SUB server on top of modern real-time transports:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev/img/protocol_pub_sub.png?v=2&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hard part is to make this concept production-ready, efficient, flexible and available from different application environments. Centrifugo is a mature solution that already helped many projects with adding real-time features and scale towards many concurrent connections. Centrifugo provides a set of features not available in other open-source solutions in the area:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Efficient real-time transports: WebSocket, HTTP-streaming, Server-Sent Events (SSE), GRPC, WebTransport&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Built-in scalability with Redis (or Redis Cluster, or Redis-compatible storage – ex. AWS Elasticache, KeyDB, DragonflyDB, etc), or Nats.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Simple HTTP and GRPC server API to communicate with Centrifugo from the app backend&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Asynchronous PostgreSQL and Kafka consumers to support transactional outbox and CDC patterns&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flexible connection authentication mechanisms: JWT and proxy-like&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Channel subscription multiplexing over a single connection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Different types of subscriptions: client-side and server-side&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various channel permission strategies, channel namespace concept&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hot message history in channels, with automatic message recovery upon reconnect, cache recovery mode (deliver latest publication immediately upon subscription)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Delta compression in channels based on Fossil algorithm&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Online channel presence information, with join/leave notifications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A way to send RPC calls to the backend over the real-time connection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Strict and effective client protocol wrapped by several official SDKs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;JSON and binary Protobuf message transfer, with optimized serialization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Beautiful embedded admin web UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And much more, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://centrifugal.dev&#34;&gt;Centrifugo documentation site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Backing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://packagecloud.io/&#34;&gt;packagecloud.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://packagecloud.io/&#34;&gt;&lt;img height=&#34;46&#34; width=&#34;158&#34; alt=&#34;Private NPM registry and Maven, RPM, DEB, PyPi and RubyGem Repository · packagecloud&#34; src=&#34;https://packagecloud.io/images/packagecloud-badge.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;JetBrains&lt;/a&gt; for supporting OSS (most of the code here written in Goland):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img height=&#34;140&#34; src=&#34;https://resources.jetbrains.com/storage/products/company/brand/logos/jb_beam.png&#34; alt=&#34;JetBrains logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>