<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-07T01:36:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>opencontainers/runtime-spec</title>
    <updated>2023-06-07T01:36:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-07:/opencontainers/runtime-spec</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OCI Runtime Specification&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Container Initiative Runtime Specification&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/actions?query=workflow%3Abuild&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/workflows/build/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Actions status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opencontainers.org&#34;&gt;Open Container Initiative&lt;/a&gt; develops specifications for standards on Operating System process and application containers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The specification can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/spec.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional documentation about how this group operates:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/org/raw/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/style.md&#34;&gt;Style and Conventions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/implementations.md&#34;&gt;Implementations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/RELEASES.md&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/tob/raw/master/CHARTER.md&#34;&gt;charter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use Cases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To provide context for users the following section gives example use cases for each part of the spec.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Application Bundle Builders&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Application bundle builders can create a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/bundle.md&#34;&gt;bundle&lt;/a&gt; directory that includes all of the files required for launching an application as a container. The bundle contains an OCI &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config.md&#34;&gt;configuration file&lt;/a&gt; where the builder can specify host-independent details such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config.md#process&#34;&gt;which executable to launch&lt;/a&gt; and host-specific settings such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config.md#mounts&#34;&gt;mount&lt;/a&gt; locations, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config.md#posix-platform-hooks&#34;&gt;hook&lt;/a&gt; paths, Linux &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config-linux.md#namespaces&#34;&gt;namespaces&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config-linux.md#control-groups&#34;&gt;cgroups&lt;/a&gt;. Because the configuration includes host-specific settings, application bundle directories copied between two hosts may require configuration adjustments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Hook Developers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/config.md#posix-platform-hooks&#34;&gt;Hook&lt;/a&gt; developers can extend the functionality of an OCI-compliant runtime by hooking into a container&#39;s lifecycle with an external application. Example use cases include sophisticated network configuration, volume garbage collection, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Runtime Developers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Runtime developers can build runtime implementations that run OCI-compliant bundles and container configuration, containing low-level OS and host-specific details, on a particular platform.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Development happens on GitHub for the spec. Issues are used for bugs and actionable items and longer discussions can happen on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/#mailing-list&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The specification and code is licensed under the Apache 2.0 license found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Discuss your design&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project welcomes submissions, but please let everyone know what you are working on.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before undertaking a nontrivial change to this specification, send mail to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/#mailing-list&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; to discuss what you plan to do. This gives everyone a chance to validate the design, helps prevent duplication of effort, and ensures that the idea fits. It also guarantees that the design is sound before code is written; a GitHub pull-request is not the place for high-level discussions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typos and grammatical errors can go straight to a pull-request. When in doubt, start on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opencontainers/runtime-spec/main/#mailing-list&#34;&gt;mailing-list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Meetings&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opencontainers/org#meetings&#34;&gt;OCI org repository README&lt;/a&gt; for the most up-to-date information on OCI contributor and maintainer meeting schedules. You can also find links to meeting agendas and minutes for all prior meetings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Mailing List&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can subscribe and join the mailing list on &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/a/opencontainers.org/forum/#!forum/dev&#34;&gt;Google Groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;IRC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OCI discussion happens on #opencontainers on Freenode (&lt;a href=&#34;http://ircbot.wl.linuxfoundation.org/eavesdrop/%23opencontainers/&#34;&gt;logs&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Git commit&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Sign your work&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sign-off is a simple line at the end of the explanation for the patch, which certifies that you wrote it or otherwise have the right to pass it on as an open-source patch. The rules are pretty simple: if you can certify the below (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://developercertificate.org&#34;&gt;http://developercertificate.org&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Developer Certificate of Origin&#xA;Version 1.1&#xA;&#xA;Copyright (C) 2004, 2006 The Linux Foundation and its contributors.&#xA;660 York Street, Suite 102,&#xA;San Francisco, CA 94110 USA&#xA;&#xA;Everyone is permitted to copy and distribute verbatim copies of this&#xA;license document, but changing it is not allowed.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Developer&#39;s Certificate of Origin 1.1&#xA;&#xA;By making a contribution to this project, I certify that:&#xA;&#xA;(a) The contribution was created in whole or in part by me and I&#xA;    have the right to submit it under the open source license&#xA;    indicated in the file; or&#xA;&#xA;(b) The contribution is based upon previous work that, to the best&#xA;    of my knowledge, is covered under an appropriate open source&#xA;    license and I have the right under that license to submit that&#xA;    work with modifications, whether created in whole or in part&#xA;    by me, under the same open source license (unless I am&#xA;    permitted to submit under a different license), as indicated&#xA;    in the file; or&#xA;&#xA;(c) The contribution was provided directly to me by some other&#xA;    person who certified (a), (b) or (c) and I have not modified&#xA;    it.&#xA;&#xA;(d) I understand and agree that this project and the contribution&#xA;    are public and that a record of the contribution (including all&#xA;    personal information I submit with it, including my sign-off) is&#xA;    maintained indefinitely and may be redistributed consistent with&#xA;    this project or the open source license(s) involved.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;then you just add a line to every git commit message:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Signed-off-by: Joe Smith &amp;lt;joe@gmail.com&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;using your real name (sorry, no pseudonyms or anonymous contributions.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can add the sign off when creating the git commit via &lt;code&gt;git commit -s&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Commit Style&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simple house-keeping for clean git history. Read more on &lt;a href=&#34;http://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit&#34;&gt;How to Write a Git Commit Message&lt;/a&gt; or the Discussion section of &lt;a href=&#34;http://git-scm.com/docs/git-commit&#34;&gt;git-commit(1)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Separate the subject from body with a blank line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Limit the subject line to 50 characters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Capitalize the subject line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do not end the subject line with a period&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the imperative mood in the subject line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wrap the body at 72 characters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the body to explain what and why vs. how &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If there was important/useful/essential conversation or information, copy or include a reference&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When possible, one keyword to scope the change in the subject (i.e. &#34;README: ...&#34;, &#34;runtime: ...&#34;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>deepflowio/deepflow</title>
    <updated>2023-06-07T01:36:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-07:/deepflowio/deepflow</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/deepflowio/deepflow" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Application Observability using eBPF&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deepflowio/deepflow/main/docs/deepflow-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;DeepFlow&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;DeepFlow is an automated observability platform for cloud-native developers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;GitHub Release&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/deepflowio/deepflow&#34;&gt;  &lt;img alt=&#34;docker pulls&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/docker/pulls/deepflowce/deepflow-agent?color=green?label=docker pulls&#34;&gt;  &lt;img alt=&#34;License&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/deepflowio/deepflow?color=purple&#34;&gt;  &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;English | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deepflowio/deepflow/main/README-CN.md&#34;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;What is DeepFlow&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeepFlow is a &lt;strong&gt;highly automated&lt;/strong&gt; observability platform for cloud-native developers. Using new technologies such as &lt;strong&gt;eBPF&lt;/strong&gt;, WASM, and OpenTelemetry, DeepFlow innovatively implements core mechanisms such as &lt;strong&gt;AutoTracing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AutoMetrics&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AutoTagging&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;SmartEncoding&lt;/strong&gt;, which greatly avoids code instrumentation and significantly reduces the resource overhead of back-end data warehouses. With the programmability and open API of DeepFlow, developers can quickly integrate it into their own observability stack.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Key Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Any Stack&lt;/strong&gt;: With the &lt;strong&gt;AutoMetrics&lt;/strong&gt; mechanism implemented by &lt;strong&gt;eBPF&lt;/strong&gt; and cBPF, DeepFlow can automatically collect RED (Request, Error, Delay) performance metrics of any application, down to every request, covering all software technologie stacks from application to infrastructure. In cloud-native environments, the &lt;strong&gt;AutoTagging&lt;/strong&gt; mechanism automatically discovers the attributes of services, instances and APIs, and automatically injects rich tags into each observability data, thereby eliminating data silos and releasing data drill-down capabilities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End to End&lt;/strong&gt;: DeepFlow innovatively implements the &lt;strong&gt;AutoTracing&lt;/strong&gt; mechanism using &lt;strong&gt;eBPF&lt;/strong&gt; technology. It automatically traces the distributed request of any application and infrastructure service in cloud-native environments. On this basis, by integrating and automatically correlating data from OpenTelemetry, DeepFlow implements a complete full-stack, full-path distributed tracing, eliminating all blind spots.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Performance&lt;/strong&gt;: The innovative &lt;strong&gt;SmartEncoding&lt;/strong&gt; tag injection mechanism can improve the storage performance by 10 times, no more high-cardinality and sampling anxiety. DeepFlow Agent is implemented in Rust for extreme processing performance and memory safety. DeepFlow Server is implemented in Golang, and rewrites standard library map and pool for a nearly 10x performance in data query and memory GC.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programmability&lt;/strong&gt;: DeepFlow supports collect HTTP(S), Dubbo, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Kafka, MQTT and DNS at the moment, and will iterate to support more application protocols. In addition, DeepFlow provides a programmable interface based on WASM technology, allowing developers to add private protocols quickly, and can be used to construct business analysis capabilities for specific scenarios, such as 5GC signaling analysis, financial transaction analysis, vehicle computer communication analysis, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Interface&lt;/strong&gt;: DeepFlow embraces the open source community, supports a wide range of observability data sources, and uses AutoTagging and SmartEncoding to provide high-performance, unified tag injection capabilities. DeepFlow has a plugable database interface, developers can freely add and replace the most suitable database. DeepFlow provides a unified standard SQL query capability for all observability data, which is convenient for users to quickly integrate into their own observability platform.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to Maintain&lt;/strong&gt;: The core of DeepFlow only consists of two components, Agent and Server, hiding the complexity within the process and reduces the maintenance difficulty to the extreme. The DeepFlow Servers can manage Agents in multiple kubernetes clusters, legacy hosts and cloud hosts in a unified manner, and can achieve horizontal scaling and load balancing without any external components.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://deepflow.yunshan.net/docs/?from=github&#34;&gt;the documentation website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Quick start&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three editions of DeepFlow:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeepFlow Community: for developers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeepFlow Enterprise: for organizations, solving team collaboration problems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeepFlow Cloud: SaaS service, currently in beta&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DeepFlow Community Edition consists of the core components of the Enterprise Edition.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DeepFlow Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://deepflow.yunshan.net/docs/install/all-in-one/?from=github&#34;&gt;the deployment documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we have also built a complete &lt;a href=&#34;https://ce-demo.deepflow.yunshan.net/?from=github&#34;&gt;DeepFlow Community Demo&lt;/a&gt;, welcome to experience it. Login account/password: deepflow/deepflow.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DeepFlow Cloud&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deepflow.yunshan.net/&#34;&gt;DeepFlow Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is the fully-managed service of DeepFlow, currently in beta and only supports Chinese.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DeepFlow Enterprise&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yunshan.net/products/deepflow.html&#34;&gt;DeepFlow Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; supports full-stack and end-to-end monitoring of hybrid cloud, covering containers, cloud servers, hosts, and NFV gateways, currently only supports Chinese, welcome to contact us for experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Compile DeepFlow from Source&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deepflowio/deepflow/main/agent/build.md&#34;&gt;compile deepflow-agent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Software Architecture&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeepFlow Community Edition consists of two components, Agent and Server. An Agent runs in each K8s node, legacy host and cloud host, and is responsible for AutoMetrics and AutoTracing data collection of all application processes on the host. Server runs in a K8s cluster and provides Agent management, tag injection, data ingest and query services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deepflowio/deepflow/main/docs/deepflow-architecture.png&#34; alt=&#34;DeepFlow Architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Milestones&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is our &lt;a href=&#34;https://deepflow.yunshan.net/docs/about/milestone/?from=github&#34;&gt;future feature plan&lt;/a&gt;. Issues and Pull Requests are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Discord：Click &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/QJ7Dyj4wWM&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to join our discussion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Twitter：&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/deepflowio&#34;&gt;DeepFlow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WeChat Group：&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/deepflowio/deepflow/main/docs/wechat-group-keeper.png&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebpf.io/&#34;&gt;eBPF&lt;/a&gt;, a revolutionary Linux kernel technology.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://opentelemetry.io/&#34;&gt;OpenTelemetry&lt;/a&gt;, provides vendor-neutral APIs to collect application telemetry data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Landscapes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeepFlow enriches the &lt;a href=&#34;https://landscape.cncf.io/?selected=deep-flow&#34;&gt;CNCF CLOUD NATIVE Landscape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeepFlow enriches the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ebpf.io/applications#deepflow&#34;&gt;eBPF Project Landscape&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>