<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-11-04T01:30:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>MightyMoud/sidekick</title>
    <updated>2024-11-04T01:30:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-11-04:/MightyMoud/sidekick</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MightyMoud/sidekick" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bare metal to production ready in mins; your own fly server on your VPS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;div&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img width=&#34;110px&#34; src=&#34;https://emoji.aranja.com/static/emoji-data/img-apple-160/1f91c-1f3fb.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img width=&#34;110px&#34; src=&#34;https://emoji.aranja.com/static/emoji-data/img-apple-160/1f91b-1f3fb.png&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;/div&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Bare metal to production ready in mins; imagine fly.io on your VPS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;div&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img width=&#34;600px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MightyMoud/sidekick/main/demo/imgs/hero.png&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;/div&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/mightymoud/sidekick&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/go-mod/go-version/mightymoud/sidekick&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub go.mod Go version&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/tag/mightymoud/sidekick&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub tag (latest SemVer)&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;👍 One command VPS setup (docker, traefik, sops, age)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;💻 deploy any application from a dockerfile&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;✊ Zero downtime deployment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🌏 High availability and load balancing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🔒 Zero config SSL Certs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;✅ Connect domains or use sslip.io out of the box&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🔥 Built in integration with SOPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🛸 Escape the vendorlock forever&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tired of the complexity involved in hosting my side projects. While some platforms, like Fly.io, stand out in the crowded field of Heroku replacements, I believe a simple VPS can be just as effective. That&#39;s why I created Sidekick: to make hosting side projects as straightforward, affordable, and production-ready as possible. You&#39;ll be surprised how much traffic a $8/month instance on DigitalOcean can handle.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using brew:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew install sidekick&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Sidekick uses &lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt; later on to handle installing &lt;code&gt;sops&lt;/code&gt; on your local. So &lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt; is a requirement at this point. Sidekick will throw an error if &lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt; is not found. You can install &lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sidekick helps you along all the steps of deployment on your VPS. From basic setup to zero downtime deploys, we got you! ✊&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First you need a VPS with Ubuntu LTS. I recommend DigitalOcean. Hetzner also gets very good reviews. You can host your own silicon too. As long as you have a public IP address you can use Sidekick.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just make sure the following is true:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;VPS running Ubuntu - LTS recommended&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SSH Key available on your machine to login to VPS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s it!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;VPS Setup&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img width=&#34;600px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MightyMoud/sidekick/main/demo/imgs/init.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First you need to setup your VPS. To do this you need to run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sidekick init&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then you need to enter the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;IP Address of your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An email address to use for setting up SSL certs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After that Sidekick will setup many things on your VPS - Usually takes around 2 mins. If you run this command once more and enter a different IP Address, Sidekick will warn you that you are overriding the current config with a prompt.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use flags instead. Read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sidekickdeploy.com/docs/command/init/&#34;&gt;in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;What does Sidekick do when I run this command?&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Login with &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Make a new user &lt;code&gt;sidekick&lt;/code&gt; and grant sudo access&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Logout from &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; and login with &lt;code&gt;sidekick&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Disable login with &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user - security best practice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Update and upgrade your Ubuntu system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;sops&lt;/code&gt; and copy over the public key to your sidekick config file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;age&lt;/code&gt; to make secret and public keys to use later for encrypting env file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Send public key back to host machine to be used later for encryption&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Install Docker&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Add user sidekick to docker group&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Setup Traefik and SSL certs on your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Which SSH key will Sidekick use to login?&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Sidekick will look up the default keys in your default .ssh directory in the following order:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;id_rsa.pub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;id_ecdsa.pub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;id_ed25519.pub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Sidekick will also get all keys from the &lt;code&gt;ssh-agent&lt;/code&gt; and try them as well. If you want to use a custom key and not a default one, you would need to add the to your agent first by running &lt;code&gt;ssh-add KEY_FILE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read more details about flags and other options for this command &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sidekickdeploy.com/docs/command/init/&#34;&gt;on the docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Launch a new application&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img width=&#34;600px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MightyMoud/sidekick/main/demo/imgs/launch.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In your application folder, make sure you have a working &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; that you can build and run. Also make sure you know at which port your app is expecting to receive traffic.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sidekick launch&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then you need to enter the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Url friendly name of your app - if you opt to use &lt;code&gt;sslip.io&lt;/code&gt; domain for testing this would be your subdomain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HTTP exposed port for your app to get requests - Sidekick will scan your docker file to try to extract this number and default it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Domain at which you want this application to be reachable - If you choose your own domain make sure to point the domain to your VPS IP address; otherwise we default to &lt;code&gt;sslip.io&lt;/code&gt; domain so you can play around.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you have any &lt;code&gt;env&lt;/code&gt; file with secrets in it. Sidekick will attempt to find &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of your folder. Sidekick will use &lt;code&gt;sops&lt;/code&gt; to encrypt your env file and inject the values securely at run time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should take around 2 more mins to be able to visit your application live on the web if all goes well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;What does Sidekick do when I run this command&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Build your docker image locally for linux&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Move the docker image to your VPS directly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Encrypt your env file, if available and push it to your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Use sops to decrypt your env file and start and env with the values injected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Spin up your docker image using docker compose and route traffic to it using Traefik on the specified port&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Deploy a new version&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img width=&#34;600px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MightyMoud/sidekick/main/demo/imgs/deploy.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; With your application deployed, it&#39;s super simple to deploy a new version. &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At any point any time you need to only run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sidekick deploy&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s all. It won&#39;t take long, we use cache from earlier docker images, your latest version should be up soon. Sidekick will deploy the new version without any downtime - you can see more in the source code. This command will also do a couple of things behind the scenes. You can check that below&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;What does Sidekick do when I run this command&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Build your docker image locally for linux&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Compare your latest env file checksum for changes from last time you deployed your application.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If your env file has changed, sidekick will re-encrypt it and replace the encrypted.env file on your server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Deploy the new version with zero downtime deploys so you don&#39;t miss any traffic.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Deploy a preview environment/app&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img width=&#34;600px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MightyMoud/sidekick/main/demo/imgs/preview.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; Sidekick also allows you to deploy preview apps at any point from your application. Preview apps are attached to your commit hash and require a clean git tree before you can initiate them. Once you have a clean git tree, you can run the following command to deploy a preview app: &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sidekick deploy preview&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;What does Sidekick do when I run this command&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Build your docker image locally for linux&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Tag the new image with the short checksum of your git commit&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Encrypt your env file, if available and push it to your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Add a new folder inside your app folder called &#34;preview&#34; where Sidekick will store and manage all your preview deployments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Deploy a new version of your app reachable on a short hash based subdomain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fly.io/&#34;&gt;https://fly.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kamal-deploy.org/&#34;&gt;https://kamal-deploy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Vision&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simple CLI tool that can help you:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deploy all your side projects on a single VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Load balance multiple container per project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deploy new versions with Zero downtime&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deploy preview environments with ease&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manage env secrets in a secure way&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect any number of domains and subdomains to your projects with ease&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Remove sidekick&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can easily remove sidekick if you hate it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;brew uninstall sidekick&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I still have a couple more feature I want to add here. Also considering some of those to be on a paid version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;✅ Preview env deployments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A way to deploy more complicated projects defined in docker compose file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Better zero downtime deploys with watchtower&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Firewall setup&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Managing multiple VPSs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easy way to deploy databases with one command&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TUI for monitoring your VPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Streaming down compose logs - ala &lt;code&gt;fly logs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto deploy on image push - to work with CICD better&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Git hooks setup for managing migrations and other concerns&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>