<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-09T01:34:38Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>hakluke/hakoriginfinder</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T01:34:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-09:/hakluke/hakoriginfinder</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hakluke/hakoriginfinder" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tool for discovering the origin host behind a reverse proxy. Useful for bypassing cloud WAFs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;hakoriginfinder&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tool for discovering the origin host behind a reverse proxy. Useful for bypassing WAFs and other reverse proxies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool will first make a HTTP request to the hostname that you provide and store the response, then it will make a request to every IP address that you provide via HTTP (80) and HTTPS (443), with the &lt;code&gt;Host&lt;/code&gt; header set to the original host. Each HTTP response is then compared to the original using the Levenshtein algorithm to determine similarity. If the response is similar, it will be deemed a match.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Provide the list of IP addresses via stdin, and the original hostname via the -h option. For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;prips 93.184.216.0/24 | hakoriginfinder -h example.com&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may set the Levenshtein distance threshold with &lt;code&gt;-l&lt;/code&gt;. The lower the number, the more similar the matches need to be for it to be considered a match, the default is 5.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The number of threads may be set with &lt;code&gt;-t&lt;/code&gt;, default is 32.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hostname is set with &lt;code&gt;-h&lt;/code&gt;, there is no default.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Output&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The output is 3 columns, separated by spaces. The first column is either &#34;MATCH&#34; or &#34;NOMATCH&#34; depending on whether the Levenshtein threshold was reached or not. The second column is the URL being tested, and the third column is the Levenshtein score.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Output example&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hakluke$ prips 1.1.1.0/24 | hakoriginfinder -h one.one.one.one&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.0 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.30 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.20 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.4 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.11 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.5 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.22 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.13 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.10 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.25 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.19 54366&#xA;... snipped for brevity ...&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.251 54366&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.248 54366&#xA;MATCH http://1.1.1.1 0&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.3 19567&#xA;NOMATCH http://1.1.1.2 19517&#xA;MATCH https://1.1.1.1 0&#xA;NOMATCH https://1.1.1.3 19534&#xA;NOMATCH https://1.1.1.2 19532&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install golang, then run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;go install github.com/hakluke/hakoriginfinder@latest&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>stellar/go</title>
    <updated>2023-08-09T01:34:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-09:/stellar/go</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/stellar/go" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stellar&#39;s public monorepo of go code&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://stellar.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Stellar&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/stellar/.github/raw/master/stellar-logo.png&#34; width=&#34;558&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;br&gt; &#xA; &lt;strong&gt;Creating equitable access to the global financial system&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;Stellar Go Monorepo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stellar/go/actions/workflows/go.yml?query=branch%3Amaster+event%3Apush&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/stellar/go/actions/workflows/go.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;master GitHub workflow&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/github.com/stellar/go&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;GoDoc&#34; src=&#34;https://godoc.org/github.com/stellar/go?status.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/stellar/go&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Go Report Card&#34; src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/stellar/go&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo is the home for all of the public Go code produced by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stellar.org&#34;&gt;Stellar Development Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains various tools and services that you can use and deploy, as well as the SDK you can use to develop applications that integrate with the Stellar network.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Package Index&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/services/horizon&#34;&gt;Horizon Server&lt;/a&gt;: Full-featured API server for Stellar network&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/clients/horizonclient&#34;&gt;Go Horizon SDK - horizonclient&lt;/a&gt;: Client for Horizon server (queries and transaction submission)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/txnbuild&#34;&gt;Go Horizon SDK - txnbuild&lt;/a&gt;: Construct Stellar transactions and operations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/services/ticker&#34;&gt;Ticker&lt;/a&gt;: An API server that provides statistics about assets and markets on the Stellar network&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/services/keystore&#34;&gt;Keystore&lt;/a&gt;: An API server that is used to store and manage encrypted keys for Stellar client applications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Servers for Anchors &amp;amp; Financial Institutions &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/services/compliance&#34;&gt;Compliance Server&lt;/a&gt;: Allows financial institutions to exchange KYC information&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/services/federation&#34;&gt;Federation Server&lt;/a&gt;: Allows organizations to provide addresses for users (&lt;code&gt;jane*examplebank.com&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is officially supported on the last two releases of Go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It depends on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/go.mod&#34;&gt;number of external dependencies&lt;/a&gt;, and uses Go &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go/wiki/Modules&#34;&gt;Modules&lt;/a&gt; to manage them. Running any &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; command will automatically download dependencies required for that operation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can choose to checkout this repository into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go/wiki/GOPATH&#34;&gt;GOPATH&lt;/a&gt; or into any directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Directory Layout&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the other top-level packages, there are a few special directories that contain specific types of packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clients&lt;/strong&gt; contains packages that provide client packages to the various Stellar services.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exp&lt;/strong&gt; contains experimental packages. Use at your own risk.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;handlers&lt;/strong&gt; contains packages that provide pluggable implementors of &lt;code&gt;http.Handler&lt;/code&gt; that make it easier to incorporate portions of the Stellar protocol into your own http server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;support&lt;/strong&gt; contains packages that are not intended for consumption outside of Stellar&#39;s other packages. Packages that provide common infrastructure for use in our services and tools should go here, such as &lt;code&gt;db&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;log&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;support/scripts&lt;/strong&gt; contains single-file go programs and bash scripts used to support the development of this repo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;services&lt;/strong&gt; contains packages that compile to applications that are long-running processes (such as API servers).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; contains packages that compile to command line applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each of these directories have their own README file that explain further the nature of their contents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other packages&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the packages described above, this repository contains various packages related to working with the Stellar network from a go program. It&#39;s recommended that you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://godoc.org/github.com/stellar/go#pkg-subdirectories&#34;&gt;godoc&lt;/a&gt; to browse the documentation for each.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Package source layout&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While much of the code in individual packages is organized based upon different developers&#39; personal preferences, many of the packages follow a simple convention for organizing the declarations inside of a package that aim to aid in your ability to find code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In each package, there may be one or more of a set of common files:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;errors.go&lt;/em&gt;: This file should contains declarations (both types and vars) for errors that are used by the package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;example_test.go&lt;/em&gt;: This file should contains example tests, as described at &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.golang.org/examples&#34;&gt;https://blog.golang.org/examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;main.go/internal.go&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;deprecated&lt;/strong&gt;): Older packages may have a &lt;code&gt;main.go&lt;/code&gt; (public symbols) or &lt;code&gt;internal.go&lt;/code&gt; (private symbols). These files contain, respectively, the exported and unexported vars, consts, types and funcs for the package. New packages do not follow this pattern, and instead follow the standard Go convention to co-locate structs and their methods in the same files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;main.go&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;new convention&lt;/strong&gt;): If present, this file contains a &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; function as part of an executable &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above files, a package often has files that contains code that is specific to one declared type. This file uses the snake case form of the type name (for example &lt;code&gt;loggly_hook.go&lt;/code&gt; would correspond to the type &lt;code&gt;LogglyHook&lt;/code&gt;). This file should contain method declarations, interface implementation assertions and any other declarations that are tied solely to that type.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each non-test file can have a test counterpart like normal, whose name ends with &lt;code&gt;_test.go&lt;/code&gt;. The common files described above also have their own test counterparts... for example &lt;code&gt;internal_test.go&lt;/code&gt; should contains tests that test unexported behavior and more commonly test helpers that are unexported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, file contents are sorted by exported/unexported, then declaration type (ordered as consts, vars, types, then funcs), then finally alphabetically.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Test helpers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often, we provide test packages that aid in the creation of tests that interact with our other packages. For example, the &lt;code&gt;support/db&lt;/code&gt; package has the &lt;code&gt;support/db/dbtest&lt;/code&gt; package underneath it that contains elements that make it easier to test code that accesses a SQL database. We&#39;ve found that this pattern of having a separate test package maximizes flexibility and simplifies package dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are welcome! See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Developing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/stellar/go/master/DEVELOPING.md&#34;&gt;DEVELOPING.md&lt;/a&gt; for helpful instructions for getting started developing code in this repository.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>