<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-13T01:44:04Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>betaflight/betaflight</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:44:04Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/betaflight/betaflight</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Source Flight Controller Firmware&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/betaflight/master/docs/assets/images/bf_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Betaflight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/betaflight/betaflight&#34; alt=&#34;Latest version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/actions/workflows/nightly.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/workflow/status/betaflight/betaflight/Nightly&#34; alt=&#34;Build&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-GPLv3-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License: GPL v3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Betaflight is flight controller software (firmware) used to fly multi-rotor craft and fixed wing craft.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This fork differs from Baseflight and Cleanflight in that it focuses on flight performance, leading-edge feature additions, and wide target support.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;01-11-2022&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Firmware 4.4 Feature freeze&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Requirements for the submission of new and updated targets&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following new requirements for pull requests adding new targets or modifying existing targets are put in place from now on:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/raw/master/docs/Manufacturer%20Design%20Guidelines.md&#34;&gt;hardware specification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;No new F3 based targets will be accepted;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For any new target that is to be added, only a Unified Target config into &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/unified-targets/tree/master/configs/default&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/unified-targets/tree/master/configs/default&lt;/a&gt; needs to be submitted. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/raw/master/docs/TargetMaintenance/CreatingAUnifiedTarget.md&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; for how to create a Unified Target configuration. If there is no Unified Target for the MCU type of the new target (see instructions above), then a &#39;legacy&#39; format target definition into &lt;code&gt;src/main/target/&lt;/code&gt; has to be submitted as well;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For changes to existing targets, the change needs to be applied to the Unified Target config in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/unified-targets/tree/master/configs/default&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/unified-targets/tree/master/configs/default&lt;/a&gt;. If no Unified Target configuration for the target exists, a new Unified Target configuration will have to be created and submitted. If there is no Unified Target for the MCU type of the new target (see instructions above), then an update to the &#39;legacy&#39; format target definition in &lt;code&gt;src/main/target/&lt;/code&gt; has to be submitted alongside the update to the Unified Target configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Betaflight has the following features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Multi-color RGB LED strip support (each LED can be a different color using variable length WS2811 Addressable RGB strips - use for Orientation Indicators, Low Battery Warning, Flight Mode Status, Initialization Troubleshooting, etc)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DShot (150, 300 and 600), Multishot, Oneshot (125 and 42) and Proshot1000 motor protocol support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blackbox flight recorder logging (to onboard flash or external microSD card where equipped)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for targets that use the STM32 F4, G4, F7 and H7 processors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PWM, PPM, SPI, and Serial (SBus, SumH, SumD, Spektrum 1024/2048, XBus, etc) RX connection with failsafe detection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Multiple telemetry protocols (CRSF, FrSky, HoTT smart-port, MSP, etc)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RSSI via ADC - Uses ADC to read PWM RSSI signals, tested with FrSky D4R-II, X8R, X4R-SB, &amp;amp; XSR&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OSD support &amp;amp; configuration without needing third-party OSD software/firmware/comm devices&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OLED Displays - Display information on: Battery voltage/current/mAh, profile, rate profile, mode, version, sensors, etc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In-flight manual PID tuning and rate adjustment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PID and filter tuning using sliders&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rate profiles and in-flight selection of them&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configurable serial ports for Serial RX, Telemetry, ESC telemetry, MSP, GPS, OSD, Sonar, etc - Use most devices on any port, softserial included&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;VTX support for Unify Pro and IRC Tramp&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;and MUCH, MUCH more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation &amp;amp; Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/wiki&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support and Developers Channel&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a dedicated Slack chat channel here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.betaflight.com/&#34;&gt;https://slack.betaflight.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And a Discord server here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/n4E6ak4u3c&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/n4E6ak4u3c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also have a Facebook Group. Join us to get a place to talk about Betaflight, ask configuration questions, or just hang out with fellow pilots.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/betaflightgroup/&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/groups/betaflightgroup/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Etiquette: Don&#39;t ask to ask and please wait around long enough for a reply - sometimes people are out flying, asleep or at work and can&#39;t answer immediately.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Configuration Tool&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To configure Betaflight you should use the Betaflight-configurator GUI tool (Windows/OSX/Linux) which can be found here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases/latest&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/releases/latest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are welcome and encouraged. You can contribute in many ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;implement a new feature in the firmware or in configurator (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/betaflight/master/#Developers&#34;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;documentation updates and corrections;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;How-To guides - received help? Help others!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;bug reporting &amp;amp; fixes;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;new feature ideas &amp;amp; suggestions;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;provide a new translation for configurator, or help us maintain the existing ones (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/betaflight/master/#Translators&#34;&gt;below&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best place to start is the Betaflight Slack (registration &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.betaflight.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Next place is the github issue tracker:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/issues&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight-configurator/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before creating new issues please check to see if there is an existing one, search first otherwise you waste people&#39;s time when they could be coding instead!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute to our efforts financially, please consider making a donation to us through &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/betaflight&#34;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute financially on an ongoing basis, you should consider becoming a patron for us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/betaflight&#34;&gt;Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Developers&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contribution of bugfixes and new features is encouraged. Please be aware that we have a thorough review process for pull requests, and be prepared to explain what you want to achieve with your pull request. Before starting to write code, please read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/betaflight/master/docs/development/Development.md&#34;&gt;development guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/betaflight/betaflight/master/docs/development/CodingStyle.md&#34;&gt;coding style definition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Pipelines are used to run automatic builds&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.azure.com/Betaflight/Betaflight%20Nightlies/_build&#34;&gt;https://dev.azure.com/Betaflight/Betaflight%20Nightlies/_build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Translators&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We want to make Betaflight accessible for pilots who are not fluent in English, and for this reason we are currently maintaining translations into 21 languages for Betaflight Configurator: Català, Dansk, Deutsch, Español, Euskera, Français, Galego, Hrvatski, Bahasa Indonesia, Italiano, 日本語, 한국어, Latviešu, Português, Português Brasileiro, polski, Русский язык, Svenska, 简体中文, 繁體中文. We have got a team of volunteer translators who do this work, but additional translators are always welcome to share the workload, and we are keen to add additional languages. If you would like to help us with translations, you have got the following options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;if you help by suggesting some updates or improvements to translations in a language you are familiar with, head to &lt;a href=&#34;https://crowdin.com/project/betaflight-configurator&#34;&gt;crowdin&lt;/a&gt; and add your suggested translations there;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;if you would like to start working on the translation for a new language, or take on responsibility for proof-reading the translation for a language you are very familiar with, please head to the Betaflight Slack (registration &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.betaflight.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), and join the &#39;#team_translation&#39; channel - the people in there can help you to get a new language added, or set you up as a proof reader.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Hardware Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Betaflight does not manufacture or distribute their own hardware. While we are collaborating with and supported by a number of manufacturers, we do not do any kind of hardware support. If you encounter any hardware issues with your flight controller or another component, please contact the manufacturer or supplier of your hardware, or check RCGroups &lt;a href=&#34;https://rcgroups.com/forums/showthread.php?t=2464844&#34;&gt;https://rcgroups.com/forums/showthread.php?t=2464844&lt;/a&gt; to see if others with the same problem have found a solution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Betaflight Releases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/betaflight/betaflight/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Open Source / Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Betaflight is software that is &lt;strong&gt;open source&lt;/strong&gt; and is available free of charge without warranty to all users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Betaflight is forked from Cleanflight, so thanks goes to all those whom have contributed to Cleanflight and its origins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Origins for this fork (Thanks!):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexinparis&lt;/strong&gt; (for MultiWii),&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;timecop&lt;/strong&gt; (for Baseflight),&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dominic Clifton&lt;/strong&gt; (for Cleanflight),&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;borisbstyle&lt;/strong&gt; (for Betaflight), and&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sambas&lt;/strong&gt; (for the original STM32F4 port).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Betaflight Configurator is forked from Cleanflight Configurator and its origins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Origins for Betaflight Configurator:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dominic Clifton&lt;/strong&gt; (for Cleanflight configurator), and&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ctn&lt;/strong&gt; (for the original Configurator).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to current and past contributors:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Budden, Martin (martinbudden)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bardwell, Joshua (joshuabardwell)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blackman, Jason (blckmn)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ctzsnooze&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Höglund, Anders (andershoglund)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ledvina, Petr (ledvinap) - &lt;strong&gt;IO code awesomeness!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kc10kevin&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keeble, Gary (MadmanK)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keller, Michael (mikeller) - &lt;strong&gt;Configurator brilliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kravcov, Albert (skaman82) - &lt;strong&gt;Configurator brilliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MJ666&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nathan (nathantsoi)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ravnav&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;sambas - &lt;strong&gt;bringing us the F4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;savaga&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stålheim, Anton (KiteAnton)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And many many others who haven&#39;t been mentioned....&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>pygame/pygame</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:44:04Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/pygame/pygame</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/pygame/pygame" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🐍🎮 pygame (the library) is a Free and Open Source python programming language library for making multimedia applications like games built on top of the excellent SDL library. C, Python, Native, OpenGL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;.. image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pygame/pygame/main/docs/reST/_static/pygame_logo.svg&#34;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pygame/pygame/main/docs/reST/_static/pygame_logo.svg&lt;/a&gt; :alt: pygame :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;|AppVeyorBuild| |PyPiVersion| |PyPiLicense| |Python3| |GithubCommits| |LGTMAlerts| |LGTMGradePython| |LGTMGradeC| |BlackFormatBadge|&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pygame_ is a free and open-source cross-platform library for the development of multimedia applications like video games using Python. It uses the &lt;code&gt;Simple DirectMedia Layer library&lt;/code&gt;_ and several other popular libraries to abstract the most common functions, making writing these programs a more intuitive task.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;We need your help&lt;/code&gt;_ to make pygame the best it can be! New contributors are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;::&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pip install pygame&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are just getting started with pygame, you should be able to get started fairly quickly. Pygame comes with many tutorials and introductions. There is also full reference documentation for the entire library. Browse the documentation on the &lt;code&gt;docs page&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The online documentation stays up to date with the development version of pygame on github. This may be a bit newer than the version of pygame you are using. To upgrade to the latest full release, run &lt;code&gt;pip install pygame --upgrade&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best of all, the examples directory has many playable small programs which can get you started playing with the code right away.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building From Source&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use features that are currently in development, or you want to contribute to pygame, you will need to build pygame locally from its source code, rather than pip installing it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing from source is fairly automated. The most work will involve compiling and installing all the pygame dependencies. Once that is done, run the &lt;code&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt; script which will attempt to auto-configure, build, and install pygame.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much more information about installing and compiling is available on the &lt;code&gt;Compilation wiki page&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has helped contribute to this library. Special thanks are also in order.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Marcus Von Appen: many changes, and fixes, 1.7.1+ freebsd maintainer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lenard Lindstrom: the 1.8+ windows maintainer, many changes, and fixes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Brian Fisher for svn auto builder, bug tracker and many contributions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rene Dudfield: many changes, and fixes, 1.7+ release manager/maintainer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Phil Hassey for his work on the pygame.org website&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DR0ID for his work on the sprite module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Richard Goedeken for his smoothscale function&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ulf Ekström for his pixel perfect collision detection code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pete Shinners: original author&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;David Clark for filling the right-hand-man position&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ed Boraas and Francis Irving: Debian packages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maxim Sobolev: FreeBSD packaging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bob Ippolito: MacOS and OS X porting (much work!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Jan Ekhol, Ray Kelm, and Peter Nicolai: putting up with early design ideas&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nat Pryce for starting our unit tests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dan Richter for documentation work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TheCorruptor for his incredible logos and graphics&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nicholas Dudfield: many test improvements&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alex Folkner for pygame-ctypes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to those sending in patches and fixes: Niki Spahiev, Gordon Tyler, Nathaniel Pryce, Dave Wallace, John Popplewell, Michael Urman, Andrew Straw, Michael Hudson, Ole Martin Bjoerndalen, Herve Cauwelier, James Mazer, Lalo Martins, Timothy Stranex, Chad Lester, Matthias Spiller, Bo Jangeborg, Dmitry Borisov, Campbell Barton, Diego Essaya, Eyal Lotem, Regis Desgroppes, Emmanuel Hainry, Randy Kaelber Matthew L Daniel, Nirav Patel, Forrest Voight, Charlie Nolan, Frankie Robertson, John Krukoff, Lorenz Quack, Nick Irvine, Michael George, Saul Spatz, Thomas Ibbotson, Tom Rothamel, Evan Kroske, Cambell Barton.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And our bug hunters above and beyond: Angus, Guillaume Proux, Frank Raiser, Austin Henry, Kaweh Kazemi, Arturo Aldama, Mike Mulcheck, Michael Benfield, David Lau&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s many more folks out there who&#39;ve submitted helpful ideas, kept this project going, and basically made our life easier. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many thank you&#39;s for people making documentation comments, and adding to the pygame.org wiki.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also many thanks for people creating games and putting them on the pygame.org website for others to learn from and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lots of thanks to James Paige for hosting the pygame bugzilla.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also a big thanks to Roger Dingledine and the crew at SEUL.ORG for our excellent hosting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pygame is obviously strongly dependent on SDL and Python. It also links to and embeds several other smaller libraries. The font module relies on SDL_ttf, which is dependent on freetype. The mixer (and mixer.music) modules depend on SDL_mixer. The image module depends on SDL_image, which also can use libjpeg and libpng. The transform module has an embedded version of SDL_rotozoom for its own rotozoom function. The surfarray module requires the Python NumPy package for its multidimensional numeric arrays. Dependency versions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CPython &amp;gt;= 3.6 or PyPy3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL &amp;gt;= 2.0.4&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_mixer &amp;gt;= 2.0.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_image &amp;gt;= 2.0.2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_ttf &amp;gt;= 2.0.11&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_gfx (optional, vendored in)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NumPy &amp;gt;= 1.6.2 (optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library is distributed under &lt;code&gt;GNU LGPL version 2.1&lt;/code&gt;_, which can be found in the file &lt;code&gt;docs/LGPL.txt&lt;/code&gt;. We reserve the right to place future versions of this library under a different license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This basically means you can use pygame in any project you want, but if you make any changes or additions to pygame itself, those must be released with a compatible license (preferably submitted back to the pygame project). Closed source and commercial games are fine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The programs in the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory are in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See docs/licenses for licenses of dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |AppVeyorBuild| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/x4074ybuobsh4myx?svg=true&#34;&gt;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/x4074ybuobsh4myx?svg=true&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/pygame/pygame&#34;&gt;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/pygame/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |PyPiVersion| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/pygame.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/pygame.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&#34;&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |PyPiLicense| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/pygame.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/pygame.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&#34;&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |Python3| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3-blue.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3-blue.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |GithubCommits| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commits-since/pygame/pygame/2.1.2.svg&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/github/commits-since/pygame/pygame/2.1.2.svg&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pygame/pygame/compare/2.1.2...main&#34;&gt;https://github.com/pygame/pygame/compare/2.1.2...main&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMAlerts| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/alerts/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/alerts/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/alerts/&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/alerts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMGradePython| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/python/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/python/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:python&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMGradeC| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/cpp/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/cpp/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:cpp&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:cpp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |BlackFormatBadge| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/code%20style-black-000000.svg&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/badge/code%20style-black-000000.svg&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/psf/black&#34;&gt;https://github.com/psf/black&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. _pygame: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org&lt;/a&gt; .. _Simple DirectMedia Layer library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libsdl.org&#34;&gt;https://www.libsdl.org&lt;/a&gt; .. _We need your help: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/contribute.html&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/contribute.html&lt;/a&gt; .. _Compilation wiki page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/wiki/Compilation&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/wiki/Compilation&lt;/a&gt; .. _docs page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/docs/&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/docs/&lt;/a&gt; .. _GNU LGPL version 2.1: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/lesser.html&#34;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/lesser.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>webserver-llc/angie</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:44:04Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/webserver-llc/angie</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/webserver-llc/angie" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Angie - drop-in replacement for Nginx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;.. image:: misc/logo.gif :alt: Angie logo :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://angie.software/&#34;&gt;https://angie.software/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Angie&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Angie is an efficient, powerful and scalable web server, that was forked from nginx by some of its former core devs, with intention to extend functionality far beyond original version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Angie is a drop-in replacement for nginx, so you can use existing nginx configuration without major changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;Documentation Site &amp;lt;https://angie.software/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;code&gt;Changes &amp;lt;CHANGES&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>