<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-22T01:38:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>aws/pgactive</title>
    <updated>2025-06-22T01:38:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-22:/aws/pgactive</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aws/pgactive" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Active-active Replication Extension for PostgreSQL (pgactive)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pgactive is a PostgreSQL replication extension for creating an active-active database.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/docs/&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/#overciew&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/#security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/#license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Database replication is a method that copies changes between databases instances, and is a key component for use cases like high availability, reducing latency between an application and its source data, moving data between systems such as production and test, infrastructure migration, and others. Relational databases such as PostgreSQL typically support an active-standby model of replication, where one database instance accepts changes and makes them available to one or more read-only databases. Because changes in an active-standby cluster can only occur on a single instance, it’s more straightforward to build applications that work with this deployment topology because there is a single source of truth that contains all of the latest changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s preferable to have a database cluster that uses an active-active replication topology, where it’s possible to write data on multiple instances in the same cluster. In an asynchronous active-active replication deployment, multiple databases in a cluster can accept changes and replicate them to other databases, but this means the database cluster doesn’t have a single source of truth. Use cases for this include running a Multi-Region high availability database cluster, reducing write latency between applications and databases, performing blue/green updates of applications, and migrating data between systems that must both be writable. Applications that work with active-active database clusters must be designed to handle situations that occur in this deployment topology, including conflicting changes, replication lag, and the lack of certain convenient database features such as incremental integer sequences.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A fundamental component of active-active replication is logical replication. Logical replication uses a data format that allows external systems to interpret changes before applying them to a target database. This lets the target system perform additional actions, such as detecting and resolving write conflicts or converting the statement into something that is supported in the target database software. PostgreSQL added native support for logical replication in PostgreSQL 10 in 2017, but still requires additional features to fully support an active-active replication topology. PostgreSQL’s design makes it possible to build the necessary components for supporting active-active replication in an extension while the development community continues to add it into the upstream project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/CONTRIBUTING.md#security-issue-notifications&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/pgactive/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;this License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>open5gs/open5gs</title>
    <updated>2025-06-22T01:38:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-22:/open5gs/open5gs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/open5gs/open5gs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open5GS is a C-language Open Source implementation for 5G Core and EPC, i.e. the core network of LTE/NR network (Release-17)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open5gs.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;100&#34; src=&#34;https://open5gs.org/assets/img/open5gs-logo-only.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open5GS logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open5gs.org/open5gs/docs/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://open5gs.org/&#34;&gt;open5gs.org&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find Open5GS useful for work, please consider supporting this Open Source project by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/acetcom&#34;&gt;Becoming a sponsor&lt;/a&gt;. To manage the funding transactions transparently, you can donate through &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/open5gs&#34;&gt;OpenCollective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Special Sponsor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://mobi.com&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;special sponsor mobi&#34; src=&#34;https://open5gs.org/assets/img/mobi-open5GS.png&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a target=&#34;_blank&#34; href=&#34;https://open5gs.org/#sponsors&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;sponsors&#34; src=&#34;https://open5gs.org/assets/img/sponsors.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Problem with Open5GS can be filed as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/open5gs/open5gs/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; in this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Other topics related to this project are happening on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/open5gs/open5gs/discussions&#34;&gt;discussions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Voice and text chat are available in Open5GS&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://discordapp.com/&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; workspace. Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/GreNkuc&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re contributing through a pull request to Open5GS project on GitHub, please read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://open5gs.org/open5gs/cla/&#34;&gt;Contributor License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; in advance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open5GS Open Source files are made available under the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.html&#34;&gt;GNU AGPL v3.0&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open5gs.org/open5gs/support/&#34;&gt;Commercial licenses&lt;/a&gt; are also available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://newplane.io/&#34;&gt;NewPlane&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sales@newplane.io&#34;&gt;sales@newplane.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technical support and customized services for Open5GS are provided by &lt;a href=&#34;https://newplane.io/&#34;&gt;NewPlane&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@newplane.io&#34;&gt;support@newplane.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>