<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-15T01:29:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lemonmade/bigfoot</title>
    <updated>2024-10-15T01:29:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-15:/lemonmade/bigfoot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lemonmade/bigfoot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A jQuery plugin for creating exceptional footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;bigfoot.js&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmsauve.com/projects&#34;&gt;Chris Sauve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bigfoot is a jQuery plugin that creates exceptional footnotes. Simply include the code on your pages and footnotes will be detected automatically and improved in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Links to footnotes will be replaced with clickable/ tappable buttons, making them substantially easier to hit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Footnote content will appear in a popover directly beside the footnote button when it is clicked/ tapped, which cuts out the annoying bouncing around the page that footnotes typically result in.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The active popovers will be resized and repositioned to ensure that they continue to be completely visible on-screen and aesthetically pleasing: this makes it perfect for mobile devices and responsive designs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project includes both the script itself and a default style to apply to the footnote button/ content that are eventually generated. There are also a variety of additional styles that illustrate some of the possibilities for styling these components.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The script has many configurable options from having popovers instantiated on hover, to allowing multiple active footnotes, to setting specific timeouts for popover creation/ deletion. It also returns an object that allows you to activate, remove, add breakpoints, and reposition popovers properly. All of these options and return functions are shown in detail at the script&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigfootjs.com/&#34;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;. You can also see a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bigfootjs.com/#demo&#34;&gt;demo of the project in action&lt;/a&gt; on the same page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Requires jQuery 1.7+ at a minimum (for &lt;code&gt;.on()&lt;/code&gt;) and jQuery 1.8+ for full functionality (1.8 automatically prefixes the &lt;code&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt;/ &lt;code&gt;transition&lt;/code&gt; properties).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Bigfoot is currently incompatible with jQuery 3.0+ (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lemonmade/bigfoot/issues/54&#34;&gt;#54&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Questions? Issues? Feature requests? Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lemonmade/bigfoot&#34;&gt;Github page&lt;/a&gt; for this project.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>