<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-29T01:31:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>code-sujan/mmc_workshop_ci</title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T01:31:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-29:/code-sujan/mmc_workshop_ci</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/code-sujan/mmc_workshop_ci" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CodeIgniter 4 Application Starter&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is CodeIgniter?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CodeIgniter is a PHP full-stack web framework that is light, fast, flexible and secure. More information can be found at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeigniter.com&#34;&gt;official site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository holds a composer-installable app starter. It has been built from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/codeigniter4/CodeIgniter4&#34;&gt;development repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;More information about the plans for version 4 can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.codeigniter.com/forumdisplay.php?fid=28&#34;&gt;CodeIgniter 4&lt;/a&gt; on the forums.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The user guide corresponding to the latest version of the framework can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeigniter4.github.io/userguide/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation &amp;amp; updates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;composer create-project codeigniter4/appstarter&lt;/code&gt; then &lt;code&gt;composer update&lt;/code&gt; whenever there is a new release of the framework.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When updating, check the release notes to see if there are any changes you might need to apply to your &lt;code&gt;app&lt;/code&gt; folder. The affected files can be copied or merged from &lt;code&gt;vendor/codeigniter4/framework/app&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;env&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; and tailor for your app, specifically the baseURL and any database settings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Important Change with index.php&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.php&lt;/code&gt; is no longer in the root of the project! It has been moved inside the &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; folder, for better security and separation of components.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means that you should configure your web server to &#34;point&#34; to your project&#39;s &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; folder, and not to the project root. A better practice would be to configure a virtual host to point there. A poor practice would be to point your web server to the project root and expect to enter &lt;em&gt;public/...&lt;/em&gt;, as the rest of your logic and the framework are exposed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please&lt;/strong&gt; read the user guide for a better explanation of how CI4 works!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository Management&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use GitHub issues, in our main repository, to track &lt;strong&gt;BUGS&lt;/strong&gt; and to track approved &lt;strong&gt;DEVELOPMENT&lt;/strong&gt; work packages. We use our &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.codeigniter.com&#34;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; to provide SUPPORT and to discuss FEATURE REQUESTS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is a &#34;distribution&#34; one, built by our release preparation script. Problems with it can be raised on our forum, or as issues in the main repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Server Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PHP version 7.4 or higher is required, with the following extensions installed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/intl.requirements.php&#34;&gt;intl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/mbstring.installation.php&#34;&gt;mbstring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, make sure that the following extensions are enabled in your PHP:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;json (enabled by default - don&#39;t turn it off)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/mysqlnd.install.php&#34;&gt;mysqlnd&lt;/a&gt; if you plan to use MySQL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://php.net/manual/en/curl.requirements.php&#34;&gt;libcurl&lt;/a&gt; if you plan to use the HTTP\CURLRequest library&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>