<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-12-15T01:30:46Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Mozilla-Ocho/Memory-Cache</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T01:30:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-15:/Mozilla-Ocho/Memory-Cache</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Mozilla-Ocho/Memory-Cache" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;MemoryCache is an experimental development project to turn a local desktop environment into an on-device AI agent&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Memory Cache&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Memory Cache is a project that allows you to save a webpage while you&#39;re browsing in Firefox as a PDF, and save it to a synchronized folder that can be used in conjunction with privateGPT to augment a local language model.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;⚠️: This setup uses the primordial version of privateGPT. I&#39;m working from a fork that can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/misslivirose/privateGPT&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/imartinez/privateGPT&#34;&gt;privateGPT&lt;/a&gt; - either using the primordial checkpoint, or from my fork.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a symlink between a subdirectory in your default Downloads folder called &#39;MemoryCache&#39; and a &#39;MemoryCache&#39; directory created inside of /PrivateGPT/source_documents/MemoryCache&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Apply patch to Firefox to add the &lt;code&gt;printerSettings.silentMode&lt;/code&gt; property to the Tabs API. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/misslivirose/MemoryCacheExt/wiki/Modifying-Firefox-to-use-Memory-Cache&#34;&gt;See wiki page for instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy /scripts/run_ingest.sh into your privateGPT directory and run it to start &lt;code&gt;inotifywait&lt;/code&gt; watching your downloads directory for new content&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setting up the Extension&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the Memory-Cache GitHub repository to your local machine&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In Firefox, navigate to &lt;code&gt;about:debugging&lt;/code&gt; and click on &#39;This Firefox&#39;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click &#39;Load Temporary Add-on&#34; and open the &lt;code&gt;extension/manifest.json&lt;/code&gt; file in the MemoryCacheExt directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using the Extension&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Under the &#39;Extensions&#39; menu, add the Memory Cache extension to the toolbar&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When you want to save a page to your Memory Cache, click the icon and select the &#39;Save&#39; button. This will save the file silently as a PDF if you are using a Firefox build with the &lt;code&gt;printerSettings.silentMode&lt;/code&gt; property addition.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T01:30:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-15:/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GoGuardian Bypass is a simple script that allows you to access blocked websites on your school&#39;s network. The script generates an iframe that displays the blocked content without being detected by the GoGuardian filter, allowing you to bypass restrictions and access the content you need. Join our discord: https://discord.gg/8ABatmss76&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;🕵️ GoGuardian Bypass&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The GoGuardian Bypass is a simple script that allows you to bypass the GoGuardian filter on your school or organization&#39;s network using iframes. To join our Discord server, click here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GoGuardian Bypass: Access blocked websites on your school or organization&#39;s network with the GoGuardian bypass script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easy to Use: Simply type in the URL of the blocked website and click the &#34;Generate&#34; button to create an iframe that displays the blocked content.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Customizable: The script is open source and can be modified to fit your specific needs or preferences.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Markdown Formatting: The README file uses Markdown formatting, making it easy to read and navigate.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Discord Community: Join our Discord server to connect with other users, share tips and tricks, and get help with any issues you may encounter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How it Works&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you type in a blocked URL into the script, it generates an iframe that displays the blocked content without being detected by GoGuardian. This allows you to access websites that would otherwise be blocked by the filter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone this repository to your local machine. Open the index.html file in a text editor. Type in the URL of the blocked website you want to access. Click the &#34;Generate&#34; button. The blocked content should now be displayed in the iframe. Note: This script should only be used for educational or research purposes. Misuse of this script may be in violation of your school or organization&#39;s policies and could result in disciplinary action.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick &amp;amp; Easy Deployment Options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://replit.com/github/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/BinBashBanana/deploy-buttons/master/buttons/remade/replit.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Run on Replit&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://glitch.com/edit/#!/import/github/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://binbashbanana.github.io/deploy-buttons/buttons/remade/glitch.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Remix on Glitch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://binbashbanana.github.io/deploy-buttons/buttons/remade/netlify.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Deploy with Netlify&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://vercel.com/new/clone?repository-url=https://github.com/AroriaNetwork/GoGuardian-Bypass.git&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://binbashbanana.github.io/deploy-buttons/buttons/remade/vercel.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Deploy with Vercel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script is provided as-is, without any warranty or guarantee of any kind. Use at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📝 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the LICENSE file for detail&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>isbendiyarovanezrin/ShoppingCart</title>
    <updated>2023-12-15T01:30:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-15:/isbendiyarovanezrin/ShoppingCart</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/isbendiyarovanezrin/ShoppingCart" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shopping Cart 🛒&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Shopping Cart 🛒&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.postimg.cc/T3B5Z02V/cart.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Shopping Cart project preview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Shopping Cart&#34; project built with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript. You can view the project &lt;a href=&#34;https://isbendiyarovanezrin.github.io/ShoppingCart&#34; title=&#34;Click me! 🛒&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theme-oxygen.com/envato/matestore/mix&#34; title=&#34;Click me! 🛒&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the template.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pull requests are welcome. For major changes, please open an issue first to discuss what you would like to change.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MIT License&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2022 Nəzrin İsbəndiyarova&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &#34;Software&#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &#34;AS IS&#34;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>