<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-02-25T01:29:47Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>polyfractal/elasticsearch-segmentspy</title>
    <updated>2025-02-25T01:29:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-02-25:/polyfractal/elasticsearch-segmentspy</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/polyfractal/elasticsearch-segmentspy" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ElasticSearch plugin to watch segment dynamics (additions, merges, deletes)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;h1. elasticsearch-segmentspy&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SegmentSpy is a tool to watch the segments in your indices. Segment graphs update in real-time, allowing you to watch as ElasticSearch (Lucene) merges your segments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;|&lt;em&gt;. elasticsearch-segmentspy |&lt;/em&gt;. ElasticSearch | | master | 0.17.0 -&amp;gt; 0.90.3 |&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: SegmentSpy has only been tested on 0.20.2 - 0.90.3, but should work all the way back to 0.17.0 when the Segments API was implemented&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;h3. Installation&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install SegmentSpy onto your node, run &lt;code&gt;bin/plugin -install polyfractal/elasticsearch-segmentspy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SegmentSpy automatically connects to the host specified in the URL used to display the plugin. For example, if you are running a node on &lt;code&gt;localhost:9200&lt;/code&gt;, point your browser to &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:9200/_plugin/segmentspy/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:9200/_plugin/segmentspy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;. The plugin will automatically connect to &lt;code&gt;localhost:9200&lt;/code&gt; and begin parsing your cluster state. Alternatively, it&#39;s possible to set a target host and refreshInterval via url parameters, for example: &lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8000/_site/#/myindex/?host=my-es-host.com:9200&amp;amp;refreshInterval=500&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8000/_site/#/myindex/?host=my-es-host.com:9200&amp;amp;refreshInterval=500&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;!screenshot.png!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;h3. Usage&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Select your index from the dropdown box at the top of the page. A graph will be loaded for each shard on every node in your cluster, grouped by node. The refresh interval can be changed (default is 500ms) or paused completely. That&#39;s it! Fire up some inserts on your cluster to watch as ElasticSearch/Lucene creates new segments or merges away old ones.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The graphs show the number of documents in each segment, plotted on a logarithmic scale. Deleted docs are represented as a red, stacked bar. If you hover over the blue &#34;docs&#34; bar, you can read the number of documents in that segment. Unfortunately, Google Charts does not support logarithmic stacked charts, so the Deleted Docs bar is preprocessed to adjust it&#39;s size. For this reason, the tooltip value of deleted docs is incorrect (but visually it is mostly accurate).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;h3. Background Information&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SegmentSpy utilizes the &#34;Indices Segments API&#34;:&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elasticsearch.org/guide/reference/api/admin-indices-segments.html&#34;&gt;http://www.elasticsearch.org/guide/reference/api/admin-indices-segments.html&lt;/a&gt; that ElasticSearch provides.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool was inspired by the fantastic article and videos produced by Mike McCandless &#34;Visualizing Lucene&#39;s Segment Merges&#34;:&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mikemccandless.com/2011/02/visualizing-lucenes-segment-merges.html&#34;&gt;http://blog.mikemccandless.com/2011/02/visualizing-lucenes-segment-merges.html&lt;/a&gt; article. The visuals of this plugin aren&#39;t as sophisticated as Mike&#39;s yet, but most of the functionality should be possible using the API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Future versions will allow you to&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Differentiate searchable vs unsearchable segments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Watch deletes accumulate in indices before merging out&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sort on factors other than doc size (doc number, deletes, etc)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More robust filtering of nodes/indices for large clusters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This plugin is functional...but messy underneath. Developers beware! If you feel like helping out, fork SegmentSpy and make some changes!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>