<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-21T01:25:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>0x48piraj/fadblock</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T01:25:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-21:/0x48piraj/fadblock</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/0x48piraj/fadblock" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Friendly Adblock for YouTube: A fast, lightweight, and undetectable YouTube Ads Blocker for Chrome, Opera and Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/0x48piraj/fadblock/assets/5800726/cf39ef9f-779b-43ca-93f7-ee0bb2a93323&#34; alt=&#34;fadblock: A fast, lightweight, and undetectable YouTube Ads Blocker for Chrome, Opera and Firefox&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;sub&gt;A fast, lightweight, and undetectable YouTube Ads Blocker for Chrome, Opera and Firefox.&lt;/sub&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/addon/fadblock/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/585534/107280546-7b9b2a00-6a26-11eb-8f9f-f95932f4bfec.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get uBlock Origin for Firefox&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fadblock/mdadjjfmjhfcibgfhfjbaiiljpllkbfc&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/585534/107280622-91a8ea80-6a26-11eb-8d07-77c548b28665.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get uBlock Origin for Chromium&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.opera.com/extensions/details/fadblock/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/585534/107280692-ac7b5f00-6a26-11eb-85c7-088926504452.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get uBlock Origin for Opera&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;FadBlock: Friendly Adblock for Youtube™&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was posted over reddit a few months ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube/comments/13cfdbi/apparently_ad_blockers_are_not_allowed_on_youtube/?rdt=64832&#34;&gt;Apparently Ad Blockers are not allowed on Youtube. Is this a new thing they&#39;ve implemented?&lt;/a&gt; and judging by all the recent comments and posts all over &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/youtube/&#34;&gt;r/youtube&lt;/a&gt;, this change was just rolled out on a &lt;strong&gt;larger scale&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blocker is designed to monitor advertisements, automatically seek the ads and skip them. It&#39;s important to note that this doesn&#39;t classify as traditional ad blocking, as the ad content is technically &#34;loaded&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the extension&#39;s underlying logic enables it to fast-forward through the ad content to its conclusion. The entire process is optimized to occur within an extremely brief timeframe, typically &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;=50 milliseconds&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring a smooth and uninterrupted user experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This extension effectively eliminates all categories of YouTube advertisements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Ads visible on the homepage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Ads overlaid atop the suggested video list.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 3:&lt;/strong&gt; Ads displayed below the video description.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Starting on April 6th, 2023, the “Overlay ads” ad format will no longer appear on YouTube to help improve the viewer experience and shift engagement to higher performing ad formats on desktop and mobile devices. Overlay ads are a legacy ad format that only served on desktop and are disruptive for viewers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 4:&lt;/strong&gt; Skippable 5-second-must-be-watched video ads, which may be positioned at the video&#39;s start, midway, or at the end.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 5:&lt;/strong&gt; Ads similar to Category 4, but with two consecutive video ads instead of one.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category 6:&lt;/strong&gt; Inescapable 10-second video ads, which must be watched.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is not working!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will have to disable other adblockers as they are getting detected &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; fadblock.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;You can also add &lt;em&gt;youtube.com&lt;/em&gt; to the exception list for domains on other adblockers (uBlock Origin, AdBlock) and then download fadblock to override regular adblock being prioritized on YouTube while the conventional adblocker will work across the remainder of the Internet.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chrome extension says &#34;Read your browsing history&#34;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prime example of Google being nonsensical, again. Firefox doesn&#39;t and they share the same code. (read in detail &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/64063834&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why there&#39;s no privacy policy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s no privacy policy as there’s no data collection at all, not even analytical data for error reporting. Everything happens locally. No remote connections are made, nada!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I use it for my phone?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately there’s no app or anything. You cannot install Chrome extensions on the Chrome browser on Android, but several Chromium-based third-party browsers support extensions (e.g. brave browser).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Note: You will have to leave YouTube app and watch over a browser (not very elegant, sorry)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install Fadblock to Opera, Edge, and Brave&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section explains on how to install the extension utilizing the &lt;em&gt;developer mode&lt;/em&gt; as well as Chromium-based browsers,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://bashvlas.com/blog/install-chrome-extension-in-developer-mode/example.gif&#34; alt=&#34;installing chrome extension in devmode&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opera Browser:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the extensions manager page (&lt;code&gt;opera://extensions&lt;/code&gt;), turn on &lt;strong&gt;developer mode&lt;/strong&gt; and click on &lt;strong&gt;Load Unpacked&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edge Browser:&lt;/strong&gt; Go to the extensions manager page (&lt;code&gt;edge://extensions&lt;/code&gt;), turn on &lt;strong&gt;developer mode&lt;/strong&gt; and click on &lt;strong&gt;Load Unpacked&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brave Browser:&lt;/strong&gt; You can visit Chrome Web Store and download the extension (&lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fadblock/mdadjjfmjhfcibgfhfjbaiiljpllkbfc&#34;&gt;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fadblock/mdadjjfmjhfcibgfhfjbaiiljpllkbfc&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Show your support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow me on GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/0x48piraj&#34;&gt;@0x48piraj&lt;/a&gt; for updates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I do not ask for donations, all I ask is that you star (⭐) this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is provided for educational purposes only and is provided &#34;AS IS&#34;, without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including but not limited to the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose and noninfringement. in no event shall the authors or copyright holders be liable for any claim, damages or other liability, whether in an action of contract, tort or otherwise, arising from, out of or in connection with the software or the use or other dealings in the software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>promet/provus-meridian-demo</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T01:25:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-21:/promet/provus-meridian-demo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/promet/provus-meridian-demo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Meridian Demo Site&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Provus Drupal kickstarter by Promet Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drupal.org/project/provus&#34;&gt;https://www.drupal.org/project/provus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For installation and general usage, please read full documentation here &lt;a href=&#34;https://promet-source.gitbook.io/provus/&#34;&gt;https://promet-source.gitbook.io/provus/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>chimma666/restaurant-file</title>
    <updated>2023-10-21T01:25:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-21:/chimma666/restaurant-file</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/chimma666/restaurant-file" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;this is a restaurant menu page where you can show your creativity by adding new features&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Restaurant Website Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Restaurant Website project! This is an open-source project aimed at creating an interactive and user-friendly website for a restaurant. We encourage open source contributors to join us in this endeavor to enhance the user experience and add new features to the menu and login pages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is focused on creating an engaging and visually appealing website for a restaurant. It currently includes the following components:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menu Page:&lt;/strong&gt; Displays the variety of dishes and beverages offered by the restaurant.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login Page:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a secure login system for customers and staff members.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions from developers of all skill levels. If you&#39;re interested in contributing to this project, consider the following ways you can help:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adding New Features:&lt;/strong&gt; Help us enhance the menu page by incorporating new functionalities or improving the user interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improving Security:&lt;/strong&gt; Work on enhancing the security features of the login page and implementing best practices for user authentication.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bug Fixes:&lt;/strong&gt; Identify and fix any bugs or issues present in the existing codebase.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimization:&lt;/strong&gt; Improve the performance of the website and optimize the code for better efficiency.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To contribute to this project, follow the steps below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the repository and clone it to your local machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make the necessary changes or add new features to the menu or login pages.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Test your changes thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a pull request, explaining the changes you&#39;ve made and how they benefit the project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code Structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project&#39;s codebase is structured as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt;: Contains the main structure of the restaurant website.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;css/&lt;/code&gt;: Directory containing the CSS files for styling the website.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;js/&lt;/code&gt;: Directory for JavaScript files used in the project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;menu/&lt;/code&gt;: Directory for the menu page components.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;login/&lt;/code&gt;: Directory for the login page components.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to explore and make changes as needed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or need further information about the project, feel free to reach out to us via the issue tracker or by contacting the project maintainers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s work together to create an outstanding restaurant website!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>