<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-28T01:34:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>caracal-js/Incognito</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T01:34:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-28:/caracal-js/Incognito</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/caracal-js/Incognito" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Source code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Incognito&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Access the world wide web&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/caracal-js/Incognito.git&#xA;cd Incognito&#xA;git submodule update --init&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Ultraviolet&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ultraviolet&#39;s bare server by default is set to Incognito&#39;s official bare server (&lt;a href=&#34;https://incog.dev/bare/&#34;&gt;https://incog.dev/bare/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change the bare server in &lt;code&gt;uv/uv.config.js&lt;/code&gt; to whatever bare server you have.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Folder prefixes in &lt;code&gt;uv.sw.js&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;uv.config.js&lt;/code&gt; will have to be changed to where &lt;code&gt;uv/&lt;/code&gt; is located&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/uv.sw.js&lt;/code&gt; --&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;/uv/uv.sw.js&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Games&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Games are not included by default due to the extremely large size of them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/caracal-js/gfiles.git source&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PrincessMaggy/cohort4-project</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T01:34:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-28:/PrincessMaggy/cohort4-project</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PrincessMaggy/cohort4-project" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Project for My Mentees in HertechTrai&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome! 👋&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do this challenge, you need a basic understanding of HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The challenge&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your challenge is to build on this portolio template and get it looking as you desire. You can use any tools you like to help you complete the challenge. So if you&#39;ve got something you&#39;d like to practice, feel free to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Your users should be able to:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;View the optimal layout for the site depending on their device&#39;s screen size See hover states for all interactive elements on the page Where to find everything&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will find all the required assets in the /images folder. The assets are already optimized.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building your project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use any workflow that you feel comfortable with. Below is a suggested process, but do not feel like you need to follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Initialize your project as a public repository on GitHub. This will make it easier to share your code with the community if you need some help. If you&#39;re not sure how to do this, have a read through of this Try Git resource.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure your repository to publish your code to a URL. This will also be useful if you need some help during a challenge as you can share the URL for your project with your repo URL. There are a number of ways to do this, but we recommend using netlify.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Deploying your project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, there are a number of ways to host your project for free. We recommend using netflify as it&#39;s an amazing service and extremely simple to get set up with.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sign up to netlify and go through the onboarding flow, ensuring your GitHub account is connected by using their netlify for GitHub integration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect your project to netlify from the &#34;Import project&#34; page, using the &#34;From Git Repository&#34; button and selecting the project you want to deploy. Once connected, every time you git push, netlify will create a new deployment and the deployment URL will be shown on your Dashboard.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have fun building!&lt;/strong&gt; 🚀&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>cli-guidelines/cli-guidelines</title>
    <updated>2022-09-28T01:34:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-28:/cli-guidelines/cli-guidelines</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cli-guidelines/cli-guidelines" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A guide to help you write better command-line programs, taking traditional UNIX principles and updating them for the modern day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Command Line Interface Guidelines&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An open-source guide to help you write better command-line programs, taking traditional UNIX principles and updating them for the modern day.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the source code for the guide. To read it, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://clig.dev/&#34;&gt;clig.dev&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/EbAW5rUCkE&#34;&gt;Join us on Discord&lt;/a&gt; if you want to discuss the guide, or just chat about CLI design.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The content of the guide lives in a single Markdown file, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cli-guidelines/cli-guidelines/main/content/_index.md&#34;&gt;content/_index.md&lt;/a&gt;. The website is built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run Hugo locally to see your changes, run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew install hugo&#xA;$ cd &amp;lt;path&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;to&amp;gt;/cli-guidelines/&#xA;$ hugo server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To view the site on an external mobile device, run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --bind 0.0.0.0 --baseURL http://$(hostname -f):1313&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- TODO: add contact info (how to reach the CLIG creators with questions) --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>