<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-24T01:35:05Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>orderedlist/minimal</title>
    <updated>2022-08-24T01:35:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-24:/orderedlist/minimal</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/orderedlist/minimal" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Theme for GitHub Pages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Minimal Theme&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orderedlist.com/minimal/&#34;&gt;Demo the Theme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the raw HTML and styles that are used for the &lt;em&gt;minimal&lt;/em&gt; theme on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting is provided on GitHub Pages by &lt;a href=&#34;http://pygments.org&#34;&gt;Pygments&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>getpelican/pelican-themes</title>
    <updated>2022-08-24T01:35:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-24:/getpelican/pelican-themes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Themes for Pelican&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pelican Themes ##############&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains themes for Pelican. Feel free to clone, add your own theme, and submit a pull request. It&#39;s community-managed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A live version can be seen at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pelicanthemes.com&#34;&gt;http://www.pelicanthemes.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Themes ############&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These instructions assume you have already read all the &lt;code&gt;Pelican documentation&lt;/code&gt;_, have a working site, and would now like to apply a non-default theme.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. _Pelican documentation: &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.getpelican.com/&#34;&gt;http://docs.getpelican.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, choose a location to hold your themes. For this example, we&#39;ll use the directory &lt;code&gt;~/pelican-themes&lt;/code&gt;, but yours could be different. Clone the &lt;code&gt;pelican-themes&lt;/code&gt; repository to that location on your local machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. code-block:: sh&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recursive https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes ~/pelican-themes&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now you should have your &lt;code&gt;pelican-themes&lt;/code&gt; repository stored at &lt;code&gt;~/pelican-themes/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use one of the themes, edit your Pelican settings file to include this line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. code-block:: python&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;THEME = &#34;/home/user/pelican-themes/theme-name&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, for instance, to use the &lt;code&gt;mnmlist&lt;/code&gt; theme, you would edit your settings file to include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. code-block:: python&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;THEME = &#34;/home/user/pelican-themes/mnmlist&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Save the changes to your settings file and then regenerate your site by using the Makefile you should already have set up using &lt;code&gt;pelican-quickstart&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. code-block:: sh&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;make html&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Themes can also be specified directly via the &lt;code&gt;-t ~/pelican-themes/theme-name&lt;/code&gt; parameter to the &lt;code&gt;pelican&lt;/code&gt; command. If you want to edit your theme, make sure that any edits you make are made to the copy stored in &lt;code&gt;~/pelican-themes/theme-name&lt;/code&gt;. Any changes made to files stored in your site&#39;s &lt;code&gt;output&lt;/code&gt; directory will be deleted the next time you generate your site.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DataTables/DataTables</title>
    <updated>2022-08-24T01:35:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-24:/DataTables/DataTables</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/DataTables/DataTables" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tables plug-in for jQuery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Legacy repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that this is a &lt;strong&gt;legacy repo&lt;/strong&gt; for DataTables. The main source repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DataTables/DataTablesSrc&#34;&gt;is DataTables/DataTablesSrc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our distribution repos (for NPM, Nuget, etc packages) are the &lt;code&gt;DataTables/Dist-*&lt;/code&gt; repos - e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DataTables/Dist-DataTables&#34;&gt;DataTables/Dist-DataTables&lt;/a&gt;. Each distribution repo has a core Javascript file or styling for DataTables or an extension. Please use our &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatables.net/download&#34;&gt;download builder&lt;/a&gt; to obtain the files you need, including for NPM, Nuget, CDN and download.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;DataTables plug-in for jQuery&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DataTables is a table enhancing plug-in for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jquery.com&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/a&gt; Javascript library, adding sorting, paging and filtering abilities to plain HTML tables with minimal effort. The stated goal of DataTables is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;To enhance the accessibility of data in HTML tables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To meet this goal, DataTables is developed with two distinct groups of users in mind:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You the developers using DataTables. For developers DataTables provides a wide array of options for how data should be obtained, displayed and acted upon, along with an extensive API for accessing and manipulating the table.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;End users. For those using the interface DataTables presents, actions to get the most from the information contained in tables, such as sorting and filtering, along with paging and scrolling of the data in table, are easy to use, intuitive and fast.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing DataTables&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use DataTables, the primary way to obtain the software is to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/download&#34;&gt;DataTables downloader&lt;/a&gt;. You can also include the individual files from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cdn.datatables.net&#34;&gt;DataTables CDN&lt;/a&gt;. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/manual/installation&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for full details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;NPM and Bower&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer to use a package manager such as NPM or Bower, distribution repositories are available with software built from this repository under the name &lt;code&gt;datatables.net&lt;/code&gt;. Styling packages for Bootstrap, Foundation and other styling libraries are also available by adding a suffix to the package name.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the DataTables &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/download/npm&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/download/bower&#34;&gt;Bower&lt;/a&gt; installation pages for further information. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/manual/installation&#34;&gt;DataTables installation manual&lt;/a&gt; also has details on how to use package managers with DataTables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In its simplest case, DataTables can be initialised with a single line of Javascript:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$(&#39;table&#39;).dataTable();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;where the jQuery selector is used to obtain a reference to the table you want to enhance with DataTables. Optional configuration parameters can be passed in to DataTables to have it perform certain actions by using a configuration object as the parameter passed in to the DataTables constructor. For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;$(&#39;table&#39;).dataTable( {&#xA;  paginate: false,&#xA;  scrollY: 300&#xA;} );&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;will disable paging and enable scrolling.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A full list of the options available for DataTables are available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full documentation of the DataTables options, API and plug-in interface are available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net&#34;&gt;DataTables web-site&lt;/a&gt;. The site also contains information on the wide variety of plug-ins that are available for DataTables, which can be used to enhance and customise your table even further.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Support for DataTables is available through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/forums&#34;&gt;DataTables forums&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/support&#34;&gt;commercial support options&lt;/a&gt; are available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DataTables is release under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datatables.net/license&#34;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;. You are free to use, modify and distribute this software, as long as the copyright header is left intact (specifically the comment block which starts with &lt;code&gt;/*!&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>