<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-23T01:33:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Kalvium-Program/lab-brrgrr</title>
    <updated>2022-11-23T01:33:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-23:/Kalvium-Program/lab-brrgrr</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Kalvium-Program/lab-brrgrr" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Lab | BRRRGRRR&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mama Jenny is the best cook you would ever met. She makes the most amazing burgers in her tiny diner across the street. Mama is extremely popular and has recently had the idea to take her business online. Unfortunately, she isn&#39;t the best at web development. Mama has heard of Kalvians and she thought you could do a great job.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help Mama create a website that&#39;ll attract more audience and help her make a living through it. Go to the &lt;code&gt;src/app.js&lt;/code&gt; file and complete all the unfinished code to let her live here dream.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What should you do&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fork this repo&#xA;Clone this repo&#xA;And get started with the lab&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Progression 1: LAYERS&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As your first task, you&#39;ve got to enable the different layers of the burger on the screen. Create a &lt;code&gt;render()&lt;/code&gt; for each ingredient and make sure that it displays the selected layer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Progression 2: LAYER THEM UP&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setup &lt;code&gt;EventListeners&lt;/code&gt;, so that we can add or remove different ingredients by clicking on the respective ingredient buttons. That&#39;s the whole point of it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Challenge 1: IT GETS CHEESEY&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make the ingredient buttons pop up based on their current active state. This would help customers identify what ingredients they&#39;ve selected and what&#39;s left out.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Challenge 2: TAKE THE ORDER&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Show the customer only the ingredients that they&#39;ve selected on the chalk board.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Challenge 3: BILL TIME&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The customer has had a good time customizing their brrrgrrr. Time for them to pay. Use ingredient prices to calculate the cost of a brrrgrrr and display it to the customer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding ❤️&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>zero-to-mastery/Animation-Nation</title>
    <updated>2022-11-23T01:33:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-23:/zero-to-mastery/Animation-Nation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zero-to-mastery/Animation-Nation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A ZTM Challenge for Hacktoberfest 2019&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Event Concluded!&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This project started as a project for Hacktoberfest 2019, Thank you to everyone that participated and made this project what it is today and we look forward to seeing you all at Hacktoberfest 2020!. Feel free to continue adding your designs to the master branch, you can check out the &lt;code&gt;Hactoberfest-Edition&lt;/code&gt; branch to see the project as it was at the end of the event.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interested in more events? keep an eye on our Events page &lt;a href=&#34;https://zerotomastery.io/events?utm_source=github&amp;amp;utm_medium=animation-nation&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zero-to-mastery/Animation-Nation/master/colourpencils.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sharpen your pencils, we&#39;re getting creative!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Animation Nation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to Animation Nation, a ZTM project for Hacktoberfest 2019! This site aims to showcase the creative talents of the ZTM community :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Rules&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rules are simple. You have to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use HTML &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;divs&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and CSS only! No JS, and no SVGs!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Have at least one animation in your work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please make sure that the code is indeed your own, and not copied from someone else&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;That&#39;s it!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All discussions around this event can now be had in our #hacktoberfest-2019 channel on Discord!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to contribute&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve never forked a repository or made a pull request before, we recommend making your first one over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zero-to-mastery/start-here-guidelines&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zero-to-mastery/start-here-guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. That will count towards your total, and then you&#39;ll be ready to take on this challenge with your new GitHub skills!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A cool resource to learn about the fork workflow can also be found here - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/comparing-workflows/forking-workflow&#34;&gt;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/comparing-workflows/forking-workflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, once you&#39;ve forked this repo and got a local version up on your computer, follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the Art directory (folder), create a directory named after yourself.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Within this folder you just made, create two files, an HTML file, and a CSS file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Link your CSS file to your HTML file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Using only HTML and CSS (no &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; allowed!!), create a work of art! It can be as simple or as complex as you like, as long as it&#39;s animated in some way!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get a screen recording of your finished work, &lt;strong&gt;and make a gif&lt;/strong&gt;! Try to crop it so that it looks good as a smallish (preferably squarish) image. Save this in your directory, together with your HTML and CSS files. Static screenshots are also acceptable.&lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you don&#39;t add a gif/screenshot, the website won&#39;t show your animation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the root &lt;code&gt;include.js&lt;/code&gt;. You will see an array of objects, each one represents a work of art that someone has created. Copy an example object and paste it at the end, filling it out with your art information and links:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;let cards = [&#xA;  //  Add your card in this section&#xA;  {&#xA;    artName: &#39;Your art name here&#39;,&#xA;    pageLink: &#39;./Art/Joy/triangle/triangle.html&#39;,&#xA;    imageLink: &#39;./Art/Joy/triangle/triangle.gif&#39;,&#xA;    author: &#39;Joy&#39;,&#xA;    githubLink: &#39;https://github.com/royranger&#39;&#xA;  }&#xA;];&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>andrewnicols/moodle-atto_htmlplus</title>
    <updated>2022-11-23T01:33:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-23:/andrewnicols/moodle-atto_htmlplus</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/andrewnicols/moodle-atto_htmlplus" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HTMLPlus plugin for Atto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HTML Plus plugin for Atto&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Moodle 2.7&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Place in lib/editor/atto/plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upgrade your Moodle&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Navigate to Site administration -&amp;gt; Plugins -&amp;gt; Text editors -&amp;gt; Atto HTML editor -&amp;gt; Atto toolbar settings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;replace any occurrence of the html plugin with htmlplus&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>