<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-12T01:32:41Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Cloudydude/ECSv8-Character-ID-Randomizer</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T01:32:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-12:/Cloudydude/ECSv8-Character-ID-Randomizer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Cloudydude/ECSv8-Character-ID-Randomizer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The ECSU Framework simple tool for choosing an ID for an Extra Character, ignoring those already registered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Cloudydude/ECSv8-Character-ID-Randomizer/main/src/img/favicon.png&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ECSv8 - Character ID Randomizer&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ECSv8 simple tool for choosing an ID for an Extra Character, ignoring those already registered.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I add my ID?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add your characters&#39; IDs to the registered list, you need to follow few simple steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Register on github.com if you haven&#39;t already. Make a fork of this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://randomizer.extra-character-slots.com/&#34;&gt;https://randomizer.extra-character-slots.com/&lt;/a&gt; and generate any ID.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the file &lt;code&gt;src/json/characters.json&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Depending on your goals: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to register your character as a release and have it displayed on the site, then go to the &lt;code&gt;Released characters&lt;/code&gt; comment and add the following code to the free space:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt; &#34;255&#34;:&#x9;{ // &amp;lt;- Character ID&#xA; &#x9;&#34;Name&#34;:&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;EXAMPLE&#34;,&#x9;&#x9;// Character Name&#xA; &#x9;&#34;Author&#34;:&#x9;&#x9;&#34;EXAMPLE&#34;,&#x9;&#x9;// Characted Author&#xA;&#xA; &#x9;// Optional -v-&#xA; &#x9;&#34;Description&#34;:&#x9;&#34;EXAMPLE&#34;,&#x9;&#x9;// Character Description&#xA; &#x9;&#34;ModVersion&#34;:&#x9;&#34;vEXAMPLE&#34;,&#x9;&#x9;// Mod Version&#xA; &#x9;&#34;URL&#34;:&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#34;https://&#34;&#x9;&#x9;// Mod Link&#xA; &#x9;// Delete &#34;ReservedBy&#34; if it was&#xA; }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you just want to register an ID, in which case your character will not be displayed on the site, then go to the &lt;code&gt;Reserved characters&lt;/code&gt; comment, and add the following code to the free space:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt; &#34;255&#34;:&#x9;{ &#34;ReservedBy&#34;:&#x9;&#34;Your Name&#34; },&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: Where &lt;code&gt;255&lt;/code&gt; is YOUR ID, replace this number with it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: Add your IDs to the end of an existing line with commas where necessary. Do not touch or change the IDs that have already been.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: Specify a link to a protected resource in the URL. Specify it only if your mod released, is in the stage of a public demo, or to attract interested parties to the wip.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save your changes and send a pull request with indicating the mod&#39;s link to your Extra Character so that we can know for sure that this ID is now being used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well done! Now the IDs you have added will be marked as used, and will not be found as suggested IDs for other people.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. I noticed a bug, where can I contact?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; A. Contact me in GitHub issues or via Discord on the Sonic 3 A.I.R Community server. Try to describe the problem in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>joy-of-react/toast-component</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T01:32:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-12:/joy-of-react/toast-component</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/joy-of-react/toast-component" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Toast Component Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Joy of React, Project II&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this project, we&#39;ll dive deep into the implementation of a single common UI component: A &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Toast&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; message component.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joy-of-react/toast-component/main/docs/toast-demo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Screen recording showing 3 toast messages popping up from user input&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is created with create-react-app. It&#39;s intended to be run locally, on your computer, using Node.js and NPM.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the first project, Wordle, we saw how to run a local development server. If you&#39;re not quite sure how to get started, I recommend reviewing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/project-wordle/03-dev-server&#34;&gt;“Local Development” instructions&lt;/a&gt; lesson.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To jog your memory, here are the terminal commands you&#39;ll need to run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Install dependencies:&#xA;npm install&#xA;&#xA;# Run a development server:&#xA;npm run start&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To create new components, you can use this helper script. It saves you a bit of time, creating all the files and adding the standard code:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Create a new component:&#xA;npm run new-component [TheNewComponentName]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 1: Wiring up form controls&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to test our &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component, we&#39;ll start by building a little playground. This will allow us to test our component throughout development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joy-of-react/toast-component/main/docs/playground.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image showing a textarea and set of radio buttons, along with a “Pop Toast!” radio button&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground.js&lt;/code&gt;, you&#39;ll find most of the markup you&#39;ll need, but there are two problems:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All of the inputs are &lt;em&gt;uncontrolled&lt;/em&gt;, meaning we can&#39;t easily access their values in React. We should use React state to drive all form controls.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We&#39;re only given a single radio button. We need one for each valid variant.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component should support 4 different variants:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;notice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;warning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;success&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;error&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This first exercise is meant to be a review of the concepts learned in Module 1 and Module 2.&lt;/strong&gt; So, it might be worth brushing up on some of those earlier lessons. In particular, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/02-state/11-bonus-cheatsheet&#34;&gt;Input Cheatsheet bonus lesson&lt;/a&gt; has some handy info about binding different types of form inputs!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The “Message” textarea should be driven by React state&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Using the data in the &lt;code&gt;VARIANT_OPTIONS&lt;/code&gt; array, render 4 radio buttons within the “Variant” row. They should all be part of the same group (so that only one can be selected at a time). They should also be driven by React state.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There should be no key warnings in the console.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 2: Live-editable toast preview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inside &lt;code&gt;src/components&lt;/code&gt;, you&#39;ll find a &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component. This component includes the basic DOM structure you&#39;ll need, but &lt;strong&gt;it&#39;s entirely static right now.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn&#39;t accept any props!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your mission in this exercise is to render the &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component within &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt; and allow the playground to customize the Toast using the state we set up in the previous exercise. We should also figure out a &#34;dismissal&#34; mechanism, so that the close button functions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what it should look like, when you&#39;ve solved this exercise:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joy-of-react/toast-component/main/docs/toast-exercise-2-demo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Screen recording showing how a demo Toast component can be edited using the playground&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now, you can import the &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component in &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt; and render it between the header and the controls:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-jsx&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;img alt=&#34;Cute toast mascot&#34; src=&#34;/toast.png&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Toast Playground&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;{/* Place a &amp;lt;Toast /&amp;gt; here! */}&#xA;&#xA;&amp;lt;div className={styles.controlsWrapper}&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;div className={styles.row}&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&#39;s up to you to come up with the best possible “Prop API” for this component!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you get stuck, you may wish to review the following lessons from the course:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/01-fundamentals/09.02-styling-exercises&#34;&gt;Styling in React, exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/04-component-design/07.01-slots-exercises&#34;&gt;Slots, exercises&lt;/a&gt; (Especially the stretch goal from the first exercise!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The toast component should show the message entered in the textarea, essentially acting as a “live preview”.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The toast&#39;s styling should be affected by the “variant” selected: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The colors can be set by specifying the appropriate class on the top-level &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. By default, it&#39;s set to &lt;code&gt;styles.notice&lt;/code&gt;, but you&#39;ll want to dynamically select the class based on the variant (eg. for a success toast, you&#39;ll want to apply &lt;code&gt;styles.success&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The icon can be selected from the &lt;code&gt;ICONS_BY_VARIANT&lt;/code&gt; object. Feel free to re-organize things however you wish!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The toast should be hidden by default, but can be shown by clicking the &#34;Pop Toast!” button.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The toast can be hidden by clicking the “×” button within the toast.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 3: Toast shelf&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the core defining characteristics of toast notifications is that they stack!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joy-of-react/toast-component/main/docs/poppin-toasts.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Several toasts popping up, one after another&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your mission in this exercise is to restructure things so that our &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt; allows us to create &lt;em&gt;multiple&lt;/em&gt; toasts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To help in your quest, you&#39;ll find a &lt;code&gt;ToastShelf&lt;/code&gt; component in this project. It will automatically apply the styles and animations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll need to replace the &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; live demo with this new &lt;code&gt;ToastShelf&lt;/code&gt; component, inside &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diff&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;img alt=&#34;Cute toast mascot&#34; src=&#34;/toast.png&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Toast Playground&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/header&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;- &amp;lt;Toast /&amp;gt;&#xA;+ &amp;lt;ToastShelf /&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;&amp;lt;div className={styles.controlsWrapper}&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;div className={styles.row}&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the end of this exercise, it should look like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joy-of-react/toast-component/main/docs/toast-exercise-3-demo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Screen recording showing toast messages popping up when “Pop Toast!” is clicked&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a very tricky exercise.&lt;/strong&gt; If you&#39;re not sure where to start / how to make this work, I share some &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/project-toast/03-hints&#34;&gt;hints on the course platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some lessons that might help, from the course:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/02-state/04.02-on-click-parable&#34;&gt;The onClick Parable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/02-state/07-key-generation&#34;&gt;Dynamic key generation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Instead of live-editing a single Toast instance, the playground should be used to push new toast messages onto a stack, rendered inside &lt;code&gt;ToastShelf&lt;/code&gt; and shown in the corner of the page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When “Pop Toast!” is clicked, the message/variant form controls should be reset to their default state (&lt;code&gt;message&lt;/code&gt; should be an empty string, &lt;code&gt;variant&lt;/code&gt; should be &#34;notice&#34;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clicking the “×” button inside the toast should remove that specific toast (but leave the rest untouched).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A proper &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;form&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag should be used in the &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt;. The toast should be created when submitting the form.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There should be no key warnings in the console!&lt;/strong&gt; Keys should be unique, and you should not use the index.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 4: Context&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As it stands, all of our state has been managed by &lt;code&gt;ToastPlayground&lt;/code&gt;. This works for our little demo app, but it wouldn&#39;t scale well in a real-world application!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we&#39;ll refactor our application to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/04-component-design/08.04-provider-component&#34;&gt;“Provider component” pattern&lt;/a&gt;. It will own all of the state related to the toasts state, and make it available to any child component who requires it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new component, &lt;code&gt;ToastProvider&lt;/code&gt;, that will serve as the “keeper” for all toast-related state. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To generate a new component, you can use the “new-component” script! Try tunning &lt;code&gt;npm run new-component ToastProvider&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Components that require the state should pull it from context with the &lt;code&gt;useContext&lt;/code&gt; hook, rather than passing through props.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;As we saw in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.joshwcomeau.com/joy-of-react/04-component-design/08.04-provider-component&#34;&gt;“Provider Components” lesson&lt;/a&gt;, we can also share &lt;em&gt;functions&lt;/em&gt; that allow consumers to alter the state. Consider making functions available that will create a new toast, or dismiss a specific toast.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is a “refactor” exercise. The user experience shouldn&#39;t change at all.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 5: Keyboard and screen reader support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our component so far works pretty well for sighted mouse users, but the experience isn&#39;t as great for everyone else.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we&#39;ll improve the experience for two different groups of people:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sighted keyboard users&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users who use a screen reader&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;5.1: Keyboard users&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s try something. Pretend that you don&#39;t have a mouse or trackpad. Using the keyboard alone, can you create and dismiss a toast message?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give it a shot now, in browser.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I do this?&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;ll use the “Tab” key to move focus between interactive elements. You can hold &#34;Shift&#34; and hit &#34;Tab&#34; to move backwards. In order to dismiss the toasts, you&#39;ll need to keep tabbing until your focus reaches the close button. Then, hit &#34;Enter&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;NOTE: If you&#39;re using Safari or Firefox on MacOS, you&#39;ll need to toggle a system setting to allow tabs to focus on buttons. Read more here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scottohara.me/blog/2014/10/03/link-tabbing-firefox-osx.html&#34;&gt;https://www.scottohara.me/blog/2014/10/03/link-tabbing-firefox-osx.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, what did you think?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found that this experience was pretty annoying. It was difficult to get the focus to reach the close buttons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we built a modal from scratch, we moved focus to within the modal, and trapped it there. This is a good idea for modals (which are urgent and blocking), but it&#39;s not the right approach for toasts (which are non-urgent and passive). Moving the user&#39;s focus is a pretty aggressive move, and not something we should do unless it&#39;s necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, here&#39;s what we should do:&lt;/strong&gt; Let&#39;s wire up the &#34;Escape&#34; key to automatically dismiss all toasts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That way, we aren&#39;t interrupting the user. They can read the messages in their own time, and hit &#34;Escape&#34; to dismiss them, without them needing to fuss with tab navigation at all.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hitting the &#34;Escape&#34; key should dismiss all toasts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You&#39;ll want to do this with a &lt;code&gt;useEffect&lt;/code&gt; hook, but it&#39;s up to you to decide which component should bear this responsibility.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;5.2: Screen reader users&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A screen reader is a piece of software that narrates the page. They&#39;re primarily used by folks who are blind or have low vision (though screen readers are also useful for folks with cognitive disabilities).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to use screen readers is a bit beyond the scope of this course, so I won&#39;t ask you to test things with a screen reader.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s imagine we reach out to an accessibility specialist, and they do us the favor of converting our HTML to be screen-reader-friendly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the changes we need to make:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-diff&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;ol&#xA;  class=&#34;ToastShelf_wrapper&#34;&#xA;+ role=&#34;region&#34;&#xA;+ aria-live=&#34;polite&#34;&#xA;+ aria-label=&#34;Notification&#34;&#xA;&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;li class=&#34;ToastShelf_toastWrapper&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;div class=&#34;Toast_toast Toast_error&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;      &amp;lt;div class=&#34;Toast_iconContainer&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;        &amp;lt;!-- Variant SVG icon --&amp;gt;&#xA;      &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#xA;      &amp;lt;p class=&#34;Toast_content&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;+       &amp;lt;div class=&#34;VisuallyHidden_wrapper&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;+         error -&#xA;+       &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#xA;        Something went wrong! Please contact customer support&#xA;      &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&#xA;      &amp;lt;button&#xA;        class=&#34;Toast_closeButton&#34;&#xA;+       aria-label=&#34;Dismiss message&#34;&#xA;+       aria-live=&#34;off&#34;&#xA;      &amp;gt;&#xA;        &amp;lt;!-- Close SVG icon --&amp;gt;&#xA;-       &amp;lt;div class=&#34;VisuallyHidden_wrapper&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;-         Dismiss message&#xA;-       &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#xA;      &amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&#xA;  &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE: This diff shows the &lt;em&gt;HTML&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Pretend that this is an HTML snippet given to you by an accessibility consultant who doesn&#39;t know React. Your job is to integrate their suggestions into our React components.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curious about these changes?&lt;/strong&gt; In the solution video, I&#39;ll share exactly why each of these changes are necessary. I realize it probably seems pretty arbitrary right now 😅 but all will be explained in the video.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; should have the specified role / aria tags&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The toast&#39;s content should be prefixed with the variant, using the &lt;code&gt;VisuallyHidden&lt;/code&gt; component. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt; The diff above shows an &lt;em&gt;error&lt;/em&gt; toast, but the prefix should be dynamic, based on the variant.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The “Dismiss message” content in the close button should be moved to an &lt;code&gt;aria-label&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;aria-live&lt;/code&gt; should also be set to &#34;off&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exercise 6: Extracting a custom hook&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whew! We&#39;ve done quite a bit with this lil’ &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; component!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the previous exercise, we added an “escape” keyboard shortcut, to dismiss all toasts in a single keystroke. This is a very common pattern, and it requires a surprising amount of boilerplate in React.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s build a &lt;strong&gt;custom reusable hook&lt;/strong&gt; that makes it easy to reuse this boilerplate to solve future problems.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are lots of different ways to tackle this, and there&#39;s no right or wrong answer, but here&#39;s one idea to get you started: what if we create a new custom hook called &lt;code&gt;useEscapeKey&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;useEscapeKey(() =&amp;gt; {&#xA;  // Code to dismiss all toasts&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an open-ended exercise.&lt;/strong&gt; Feel free to experiment with different APIs and see what works best for you!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We want to create a new generic hook that makes it easy to listen for &lt;code&gt;keydown&lt;/code&gt; events in React. It&#39;s up to you to come up with the best “consumer experience”.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Because this is a generic hook, it shouldn&#39;t be stored with the &lt;code&gt;ToastProvider&lt;/code&gt; component. Create a new &lt;code&gt;/src/hooks&lt;/code&gt; directory, and place your new hook in there.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;ToastProvider&lt;/code&gt; component should use this new hook.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure there are no ESLint warnings.&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In VSCode, ESLint warnings are shown as squiggly yellow underlines. You can view the warning by hovering over the underlined characters, or by opening the “Problems” tab (&lt;code&gt;⌘&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;M&lt;/code&gt;, or Ctrl + &lt;code&gt;Shift&lt;/code&gt; + &lt;code&gt;M&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RustMagazine/rustmagazine</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T01:32:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-12:/RustMagazine/rustmagazine</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/RustMagazine/rustmagazine" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A publication dedicated to the Rust programming language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Rust Magazine&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A publication dedicated to the Rust programming language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rustmagazine.org&#34;&gt;https://rustmagazine.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discord: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/DdwgBuReJe&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/DdwgBuReJe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Call for editors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RustMagazine/rustmagazine/issues/4&#34;&gt;#4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Call for articles&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RustMagazine/rustmagazine/issues/5&#34;&gt;#5&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute to magazine&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rustmagazine.org/contribution/&#34;&gt;https://rustmagazine.org/contribution/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>