<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-07T01:26:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mrrfv/open-android-backup</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T01:26:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-07:/mrrfv/open-android-backup</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Back up your device without vendor lock-ins, using insecure software or root. Supports encryption and compression out of the box. Works cross-platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Android Backup&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Formerly Linux Android Backup.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Android Backup is a tiny shell script &amp;amp; Flutter app that makes securely backing up Android devices easy, without vendor lock-ins or using closed-source software that could put your data at risk. It&#39;s based on ADB but doesn&#39;t use the deprecated &lt;code&gt;adb backup&lt;/code&gt; command. This project works on Windows, macOS and Linux.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/raw/c86602f9e5dbc501e0eacc43fe781c352998e712/.github/images/demo.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Demo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch is reserved for development. If you are looking for a download, please go to Releases or select a tag instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data backed up&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Restorable&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following data types can be automatically restored back to the device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Apps (.apk files of installed apps - app data not included - split APK support is experimental and can be found in the &lt;code&gt;split-apk-support&lt;/code&gt; branch)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Internal storage (pictures, downloads, videos, Signal backups if enabled, etc)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contacts (exported in vCard format)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;View-only&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following data types are only viewable by opening the backup archive with 7-Zip and cannot be restored to a device at the moment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SMS Messages (exported in CSV format - MMS attachments not saved)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Call Logs (exported into a text file)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These things are the majority of what most people would want to keep safe, but everybody has different expectations and requirements, so suggestions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically restores backed up data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Works on the 3 major operating systems, and supports &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; modern Android device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wireless backups that allow you to normally use your phone while it&#39;s being backed up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Backs up data not normally accessible through ADB using a native companion app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tiny - the script is 5KB in size, and the companion app is around 15 megabytes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Doesn&#39;t use proprietary formats - your data is safe even if you can&#39;t run the script. Simply open archives created by this script using 7-Zip.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Backups are encrypted along with their metadata.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally securely erases all unencrypted temporary files created by the script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All data is compressed using 7-Zip with maximum compression settings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Linux&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install p7zip, adb, curl, whiptail, pv and optionally secure-delete. If you&#39;re on Debian or Ubuntu, run this command: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt update; sudo apt install p7zip-full adb curl whiptail pv secure-delete&lt;/code&gt;. On Fedora enable the RPM Sphere repo using instructions from here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpmsphere.github.io/&#34;&gt;https://rpmsphere.github.io/&lt;/a&gt; then execute this command &lt;code&gt;sudo dnf install p7zip p7zip-plugins adb curl newt pv secure-delete&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; the Open Android Backup bundle, which contains the script and companion app in one package. You can also grab an experimental build (heavily discouraged) by clicking on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/archive/refs/heads/master.zip&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; or cloning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/debug/dev-options#enable&#34;&gt;developer options&lt;/a&gt; and USB debugging on your device, then run &lt;code&gt;backup.sh&lt;/code&gt; in a terminal.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;macOS&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; I&#39;ve recently switched to an AMD CPU+NVIDIA GPU rig, making it impossible for me to test this script on macOS without buying a Mac. Whilst there is nothing that could prevent this script from running on macOS, you are on your own and support will be very limited. (script last tested on Janurary 11th 2023)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install p7zip and adb using &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Tip: Run these commands in the built-in Terminal app (or iTerm if you have that installed).&#xA;# Install Homebrew if you haven&#39;t yet&#xA;/bin/bash -c &#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)&#34;&#xA;# If you already have Homebrew installed, just run these 2 commands:&#xA;brew install --cask android-platform-tools&#xA;brew install p7zip pv bash dialog&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the steps 2 and 3 from the install guide for Linux.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install#install&#34;&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)&lt;/a&gt;, a compatibility layer allowing you to run Linux applications (such as this one) on Windows. You only need to follow the &lt;code&gt;Install&lt;/code&gt; step.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; the Open Android Backup bundle, which contains the script and companion app in one package. You can also grab an experimental build (heavily discouraged) by clicking on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/archive/refs/heads/master.zip&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; or cloning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the repository in the file explorer. Right click on a file called &lt;code&gt;backup-windows.ps1&lt;/code&gt;, and click on &#34;Run with PowerShell&#34;. &lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: If you see an error after running the script, search for &#34;Developer Settings&#34; in the Settings app, and apply the settings related to PowerShell.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mrrfv/open-android-backup/master/.github/images/windows-powershell-developer-settings.png&#34; alt=&#34;Powershell Developer Settings&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just run &lt;code&gt;backup.sh&lt;/code&gt; and the script will walk you through the process. This section covers advanced usage of this program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Hooks&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Android Backup hooks allow you to effortlessly include your own backup steps, such as those that require root or work only on specific devices, without modifying the main script. You can upload these hooks to your own GitHub repositories and share them with others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Info for users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After writing or downloading a hook you&#39;d like to use, rename it to &lt;code&gt;hooks.sh&lt;/code&gt; and place in in the same directory as this script. Next, allow the use of hooks when the script asks you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Info for the security conscious&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using hooks that you don&#39;t trust is a security risk that we don&#39;t claim responsibility for! They have the same access over your phone and computer as Open Android Backup, making it possible for attackers to backdoor or wipe your devices. You must check the contents of the hook you&#39;d like to use before running the script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Android Backup doesn&#39;t automatically load hooks, and you have to allow the use of them before they are even touched by the program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Info for developers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guidelines&lt;/em&gt; - follow these to futureproof your backups.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Store the files your hook is backing up to &lt;code&gt;./backup-tmp/Hooks/&amp;lt;hook name&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt; and make sure to create the directory before doing anything.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the restore hook, check if your hook&#39;s directory exists in the extracted archive (backups are always extracted to &lt;code&gt;./backup-tmp&lt;/code&gt;), and don&#39;t do anything (after notifying the user) if it doesn&#39;t. This allows your hook to work with vanilla backup archives.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the after backup hook, you can get the backup archive path using &lt;code&gt;$backup_archive&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Useful functions and commands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cecho &amp;lt;text&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; lets you have yellow terminal output.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wait_for_enter&lt;/code&gt; waits for a keypress, and is compatible with unattended mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;get_file &amp;lt;phone_directory&amp;gt; &amp;lt;phone_file&amp;gt; &amp;lt;destination&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; lets you copy files off the device with the best reliability and speed, an alternative to &lt;code&gt;adb pull&lt;/code&gt;. Useful for backing up data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;adb push &amp;lt;file&amp;gt; &amp;lt;destination&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; lets you upload files to the device, useful when restoring your data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Required functions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need 3 functions in your hook for it to be properly initialized by the script:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;after_backup_hook&lt;/code&gt; - code that runs after a backup is complete, i.e. after everything gets compressed into a backup archive.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;backup_hook&lt;/code&gt; - code that runs after the internal storage, apps, contacts and other data have been copied off the device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;restore_hook&lt;/code&gt; - code that runs during the restore process, allowing you to restore the data you&#39;ve previously backed up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Automation/Unattended Backups&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that this project has minimal support for automation and very little support will be provided. In order to export contacts, you still need to have physical access to the device you&#39;re backing up as an &#34;unattended mode&#34; for the companion app hasn&#39;t been implemented yet.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 8 environment variables that control what the script does without user input:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;unattended_mode&lt;/code&gt; - Instead of waiting for a key press, sleeps for 5 seconds. Can be any value.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;selected_action&lt;/code&gt; - What the script should do when run. Possible values are &lt;code&gt;Backup&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Restore&lt;/code&gt; (case sensitive).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;archive_path&lt;/code&gt; - Path to the backup. Works for both Restore and Backup actions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;archive_password&lt;/code&gt; - Backup password.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;mode&lt;/code&gt; - How the script should connect to the device. Possible values are &lt;code&gt;Wired&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Wireless&lt;/code&gt; (case sensitive).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;export_method&lt;/code&gt; - The method Open Android Backup should use to export data from the device. Possible values are &lt;code&gt;tar&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;adb&lt;/code&gt; (case sensitive) - the former is fast &amp;amp; very stable but might not work on all devices, and the latter is widely compatible but has stability issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;use_hooks&lt;/code&gt; - Whether to use hooks or not. Possible values are &lt;code&gt;yes&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;no&lt;/code&gt; (case sensitive).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;data_erase_choice&lt;/code&gt; - Whether to securely erase temporary files or not. Possible values are &lt;code&gt;Fast&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Slow&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Extra Slow&lt;/code&gt; (case sensitive). The value of this variable is ignored if the command &lt;code&gt;srm&lt;/code&gt; isn&#39;t present on your computer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Enable unattended mode, backup the device over the wire to the working directory and use the password &#34;123&#34;&#xA;$ unattended_mode=&#34;yes&#34; selected_action=&#34;Backup&#34; mode=&#34;Wired&#34; export_method=&#34;tar&#34; archive_path=&#34;.&#34; archive_password=&#34;123&#34; ./backup.sh&#xA;# Keep unattended mode disabled, but automatically use the password &#34;456&#34;&#xA;$ archive_password=&#34;456&#34; ./backup.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Convenience Script&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to quickly run the latest version of Open Android Backup without having to follow the usage instructions, you can use the convenience script. It&#39;s a &lt;strong&gt;work in progress&lt;/strong&gt;, but it should work on most systems.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that there are &lt;strong&gt;security risks&lt;/strong&gt; associated with running scripts from the internet. It&#39;s recommended that you review the script before running it. If you don&#39;t trust me or Cloudflare, you can always download the script and run it manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Linux or macOS&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run the following command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;curl -fsSL get.openandroidbackup.me | bash&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run the following command in PowerShell:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;irm https://get.openandroidbackup.me/ | iex&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The same path is used because the server automatically detects your operating system based on the user agent and serves the correct script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building companion app&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You don&#39;t need to do this, as the precompiled companion app is automatically downloaded at runtime from GitHub Releases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install Flutter and Android Studio.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;flutter doctor&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;flutter doctor --android-licenses&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;cd companion_app/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;flutter build apk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TODO&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRs are appreciated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Migrate the companion app to the Storage Access Framework API for forward compatibility (waiting for Flutter packages providing this functionality to become stable).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve the error handling and design of the mobile app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Export the calendar and other data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>arncv/Intima</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T01:26:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-07:/arncv/Intima</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/arncv/Intima" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bridging the Gap in Sexual Education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Intima: Bridging the Gap in Sexual Education&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/arncv/Intima.svg?style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;Contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/network/members&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/arncv/Intima.svg?style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;Forks&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/stargazers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/arncv/Intima.svg?style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;Stargazers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/arncv/Intima.svg?style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;Issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/arncv/Intima.svg?style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;MIT License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://linkedin.com/in/arnvgl&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/-LinkedIn-black.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;logo=linkedin&amp;amp;colorB=555&#34; alt=&#34;LinkedIn&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- PROJECT LOGO --&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/arncv/Intima/main/public/assets/img/logo-real.png&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;240&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.intima.tv/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intima »&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; Bridging the Gap in Sexual Education &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QsxzGdG3how&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demo Video Link! »&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://devpost.com/software/intima&#34;&gt;Devpost Link&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/issues&#34;&gt;Report Bug&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intima is a comprehensive platform designed to address the need for proper sex education in India. The platform aims to tackle the challenges associated with the taboo nature of sexual health discussions by providing accurate and reliable information on safe sex practices, consent, sexually transmitted diseases, and more. With the integration of ChatGPT and an interactive forum, users can access information and seek answers to their questions without fear of judgment or embarrassment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Problem&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite being a natural aspect of life, sex remains a taboo topic in India. The absence of adequate sex education in schools and homes has led to issues such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Polarization between genders&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Objectification of women&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Misunderstanding of sexual health&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unrealistic expectations about sex&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Misinformation and myths about sex&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Young people often resort to unreliable sources like pornography, leading to misconceptions and unhealthy sexual practices. This situation hinders the development of healthy relationships and informed sexual behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intima is an all-in-one platform for sexual education, created to bridge the gap in sex education in India. The platform offers a comprehensive and inclusive space for adolescents and young adults to access accurate information on sex, relationships, and related topics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intima covers essential topics such as safe sex practices, contraception, emergency contraception, consent, legal implications of sexual assault, sexually transmitted diseases (STDs), and more. It also provides information on accessing STI testing and treatment services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the wealth of information, Intima features an interactive forum where users can ask questions and receive answers from experts in the field. This forum fosters open communication and allows users to seek guidance on sensitive topics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To further enhance user experience, Intima integrates ChatGPT, an AI-powered chatbot that provides personalized support and answers to questions. Available 24/7, ChatGPT ensures that users have access to reliable information whenever they need it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive sexual education platform&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Accurate information on safe sex practices, consent, STDs, and more&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Interactive forum for expert-guided discussions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integration of ChatGPT for personalized support and answers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;24/7 availability for easy access to information&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Make Contribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code Of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click Here &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/Intima/raw/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;CODE_OF_CONDUCT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- LICENSE --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Distributed under the MIT License. See &lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/arncv/Intima/main/#readme-top&#34;&gt;back to top&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Our ♥️ Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arncv/intima/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=arncv/intima&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ACM-CIET/ACM_Hacking-Wizards</title>
    <updated>2023-10-07T01:26:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-07:/ACM-CIET/ACM_Hacking-Wizards</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ACM-CIET/ACM_Hacking-Wizards" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contribute to this begineer friendly open source repository and be an ACM Hacking Wizard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ACM-CIET&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributions to repository are encouraged. Here&#39;s how you can get started:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fork the Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: Click on the &#34;Fork&#34; button at the top-right corner of this repository to create your own fork.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone Your Fork&lt;/strong&gt;: Clone your fork to your local machine using the following command (replace &lt;code&gt;[your-username]&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/[your-username]/HacktoberFest2023.git&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add your details in src/contributors/main.json&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure not to delete or change any other thing, pull requests with conflicts won&#39;t be merged. Add your details as:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;{&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; &#34;githubUsername&#34;:&#34;your github_username&#34;,&#xA; &#34;role&#34;:&#34;your role&#34;,&#xA; &#34;school&#34;:&#34;your school&#34;,&#xA; &#34;twitter&#34;:&#34;your twitter&#34;,&#xA; &#34;insta&#34;:&#34;your insta&#34;,&#xA; &#34;github&#34;:&#34;your github&#34;,&#xA; &#34;linkedin&#34;:&#34;your linkedin&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h1&gt;}&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;and be sure to add commas before this js object and don&#39;t add any comma&#39;s after this object&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit your changes&lt;/strong&gt;: Commit your changes with successfull and precise message&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Pull Request&lt;/strong&gt;: Then create a Pull Request with precise information and wait patiently for it to get merged.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add extra feature&lt;/strong&gt;: Feel free to raise issues or solve existing one to recieve special goodies from us.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Have fun in this exciting open source space make sure to follow us on social and tag us on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;© ACM - CIET&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maintained by Aryainguz [https://github.com/Aryainguz]&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>