<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-06T01:25:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CodegirlSchool/pomodoro-timer</title>
    <updated>2024-03-06T01:25:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-06:/CodegirlSchool/pomodoro-timer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CodegirlSchool/pomodoro-timer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Домашнее задание к модулю &#34;Продвинутая работа с функциями&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Домашнее задание к модулю &#34;Продвинутая работа с функциями&#34;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Слышала о таймере Pomodoro 🍅? А, может, даже пользовалась? Если нет, можешь почитать о нем &lt;a href=&#34;https://lifehacker.ru/special/pomodoro/&#34;&gt;тут&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;В качестве домашнего задания тебе предстоит разработать нечто подобное. Верстка уже готова, но если хочешь, можешь поменять дизайн на свой вкус.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Задание разделено на два уровня сложности. Первый обязателен для выполнения, второй — по желанию.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Базовый уровень&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Реализуй таймер обратного отсчета от 25 минут до нуля. Можешь сделать его ускоренным.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Требования:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;при клике на кнопку &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt; текст на ней меняется на &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;при клике на &lt;strong&gt;stop&lt;/strong&gt; таймер останавливается, но &lt;strong&gt;не сбрасывается&lt;/strong&gt;, текст на кнопке снова меняется на &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;если снова кликнуть на кнопку, то отсчет возобновится со значения, на котором остановились&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;когда таймер дойдет до нуля, он должен сброситься в начальное состояние: &lt;strong&gt;25:00&lt;/strong&gt; и текст на кнопке снова &lt;strong&gt;start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Демо:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CodegirlSchool/pomodoro-timer/main/assets/basic.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Basic level&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Продвинутый уровень&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;В дополнение к базовому уровню добавится режим отдыха &lt;strong&gt;break&lt;/strong&gt; и кнопка сброса отсчета (рядом с кнопкой stop / start)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Требования:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;при переключении между режимами меняется время: &lt;strong&gt;25:00&lt;/strong&gt; для pomodoro и &lt;strong&gt;05:00&lt;/strong&gt; для break&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;при нажатии на кнопку сброса должно устанавливаться &lt;strong&gt;начальное значение&lt;/strong&gt; таймера в зависимости от выбранного режима&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;переключение между режимами и кнопка сброса &lt;strong&gt;останавливают&lt;/strong&gt; таймер (то есть отсчет должен заморозиться), даже если действие выполнено во время работы таймера&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Демо:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CodegirlSchool/pomodoro-timer/main/assets/advanced.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Advanced level&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jjoao/h5i</title>
    <updated>2024-03-06T01:25:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-06:/jjoao/h5i</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jjoao/h5i" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;History after 5 images&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;h5i&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;History after 5 images&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(for learning purposes and intertainment)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optional Keyword adding.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See example for a Christmas story after 2 images&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kaloslazo/Habu</title>
    <updated>2024-03-06T01:25:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-06:/kaloslazo/Habu</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kaloslazo/Habu" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🐨 Habu it&#39;s a minimalistic startpage made with the essence of neovim dashboard with the catppuccin mocha palette. Fully customizable and easy to setup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kaloslazo/Habu/main/docs/videos/bannerHabu.gif&#34; alt=&#34;banner habu&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experience the minimalist design of Neovim&#39;s based dashboard &amp;amp; Catppuccin Mocha palette in your browser with Habu. Simple to set up and fully customizable. 🚀 Take a look at this productive space with this &lt;a href=&#34;https://habu.netlify.app/&#34;&gt;demo page&lt;/a&gt;, currently hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/&#34;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;⚙️ Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re planning to improve or delete features you must look at the following guide that explains you how to get started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install packages, this starter page was created using Tailwindcss and custom plugins for catppuccin palette, so you must install it, do &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After dependencies are installed, you can run the script defined in the package.json as &lt;code&gt;habu:build_tailwind&lt;/code&gt;. This will refresh in real times your changes using a web server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re done, just upload the &lt;code&gt;app&lt;/code&gt; folder to your hosting or create a image container.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;⚠️ &lt;em&gt;For custom data you must modify the json files at app/db with your own information. The application made a get request to Open-Meteo, a free weather API, thanks to the team for the free access!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🐋 Docker Selfhost&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selfhosted means that you&#39;re gonna run this website in your own computer, no external server needed. To start you must check the following steps. We&#39;re gonna use docker. By this method we will not have cors problems.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install docker, check de &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the build for the container (.dockerfile) with the following command &lt;code&gt;docker build -t app .&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After image it&#39;s created map a port for running as background with &lt;code&gt;docker run -d -p 8080:80 --restart=always app&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you followed the steps your site must be running at &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:8080/&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;em&gt;if you change the port in the step [3] change 8080 for your desired port&lt;/em&gt;). If in the process you got an error or something work unexpected, please submit a PR.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;⚠️ &lt;em&gt;If problems of daemon appears, please run as a superuser. If you&#39;re using firefox maybe this &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/es/firefox/addon/custom-new-tab-page/&#34;&gt;extension&lt;/a&gt; will interest you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📄 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Released under &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kaloslazo/Habu/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; License. Developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com/kaloslazo&#34;&gt;Kalos Lazo&lt;/a&gt; from Perú. If you&#39;re interested in contributing, feel free to fork this repository, make your changes and submit a pull request!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Under the terms of this license you are permitted to: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modify&lt;/strong&gt;: You can alter, transform, or build upon this work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reuse&lt;/strong&gt;: You can use the content for personal or commercial purposes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;On the other hand, under this license you are required to: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include the original license&lt;/strong&gt;: A copy of the original MIT license must be included with any substantial portions of this software.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attribute the work&lt;/strong&gt;: If you use parts of this source code, an acknowledgment in the form of a link back to this repository is appreciated but not required.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>