<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haskell Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-01T02:02:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of Haskell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>iburzynski/haskell-dojo</title>
    <updated>2023-11-01T02:02:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-01:/iburzynski/haskell-dojo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/iburzynski/haskell-dojo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Guided projects for EMURGO Academy&#39;s Cardano-Haskell Developer Open Course&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;🏯 &lt;strong&gt;Haskell Dojo&lt;/strong&gt; 🥷&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Haskell Dojo can be set up in several ways, depending on your learning goals:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iburzynski/haskell-dojo/main/#with-jambhala-cardano-development-suite&#34;&gt;With Jambhala Cardano Development Suite&lt;/a&gt; -- &lt;em&gt;recommended for Cardano developers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iburzynski/haskell-dojo/main/#with-gitpod&#34;&gt;With Gitpod&lt;/a&gt; (cloud-based browser editing) -- &lt;em&gt;recommended for sampling Haskell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iburzynski/haskell-dojo/main/#with-a-local-haskell-installation&#34;&gt;With a local Haskell installation&lt;/a&gt; (GHCup) -- &lt;em&gt;recommended for non-Cardano developers learning Haskell long-term&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Jambhala Cardano Development Suite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository can be used as an add-on to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iburzynski/jambhala&#34;&gt;Jambhala Cardano Development Suite&lt;/a&gt;. This allows aspiring Cardano developers to complete this Haskell course within the same fully pre-configured environment they&#39;ll use to learn &lt;code&gt;cardano-cli&lt;/code&gt; and Plutus afterward.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you intend to use Jambhala for learning Cardano development, follow these steps to get started with Haskell Dojo in Jambhala:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork this repository. &#xA;  &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; keep the name &lt;code&gt;haskell-dojo&lt;/code&gt; as the name/URL slug for your fork: using this name is required for integration with Jambhala.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iburzynski/jambhala&#34;&gt;Install Jambhala&lt;/a&gt; by following the instructions in the official README.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After completing the installation, navigate to the &lt;code&gt;jambhala&lt;/code&gt; directory in your terminal and run &lt;code&gt;jcode&lt;/code&gt; to open Jambhala&#39;s integrated VS Codium editor:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cd jambhala&#xA;jcode&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file in the Jambhala root directory and add your Github username to the &lt;code&gt;GITHUB_ID&lt;/code&gt; variable. I.e.:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# jambhala/.env&#xA;&#xA;GITHUB_ID=&#34;iburzynski&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;refresh&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal session. Your forked &lt;code&gt;haskell-dojo&lt;/code&gt; should now automatically clone itself into the &lt;code&gt;jambhala&lt;/code&gt; directory (and will be ignored by &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;). Exit the editor and reopen it in the &lt;code&gt;haskell-dojo&lt;/code&gt; directory by running &lt;code&gt;jcode haskell-dojo&lt;/code&gt; (use this same command from the &lt;code&gt;jambhala&lt;/code&gt; directory in your terminal each time to ensure proper functioning).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With Gitpod&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a preconfigured Gitpod Haskell development environment, allowing you to start coding in Haskell with zero installation using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gitpod.io/&#34;&gt;Gitpod&lt;/a&gt; and a browser-based version of VS Code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re looking to dive into Haskell quickly and aren&#39;t ready to commit to a local installation, follow these steps to get started with Gitpod:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork this repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy the link to your new repository and prefix it with &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitpod.io/#&#34;&gt;https://gitpod.io/#&lt;/a&gt;&#34; in your browser&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;code&gt;Continue with GitHub&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Authorize gitpod-io&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait for the environment to build. This can take a while the first time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &#34;VS Code Browser&#34; as your editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; you may need to enable additional permissions to allow GitPod to push changes to your forked repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitpod.io&#34;&gt;https://gitpod.io&lt;/a&gt; (login with your GitHub account if not already logged in)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Click your user avatar image in the top right and select &lt;code&gt;User Settings&lt;/code&gt; from the dropdown menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Git Providers&lt;/code&gt; from the left menu, find &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt; and click the three dots to the right, then &lt;code&gt;Edit Permissions&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Check the box next to &lt;code&gt;public_repo&lt;/code&gt; and click &lt;code&gt;Update Permissions&lt;/code&gt;. You should now be able to push committed changes to your repository from the GitPod VS Code editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With a Local Haskell Installation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository can also be used with a local Haskell toolchain installation through &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/ghcup/&#34;&gt;GHCup&lt;/a&gt; and either VS Codium or VS Code. This method may not be ideal for new Haskellers, as correct configuration to get Haskell to work properly in VS Code can be tricky and delay the process of actually learning Haskell. Having a system-wide Haskell installation can also occasionally cause conflicts with Haskell Nix development environments, such as used by Jambhala. For these reasons it is recommended to use the Jambhala suite (if you&#39;re learning Haskell for Cardano development) or Gitpod instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you do choose to install Haskell globally on your machine, be sure to do so using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/ghcup/&#34;&gt;GHCup&lt;/a&gt;, which is the canonical installation method for Haskell at the time of writing, and has good synergy with VS Codium/Code. Follow the official installation process at the link above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have Haskell installed locally and don&#39;t intend to use Jambhala later, the Haskell Dojo code should compile and run with &lt;code&gt;cabal&lt;/code&gt; for most versions of GHC. After forking and cloning Haskell Dojo on your system, navigate to the directory in your terminal and run &lt;code&gt;cabal run&lt;/code&gt; to compile and run the program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For IDE support in VS Codium/Code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must have Haskell Language Server installed. If you didn&#39;t choose to install this when you installed GHCup, you can do so in the &lt;code&gt;ghcup tui&lt;/code&gt; interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must have the Haskell VS Code extension installed. &#xA;  &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; this should be installed after GHCUp to prevent duplicate Haskell binaries being created on your system, which can break functionality in VS Codium/Code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completing the Course&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Complete the 8 assignments in the &lt;code&gt;assignments&lt;/code&gt; directory sequentially, filling in the required Haskell code in the designated &lt;code&gt;.hs&lt;/code&gt; file mentioned at the top of each markdown file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Try opening the markdown files on Github for better viewing. Alternatively you can right-click the markdown files and click &lt;code&gt;Open preview&lt;/code&gt; to view them in your VS Codium/Code editor (then open a split window).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; be sure to stage, commit, and push the changes you make to your fork (using the &lt;code&gt;Source Control&lt;/code&gt; tab in VS Codium/Code, or a source control method of your choice). &lt;strong&gt;If you are using Gitpod&lt;/strong&gt; this is especially important, as any changes you make will be lost when you close your browser session unless they are pushed to your fork!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the Sandbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Haskell Dojo provides a special empty file called &lt;code&gt;Sandbox.hs&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;src/&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use this file as a scratchpad to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;practice/experiment with writing arbitrary Haskell code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;test this practice code in GHCi&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The provided &lt;code&gt;sbox&lt;/code&gt; script launches GHCi with the &lt;code&gt;Sandbox&lt;/code&gt; module open:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;./sbox&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use this GHCi session to experiment and test simple code directly in the interpreter, or run any code you&#39;ve saved in &lt;code&gt;src/Sandbox.hs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;:r&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;:reload&lt;/code&gt;) command in GHCi to reload the &lt;code&gt;Sandbox&lt;/code&gt; contents after making changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Sandbox.hs&lt;/code&gt; is a module of our larger Cabal project, which means we can use it to test functions from libraries our project is using besides the Haskell standard library (&lt;code&gt;base&lt;/code&gt;), such as &lt;code&gt;random&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;directory&lt;/code&gt;. This isn&#39;t possible in an ordinary GHCi session. However, this also means &lt;code&gt;Sandbox.hs&lt;/code&gt; must always compile with no errors before we can run any other code inside the project. Correct or comment out any erroneous code in this file as needed to ensure successful compilation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>simonmichael/hledger</title>
    <updated>2023-11-01T02:02:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-01:/simonmichael/hledger</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/simonmichael/hledger" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Robust, fast, intuitive plain text accounting tool with CLI, TUI and web interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;hledger&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Robust, intuitive plain text accounting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-GPLv3+-brightgreen.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;license&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackage.haskell.org/package/hledger&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/hackage/v/hledger.svg?label=hackage&amp;amp;colorB=green&#34; alt=&#34;on hackage&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://repology.org/metapackage/hledger&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://repology.org/badge/version-for-repo/stackage_nighly/hledger.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://repology.org/metapackage/hledger&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://repology.org/badge/version-for-repo/stackage_lts/hledger.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://bugs.hledger.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/simonmichael/hledger.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;github issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome! This a brief intro to hledger. For a more detailed version, see the home page: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org&#34;&gt;https://hledger.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;hledger is lightweight, cross platform, multi-currency, double-entry accounting software. It lets you track money, investments, cryptocurrencies, invoices, time, inventory and more, in a safe, future-proof plain text data format with full version control and privacy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;hledger aims to help both computer experts and regular folks gain clarity in their finances and time management. Though the UIs are basic, hledger can model any accounting situation and provide precise, clear reports. It is reliable, quick, and backed by the highly supportive &lt;a href=&#34;https://plaintextaccounting.org&#34;&gt;Plain Text Accounting&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem. Using it is an excellent way to learn double entry accounting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compared to &lt;a href=&#34;https://plaintextaccounting.org/#software&#34;&gt;other PTA apps&lt;/a&gt;, hledger is actively maintained, with regular releases, and a strong focus on being easy to use and practical for everyday accounting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;More features:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Installs easily on unix, mac or windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Complete, built-in documentation in multiple formats, beginner videos, tutorials etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Multiple UIs: command-line, terminal, web, mobile, editors/IDEs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Good at importing and exporting CSV; also outputs text/HTML/JSON/SQL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A robust, general, well-specified multi-currency accounting engine&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fast, analysing 25k transactions per second on a macbook air m1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Accurate to 255 decimal places&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports your preferred account names, currencies, number formats&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Inspired by and partly compatible with Ledger CLI; interconvertible with Beancount&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scriptable by CLI, HTTP or API, with plenty of examples&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clean Haskell codebase, continually improved since 2007, with $100 regression bounties&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Free software licensed under GPLv3+.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I use hledger to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;track income and spending, sometimes with budgets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;see time reports by day/week/month/project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;track reimbursables, invoices and payments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;predict cashflow and account balances&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;get accurate numbers for tax filing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;research past events&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s an example of the journal file format:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-journal&#34;&gt;2022-01-01 opening balances as of this date&#xA;    assets&lt;span&gt;🏦&lt;/span&gt;checking                $1000&#xA;    assets&lt;span&gt;🏦&lt;/span&gt;savings                 $2000&#xA;    assets:cash                          $100&#xA;    liabilities:creditcard               $-50&#xA;    equity:opening/closing balances&#xA;&#xA;2022-01-15 market&#xA;    expenses:food             $50&#xA;    assets:cash              $-50&#xA;&#xA;2022-02-01 GOODWORKS CORP&#xA;    assets&lt;span&gt;🏦&lt;/span&gt;checking           $1000&#xA;    income:salary                 $-1000&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and some simple reports:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cli&#34;&gt;$ hledger bs&#xA;Balance Sheet 2022-02-15&#xA;&#xA;                        || 2022-02-15 &#xA;========================++============&#xA; Assets                 ||            &#xA;------------------------++------------&#xA; assets&lt;span&gt;🏦&lt;/span&gt;checking   ||      $2000 &#xA; assets&lt;span&gt;🏦&lt;/span&gt;savings    ||      $2000 &#xA; assets:cash            ||        $50 &#xA;------------------------++------------&#xA;                        ||      $4050 &#xA;========================++============&#xA; Liabilities            ||            &#xA;------------------------++------------&#xA; liabilities:creditcard ||        $50 &#xA;------------------------++------------&#xA;                        ||        $50 &#xA;========================++============&#xA; Net:                   ||      $4000 &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cli&#34;&gt;$ hledger is --monthly                                            &#xA;Income Statement 2022-01-01..2022-02-28                                               &#xA;                                                                                      &#xA;               ||  Jan    Feb                                                         &#xA;===============++=============                                                        &#xA; Revenues      ||                                                                     &#xA;---------------++-------------                                                        &#xA; income:salary ||    0  $1000                                                         &#xA;---------------++-------------                                                        &#xA;               ||    0  $1000                                                         &#xA;===============++=============                                                        &#xA; Expenses      ||                                                                     &#xA;---------------++-------------                                                        &#xA; expenses:food ||  $50      0                                                         &#xA;---------------++-------------                                                        &#xA;               ||  $50      0                                                         &#xA;===============++=============                                                        &#xA; Net:          || $-50  $1000                                                         &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;More examples and screenshots: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org/#how-to-get-started&#34;&gt;https://hledger.org/#how-to-get-started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Funding&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;hledger is brought to you by &lt;a href=&#34;http://joyful.com&#34;&gt;Simon Michael&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/simonmichael/hledger/master/CREDITS.md&#34;&gt;140+ contributors&lt;/a&gt;, and the generous financial sponsors below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After enjoying some personal or organisational success with hledger, you might want to become one of them, to help support this work. It&#39;s easy! Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://hledger.org/sponsor.html&#34;&gt;https://hledger.org/sponsor.html&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- keep synced with sponsor.md: --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Organisational sponsors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/0/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/0/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/1/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/1/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/2/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/2/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/3/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/3/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/4/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/4/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/5/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/5/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/6/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/6/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/7/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/7/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/8/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/8/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/9/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/9/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/10/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/10/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/11/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/11/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/12/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/12/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/13/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/13/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/14/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/14/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/15/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/15/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/16/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/16/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/17/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/17/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/18/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/18/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/19/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/organization/19/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Individual sponsors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/0/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/0/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/1/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/1/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/2/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/2/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/3/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/3/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/4/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/4/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/5/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/5/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/6/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/6/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/7/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/7/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/8/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/8/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/9/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/9/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/10/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/10/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/11/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/11/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/12/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/12/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/13/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/13/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/14/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/14/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/15/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/15/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/16/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/16/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/17/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/17/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/18/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/18/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/19/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/19/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/20/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/20/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/21/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/21/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/22/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/22/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/23/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/23/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/24/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/24/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/25/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/25/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/26/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/26/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/27/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/27/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/28/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/28/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/29/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/29/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/30/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/30/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/31/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/31/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/32/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/32/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/33/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/33/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/34/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/34/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/35/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/35/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/36/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/36/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/37/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/37/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/38/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/38/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/39/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/hledger/individual/39/avatar.svg?avatarHeight=100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your logo/avatar needs to be added, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:webmaster@hledger.org&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kajgo/befunge-haskell</title>
    <updated>2023-11-01T02:02:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-01:/kajgo/befunge-haskell</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kajgo/befunge-haskell" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Haskell implementation of the Befunge esoteric programming language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>