<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PHP Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-12T01:34:46Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PHP in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/msphpsql</title>
    <updated>2023-10-12T01:34:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-12:/microsoft/msphpsql</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Drivers for PHP for SQL Server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Drivers for PHP for Microsoft SQL Server&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Microsoft Drivers for PHP for Microsoft SQL Server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/microsoft-php-driver-for-sql-server&#34;&gt;Microsoft Drivers for PHP for Microsoft SQL Server&lt;/a&gt; are PHP extensions that allow for the reading and writing of SQL Server data from within PHP scripts. The SQLSRV extension provides a procedural interface while the PDO_SQLSRV extension implements PHP Data Objects (PDO) for accessing data in all editions of SQL Server 2012 and later (including Azure SQL DB). These drivers rely on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/odbc/microsoft-odbc-driver-for-sql-server&#34;&gt;Microsoft ODBC Driver for SQL Server&lt;/a&gt; to handle the low-level communication with SQL Server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This release contains the SQLSRV and PDO_SQLSRV drivers for PHP 8.0+ with improvements on both drivers and some limitations. Upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/releases&#34;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt; will contain additional functionalities, bug fixes, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Take our survey&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to participate in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/wiki/Survey-Results&#34;&gt;sentiment survey&lt;/a&gt;. You can continue to help us improve by letting us know how we are doing and how you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://php.net&#34;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/mssqlphpsurvey&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to start the PHP survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Status of Most Recent Builds&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Azure Pipelines (Linux)&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;AppVeyor (Windows)&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Coverage (Windows)&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.azure.com/sqlclientdrivers-ci/msphpsql/_build/latest?definitionId=6&amp;amp;branchName=dev&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dev.azure.com/sqlclientdrivers-ci/msphpsql/_apis/build/status/Microsoft.msphpsql?branchName=dev&#34; alt=&#34;az-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/msphpsql/msphpsql/branch/dev&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/vo4rfei6lxlamrnc?svg=true&#34; alt=&#34;av-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/microsoft/msphpsql&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/microsoft/msphpsql/branch/dev/graph/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Codecov&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/getting-started-with-the-php-sql-driver&#34;&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Announcements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/SQL-Server/bg-p/SQLServer/label-name/SQLServerDrivers&#34;&gt;SQL Server Drivers&lt;/a&gt; for announcements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For full details on the system requirements for the drivers, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/system-requirements-for-the-php-sql-driver&#34;&gt;system requirements&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft Docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the client machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;8.0.x, 8.1.x, 8.2.x&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/odbc/microsoft-odbc-driver-for-sql-server&#34;&gt;Microsoft ODBC Driver 18, 17 or 13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If using a Web server such as Internet Information Services (IIS) or Apache, it must be configured to run PHP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the server side, Microsoft SQL Server 2012 and above on Windows are supported, as are Microsoft SQL Server 2016 and above on Linux.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building and Installing the Drivers on Windows&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The drivers are distributed as pre-compiled extensions for PHP found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/releases&#34;&gt;releases page&lt;/a&gt;. They are available in thread-safe and non-thread-safe versions, and in 32-bit (Windows only) and 64-bit versions. The source code for the drivers is also available, and you can compile them as thread safe or non-thread-safe versions. The thread safety configuration of your web server will determine which version you need.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you choose to build the drivers, you must be able to build PHP 8.* without including these extensions. For help building PHP on Windows, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.php.net/internals/windows/stepbystepbuild_sdk_2&#34;&gt;official PHP website&lt;/a&gt;. For details on compiling the drivers, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/raw/master/buildscripts/README.md&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; -- an example buildscript is provided, but you can also compile the drivers manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To load the drivers, make sure that the driver is in your PHP extension directory and enable it in your PHP installation&#39;s php.ini file by adding &lt;code&gt;extension=php_sqlsrv.dll&lt;/code&gt; and/or &lt;code&gt;extension=php_pdo_sqlsrv.dll&lt;/code&gt; to the ini file. If necessary, specify the extension directory using &lt;code&gt;extension_dir&lt;/code&gt;, for example: &lt;code&gt;extension_dir = &#34;C:\PHP\ext&#34;&lt;/code&gt;. Note that the precompiled binaries have different names -- substitute accordingly in php.ini. For more details on loading the drivers, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/loading-the-php-sql-driver&#34;&gt;Loading the PHP SQL Driver&lt;/a&gt; on Microsoft Docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if running PHP in a Web server, restart the Web server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install (UNIX)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For full instructions on installing the drivers on all supported Unix platforms, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/installation-tutorial-linux-mac&#34;&gt;the installation instructions on Microsoft Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sample Code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For PHP code samples, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/msphpsql/tree/master/sample&#34;&gt;sample&lt;/a&gt; folder or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/code-samples-for-php-sql-driver&#34;&gt;code samples on Microsoft Docs&lt;/a&gt;. For information on how to use the driver, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/microsoft-php-driver-for-sql-server&#34;&gt;Microsoft Drivers for PHP for Microsoft SQL Server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations and Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; for the latest limitations and known issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version number&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The version numbers of the PHP drivers follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://semver.org/&#34;&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given a version number MAJOR.MINOR.PATCH,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MAJOR version is incremented when an incompatible API change is made,&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MINOR version is incremented when functionality is added in a backwards-compatible manner, and&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PATCH version is incremented when backwards-compatible bug fixes are made.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The version number may have trailing pre-release version identifiers to indicate the stability and/or build metadata.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pre-release version is denoted by a hyphen followed by &lt;code&gt;beta&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;RC&lt;/code&gt; followed by a number. Production quality releases do not contain the pre-release version. &lt;code&gt;beta&lt;/code&gt; has lower precedence than &lt;code&gt;RC&lt;/code&gt;. Note that the PECL package version numbers do not have the hyphen before the pre-release version, owing to restrictions in PECL. An example of a PECL package version is &lt;code&gt;5.9.0beta2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build metadata may be denoted by a plus sign followed by a number of digits, such as &lt;code&gt;5.9.0-beta2+13930&lt;/code&gt;. Build metadata does not affect the precedence order.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Expand SQL Server feature support (example: Azure Active Directory, Always Encrypted, etc.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add more verification/fundamental tests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve performance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Guidelines for Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We appreciate you taking the time to test the driver, provide feedback and report any issues. It would be extremely helpful if you:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/msphpsql/wiki/FAQ&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; for common problems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Report each issue as a new issue (but check first if it&#39;s already been reported)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please address the questions in the new issue template and provide scripts, table schema, and/or any details that may help reproduce the problem(s)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Can we get dates for any of the Future Plans listed above?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; At this time, Microsoft is not able to announce dates. We are working hard to release future versions of the driver and will share future plans as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What&#39;s next?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; We will continue working on our future plans and releasing previews of upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/releases&#34;&gt;releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Is Microsoft taking pull requests for this project?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes. Please submit pull requests to the &lt;strong&gt;dev&lt;/strong&gt; branch, not the &lt;strong&gt;master&lt;/strong&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Drivers for PHP for SQL Server are licensed under the MIT license. See the LICENSE file for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct. For more information see the Code of Conduct FAQ or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sql/connect/php/microsoft-php-driver-for-sql-server&#34;&gt;Microsoft Docs Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SQL Server Drivers&lt;/strong&gt;: Please browse the articles for announcements of various &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/SQL-Server/bg-p/SQLServer/label-name/SQLServerDrivers&#34;&gt;SQL Server Drivers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Known Issues&lt;/strong&gt;: Please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql&#34;&gt;project on Github&lt;/a&gt; to view outstanding &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/msphpsql/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and report new ones.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>