<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PHP Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-04T01:45:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PHP in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Not-Quite-RARBG/main</title>
    <updated>2023-06-04T01:45:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-04:/Not-Quite-RARBG/main</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Not-Quite-RARBG/main" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Not Quite RARBG&#39;s main website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Not Quite RARBG&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Not-Quite-RARBG/main/main/NQ-RARBG.png&#34; alt=&#34;Not Quite RARBG&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuing the legacy of the original RARBG, Not Quite RARBG aims to provide a comprehensive collection of torrents for movies, TV shows, anime, software, and games, following the unfortunate shutdown of the original site. Our goal is to offer the same level of quality and variety that made RARBG the greatest of all time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Active Domains&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nq-rarbg.to/&#34;&gt;nq-rarbg.to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nq-rarbg.slidemovies.org/&#34;&gt;nq-rarbg.slidemovies.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to contribute to Not Quite RARBG, please refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Not-Quite-RARBG/main/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guide&lt;/a&gt; for detailed instructions. Your help will be greatly appreciated in maintaining and expanding our collection of torrents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About Not Quite RARBG&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this website is to fill the void left by the closure of the original RARBG. We strive to gather all existing RARBG torrents for various categories, including movies, TV shows, anime, software, and games. Once we have achieved this goal, we plan to open registrations, allowing users to upload their own torrents. However, to ensure the safety of our users, all uploads will be subject to strict moderation to prevent the distribution of malware.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Join the Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We understand the strong nostalgia and longing for the original RARBG within the community. We invite you to join our Divolt server and be a part of the revival of RARBG. Together, we can recreate the spirit and experience that made it so beloved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nqrarbg.divolt.xyz&#34;&gt;nqrarbg.divolt.xyz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Consumet&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please host your own consumet instance, as the public instance will be shut down in the coming few months.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that piracy and copyright infringement are illegal activities. This repository and its contents are purely for educational, academic and archiving purposes. The owners and contributors are not responsible for ill-intended usage.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>