<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PHP Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-17T01:36:19Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PHP in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>nadrad/h-m-m</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T01:36:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-17:/nadrad/h-m-m</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/nadrad/h-m-m" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hackers Mind Map&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;h-m-m (hackers mind map)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h-m-m&lt;/strong&gt; (pronounced like the interjection &#34;hmm&#34;) is a simple, fast, keyboard-centric terminal-based tool for working with mind maps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nadrad/h-m-m/main/screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Key bindings&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adding, removing, and editing nodes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; - create a new sibling to the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;O&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Tab&lt;/code&gt; - create a new child for the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; - yanks (copies) the active node and its descendants&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Y&lt;/code&gt; - yanks (copies) the descendants of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt; - deletes (cuts) the active node and its descendants&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;D&lt;/code&gt; - deletes (cuts) the descendants of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delete&lt;/code&gt; - deletes the active node and its descendants without putting them in the clipboard&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; - pastes as descendants of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;P&lt;/code&gt; - pastes as siblings of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+p&lt;/code&gt; - appends the clipboard text at the end of the active node&#39;s title&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; - edits the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;I&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; - edits the active node, ignoring the existing text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;u&lt;/code&gt; - undo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+r&lt;/code&gt; - redo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relative navigating and moving:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;←&lt;/code&gt; - activate the parent of the previously active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;→&lt;/code&gt; - activate the middle child of the previously active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;↓&lt;/code&gt; - activate the lower sibling (or the nearest lower node if there&#39;s no lower sibling)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;↑&lt;/code&gt; - activate the higher sibling (or the nearest higher node if there&#39;s no higher sibling)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;J&lt;/code&gt; - moves the current node down among its siblings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;K&lt;/code&gt; - moves the current node up among its siblings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adjusting the view:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; - centers the active node on the screen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; - locks and always keeps active nodes on the center&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; - activate the root element&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;g&lt;/code&gt; - goes to the highest element&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;G&lt;/code&gt; - goes to the lowest element&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt; - increases the maximum node width&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;W&lt;/code&gt; - decreases the maximum node width&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;z&lt;/code&gt; - decreases line spacing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Z&lt;/code&gt; - increases line spacing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Collapsing and expanding:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; - toggles the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt; - collapses everything other than the first-level nodes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; - expands all nodes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;9&lt;/code&gt; - collapse the nth level and expand those before&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;f&lt;/code&gt; - focuses by collapsing all, but the ancestors and descendants of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt; - locks focus as the active node changes (try it with the center lock)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;r&lt;/code&gt; - collapses all the first level items except for the one that contains the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; - collapses the children of the active node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Search:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;?&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+f&lt;/code&gt; - searches for a phrase&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; - goes to the next search result&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; - goes to the previous search result&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Save, export, and quit:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; - saves with the previous file name (or asks for one if there&#39;s none)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; - saves with a new file name&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; - export as HTML&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; - quits (if the changes were already saved)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Q&lt;/code&gt; - quits, ignoring the changes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the text editor:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;↓&lt;/code&gt; - move the cursor to the end of the line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;↑&lt;/code&gt; - move the cursor to the beginning of the line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;←&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt; - move the cursor to the left&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;→&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt; - move the cursor to the right&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Left&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Shift+Left&lt;/code&gt; - move cursor to the previous word&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Right&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Shift+right&lt;/code&gt; - move cursor to the next word&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delete&lt;/code&gt; - delete character&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Delete&lt;/code&gt; - delete word&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Backspace&lt;/code&gt; - delete previous character&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ctrl+Backspace&lt;/code&gt; - delete previous word&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+v&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+v&lt;/code&gt; - paste&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt; - cancel editing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enter&lt;/code&gt; - wanna guess? ;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Configuration&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can create an &lt;code&gt;h-m-m.conf&lt;/code&gt; file in the same directory as the application and use it to change some or all of the following default values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;max_parent_width = 25&#xA;max_leaf_width = 55&#xA;line_spacing = 1&#xA;initial_depth = 1&#xA;active_node_color = &#34;\033[38;5;0m\033[48;5;172m\033[1m&#34;&#xA;message_color = &#34;\033[38;5;0m\033[48;5;141m\033[1m&#34;&#xA;center_lock = false&#xA;focus_lock = false&#xA;undo_steps = 24&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The colors are ASCII escape codes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Data format&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mind maps are stored in plain text files (with &lt;code&gt;hmm&lt;/code&gt; file extension by default) without metadata. The tree structure is represented by tab indentations; e.g.,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;root (level 0)&#xA;   item A (level 1)&#xA;   item B (level 1)&#xA;      item Ba (level 2)&#xA;      item Bb (level 2)&#xA;      item Bc (level 2)&#xA;         item BaX (level 3)&#xA;         item BaY (level 3)&#xA;      item Bd (level 2)&#xA;   item C (level 1)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you yank (copy) or delete (cut) a subtree, the data will be put into your clipboard with a similar structure, and when pasting, the data will be interpreted as such.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most mind mapping applications use a similar format for copying and pasting. As a result, if you want to import a map from another application, you can probably select everything in that application, copy it, come to &lt;strong&gt;h-m-m&lt;/strong&gt;, and paste it. The same usually works well when copying from HTML/PDF/Doc lists, spreadsheets (e.g., Calc and Excel), etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;1. Manual installation (Linux, Windows, and Mac)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;h-m-m&lt;/strong&gt; is a single php file. You can download it from here, or clone it on your computer using git and add a scheduled job to update it once a day or week.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You also need to have the following installed for h-m-m to work:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;php &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;either php 8, or&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;older versions of php along with the &lt;code&gt;mbstring&lt;/code&gt; package (e.g., &lt;code&gt;php7.2-mbstring&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;xclip&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;xsel&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;wl-clipboard&lt;/code&gt; in Linux. (Windows and Mac don&#39;t need it)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After downloading or cloning, you can run &lt;code&gt;php h-m-m&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal to run the program with a blank map or &lt;code&gt;php h-m-m filename&lt;/code&gt; to open an existing file. If you don&#39;t already have a php interpreter installed, you would need to install it as well. Note: You don&#39;t need to set up a &#34;web server&#34; to run it because it&#39;s not a web application, but rather a terminal application that works like those written in Python, Bash, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, you can make the file executable by running the &lt;code&gt;chmod +x h-m-m&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal, and afterward, you can run it as &lt;code&gt;h-m-m filename&lt;/code&gt; (assuming that &lt;strong&gt;h-m-m&lt;/strong&gt; is in your path).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;2. Installation for Arch Linux&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Arch Linux, you can use the &lt;code&gt;h-m-m-git&lt;/code&gt; AUR package to install it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;3. Installation script for Linux&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can run the following command to install h-m-m:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget -q -O - &#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nadrad/h-m-m/main/install.sh&#39; | bash&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This command downloads and runs the install.sh script, which it turn downloads h-m-m, copies it to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin&lt;/code&gt;, checks the dependencies, and makes it executable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After installing, you can run &lt;code&gt;h-m-m&lt;/code&gt; from anywhere in your terminal to run the application with an empty map, or &lt;code&gt;h-m-m filename&lt;/code&gt; to open an existing file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Compatibility&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think the method I&#39;ve used in this program to interact with the terminal emulator is general and standard enough to be cross-platform, but I&#39;ve developed it in Linux and I don&#39;t have any other operating system to test it on. If you run into a problem in Windows or Mac, let me know, especially if you know how to fix it, and I&#39;ll try to make it work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Feedback&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Programming is not my career, but rather a hobby, and I developed &lt;strong&gt;h-m-m&lt;/strong&gt; because I wanted to have something like this and couldn&#39;t find one. Therefore, what I&#39;ve done here may have a lot of room for improvement. If you see an embarrassing problem in the program or have an idea for improvement, feel free to contact me; I&#39;d be happy to receive your feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why php? It&#39;s simple: I only have a rusty knowledge of Pascal and a little familiarity with php. I thought about learning another language for this project (Haskell and Go were my top choices), but I didn&#39;t have time to do it. I&#39;ll probably do it later and convert it into a language I can compile :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>magicblack/maccms10</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T01:36:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-17:/magicblack/maccms10</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/magicblack/maccms10" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;苹果cms官网,苹果cmsv10,maccmsv10,麦克cms,开源cms,内容管理系统,视频分享程序,分集剧情程序,网址导航程序,文章程序,漫画程序,图片程序&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;苹果cms-v10&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;苹果CMS程序是一套采用PHP+MYSQL环境下运行的完善而强大的快速建站系统。经过近多年的开发经验和技术积累，苹果CMS程序已逐步走向成熟，在易用性和功能上已经成为同行中的佼佼者。程序体积小-&amp;gt;优化程序代码，运行速度快-&amp;gt;高效的缓存处理，只要普通的虚拟主机就可以完美搭建起来，建站成本非常低。仿MVC模板分离，内置标签，自定义函数标签接口，强大的自定义采集功能，只要你会HTML就可以轻松做出个性化的网站。 程序易用性和功能上一直以来都积极采纳广大站长提出的各种好的建议，迅速响应各种紧急问题，我们的服务理念贯穿其中，保证每一位站长每一个环节都可以从容应对。v10采用tp5.x内核进行开发，扩展了模板处理引擎，将后台程序与html模板简单的分离出来，让设计人员与程序人员最大限度的发挥自己的优势而互不干扰，大大加快了项目有序、快速的完成。即使您是第一次接触，也会在最短的时间内熟练掌握它的使用方法。后台管理模块，一目了然，操作简单，绝对不会让您眼花缭乱。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apple CMS program is a set of PHP and MYSQL environment operating in a perfect and powerful fast station system. After nearly years of development experience and technology accumulation, Apple CMS program has gradually matured, in ease of use and functionality has become the leader in peers. The program size is small - &amp;gt; optimizer code, running fast - &amp;gt; efficient caching processing, as long as the ordinary virtual host can be perfectly built, the cost of building a station is very low. Imitation MVC template separation, built-in tags, custom function label interface, powerful custom acquisition function, as long as you will HTML can easily make personalized website. Program ease of use and function has been actively adopted by the vast number of station director put forward a variety of good suggestions, quickly respond to a variety of urgent issues, our service concept throughout it, to ensure that every station director every link can be calmly coped with. v10 using the tp5.x kernel for development, extended the template processing engine, the background program and html template simple separation, so that designers and programmers to maximize their advantages without interference, greatly speed up the project orderly and fast completion. Even if you are in first contact, you will master how to use it in the shortest possible time. Back-office management module, at a glance, easy to operate, will never dazzle you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;免责声明&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;本程序仅供内部学习和交流使用，没有内置任何数据，请在遵守当地法律的前提下使用本站程序，对用户在使用过程中的自行维护的信息内容本站不负任何责任！&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is for internal learning and communication use only, there is no built-in data, please comply with local laws under the premise of using the site program, the user in the process of self-maintenance of the information content of this site is not responsible!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>