<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dart Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-19T01:33:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dart in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>WeteeDAO/dao-entrance</title>
    <updated>2023-04-19T01:33:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-19:/WeteeDAO/dao-entrance</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/WeteeDAO/dao-entrance" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are creating a Web3 native, secure and powerful instant collaboration tool. To meet the basic office needs of DAO, this tool must be open, equal, decentralized, open and transparent, and sufficiently automated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/WeteeDAO/dao-entrance/main/docs/icon-152x152.png&#34; style=&#34;width:80px&#34; ;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview &lt;span&gt;📄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In recent years, with the rapid development of information technology and technology, people&#39;s work mode has gradually changed from centralized work to decentralized work. Besides, the spread and prevalence of COVID-19 in recent years get people know the importance of diverse work modes. With this trend, the concept web3 steps out from its previous version web2.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, most Web3 companies are still working with tools within Web2, such as Telegram, Discord, Google Drive, Enterprise WeChat, DingTalk, Lark, and etc, Which user&#39;s information and initiative are limited.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; is trying to create a safe, efficient, powerful and Web3-based instant collaboration tool, which is a breakthrough. It establishes solid trust relationship among organization members through open and transparent smart contract; it maintain end-to-end encrypted communication, to ensure efficient and confidentiallity; it improves work efficiency with thousands of open-source collaborative tool libraries; it keeps data in safe hands through distributed and decentralized storage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on providing DAO with a comprehensive collaborative tool. The tool will help DAO to set up a core team. After the core team authorized by the community, they can make decisions on the daily affairs of DAO, in order to avoiding endless voting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Project Details&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our long-term goal is to provide a safe, private, efficient and automated DAO tool for enterprises, blockchains and web3 practitioners, in a multi-stage style in different period, and, in the meantime, to offer communication, consensus, production, settlement and other basic needs of members.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, we provide not only &#34;ink!&#34;-based DAO smart contract templates, but also substrate-based pallet templates, which support instant integration of all substrate-based blockchains. By compatible with existing DAOs through a non-instrusive way, it allows enterprises and organization to create their own DAOs in a more convenient way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this stage, &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; will provide a slack-like client which is based on the matrix protocol for instant messaging. Users can log in with a blockchain account. This tool is designed for modern devices and is compatible with devices equipped with Windows/mac/Linux/android/iOS, and provides organization members with a concise and convenient collaboration platform.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dao-entrance/app/raw/main/docs/ui.png&#34; style=&#34;width:800px&#34; ;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through&amp;nbsp;DAPP rendering engine which is based on flutter, &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; is compatible with most DAPPs and run at a faster speed. The core business would be materialized by flutter native applications, and DAPPs would be rendered by the dapp engine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dao-entrance/app/raw/main/docs/client.png&#34; style=&#34;width:800px&#34; ;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; Client is a non-intrusive client that supports layer1 blockchain and layer2 smart contracts, and it&#39;s dedicated to adapting DAO scenarios. As an initial stage, we build the &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; chain based on the substrate, and manage the &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; chain by using DAO. After continuous improvement of the Client, we create &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; DAO, which is a fully autonomous and decentralized organization. Through our own requirements of &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; and continuous introduction of other work modes of DAO, we provide substrate pallet and &#34;ink!&#34; smart contracts with a fast DAO solution Polkadot Ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to business needs, DAO organizations will set up skill groups, called &#34;guilds&#34;, and each guild will automatically create public chat channels and Kanbans in &lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt;. Users can join a guild based on their own strengths or willings. Members can choose whether to participate in projects or events according to their own strengths and willingness.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We provide DAO templates the substrate pallet and ink! Smart contracts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RoadMap management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manage DAO share.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Management of core team and guild.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Workflow management (board/task).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Financial management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Task bounty management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hot-swap voting management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contribution value and medal management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Level management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAO-entrance&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on providing DAO with a comprehensive collaborative tool. The tool will help DAO to set up a core team. After the core team authorized by the community, they can make decisions on the daily affairs of DAO, in order to avoiding endless voting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to business needs, DAO organizations will set up skill groups, called &#34;guilds&#34;, and each guild will automatically create public chat channels and Kanbans in DAO-entrance. Users can join a guild based on their own strengths or willings. Members can choose whether to participate in projects or events according to their own strengths and willingness.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/dao-entrance/app/raw/main/docs/structure.png&#34; style=&#34;width:800px&#34; ;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We provide DAO templates the substrate pallet and ink! Smart contracts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RoadMap management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manage DAO share.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Management of core team and guild.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Workflow management (board/task).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Financial management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Task bounty management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hot-swap voting management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contribution value and medal management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Level management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;打包需集成&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pub.flutter-io.cn/packages/tray_manager&#34;&gt;https://pub.flutter-io.cn/packages/tray_manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pub.flutter-io.cn/packages/window_manager&#34;&gt;https://pub.flutter-io.cn/packages/window_manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cjycode.com/flutter_rust_bridge/quickstart.html&#34;&gt;https://cjycode.com/flutter_rust_bridge/quickstart.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dinesh-Sowndar/flutter_furniture_app_ui_challenge</title>
    <updated>2023-04-19T01:33:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-19:/Dinesh-Sowndar/flutter_furniture_app_ui_challenge</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Dinesh-Sowndar/flutter_furniture_app_ui_challenge" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Flutter furniture app UI challenge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Flutter furniture app UI challenge&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/29474697/232321900-a1ae5ba9-68a1-4126-9c47-51b256f44f33.mp4&#34;&gt;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/29474697/232321900-a1ae5ba9-68a1-4126-9c47-51b256f44f33.mp4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>