<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dart Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-16T01:31:37Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dart in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter</title>
    <updated>2023-11-16T01:31:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-16:/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Companion repository for our mobile app development course: Learn, code, and publish with Flutter &amp; Dart, from the first UI to a multi-screen app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;create_apps_with_flutter&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &#34;Create Apps with Flutter,&#34; the GitHub repository supporting our course on mobile app development using Flutter and Dart. This course, designed with practicality at its core, is a step-by-step guide to mastering the creation of mobile applications from concept to deployment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this course, you&#39;ll start from the basics of Flutter and Dart and advance to building complete mobile applications ready for the Google Play Store. The learning path is designed to be hands-on, with immediate application of concepts in practical projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;flutter_app_1&lt;/code&gt; is our starting point, where you&#39;ll write your first lines of UI code directly within the main function. With &lt;code&gt;flutter_app_2&lt;/code&gt;, we expand our horizons, organizing our project into separate files for screens, modules, and widgets.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the end of this course, you&#39;ll be equipped with the knowledge to craft intuitive and performant apps and publish them for Android users worldwide, with an awareness that the skills you&#39;re developing are also applicable to other platforms thanks to Flutter&#39;s cross-platform capabilities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository Structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what you&#39;ll find in this repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter/main/flutter_app_1&#34;&gt;flutter_app_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Our initial project, where the focus is on getting acquainted with Flutter by writing UI code in the main function.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter/main/flutter_app_2&#34;&gt;flutter_app_2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: The second phase of our learning where we begin to structure our code into different files, encouraging modularity and maintainability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository will evolve with more directories and examples as we progress through the course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started with the projects:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clone the repository:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/&amp;lt;your-username&amp;gt;/create_apps_with_flutter.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Move into a project directory, like &lt;code&gt;flutter_app_1&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;cd flutter_app_1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run the Flutter app:&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;flutter run&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Should you have any suggestions or questions, feel free to open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter/issues&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter/discussions&#34;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; in the repository. Your input is valuable for the improvement of this course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository and its contents are provided under the MIT License, which is detailed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/eduhoratiu/create_apps_with_flutter/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>