<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dart Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-07T01:34:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dart in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>iiitl/introduce-yourself-app</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T01:34:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-07:/iiitl/introduce-yourself-app</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/iiitl/introduce-yourself-app" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Introduce Yourself App&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduce Yourself is an application to tell a little about yourself. Ask to get an issue assigned.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to contribute to this project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure to read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iiitl/introduce-yourself-app/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; before contributing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Fork&lt;/code&gt; this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Clone&lt;/code&gt; your fork on local machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Switch to the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make a new &lt;code&gt;branch&lt;/code&gt;, preferably with the feature/issue name.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Checkout to the new branch with &lt;code&gt;git checkout &amp;lt;new_branch_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do the desired changes and &lt;code&gt;commit&lt;/code&gt; them with &lt;code&gt;git commit -m &#39;&amp;lt;a nice commit message here&amp;gt;&#39;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Push&lt;/code&gt; the change to your fork on GitHub with &lt;code&gt;git push origin &amp;lt;your_branch_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make a &lt;code&gt;Pull Request&lt;/code&gt; to the main branch in the original repository, i.e. this one.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: Make sure you are always up to date with sync and pull upstream. Sync and pull before you start and before you push your work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ Clone the project.&#xA;$ Open it on Android Studio, or Visual Studio Code or any other IDE that supports the technologies used.&#xA;$ Run the following command on the terminal:- &#34;flutter pub get&#34;.&#xA;$ Select the device where you want to run this project.&#xA;$ Run the project.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;General Info&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This application basically tells about the owner, basically the medium to contact you own&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Technologies used&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technologies used to build this app is flutter which designs the app for all major operataing systems. It uses the the language dart which is interconvertible into all the languages like kotlin etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we talk about the features of flutter, then they are uncountable, but for the sake of completion it reduces the human effort by providing the single platform to create apps for variety of operating system in the single time If we talk about the app it is the nice way to start with the journey of learning flutter&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally the readme.md file does not contain the apps screenshots that&#39;s why they are not here Suerly they will be in the comments&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run the app When you are developing the app you need an emulator to run or test the app it may be your mobile device of the system generated emulator&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To design the app You must need the platform like android studio to design it&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we talk about the app it provides the nice way to start the journey&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>