<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dart Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-11-23T01:29:50Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dart in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Losses/rune</title>
    <updated>2024-11-23T01:29:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-11-23:/Losses/rune</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Losses/rune" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experience timeless melodies with a music player that blends classic design with modern technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/losses/rune&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/Losses/rune/raw/master/assets/icons/breeze/apps/512/rune.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Logo&#34; width=&#34;80&#34; height=&#34;80&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Rune&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; The player that blends classic design with modern technology. &lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Losses/rune/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;GitHub License&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/losses/rune&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Losses/rune/raw/master/flake.nix&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Nix Flakes&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/nix-flake-blue?logo=nixos&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Losses/rune/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;GitHub Issues&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/losses/rune&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Losses/rune/pulls&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;GitHub Pull Requests&#34; src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr/losses/rune&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7c56e9ac-1e20-405b-b281-dce471870b66&#34;&gt;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/7c56e9ac-1e20-405b-b281-dce471870b66&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rune Player is a music player that offers audio analysis and recommendation features. It introduces a new, modern music management paradigm to enhance your experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rune is a UX experiment inspired by the question: What if Zune[^1] had continued to evolve? Using a modern tech stack (Flutter + Rust), Rune captures the essence of Zune, drawing from the design highlights of various Windows products since the Windows XP era, including Windows Mobile and Windows Media Center[^1].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The motivation behind Rune is to provide a modernized audio listening and management experience. With the rise of streaming services, localized music players have become less common, and many well-known media players have stagnated. Rune aims to offer a clean, consistent, and efficient audio playback experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Unique Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distinctive Design&lt;/strong&gt;: Rune boasts a unique design style.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Analysis and Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can analyze their entire music library to receive recommendations based on tracks, albums, or playlists.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic &#34;Mix&#34; Feature&lt;/strong&gt;: Users can create dynamic playlists based on customizable rules, such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&#34;Similar to this album&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&#34;Top 100 most played tracks&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&#34;Tracks similar to my favorites&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&#34;Playlists including specific artists&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;These mixes automatically update as users listen to and add new tracks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation and Running&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rune is still in the early stages of development and does not provide pre-compiled binaries. However, you can set up a development environment by following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Losses/rune/master/documents/compiling.md&#34;&gt;compiling instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re thrilled you&#39;re interested in contributing. Before you dive in, please take a moment to review these key points to ensure smooth collaboration. For detailed instructions, please refer to the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Losses/rune/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language Requirement&lt;/strong&gt;: To facilitate clear communication across all developers, all contributions, including issues and pull requests, must be submitted in English. If you are not confident in your English proficiency, consider using a language model for assistance.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature Requests&lt;/strong&gt;: As Rune is in the early stages of development, we are currently not accepting feature requests.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feature Implementation&lt;/strong&gt;: If you have a feature proposal, please reach out to the development team for a preliminary discussion to ensure it aligns with Rune&#39;s vision.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Collaboration is conducted exclusively in English. While we do not accept pull requests for translating the README or other development documentation, contributions for translating Rune itself are welcome.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We extend our gratitude to the open-source project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/meyda/meyda&#34;&gt;Meyda&lt;/a&gt; for enabling the audio analysis functionality. We also thank the countless developers in the Rust and Flutter ecosystems for making Rune possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MPL License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[^1]: All mentioned Microsoft products are trademarks of Microsoft. This project is not affiliated with Microsoft, and the founders of this project are not Microsoft employees.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>