<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-01T02:51:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>rdpeng/ProgrammingAssignment2</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T02:51:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/rdpeng/ProgrammingAssignment2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rdpeng/ProgrammingAssignment2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repository for Programming Assignment 2 for R Programming on Coursera&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This second programming assignment will require you to write an R function that is able to cache potentially time-consuming computations. For example, taking the mean of a numeric vector is typically a fast operation. However, for a very long vector, it may take too long to compute the mean, especially if it has to be computed repeatedly (e.g. in a loop). If the contents of a vector are not changing, it may make sense to cache the value of the mean so that when we need it again, it can be looked up in the cache rather than recomputed. In this Programming Assignment you will take advantage of the scoping rules of the R language and how they can be manipulated to preserve state inside of an R object.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Example: Caching the Mean of a Vector&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this example we introduce the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; operator which can be used to assign a value to an object in an environment that is different from the current environment. Below are two functions that are used to create a special object that stores a numeric vector and caches its mean.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first function, &lt;code&gt;makeVector&lt;/code&gt; creates a special &#34;vector&#34;, which is really a list containing a function to&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;set the value of the vector&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;get the value of the vector&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;set the value of the mean&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;get the value of the mean&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- --&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;makeVector &amp;lt;- function(x = numeric()) {&#xA;        m &amp;lt;- NULL&#xA;        set &amp;lt;- function(y) {&#xA;                x &amp;lt;&amp;lt;- y&#xA;                m &amp;lt;&amp;lt;- NULL&#xA;        }&#xA;        get &amp;lt;- function() x&#xA;        setmean &amp;lt;- function(mean) m &amp;lt;&amp;lt;- mean&#xA;        getmean &amp;lt;- function() m&#xA;        list(set = set, get = get,&#xA;             setmean = setmean,&#xA;             getmean = getmean)&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following function calculates the mean of the special &#34;vector&#34; created with the above function. However, it first checks to see if the mean has already been calculated. If so, it &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt;s the mean from the cache and skips the computation. Otherwise, it calculates the mean of the data and sets the value of the mean in the cache via the &lt;code&gt;setmean&lt;/code&gt; function.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cachemean &amp;lt;- function(x, ...) {&#xA;        m &amp;lt;- x$getmean()&#xA;        if(!is.null(m)) {&#xA;                message(&#34;getting cached data&#34;)&#xA;                return(m)&#xA;        }&#xA;        data &amp;lt;- x$get()&#xA;        m &amp;lt;- mean(data, ...)&#xA;        x$setmean(m)&#xA;        m&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Assignment: Caching the Inverse of a Matrix&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matrix inversion is usually a costly computation and there may be some benefit to caching the inverse of a matrix rather than computing it repeatedly (there are also alternatives to matrix inversion that we will not discuss here). Your assignment is to write a pair of functions that cache the inverse of a matrix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Write the following functions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;makeCacheMatrix&lt;/code&gt;: This function creates a special &#34;matrix&#34; object that can cache its inverse.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cacheSolve&lt;/code&gt;: This function computes the inverse of the special &#34;matrix&#34; returned by &lt;code&gt;makeCacheMatrix&lt;/code&gt; above. If the inverse has already been calculated (and the matrix has not changed), then &lt;code&gt;cacheSolve&lt;/code&gt; should retrieve the inverse from the cache.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Computing the inverse of a square matrix can be done with the &lt;code&gt;solve&lt;/code&gt; function in R. For example, if &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; is a square invertible matrix, then &lt;code&gt;solve(X)&lt;/code&gt; returns its inverse.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, assume that the matrix supplied is always invertible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to complete this assignment, you must do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the GitHub repository containing the stub R files at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rdpeng/ProgrammingAssignment2&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rdpeng/ProgrammingAssignment2&lt;/a&gt; to create a copy under your own account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone your forked GitHub repository to your computer so that you can edit the files locally on your own machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit the R file contained in the git repository and place your solution in that file (please do not rename the file).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Commit your completed R file into YOUR git repository and push your git branch to the GitHub repository under your account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit to Coursera the URL to your GitHub repository that contains the completed R code for the assignment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Grading&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This assignment will be graded via peer assessment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>swirldev/swirl_courses</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T02:51:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/swirldev/swirl_courses</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/swirldev/swirl_courses" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🎓 A collection of interactive courses for the swirl R package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;swirl courses&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of interactive courses for use with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://swirlstats.com&#34;&gt;swirl R package&lt;/a&gt;. You&#39;ll find instructions for installing courses further down on this page. Some courses are still in development and we&#39;d love to hear any &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swirldev/swirl_courses/issues/new&#34;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; you have as you work through them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information regarding swirl, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://swirlstats.com&#34;&gt;swirlstats.com&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swirldev/swirl&#34;&gt;swirl GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;. If you&#39;d like to write your own interactive content, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://swirlstats.com/instructors.html&#34;&gt;Instructors page&lt;/a&gt; of our website.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are our current offerings, organized by level of difficulty:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Beginner&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R Programming&lt;/strong&gt;: The basics of programming in R&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swirldev/R_Programming_E&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R Programming E&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Same as the original, but modified slightly for in-class use (see below ***)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://swirlstats.com/scn/rpe.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The R Programming Environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- - **Data Analysis**: Basic ideas in statistics and data visualization --&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- - **Mathematical Biostatistics Boot Camp**: One- and two-sample t-tests, power, and sample size --&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- - **Open Intro**: A very basic introduction to statistics, data analysis, and data visualization --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;em&gt;R Programming E is identical to R Programming, except we&#39;ve eliminated the prompts for Coursera credentials at the end of each lesson and instead give students the option to send an email to their instructor notifying them of completion. Admittedly, it&#39;s sort of a hack until we come up with a more robust solution for in-class use (i.e. an instructor &#34;dashboard&#34;).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Intermediate&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regression Models&lt;/strong&gt;: The basics of regression modeling in R&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting and Cleaning Data&lt;/strong&gt;: dplyr, tidyr, lubridate, oh my!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Advanced&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistical Inference&lt;/strong&gt;: This intermediate to advanced level course closely follows the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/statinference&#34;&gt;Statistical Inference course&lt;/a&gt; of the Johns Hopkins &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/specialization/jhudatascience/1&#34;&gt;Data Science Specialization&lt;/a&gt; on Coursera. It introduces the student to basic concepts of statistical inference including probability, hypothesis testing, confidence intervals and p-values. It concludes with an initiation to topics of particular relevance to big data, issues of multiple testing and resampling.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://swirlstats.com/scn/arp.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced R Programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since our users come from a variety backgrounds, it&#39;s very hard to label material as &lt;strong&gt;Beginner&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Intermediate&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Advanced&lt;/strong&gt;. If you find something that is labelled &lt;strong&gt;Beginner&lt;/strong&gt; to be challenging, please don&#39;t be discouraged. The first step of learning anything is to acknowledge that you are capable of understanding it. True understanding will come with time and practice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Course Authors&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing swirl Courses&lt;/strong&gt;: An interactive guides and example for swirl course authors. The first group of lessons cover basics. The rest cover special topics useful primarily as samples--points of departure for one&#39;s own material. For more comprehensive documentation about writing your own swirl courses see &lt;a href=&#34;http://swirlstats.com/swirlify/&#34;&gt;http://swirlstats.com/swirlify/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install and run a course automatically from swirl&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the preferred method of installing courses.&lt;/strong&gt; It automates the process by allowing you to do everything right from the R console.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have a recent version version of swirl:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;swirl&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter the following from the R console, &lt;strong&gt;substituting the name of the course&lt;/strong&gt; that you wish to install:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(swirl)&#xA;install_course(&#34;Course Name Here&#34;)&#xA;swirl()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;code&gt;install_course(&#34;R Programming&#34;)&lt;/code&gt; will install the R Programming course. &lt;strong&gt;Please note that course names are case sensitive!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If that doesn&#39;t work for you...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install and run a course manually&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the automatic course installation method outlined above does not work for you, then there&#39;s a simple alternative.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find the course you want to install on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://swirlstats.com/scn/title.html&#34;&gt;Swirl Course network website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the manual installation instructions on the course page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If that does not work for you, consider taking a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swirldev/swirl_courses/wiki/Legacy-Manual-Install-Instructions-for-Swirl-Courses&#34;&gt;legacy manual install instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Uninstall a course&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to remove a course at any time, you can use &lt;code&gt;uninstall_course(&#34;Course Name Here&#34;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using swirl in the classroom&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instructors around the world are using swirl in their classrooms. We think this is awesome. If you&#39;re an instructor, please feel free to do the same -- free of charge. While your students may be paying to take your course or attend your institution, we simply ask that you don&#39;t charge people &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; for the use of our software or instructional content.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are not sure about a particular use case, don&#39;t hesitate to post a question to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/swirl-discuss&#34;&gt;Google Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>rmaia/pavo</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T02:51:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/rmaia/pavo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rmaia/pavo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;tools for the analysis of color data in R&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;code&gt;pavo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: start --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/package=pavo/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.r-pkg.org/badges/version-ago/pavo&#34; alt=&#34;cran version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/package=pavo/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/grand-total/pavo&#34; alt=&#34;cran downloads&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rmaia/pavo/actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/rmaia/pavo/workflows/R-CMD-check/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;R build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cranchecks.info/pkgs/pavo&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cranchecks.info/badges/worst/pavo&#34; alt=&#34;cran checks&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: end --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;An &lt;code&gt;R&lt;/code&gt; package for the spectral and spatial analysis of color patterns&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Currently maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thomased&#34;&gt;Thomas White&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bisaloo&#34;&gt;Hugo Gruson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pavo&lt;/code&gt; is an R package developed with the goal of establishing a flexible and integrated workflow for working with spectral and spatial colour data. It includes functions that take advantage of new data classes to work seamlessly from importing raw spectra and images, to visualisation and analysis. It provides flexible ways to input spectral data from a variety of equipment manufacturers, process these data, extract variables, and produce publication-quality figures.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pavo&lt;/code&gt; was written with the following workflow in mind:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organise&lt;/strong&gt; data by importing and processing spectra and images (e.g., to remove noise, negative values, smooth curves, etc.).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyse&lt;/strong&gt; the resulting files, using spectral analyses of shape (hue, saturation, brightness), visual models based on perceptual data, and/or spatial adjacency and boundary strength analyses.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualise&lt;/strong&gt; the output, with multiple options provided for exploration, presentation, and analysis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Need more information, or help with the package?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://book.colrverse.com&#34;&gt;package documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed examples and discussion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://pavo.colrverse.com/news/index.html&#34;&gt;latest news&lt;/a&gt; for changes and updates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need help or advice and can&#39;t find what you&#39;re looking for?&lt;/strong&gt; Head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/colrverse/colRverse/discussions&#34;&gt;colRverse discussion board&lt;/a&gt; and feel free to post a message.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If all else fails&lt;/strong&gt; (or you don&#39;t have a GitHub account), &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:thomas.white@sydney.edu.au&#34;&gt;email Tom&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Citing pavo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The manuscript describing the current iteration of the package has been published and is free to access:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maia R., Gruson H., Endler J.A., and White T.E. 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/2041-210X.13174&#34;&gt;pavo 2: New tools for the spectral and spatial analysis of colour in R&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Methods in Ecology and Evolution&lt;/em&gt;, 10(7):1097‑1107.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the development page for &lt;code&gt;pavo&lt;/code&gt;. The stable release is available from CRAN. Simply use &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;pavo&#34;)&lt;/code&gt; to install.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to install the bleeding edge version of &lt;code&gt;pavo&lt;/code&gt;, you can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/r-lib/remotes&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;remotes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;# install.packages(&#34;remotes&#34;)&#xA;remotes::install_github(&#34;rmaia/pavo&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;download files from GitHub and install using &lt;code&gt;$R CMD INSTALL&lt;/code&gt; or, from within R:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(path, type = &#34;source&#34;, repos = NULL)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>