<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-21T03:29:33Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>osmandapp/OsmAnd</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T03:29:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-21:/osmandapp/OsmAnd</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;OsmAnd&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;OsmAnd (OSM Automated Navigation Directions)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project aims at providing comfortable map viewing and navigation (routing) application for mobile devices. Particular stress lies with complete offline features (via pre-loaded offline map data) or economic internet usage. To get started, continue with the basic description below, then find more detail on our Welcome Wiki Pages, the Project Homepage, or the OpenStreetMap OsmAnd Wiki Page. You are welcome to discuss any question regarding the project at the Google group OsmAnd. Please do not use comments on wiki pages because it is rather difficult to find them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Android markets&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=8483587772816822023&#34; rel=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd-misc/raw/master/logo/stores/googleplay.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google Play&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C101486545&#34; rel=&#34;Explore it on AppGallery&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd-misc/raw/master/logo/stores/appgallery.png&#34; alt=&#34;Huawei AppGallery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/s?i=mobile-apps&amp;amp;rh=p_4%3AOsmAnd&amp;amp;search-type=ss&#34; rel=&#34;Get it on Amazon&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd-misc/raw/master/logo/stores/amazon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Amazon&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/packages/net.osmand.plus/&#34; rel=&#34;Get it on F-Droid&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd-misc/raw/master/logo/stores/fdroid.png&#34; alt=&#34;F-droid&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;App Store - Apple&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/app/apple-store/id934850257&#34; rel=&#34;Get it on AppStore&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/osmandapp/OsmAnd-misc/raw/master/logo/stores/appstore.png&#34; alt=&#34;App Store Apple&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/osmand/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/osmand/-/svg-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Translation status&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OsmAnd (OSM Automated Navigation Directions)&lt;/strong&gt; is a map and navigation application with access to the free, worldwide, and high-quality OpenStreetMap (OSM) database. All map data can be stored on your device&#39;s memory card for offline use. Via your device&#39;s GPS, OsmAnd offers routing, with optical and voice guidance, for car, bike, and pedestrian usage. All main functionalities work both online and offline (no internet needed).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Some of the main features:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Navigation&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Works online (fast) or offline (no roaming charges when you are abroad)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Turn-by-turn voice guidance (recorded and synthesized voices)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional lane guidance, street name display, and estimated time of arrival&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports intermediate points on your itinerary&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatic re-routing whenever you deviate from the route&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Search for places by address, by type (e.g. restaurant, hotel, gas station, museum), or by geographical coordinates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Map Viewing&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Display your position and orientation on the map&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally align the map according to compass or your direction of motion&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save your most important places as Favorites&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Display POIs (point of interests) around you&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can display specialized online tile maps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can display satellite view (from Bing)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Can display different overlays like touring/navigation GPX tracks and additional maps with customizable transparency&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally display place names in English, local, or phonetic spelling&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Use OpenStreetMap and Wikipedia Data&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;High quality information from the world&#39;s best collaborative projects&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Global maps from OpenStreetMap, available per country or region&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wikipedia POIs, great for sightseeing (not available in free version)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unlimited free downloading, directly from the app (download limit is 16 map files in free version)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Always up-to-date maps (updated at least once a month)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compact offline vector maps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select between complete map data and just road network (Example: All of Japan is 700 MB, or 200 MB for the road network only)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Also supports online or cached tile maps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Safety Features&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional automated day/night view switching&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional speed limit display, with reminder if you exceed it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional speed-dependent map zooming&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Share your location so that your friends can find you&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Bicycle and Pedestrian Features&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The maps include foot, hiking, and bike paths (great for outdoor activities)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Special routing and display modes for bike and pedestrian usage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional public transport stops (bus, tram, train), including line names&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional trip recording to local GPX file or online service&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional speed and altitude display&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Display of contour lines and hill-shading (via additional paid plugin)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Directly Contribute to OpenStreetMap&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Report map bugs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upload GPX tracks to OSM directly from the app&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add POIs and directly upload them to OSM (or later if offline)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional trip recording in background mode (while device is in sleep mode)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Contribute to OsmAnd&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OsmAnd is open-source and actively being developed. Everyone can contribute to the application by reporting bugs, &lt;a href=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/osmand/&#34;&gt;improving translations&lt;/a&gt;, or coding new features. The project experiences continuous improvement by all such forms of developer and user interaction. The project progress also relies on financial contributions to fund the development, coding, and testing of new functionality. By buying OsmAnd+ and subscribing to OsmAnd Pro (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://osmand.net/docs/user/purchases/&#34;&gt;https://osmand.net/docs/user/purchases/&lt;/a&gt;), you help the application become even more awesome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Map Coverage and Quality - How Good is OSM Data?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to research, OSM map data rivals and often surpasses commercially available maps both in terms of data completeness and data actuality. This is indicated by different metrics like the amount of road distance mapped, or the number of objects like points of interest or buildings mapped. The fact that the maps are globally crowd-sourced ensures continuous improvements and updates, the incorporation of local on-the-ground expertise, and reflects things like neighborhood development, ongoing construction, or even the results of recent natural disasters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Comparing the different metrics, it is safe to say that OSM maps cover all continents and countries globally for all your travel needs, and you will find their quality and completeness nothing less than stunning in the vast majority of countries. Latest research mentions only few countries in continental Asia and central Africa where e.g the incorporation of a noticeable portion or roadways is still ongoing to catch up with the high levels already reached anywhere else.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;List of countries supported&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coverage is world wide, e.g.: Afghanistan, Albania, Algeria, Andorra, Angola, Anguilla, Antigua and Barbuda, Argentina, Armenia, Aruba, Australia, Austria, Azerbaijan, Bahamas, Bahrain, Bangladesh, Barbados, Belarus, Belgium, Belize, Benin, Bermuda, Bhutan, Bolivia, Bonaire, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Botswana, Brazil, British Virgin Islands, Brunei, Bulgaria, Burkina Faso, Burundi, Cambodia, Cameroon, Canada, Cape Verde, Central African Republic, Chad, Chile, China, Colombia, Comoros, Congo, Costa Rica, Croatia, Cuba, Curaçao, Cyprus, Czechia, Denmark, Djibouti, Dominica, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, Egypt, El Salvador, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Estonia, Ethiopia, Fiji, Finland, France, French Guiana, French Polynesia, Gabon, Gambia, Georgia, Germany, Ghana, Gibraltar, Greece, Greenland, Grenada, Guadeloupe, Guam, Guatemala, Guernsey, Guinea, Guinea-Bissau, Guyana, Haiti, Vatican, Honduras, Hong Kong, Hungary, Iceland, India, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Ireland, Isle of Man, Israel, Italy, Ivory Coast, Jamaica, Japan, Jersey, Jordan, Kazakhstan, Kenya, Kiribati, North Korea and South Korea, Kuwait, Kyrgyzstan, Laos, Latvia, Lebanon, Lesotho, Liberia, Libya, Liechtenstein, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Macao, Macedonia, Madagascar, Malawi, Malaysia, Maldives, Mali, Malta, Martinique, Mauritania, Mauritius, Mayotte, Mexico, Micronesia, Moldova, Monaco, Mongolia, Montenegro, Montserrat, Morocco, Mozambique, Myanmar, Namibia, Nauru, Nepal, Netherlands, Netherlands Antilles, New Caledonia, New Zealand, Nicaragua, Niger, Nigeria, Norway, Oman, Pakistan, Palau, Palestinian Territory, Panama, Papua New Guinea, Paraguay, Peru, Philippines, Poland, Portugal, Puerto Rico, Qatar, Romania, Russia, Rwanda, Saint Barthelemy, Saint Helena, Saint Kitts and Nevis, Saint Lucia, Saint Martin, Saint Pierre and Miquelon, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, Samoa, San Marino, Saudi Arabia, Senegal, Serbia, Seychelles, Sierra Leone, Singapore, Slovakia, Slovenia, Somalia, South Africa, South Georgia, South Sudan, Spain, Sri Lanka, Sudan, Suriname, Swaziland, Sweden, Switzerland, Syria, Taiwan, Tajikistan, Tanzania, Thailand, Timor-Leste, Togo, Tokelau, Tonga, Trinidad and Tobago, Tunisia, Turkey, Turkmenistan, Tuvalu, Uganda, Ukraine, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom (UK), United States of America (USA), Uruguay, Uzbekistan, Vanuatu, Venezuela, Vietnam, Wallis and Futuna, Western Sahara, Yemen, Zambia, Zimbabwe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>apache/hadoop</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T03:29:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-21:/apache/hadoop</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apache/hadoop" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apache Hadoop&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the latest information about Hadoop, please visit our website at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hadoop.apache.org/&#34;&gt;http://hadoop.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and our wiki, at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/HADOOP/&#34;&gt;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/HADOOP/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kumaransg/LLD</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T03:29:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-21:/kumaransg/LLD</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Curated Collection of all Low level design Questions and implementation asked in major Tech companies , Get yourself prepared for the LLD round and ace the interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Low level Design / Machine Coding Question Collections&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is Machine Coding Round ?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Machine Coding Round has become very popular interview round in most Product and startup companies like Flipkart, Cleartrip, navi and Udaan,the way the round is structured is the candidate will be provided with a Problem statement and the minimum set of features which needs to implemented within the 90 min window period, we as a candidate need to identity the data models, the service interfaces which will be consumed by the clients and other set of functions and classes, we should be able to present the same to the panel with are design choices / design patterns being made / used and the complete working code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is the purpose behind this LLD repo ?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;During my recent Preparation, found out that there was no single resources where we get a collections of all the questions and the corresponding Answers, so currently updating the repo with all the materials I found out from the web and the Questions which has been asked during my interview. feel free to contribute any questions you have got during your recent interview.There other useful YT channel and Git repo which are attached in the resources section.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is target Audience, do all companies ask ?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you are currently targeting/looking out for any SDE - I,II opportunities. It totally depends on the company you interviewing with, you can check with the HR if they evaluate via machine coding round, but certain companies do ask a object oriented design round where they focus only on one particular feature and DB design as well, so its good get practiced with few problems beforehand.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Below are the list of LLD problem which are asked during my machine coding rounds from tech companies and the resources I collected.&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Note : page is under construction, you can click on the individual packages to view all the questions and solutions.&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Low Level Design Question &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Question Link to PDF / Drive &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Company Asked&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Credits to author &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/Cricket%20Match%20Dashboard&#34;&gt;Cricket Match Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/discuss/interview-question/990227/udaan-assignment-cricket-match-dashboard&#34;&gt;Leetcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Udaan Assignment&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/Event_calendar_flipkart&#34;&gt;Event Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/raw/main/Event_calendar_flipkart/Event%20Calendar.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Flipkart LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/FoodKart&#34;&gt;FoodKart or food ordering System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Bmkz9omByHqVvwU45cvkBRSwJAPKw9yaDsRlEnCg_lg/edit#&#34;&gt;Doc link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Flipkart LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/StockExchange&#34;&gt;Stock Exchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/StockExchange&#34;&gt;Problem Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Navi LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/PropertyHunt&#34;&gt;PropertyHunt or property Listing site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/PropertyHunt/Question%20Image&#34;&gt;Question image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;ClearTrip LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/ledger_company_navi&#34;&gt;ledger company&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geektrust.in/coding-problem/backend/ledger-co&#34;&gt;Question Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Navi LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gauravmassand/ledger-company&#34;&gt;Github code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/leetcode-lld-flipkart-coding-blox&#34;&gt;Leetcode Like platform LLD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/raw/main/leetcode-lld-flipkart-coding-blox/SDE2-%20MC%20Question.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Flipkart LLD Question&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hocyadav/leetcode-lld-flipkart-coding-blox&#34;&gt;Github code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Frequently asked Problems&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Low Level Design Question&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Question Link to PDF / Drive&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Company Asked&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Credits to author&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/Ride%20Sharing%20&#34;&gt;Ride Sharing like App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kumaransg/LLD/tree/main/Ride%20Sharing%20/RideShare_MachineCoding_Sample&#34;&gt;Problem Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Lift/Elevator&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-lift-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design 2048 Game&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-2048-game-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Splitwise&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-splitwise-application-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design AWS Lambda&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-aws-lambda-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Game Engine&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-game-engine-like-unreal-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Newsletter Service&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-newsletter-service-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Gmail&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-gmail-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Whatsapp&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-whatsapp-messenger-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Event Calender&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-event-calendar-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Tinder&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-tinder-dating-app-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Zoom&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-video-conferencing-application-like-zoom-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Google Doc&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-real-time-collaborative-document-editing-platform-like-google-docs-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Mentorship Platform&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-mentorship-platform-like-preplaced-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design CryptoCurrency Exchange&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-cryptocurrency-exchange-platform-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Food Delivery App&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-system-for-online-food-ordering-and-delivery-like-zomato-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Codepair Platform&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-pair-programming-platform-like-hackerrank-codepair-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Chat System&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-real-time-chat-system-with-support-for-millions-of-concurrent-users-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Dropbox&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-file-sharing-system-like-dropbox-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Music Recognition System&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-music-recognition-system-using-audio-fingerprinting-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Spotify&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/implement-a-music-streaming-service-like-spotify-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Bittorrent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-peer-to-peer-file-sharing-system-like-bittorrent-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Distributed Search&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-distributed-search-engine-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Google Maps&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-google-maps-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Twitter/X&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-twitter-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Blockchain&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-blockchain-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Video Streaming&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-video-streaming-platform-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Spotify&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/implement-a-music-streaming-service-like-spotify-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Design Bittorrent&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lldcoding.com/design-lld-a-peer-to-peer-file-sharing-system-like-bittorrent-machine-coding&#34;&gt;Solution-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Frequently asked in all companies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contribute&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions welcome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you found this resource helpful, give it a 🌟 otherwise contribute to it and give it a ⭐️.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>