<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haskell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-27T01:36:18Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Haskell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>holmisen/hrunner</title>
    <updated>2023-04-27T01:36:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-27:/holmisen/hrunner</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/holmisen/hrunner" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Runner dialog for starting applications and searching etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;hRunner&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Runner dialog for starting applications, searching the web and calculating arithmetic expressions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is made to be small, fast and simple with a minimum of dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and it&#39;s implemented in Haskell.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Autocomple (of previous commands)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Evaluation of arithmetic expressions (using python, so any python expression would evaluate)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;User configurable shortcuts&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Build it and put the executable somewhere&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run it to create a &lt;code&gt;.hrunner&lt;/code&gt; directory in &lt;code&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt; (on Windows this will go somewhere else)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;.hrunner/shortcuts&lt;/code&gt; to your liking. See &lt;code&gt;doc/example_shortcuts&lt;/code&gt; for examples.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Create a desktop shortcut to the hrunner executable (I use &lt;code&gt;Win+R&lt;/code&gt; in xfce and &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Alt+P&lt;/code&gt; in Gnome3)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Start using! Hit your shortcut and start running things.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some years ago I was running KDE 3.5 as my primary desktop. It had, among many other great things, a very nice application starter (accessible by hitting &lt;code&gt;ALT+F2&lt;/code&gt;). Not only did it start applications, but could also send text strings to web pages for searching and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then when KDE 4 came out I migrated to XFCE. Although being a much simpler desktop environment it still served my needs (and still does) pretty well. But the one thing I missed the most from KDE was the application starter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is how hrunner came to be. XFCE also has an application runner, but it cannot search the web, and at the time it didn&#39;t even have auto completion.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;And here it is&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wrote hrunner for my own needs with no thought of making it publicly available. But now I have been using it for some years and it serves me well, so why not make it available for anyone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is still in need of polish and the code is rather old (I just make minor code changes). But it has a small code base, few dependencies and hence should be rather simple to hack on for those who like.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>