<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haskell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-19T01:36:46Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Haskell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>agra-uni-bremen/libriscv</title>
    <updated>2023-04-19T01:36:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-19:/agra-uni-bremen/libriscv</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/agra-uni-bremen/libriscv" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Extensible implementation of the RISC-V ISA based on FreeMonads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;A Versatile and Flexibel RISC-V Model&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an extensible &lt;a href=&#34;https://riscv.org&#34;&gt;RISC-V&lt;/a&gt; implementation which is based on a formal model of the architecture. The formal model is implemented using &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1145/2887747.2804319&#34;&gt;free monads&lt;/a&gt; and a custom expression language for arithmetic operations. Based on this formal model, custom interpreters for RISC-V instructions can be easily implemented, e.g. to perform a taint analysis. More information about LibRISCV is available in the publication &lt;em&gt;Versatile and Flexible Modelling of the RISC-V Instruction Set Architecture&lt;/em&gt; which will be published as part of the proceedings of the 2023 &lt;em&gt;Trends in Functional Programming&lt;/em&gt; conference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Abstract description of RISC-V instructions based on free monads&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom expression language to perform operations on arbitrary types &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Instruction operands must not be concrete fixed-width integers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can also be SMT expressions for example (useful for symbolic execution)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Polymorphic implementations of byte-addressable memory and register file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Algebraic effects for instruction tracing etc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RISC-V instruction decoder which is auto-generated from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-opcodes&#34;&gt;riscv-opcodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software can be installed either using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/cabal/&#34;&gt;Cabal&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.io&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;. The latter installation method may be preferable if you don&#39;t have a RISC-V cross compiler installed on your system. Both methods are described further below under the assumption that the repository has been cloned already.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Cabal&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming cabal has already been setup, run the following command within the source directory to install LibRISCV:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cabal install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This should place the concrete example interpreter (&lt;code&gt;riscv-tiny&lt;/code&gt;) in your &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To ease installation of a RISC-V cross compiler toolchain a Dockerfile is provided. To build and run a Docker container using this file invoke the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ docker build -t libriscv .&#xA;$ docker run -it libriscv&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will drop you in an interactive shell within the Docker container. See the section below for more information on which commands can be run within the container. Within the container, the LibRISCV source code is available in the LibRISCV subdirectory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section provides more information on using the provided library and the concrete interpreter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Concrete Interpreter&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concrete interpreter, which is build upon the formal RISC-V model, can execute any &lt;code&gt;rv32i&lt;/code&gt; RISC-V machine code. Assuming you have a RISC-V compiler toolchain available, run the following commands to execute a sample assembly program:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat sample.S&#xA;.globl _start&#xA;.myword:&#xA;    .word 0xffffffff&#xA;_start:&#xA;    lw t0, .myword&#xA;    addi a0, t0, -1&#xA;&#xA;    # Invalid instruction to cause riscv-tiny exit&#xA;    .word 0xffffffff&#xA;$ clang --target=-riscv32-unknown-elf -march=rv32i -mabi=ilp32 -nostdlib -o sample sample.S&#xA;$ riscv-tiny --trace --registers sample&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sample program loads a value from memory and then decrements this value by 1. The &lt;code&gt;riscv-tiny&lt;/code&gt; invocation will then print all instructions executed for this program and exits after encountering the first invalid instruction. Afterwards, it will dump all register values.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Library Interface&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concreter interpreter implements just one possible interpretation of RISC-V instructions. As the name suggests, LibRISCV is specifically intended to implement custom interpreters on top of the abstract RISC-V model. For this purpose, the Cabal file provides a Haskell library component. Based on this library, the &lt;code&gt;example/&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory contains a custom example interpreter which performs a primitive taint analysis on RISC-V machine code. Refer to &lt;code&gt;example/README.md&lt;/code&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A unit test suite is available which can be invoked using:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cabal test&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv-software-src/riscv-tests&#34;&gt;riscv-tests&lt;/a&gt; is included in this repository for performing minimal compliance tests. These tests require a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv-collab/riscv-gnu-toolchain&#34;&gt;riscv-gnu-toolchain&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/make&#34;&gt;GNU Make&lt;/a&gt;. If these dependencies are installed (e.g. if you are using the provided Docker image), run the tests using:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ./riscv-tests/run.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work was supported in part by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF) within the project EXCL under contract no. 01IW22002 and within the project Scale4Edge under contract no. 16ME0127.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>