<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Haskell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-29T01:31:35Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Haskell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>input-output-hk/marlowe-plutus</title>
    <updated>2023-11-29T01:31:35Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-29:/input-output-hk/marlowe-plutus</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/input-output-hk/marlowe-plutus" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Plutus validators for the Marlowe financial contract DSL&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Marlowe Plutus Validators&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project implements the on-chain component of the Cardano implementation of Marlowe as a Plutus smart contract. The main outputs are the marlowe semantics validator, which checks the spending of Marlowe script outputs, and the marlowe role payout validator, which checks the spending of role payouts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dev Shell&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository uses nix to provide the development and build environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instructions on how to install and configure nix (including how to enable access to our binary caches), refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/input-output-hk/iogx/raw/main/doc/nix-setup-guide.md&#34;&gt;this document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you already have nix installed and configured, you may enter the development shell by running &lt;code&gt;nix develop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have direnv installed, you can have the shell automatically load and refresh for you by running these commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mkdir .direnv&#xA;direnv allow&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, whenever you enter the repo the shell will be automatically loaded for you and will be refreshed when the environment changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once in the dev shell, type &lt;code&gt;info&lt;/code&gt; to see the available commands and environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compiling the project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the dev shell, you can compile the project with &lt;code&gt;cabal build all&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can compile with &lt;code&gt;nix&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;nix build .#marlowe-validators&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compiling the validators&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can compile the validators using the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;nix build .#marlowe-validators&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will build the project and run the &lt;code&gt;marlowe-validators&lt;/code&gt; executable and output the compiled plutus scripts into local directory called &lt;code&gt;result&lt;/code&gt;. This directory will contain two files:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;marlowe-rolepayout.plutus&lt;/code&gt; The compiled role payout validator as a JSON-encoded CBOR text-envelope.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;marlowe-semantics.plutus&lt;/code&gt; The compiled marlowe validator as a JSON-encoded CBOR text-envelope.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>