<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-13T01:50:50Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>apple/swift-certificates</title>
    <updated>2024-10-13T01:50:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-13:/apple/swift-certificates</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apple/swift-certificates" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An implementation of X.509 for Swift&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;swift-certificates&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A library for working with X.509 certificates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;X.509 certificates are a commonly-used identity format to cryptographically attest to the identity of an actor in a system. They form part of the X.509 standard created by the ITU-T for defining a public key infrastructure (PKI). X.509-style PKIs are commonly used in cases where it is necessary to delegate the authority to attest to an actor&#39;s identity to a small number of trusted parties (called Certificate Authorities).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most common usage of X.509 certificates today is as part of the WebPKI, where they are used to secure TLS connections to websites. X.509 certificates are also used in a wide range of other TLS-based communications, as well as in code signing infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This module makes it possible to serialize, deserialize, create, and interact with X.509 certificates. This is an essential building-block for a wide range of PKI applications. It enables building verifiers, interacting with certificate authorities, authenticating peers, and more. It also ships with a default verifier and a number of built-in verifier policies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Supported Swift Versions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library was introduced with support for Swift 5.7 or later. This library will support the latest stable Swift version and the two versions prior.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use swift-certificates, add the following dependency to your Package.swift:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;dependencies: [&#xA;    .package(url: &#34;https://github.com/apple/swift-certificates.git&#34;, .upToNextMajor(from: &#34;1.0.0&#34;))&#xA;]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can then add the specific product dependency to your target:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;dependencies: [&#xA;    .product(name: &#34;X509&#34;, package: &#34;swift-certificates&#34;),&#xA;]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For detailed usage and API documentation, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://swiftpackageindex.com/apple/swift-certificates/main/documentation/x509&#34;&gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Benchmarks for &lt;code&gt;swift-certificates&lt;/code&gt; are in a separate Swift Package in the &lt;code&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/code&gt; subfolder of this repository. They use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ordo-one/package-benchmark&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;package-benchmark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; plugin. Benchmarks depends on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jemalloc.net&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jemalloc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; memory allocation library, which is used by &lt;code&gt;package-benchmark&lt;/code&gt; to capture memory allocation statistics. An installation guide can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://swiftpackageindex.com/ordo-one/package-benchmark/documentation/benchmark/gettingstarted#Installing-Prerequisites-and-Platform-Support&#34;&gt;Getting Started article&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;code&gt;package-benchmark&lt;/code&gt;. Afterwards you can run the benchmarks from CLI by going to the &lt;code&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/code&gt; subfolder (e.g. &lt;code&gt;cd Benchmarks&lt;/code&gt;) and invoking:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;swift package benchmark&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information please refer to &lt;code&gt;swift package benchmark --help&lt;/code&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://swiftpackageindex.com/ordo-one/package-benchmark/documentation/benchmark&#34;&gt;documentation of &lt;code&gt;package-benchmark&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>