<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-01T01:50:13Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>khanhduytran0/LiveContainer</title>
    <updated>2024-12-01T01:50:13Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-01:/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Run iOS app without actually installing it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;LiveContainer&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run iOS app without actually installing it!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows you to install unlimited apps (10 apps limit of free developer account do not apply here!), have multiple versions of an app installed and multiple data containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When JIT is available, codesign is entirely bypassed, no need to sign your apps before installing. Otherwise, app will be signed with the same certificate used by LiveContainer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, not all apps work in LiveContainer, so we have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer/labels/compatibility&#34;&gt;compatibility list&lt;/a&gt; to tell if there is apps that have issues. If they aren&#39;t on this list, then it&#39;s likely going run. However, if it doesn&#39;t work, please make an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; about it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Requires AltStore or SideStore&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build from source or get prebuilt ipa in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer/actions&#34;&gt;the Actions tab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open LiveContainer, tap the plus icon in the upper right hand corner and select IPA files to install.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choose the app you want to open in the next launch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can long-press the app to manage it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Without JIT&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without JIT, guest apps need to be codesigned, which requires retrieving the certificate and password from SideStore or AltStore. This process involves applying a tweak to SideStore/AltStore, allowing it to expose the certificate to LiveContainer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open Settings in LiveContainer, tap &#34;Patch SideStore/AltStore&#34;, and the app will switch to SideStore/AltStore to reinstall it with the tweak applied. If you use AltWidget, select &#34;Keep Extension.&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Wait for the installation to finish, then &lt;strong&gt;reopen SideStore/AltStore&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Return to LiveContainer and press &#34;Test JIT-Less Mode.&#34; If it says &#34;Test Passed,&#34; JIT-less mode is ready.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install your app via the &#34;Apps&#34; tab.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tap the run icon, it will attempt to restart LiveContainer with guest app loaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: If you update or reinstall SideStore/AltStore, you&#39;ll need to reapply the patch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;With JIT (requires SideStore)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tap the play icon, it will jump to SideStore and exit.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In SideStore, hold down LiveContainer and tap &lt;code&gt;Enable JIT&lt;/code&gt;. If you have SideStore build supporting JIT URL scheme, it jumps back to LiveContainer with JIT enabled and the guest app is ready to use.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Add to Home Screen&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long press the app and you will see 2 ways to add your app to home screen:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launch URL&lt;/strong&gt;: Copy the provided URL, create a shortcut that opens the app, and add it to your home screen. You’ll need to create a separate shortcut for each app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create App Clip&lt;/strong&gt;: Install an App Clip MDM profile, which adds the app to your home screen. Note that launching the app includes an extra jump, and the App Clip will remain in the app switcher.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Multiple LiveContainers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using two LiveContainers allows you to run two different apps simultaneously, with &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; seamless data transfer between the LiveContainers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install a second LiveContainer, go to Settings and tap &#34;Install Another LiveContainer.&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first LiveContainer (blue icon) always launches by default. If an app is already running in the first container, you&#39;ll be prompted to either open it in the second LiveContainer (gray icon) or terminate the current app and relaunch it in the first. If the app is already running in the second container, it will switch automatically. To use an app in the second container, you must convert this app to a shared app. You can do that by opening the first LiveContainer (blue), long press on your app, open the settings of your app and then &#34;Convert to Shared App&#34;. After that, you can launch your app using LiveContainer2 (grey).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Fix File Picker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some apps may experience issues with their file pickers in LiveContainer. To resolve this, enable &#34;Fix File Picker&#34; in the app-specific settings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&#34;Open In App&#34; Support&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tap the link icon in the top-right corner of the &#34;Apps&#34; tab and input the URL. LiveContainer will detect the appropriate app and ask if you want to launch it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;What&#39;s more, you can share a web page to LiveContainer using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/44ea82ce7ed8469ea24198c375db09a0&#34;&gt;this shortcut&lt;/a&gt;. Be sure to add this shortcut to &#34;Favorites&#34; in share sheet actions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;JIT Support&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable JIT for a guest app:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter your SideJITServer/JITStreamer address and device UDID in LiveContainer settings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable &#34;Launch with JIT&#34; in its app-specific settings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LiveContainer will communicate with the server before launching the app to enable JIT.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installing external tweaks&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LiveContainer comes with its own TweakLoader, which automatically load CydiaSubstrate and tweaks. TweakLoader is injected to every app you install. You can override &lt;code&gt;TweakLoader.dylib&lt;/code&gt; symlink with your own implementation if you wish.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.dylib files in &lt;code&gt;Tweaks&lt;/code&gt; folder are global, they are loaded to all apps. You can create app-specific tweaks folder and switch between them instantly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install tweaks, you can use the built-in tweak manager in LiveContainer, which will automatically sign tweaks as you import. Otherwise, you can manually add them and then use the tweak manager to sign them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Hiding Apps&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LiveContainer offers three levels of app hiding:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock Apps&lt;/strong&gt;: In the app-specific settings, you can lock an app, requiring Face ID or a password to launch it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hide Locked Apps&lt;/strong&gt;: Once locked, you can hide the app. It will appear as a placeholder in the &#34;Hidden Apps&#34; section, and authentication is needed to view or launch it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strict Hiding Mode&lt;/strong&gt;: For complete invisibility, enable &#34;Strict Hiding Mode&#34; in LiveContainer&#39;s settings after authentication. Hidden apps will no longer appear in the interface. To access them, triple-tap the &#34;x Apps in total&#34; text on the main screen and authenticate to unlock the apps when you relaunch LiveContainer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export THEOS=/path/to/theos&#xA;git submodule update --init --recursive&#xA;make package&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Main executable&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Core of LiveContainer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contains the logic of setting up guest environment and loading guest app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If no app is selected, it loads LiveContainerSwiftUI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;LiveContainerSwiftUI&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SwiftUI rewrite of LiveContainerUI (by @hugeBlack)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lanaguage file &lt;code&gt;Localizable.xcstrings&lt;/code&gt; is in here for multilingual support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;TweakLoader&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A simple tweak injector, which loads CydiaSubstrate and load tweaks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Injected to every app you install in LiveContainer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;AltStoreTweak&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The tweak that got injected into SideStore/AltStore to retrieve certificate from it everytime it launches.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Patching guest executable&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Patch &lt;code&gt;__PAGEZERO&lt;/code&gt; segment: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Change &lt;code&gt;vmaddr&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;0xFFFFC000&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;0x100000000 - 0x4000&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Change &lt;code&gt;vmsize&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;0x4000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change &lt;code&gt;MH_EXECUTE&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;MH_DYLIB&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Inject a load command to load &lt;code&gt;TweakLoader.dylib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Patching &lt;code&gt;@executable_path&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Call &lt;code&gt;_NSGetExecutablePath&lt;/code&gt; with an invalid buffer pointer input -&amp;gt; SIGSEGV&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Do some &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer/raw/5ef1e6a/main.m#L74-L115&#34;&gt;magic stuff&lt;/a&gt; to overwrite the contents of executable_path.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Patching &lt;code&gt;NSBundle.mainBundle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This property is overwritten with the guest app&#39;s bundle.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bypassing Library Validation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;JIT is optional to bypass codesigning. In JIT-less mode, all executables are signed so this does not apply.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Derived from &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.xpnsec.com/restoring-dyld-memory-loading&#34;&gt;Restoring Dyld Memory Loading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;dlopening the executable&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Call &lt;code&gt;dlopen&lt;/code&gt; with the guest app&#39;s executable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TweakLoader loads all tweaks in the selected folder&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find the entry point&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Jump to the entry point&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The guest app&#39;s entry point calls &lt;code&gt;UIApplicationMain&lt;/code&gt; and start up like any other iOS apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Entitlements from the guest app are not applied to the host app. This isn&#39;t a big deal since sideloaded apps requires only basic entitlements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;App Permissions are globally applied.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Guest app containers are not sandboxed. This means one guest app can access other guest apps&#39; data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Only one guest app can run at a time. This is much more like 3 apps limit where you have to disable an app to run another (switching between app in LiveContainer is instant).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Remote push notification might not work. &lt;del&gt;If you have a paid developer account then you don&#39;t even have to use LiveContainer&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Querying custom URL schemes might not work(?)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TODO&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Isolate Keychain per app&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use ChOma instead of custom MachO parser&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/khanhduytran0/LiveContainer/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Apache License 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.xpnsec.com/restoring-dyld-memory-loading&#34;&gt;xpn&#39;s blogpost: Restoring Dyld Memory Loading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pinauten/PatchfinderUtils/raw/master/Sources/CFastFind/CFastFind.c&#34;&gt;LinusHenze&#39;s CFastFind&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pinauten/PatchfinderUtils/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/fishhook&#34;&gt;fishhook&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebook/fishhook/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;BSD 3-Clause license&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/saturngod/1224648&#34;&gt;MBRoundProgressView&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@haxi0 for icon&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@Vishram1123 for the initial shortcut implementation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@hugeBlack for SwiftUI contribution&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@Staubgeborener for automatic AltStore/SideStore source updater&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@fkunn1326 for improved app hiding&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;@slds1 for dynamic color feature&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>