<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Swift Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-08T01:49:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Swift in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp</title>
    <updated>2025-06-08T01:49:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-08:/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Language Server Protocol implementation for Swift and C-based languages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;SourceKit-LSP&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SourceKit-LSP is an implementation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/&#34;&gt;Language Server Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (LSP) for Swift and C-based languages. It provides intelligent editor functionality like code-completion and jump-to-definition to editors that support LSP. SourceKit-LSP is built on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apple/swift/tree/main/tools/SourceKit&#34;&gt;sourcekitd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://clang.llvm.org/extra/clangd.html&#34;&gt;clangd&lt;/a&gt; for high-fidelity language support, and provides a powerful source code index as well as cross-language support. SourceKit-LSP supports projects that use the Swift Package Manager and projects that generate a &lt;code&gt;compile_commands.json&lt;/code&gt; file, such as CMake.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SourceKit-LSP is included in the the Swift toolchains available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://swift.org/install/&#34;&gt;swift.org&lt;/a&gt; and is bundled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.apple.com/xcode/&#34;&gt;Xcode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swift.org/tools&#34;&gt;swift.org/tools&lt;/a&gt; has a list of popular editors that support LSP and can thus be hooked up to SourceKit-LSP to provide intelligent editor functionality as well as set-up guides.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT] SourceKit-LSP does not update its global index in the background or build Swift modules in the background. Thus, a lot of cross-module or global functionality is limited if the project hasn&#39;t been built recently. To update the index or rebuild the Swift modules, build your project or enable the experimental background indexing as described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp/main/Documentation/Enable%20Experimental%20Background%20Indexing.md&#34;&gt;Enable Experimental Background Indexing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about SourceKit-LSP, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp/main/Documentation&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] If you are using SourceKit-LSP with a SwiftPM project in which you need to pass additional arguments to the &lt;code&gt;swift build&lt;/code&gt; invocation, as is commonly the case for embedded projects, you need to teach SourceKit-LSP about those arguments as described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp/main/Documentation/Using%20SourceKit-LSP%20with%20Embedded%20Projects.md&#34;&gt;Using SourceKit-LSP with Embedded Projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you should hit any issues while using SourceKit-LSP, we appreciate bug reports on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;GitHub Issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute code to SourceKit-LSP, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/swiftlang/sourcekit-lsp/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>