<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-15T01:33:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>joaotavora/breadcrumb</title>
    <updated>2023-05-15T01:33:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-15:/joaotavora/breadcrumb</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/joaotavora/breadcrumb" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Emacs headerline indication of where you are in a large project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;M-x breadcrumb-mode&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/joaotavora/breadcrumb/master/screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Breadcrumbs are sequences of short strings indicating where you are in some big tree-like maze that is probably your code. Hopefully the screenshot above clears it up.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-x breadcrumb-mode&lt;/code&gt; is global mode. Will try to turn itself on conservatively and only if there&#39;s a project.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-x breadcrumb-local-mode&lt;/code&gt; is a buffer-local minor mode, if you don&#39;t want the default heuristics for turning it on everywhere.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s not much more to it. Breadcrumb will try to query &lt;code&gt;imenu.el&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;project.el&lt;/code&gt; for the best information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now, just download the &lt;code&gt;breadcrumb.el&lt;/code&gt; file and load it somehow.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;More usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want some leet modeline you may also manually put the mode-line constructs&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34;&gt;(:eval (breadcrumb-imenu-crumbs))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34;&gt;(:eval (breadcrumb-project-crumbs))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;in your settings of the &lt;code&gt;mode-line-format&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;header-line-format&lt;/code&gt; variables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tweaks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shape and size of each breadcrumb groups may be tweaked via &lt;code&gt;breadcrumb-imenu-max-length&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;breadcrumb-project-max-length&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;breadcrumb-imenu-crumb-separator&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;breadcrumb-project-crumb-separator&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The structure each of the breadcrumbs varies depending on whether either &lt;code&gt;project.el&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;imenu.el&lt;/code&gt; (or both) can do useful things for your buffer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Project breadcrumbs, this depends on whether &lt;code&gt;project.el&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s &lt;code&gt;project-current&lt;/code&gt; can guess what project the current buffer belongs to.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Imenu breadcrumbs, this varies. Depending on the major-mode author&#39;s taste, the Imenu tree (in variable &lt;code&gt;imenu--index-alist&lt;/code&gt;) may have different structure. Sometimes, minor mode also tweak the Imenu tree in useful ways. For example, with recent Eglot (I think Eglot 1.14+), managed buffers get extra region info added to it, which makes Breadcrumb show &#34;richer&#34; paths.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>