<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-20T01:34:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lazzalazza/org-footnote-assistant</title>
    <updated>2023-05-20T01:34:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-20:/lazzalazza/org-footnote-assistant</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lazzalazza/org-footnote-assistant" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A minor mode for editing and browsing org-footnotes from a sidebar&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Org-footnote-assistant&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A minor mode for editing and browsing org-footnotes from an indirect buffer in a side window.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The package &lt;strong&gt;org-footnote-assistant&lt;/strong&gt; is designed to enhance the functionality of footnotes in Org Mode. It provides additional features and keybindings to assist in navigating, editing, and managing footnotes within an Org Mode buffer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Improved Footnote Viewing and Editing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package might offer a solution to the limited inline viewing of Org Mode footnotes, which can often hinder the reviewing and modification of content. In Org Mode, the content of footnotes is not directly visible from the text, and vice versa, making it harder to seamlessly review or modify the content. Additionally, navigating between footnote references and their corresponding content can be cumbersome, disrupting the flow of reading or writing. With &lt;strong&gt;org-footnote-assistant&lt;/strong&gt;, you can easily navigate between footnote references, view their definitions in an editable buffer, and streamline your workflow when working with footnotes in Org Mode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lazzalazza/org-footnote-assistant/main/ofa.png&#34; alt=&#34;Org-footnote-assistant&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Functionality&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The package defines a minor mode called &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant-mode&lt;/code&gt; that can be toggled on or off. When activated, it adds several keybindings to the Org Mode keymap to facilitate working with footnotes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is an overview of the functionality provided by &lt;strong&gt;org-footnote-assistant&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navigation:&lt;/strong&gt; The package allows you to quickly navigate between footnote references in an Org Mode buffer. The keybinding &lt;code&gt;C-c C-n&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--goto-next-footnote&lt;/code&gt;) moves the cursor to the next footnote reference in the buffer, while &lt;code&gt;C-c C-p&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--goto-previous-footnote&lt;/code&gt;) moves to the previous footnote reference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definition Display:&lt;/strong&gt; The command &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--show-definition&lt;/code&gt; narrows the buffer to the region of the current footnote definition if the cursor is positioned at a footnote reference. It retrieves the label of the current footnote and uses it to determine the corresponding definition&#39;s location. The narrowed buffer with the footnote definition is displayed in a separate window.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnote Editing Window:&lt;/strong&gt; The function &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--create-editor-window&lt;/code&gt; is responsible for creating and managing the &#34;&lt;em&gt;footnote-editor&lt;/em&gt;&#34; buffer, which displays the narrowed region containing the footnote definition. If the &#34;&lt;em&gt;footnote-editor&lt;/em&gt;&#34; buffer already exists and is related to the current buffer, it narrows the buffer to the new definition region and displays it. If the buffer exists but is not related to the current buffer, it is killed and a new indirect buffer is created. If the buffer does not exist, a new indirect buffer is created.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customized Footnote Definition Jumping:&lt;/strong&gt; The package overrides the default behavior of &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-goto-definition&lt;/code&gt; with the modified function &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--goto-definition&lt;/code&gt;. This function integrates with &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant--create-editor-window&lt;/code&gt; to jump to the definition of a specified footnote label. It narrows the buffer to the definition region and positions the cursor at the appropriate location.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Footnote Reference Searching:&lt;/strong&gt; The package also modifies the behavior of &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-goto-previous-reference&lt;/code&gt; by advising the function with &lt;code&gt;org-goto-previous-reference-advice&lt;/code&gt;. This advice ensures that if the current buffer is the &#34;&lt;em&gt;footnote-editor&lt;/em&gt;&#34; buffer, the focus is switched to the base buffer where the original footnote reference was found.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eeasier Footnote Deletion:&lt;/strong&gt; To delete a footnote, you can use the &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant-delete-footnote&lt;/code&gt; function. By default, this function prompts for confirmation before deleting the footnote. However, you can customize this behavior by setting the variable &lt;code&gt;org-footnote-assistant-ask-before-delete&lt;/code&gt; to nil in your Emacs configuration file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In summary, &#34;org-footnote-assistant&#34; provides convenient keybindings for navigating between footnote references, displaying the definitions in an editable buffer, and customizing the behavior of footnote definition jumping. It enhances the overall experience of working with footnotes in Org Mode by simplifying navigation and providing a dedicated editing environment for footnote definitions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback and Collaboration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is my first Org Mode package, and I am eager to receive feedback and external input from the community. I encourage you to try out the package, test its functionality, and explore how it can improve your experience working with footnotes in Org Mode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is valuable in enhancing and extending the functionality of the code. If you have ideas for additional features or improvements, I am open to suggestions. Together, we can make this package more robust and user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip</title>
    <updated>2023-05-20T01:34:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-20:/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Display Flycheck error messages using popup.el&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;flycheck-popup-tip&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip/raw/master/COPYING&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License GPL 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveralls.io/github/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is extension for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flycheck.org/&#34;&gt;Flycheck&lt;/a&gt;. It implements minor-mode for displaying errors from Flycheck using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/auto-complete/popup-el&#34;&gt;popup.el&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flycheck/flycheck-popup-tip/master/screenshots/01.png&#34; alt=&#34;flycheck-popup-tip screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flycheck/flycheck-pos-tip&#34;&gt;another official flycheck-pos-tip&lt;/a&gt; extension for displaying errors under point. However, it does not display popup if you run Emacs under TTY. It displays message on echo area and that is often used for ELDoc. Also, popups made by &lt;code&gt;pos-tip&lt;/code&gt; library does not always look good, especially on macOS and Windows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Melpa&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Package is available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://melpa.org/&#34;&gt;Melpa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In your &lt;a href=&#34;http://cask.github.io&#34;&gt;Cask&lt;/a&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cl&#34;&gt;(source gnu)&#xA;(source melpa)&#xA;&#xA;(depends-on &#34;flycheck-popup-tip&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In your &lt;code&gt;init.el&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cl&#34;&gt;(with-eval-after-load &#39;flycheck&#xA;  &#39;(add-hook &#39;flycheck-mode-hook &#39;flycheck-popup-tip-mode))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Configuration options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is only one configuration option, &lt;code&gt;flycheck-popup-tip-error-prefix&lt;/code&gt;. Default value is &#34;\u27a4 &#34;: &lt;code&gt;➤ &lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cl&#34;&gt;(custom-set-variables&#xA; &#39;(flycheck-popup-tip-error-prefix &#34;* &#34;))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage with &lt;code&gt;flycheck-pos-tip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are planning to use &lt;code&gt;flycheck-pos-tip&lt;/code&gt; with GUI Emacs and this extension on TTY, you can do it with following configuration:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-elisp&#34;&gt;(eval-after-load &#39;flycheck&#xA;  (if (display-graphic-p)&#xA;      (flycheck-pos-tip-mode)&#xA;    (flycheck-popup-tip-mode)))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-elisp&#34;&gt;(setq flycheck-pos-tip-display-errors-tty-function #&#39;flycheck-popup-tip-show-popup)&#xA;(flycheck-pos-tip-mode)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That will help if you start Emacs in GUI, but run emacsclient in TTY.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome all kinds of contributions, whether you write patches, open pull requests, write documentation, help others with Flycheck issues, or just tell other people about your experiences with Flycheck. Please take a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flycheck.org/en/latest/contributor/contributing.html&#34;&gt;Contributor’s Guide&lt;/a&gt; for help and guidance about contributing to Flycheck.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Running tests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;UNDERCOVER_FORCE=true UNDERCOVER_CONFIG=&#39;(&#34;*.el&#34; (:report-file &#34;local-report.json&#34;) (:send-report nil))&#39; cask exec buttercup -L . -L tests&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will also generate &lt;code&gt;local-report.json&lt;/code&gt; file where you can check if coverage dropped below 100%.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>