<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-23T01:39:01Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>emacsmirror/compat</title>
    <updated>2022-06-23T01:39:01Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-23:/emacsmirror/compat</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/emacsmirror/compat" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Compatibility Library&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;COMPATibility Library for Emacs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Find here the source for compat.el, a forwards-compatibility library for (GNU) Emacs Lisp, versions 24.3 and newer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intended audience of this library aren&#39;t day-to-day users, but package developers that wish to make use of newer functionality, not provided in older versions of Emacs, without breaking compatibility for users bound to specific Emacs releases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 24.3 is chosen as the oldest version, because this is the newest version on CentOS 7. It is intended to preserve compatibility for at least as the Centos 7 reaches &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.centos.org/About/Product&#34;&gt;EOL&lt;/a&gt;, 2024.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are developing a package with compat.el in mind, consider loading &lt;code&gt;compat-help&lt;/code&gt; (on your system, not in a package) to get relevant notes inserted into the help buffers of functions that are implemented or advised in compat.el.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that compat.el provides a few prefixed function, ie. functions with a &lt;code&gt;compat-&lt;/code&gt; prefix. These are used to provide extended functionality for commands that are already defined (&lt;code&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;assoc&lt;/code&gt;, ...). It might be possible to transform these into advised functions later on, so that the modified functionality is accessible without a prefix. Feedback on this point is appreciated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;compat.el shouldn&#39;t be installed directly, but downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;http://elpa.gnu.org/packages/compat.html&#34;&gt;GNU ELPA&lt;/a&gt;. If necessary, this can be done using M-x package-install-file in the current working directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intended use-case for this library is for package developers to add as a dependency in the header:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;;; Package-Requires: ((emacs &#34;24.3&#34;) (compat &#34;28.1.1.1&#34;))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and later on a&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(require &#39;compat)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will load all non-prefixed definitions (functions and macros with a leading &lt;code&gt;compat-&lt;/code&gt;). To load these, an additional&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;(require &#39;compat-XY) ; e.g. 26&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;will be necessary, to load compatibility code for Emacs version XY.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to subscribe to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.sr.ht/~pkal/compat-announce&#34;&gt;compat-announce&lt;/a&gt; mailing list to be notified when new versions are released or relevant changes are made.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As compat.el is distribed as part of GNU ELPA, and therefore requires a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Copyright-Assignment.html&#34;&gt;copyright assignment&lt;/a&gt; to the FSF, for all non-trivial code contributions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Source code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compat is developed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sr.ht/~pkal/compat&#34;&gt;SourceHut&lt;/a&gt;. A restricted &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/phikal/compat.el&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; mirror is also provided.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bug and patches&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patches and comments can be sent to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.sr.ht/~pkal/compat-devel&#34;&gt;development mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. Bug reports and issues should be directed to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://todo.sr.ht/~pkal/compat&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; (also accessible via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:~pkal/compat@todo.sr.ht&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/phikal/compat.el&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to submit patches (&#34;Pull Request&#34;). These may include issues in the compatibility code, missing definitions or performance issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When contributing, make sure to provide test and use the existing tests defined in compat-test.el. These can be easily executed using the bundled Makefile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;make test&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Distribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;compat.el and all other files in this directory are distributed under the GPL, Version 3 (like Emacs itself).&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>