<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-20T01:34:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>bastibe/annotate.el</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T01:34:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-20:/bastibe/annotate.el</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Annotate.el&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;#+OPTIONS: html-postamble:nil html-preamble:nil toc:nil #+AUTHOR: #+TITLE: Annotate.el&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://elpa.nongnu.org/nongnu/annotate.svg][https://elpa.nongnu.org/nongnu/annotate.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[http://melpa.org/#/annotate][http://melpa.org/packages/annotate-badge.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[http://stable.melpa.org/#/annotate][http://stable.melpa.org/packages/annotate-badge.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;introduction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package provides a minor mode &lt;del&gt;annotate-mode&lt;/del&gt;, which can add annotations to arbitrary files without changing the files themselves. This is very useful for code reviews. When &lt;del&gt;annotate-mode&lt;/del&gt; is active, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; will create, edit, or delete annotations. [[https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bastibe/annotate.el/master/example.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Usage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Quick start&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With an active region, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; creates a new annotation for that region. With no active region, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; will create an annotation for the word under point. If point is on an annotated region, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; will edit that annotation instead of creating a new one. Typing &lt;del&gt;C-c C-d&lt;/del&gt; or clearing the annotation deletes them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;del&gt;C-c ]&lt;/del&gt; to jump to the next annotation and &lt;del&gt;C-c [&lt;/del&gt; to jump to the previous annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Metadata&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current database for annotations is contained in the file indicated by the variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-file&lt;/del&gt; (=~/.emacs.d/annotations= by default) but each user can change this value in a dynamic way using the command &lt;del&gt;annotate-switch-db&lt;/del&gt;. This command will take care to refresh/redraw all annotations in the buffers that uses &lt;del&gt;annotate-mode&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The database holds the hash of each annotated file so it can print a warning if the file has been modified outside Emacs (for example).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Warning can be suppressed setting the variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-warn-if-hash-mismatch&lt;/del&gt; to nil.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that switching database, in this context, means rebinding the aforementioned variable (&lt;del&gt;annotate-file&lt;/del&gt;). This means than no more than a single database can be active for each Emacs session.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an empty annotation database (in memory) is saved the database file is deleted instead, if &lt;del&gt;annotate-database-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt; is non nil (the default) a confirmation action is asked to the user before actually remove the file from the file system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-file&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-warn-if-hash-mismatch&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-database-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** Non centralized database&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use multiple database in the same Emacs session &lt;del&gt;annotate-file&lt;/del&gt; should be made [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/elisp/Buffer_002dLocal-Variables.html][buffer-local]],&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;see:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el/issues/68][this thread]] and, in particular [[https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el/issues/68#issuecomment-728218022][this message]].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if the customizable variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-file-buffer-local&lt;/del&gt; is non-nil (default &lt;del&gt;nil&lt;/del&gt;), for each annotated file an annotation database is saved under the same directory that contains the annotated file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The name of the annotation database is built concatenating the name of the annotated file without the optional extension and the string value bound to the customizable variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-buffer-local-database-extension&lt;/del&gt; (default: &lt;del&gt;notes&lt;/del&gt;), example follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;| annotated file | annotations file | |------------------+----------------------| | /home/user/foo.c | /home/user/foo.notes | |------------------+----------------------|&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important note: if &lt;del&gt;/home/user/foo.notes&lt;/del&gt; exists, &lt;em&gt;will be overwritten&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-file-buffer-local&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-buffer-local-database-extension&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** Uninstalling&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users of [[https://github.com/emacscollective/no-littering][no-littering]] can take advantage of its packages generated files management.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** keybindings&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; (function annotate-annotate) Creates a new annotation for that region.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With no active region, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; will create an annotation for the word under point. If point is on an annotated region, &lt;del&gt;C-c C-a&lt;/del&gt; will edit that annotation instead of creating a new one. Clearing the annotation deletes them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt; is non nil (the default is &lt;em&gt;nil&lt;/em&gt;) a confirmation action is asked, using &lt;del&gt;y-or-n-p&lt;/del&gt;, to the user before actually remove the annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If point is the newline character and the customizable variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-endline-annotate-whole-line&lt;/del&gt; is not nil (default is non nil) the whole line is annotated (or the next if the line is empty).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the line contains a single annotation that cover all the line, annotating the newline will ask to edit the annotation. If &lt;del&gt;annotate-endline-annotate-whole-line&lt;/del&gt; is nil annotating a newline will signal an error.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a numeric prefix the annotations will be displayed with the faces indicated in &lt;del&gt;annotate-endline-annotate-whole-line&lt;/del&gt; and &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-text-faces&lt;/del&gt;, respectively. The numeric prefix is used as index in the lists bound to the aforementioned variables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first theme can be addressed by the prefix &lt;del&gt;1&lt;/del&gt;, the second by the prefix &lt;del&gt;2&lt;/del&gt; and so on.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-column&lt;/del&gt;; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt;; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-max-size-not-place-new-line&lt;/del&gt;; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-position-policy&lt;/del&gt;; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-endline-annotate-whole-line&lt;/del&gt;; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-text-faces&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;del&gt;C-c C-d&lt;/del&gt; Delete an annotation under point, if such annotation exists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt; is non nil (the default is &lt;em&gt;nil&lt;/em&gt;) a confirmation action is asked, using &lt;del&gt;y-or-n-p&lt;/del&gt;, to the user before actually remove the annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-confirm-deletion&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;del&gt;C-c ]&lt;/del&gt; (function annotate-goto-next-annotation) Jump to the next annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;del&gt;C-c [&lt;/del&gt; (function annotate-goto-previous-annotation) Jump to the previous annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** &lt;del&gt;C-c C-s&lt;/del&gt; (function annotate-show-annotation-summary) Show summary window.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A window with a list of annotated files together with their annotations is shown. If &lt;del&gt;annotate-summary-ask-query&lt;/del&gt; is non nil (default is &lt;del&gt;t&lt;/del&gt;) then a prompt is shown where the user can insert a query to filter the annotation database, see &#34;Query Language&#34; below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The summary window allow editing and removing of annotation using the provided buttons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The annotation text can be pressed to and will open the annotated file, placing the cursor at the point where the corresponding annotated text appears.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-summary-ask-query&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Exporting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Annotations can be exported &lt;del&gt;annotate-export-annotations&lt;/del&gt; as commented unified diffs, like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bastibe/annotate.el/master/diff-example.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, they can be integrated &lt;del&gt;annotate-integrate-annotations&lt;/del&gt; as comments into the current buffer, like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bastibe/annotate.el/master/integrate-example.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-integrate-marker&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-diff-export-options&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-integrate-highlight&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-fallback-comment&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Importing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An annotation database file can be imported using the command &lt;del&gt;annotate-import-annotations&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When importing, overlapping annotations will be merged in a single annotation with the new annotated text that maximizes the portion of text annotated, e.g.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC The quick brown fox ← text ^^^^^^^^ ← first annotation ******** ← second annotation +++++++++++++ ← merged annotation #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The text of the merged annotation is the concatenated text of the two annotations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that importing a database will modify permanently the file bound to the variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-file&lt;/del&gt;. If unsure of the results, backup that file before importing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-database-confirm-import&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alternative visualization of annotations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For typographically difficult scenarios (or just because you prefer it), such as variable-width fonts or overlay-heavy modes, the default visualization system that renders the annotation into the buffer could not properly works.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this case the users can switch to a &#34;pop-up&#34; style annotation setting to a non-nil value the variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-use-echo-area&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When such variable&#39;s value is not null, moving the mouse pointer over the annotated text will temporary show the annotation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The actual visuals of this &#34;pop-up&#34; can be different depending of your system&#39;s setup (see [[https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el/pull/81][this pull request]] for a couple of examples.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moreover if &lt;del&gt;annotate-use-echo-area&lt;/del&gt; and &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor&lt;/del&gt; value &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; non null, placing the cursor over an annotated text region will print the annotation&#39;s text in the minibuffer prefixed by the value of customizable variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor-prefix&lt;/del&gt;, after a delay (in seconds) defined by the variable &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor-delay&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another alternative way to show annotations is provided by the command: &lt;del&gt;annotate-summary-of-file-from-current-pos&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calling this command will show a summary window that prints all the annotations related to annotated text that appears (in the active buffer) beyond the current cursor position.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;**** related customizable variable - &lt;del&gt;annotate-use-echo-area&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor-prefix&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-print-annotation-under-cursor-delay&lt;/del&gt; - &lt;del&gt;annotate-summary-of-file-from-current-pos&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Other commands&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** annotate-switch-db&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This command will ask the user for a new annotation database files, load it and refresh all the annotations contained in each buffer where annotate minor mode is active.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the docstring for more information and [[https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el/issues/68][this thread]] for a possible workflow where this command could be useful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** annotate-toggle-annotation-text Shows or hides annotation&#39;s text under cursor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** annotate-toggle-all-annotations-text Shows or hides the annotation&#39;s text in the whole buffer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More documentation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please check &lt;del&gt;M-x customize-group RET annotate&lt;/del&gt; as there is extensive documentation for each customizable variable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;BUGS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Known bugs&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Annotations in org-mode source blocks will be underlined, but the annotations don&#39;t show up. This is likely a fundamental incompatibility with the way source blocks are highlighted and the way annotations are displayed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because of a limitation in the Emacs display routines &lt;del&gt;scroll-down-line&lt;/del&gt; could get stuck on a annotated line. So no fix can be provided by the authors of &lt;del&gt;annotate.el&lt;/del&gt;, a possible workaround is to call the command with a numeric prefix equals to one plus the number of annotation text lines below the annotated text.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text foo bar baz annotation #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;needs a prefix of 2: &lt;del&gt;C-u 2 M-x scroll-down-line&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But note that:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text foo bar baz annotation #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Needs no prefix.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Deleting the first character of an annotated text will remove the annotation (this turned out to be useful, though).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Report bugs&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To report bugs please, point your browser to the [[https://github.com/bastibe/annotate.el/issues][issue tracker]].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Query Language&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The summary window can shows results filtered by criteria specified with a very simple query language, the basis syntax for that language is shown below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text [file-mask] [(and | or) [not] regex-note [(and | or) [not] regexp-note ...]] #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;where:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;file-mask :: is a regular expression that should match the path of file the annotation refers to;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;and, or, not :: you guess? Classics logical operators;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;regex-note :: the text of annotation must match this regular expression.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Examples&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text lisp$ and TODO #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;matches the text &lt;del&gt;TODO&lt;/del&gt; in all lisp files&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parenthesis can be used for the expression related to the text of annotation, like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text lisp$ and (TODO or important) #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;the same as above but checks also for string `important&#39;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text /home/foo/ #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;matches all the annotation that refers to file in the directory &lt;del&gt;/home/foo&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text /home/foo/ and not minor #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;matches all the annotation that refers to file in the directory &lt;del&gt;/home/foo&lt;/del&gt; and that not contains the text &lt;del&gt;minor&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC text .* and &#34;not&#34; #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;the quotation mark (&#34;) can be used to escape strings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a shortcut, an empty query will match everything (just press &lt;del&gt;return&lt;/del&gt; at prompt).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;FAQ&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the package does not respect the customizable variable&#39;s value of &lt;del&gt;annotate-annotation-position-policy&lt;/del&gt;, is this a bug?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No it is not, when a line which is using a non default font is annotated the software force the &lt;del&gt;:new-line&lt;/del&gt; policy, that is the annotation will be displayed on a new line regardless of the value of the variable mentioned in the question.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is necessary to prevent the annotation to be pushed beyond the window limits if an huge font is used by the annotated text.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LICENSE&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package is released under the MIT license, see file [[./LICENSE][LICENSE]]&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>timdrichards/emacs-config</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T01:34:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-20:/timdrichards/emacs-config</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/timdrichards/emacs-config" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;emacs configuration directory&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;emacs-config&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;emacs configuration directory&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>