<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-24T01:33:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>jackrusher/scimacs</title>
    <updated>2023-03-24T01:33:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-24:/jackrusher/scimacs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jackrusher/scimacs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Small Clojure Interpreter (SCI) integrated with emacs as a loadable module&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;scimacs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/babashka/sci&#34;&gt;Small Clojure Interpreter&lt;/a&gt; (sci) compiled to a native library and integrated with emacs as a loadable module.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This code is very not ready for general consumption!&lt;/strong&gt; If you aren&#39;t excited about figuring out how to build it on your platform, it&#39;s probably not ready for you yet.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Requires Clojure, babashka, GraalVM version 22.3.1, and Rust.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using a recent version of MacOS, have all the deps installed, and are a relatively lucky person, it might be as easy as doing this from the top-level of this project&#39;s directory structure (making sure that the Java on your path is the GraalVM version mentioned above):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ bb all&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a small &lt;code&gt;elisp&lt;/code&gt; file that can be used to make sure things work. It&#39;s invoked like this (&lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt; if you have to):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ ./test.el&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the shebang line in this file assumes a particular version of emacs at the path where homebrew installs it. It&#39;s entirely likely that you have a different version installed in a different place, so you may prefer to use:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$ emacs --script test.el&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;code&gt;test.el&lt;/code&gt; for how to load this module in emacs. It currently has a &lt;em&gt;single function&lt;/em&gt; API. Additional Work will be required to make things more pleasant to use from within emacs, including the addition of some callback functions on the &lt;code&gt;sci&lt;/code&gt; side to operate on buffers and such.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>