<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-17T01:30:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kickingvegas/casual</title>
    <updated>2025-01-17T01:30:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-17:/kickingvegas/casual</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kickingvegas/casual" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A collection of opinionated keyboard-driven user interfaces for various built-in Emacs modes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;[[https://melpa.org/#/casual][file:https://melpa.org/packages/casual-badge.svg]] [[https://stable.melpa.org/#/casual][file:https://stable.melpa.org/packages/casual-badge.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Casual&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casual is a project to re-imagine the primary user interface for Emacs using keyboard-driven menus.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emacs has many commands that are easy to forget if not used frequently. Menus are a user interface (UI) affordance that offers discoverability and recognition. While menus are commonly associated with mouse-driven UI, the inclusion of [[https://github.com/magit/transient][Transient]] in Emacs core allows for building menus that are keyboard-driven instead. This appeals to users that prefer keyboard-driven workflows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casual organizes itself primarily around the different built-in modes Emacs provides. For each mode Casual supports, there is a bespoke designed library of Transient menus for that mode&#39;s command set.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casual has no aims to be a mutually exclusive user interface. All existing user interfaces to commands (keybinding, mini-buffer prompt, mouse menus) are still available to the user.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the motivations and design considerations for Casual as well as seeing it at work, please watch the presentation [[https://emacsconf.org/2024/talks/casual/][“Re-imagining the Emacs User Experience with Casual Suite”]] from EmacsConf 2024.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Goals&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To provide a keyboard-driven menu UI toolkit for common Emacs commands.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To allow for casual discovery and use of infrequently used Emacs commands.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To be a frequently used interface to the modes Casual does support.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Non-Goals&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Full coverage of all Emacs commands. Casual is not intended to be a power user tool nor is it intended to be a replacement for mouse-driven menus. Casual has no intent to exhaustively cover all modes available in Emacs with keyboard-driven menus.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Strict adherence to Emacs command naming. While Casual is &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;/em&gt; in alignment with Emacs command naming, there are cases where it will make an opinionated change if the name is deemed too vague or idiomatic.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No intention is made by Casual to help on-board users to the existing default bindings of a mode, nor to cater to users who already know them. That said, many existing default Emacs bindings are replicated in Casual. Such correspondence should be considered incidental.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UX Stability (for now). Given that Casual is early in its life-cycle, expect changes to its user experience in terms of menu hierarchy and keybinding choices in future releases.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Editorially, all design decisions for Casual are ultimately the opinion of Charles Y. Choi.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Table of Contents :TOC_3:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#casual][Casual]] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#goals][Goals]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#non-goals][Non-Goals]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#supported-modes][Supported Modes]] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#agenda-elisp-library-casual-agenda][Agenda (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-agenda&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#bookmarks-elisp-library-casual-bookmarks][Bookmarks (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-bookmarks&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#calc-elisp-library-casual-calc][Calc (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-calc&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#calendar-elisp-library-casual-calendar][Calendar (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-calendar&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#dired-elisp-library-casual-dired][Dired (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-dired&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#editkit-elisp-library-casual-editkit][EditKit (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-editkit&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#ibuffer-elisp-library-casual-ibuffer][IBuffer (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-ibuffer&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#info-elisp-library-casual-info][Info (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-info&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#i-search-elisp-library-casual-isearch][I-Search (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-isearch&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#re-builder-elisp-library-casual-re-builder][Re-Builder (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-re-builder&lt;/del&gt;)]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#requirements][Requirements]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#install][Install]] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#upgrading-to-casual-2x][Upgrading to Casual 2.x]] &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;[[#if-you-do-not-use-use-package-to-configure-casual][If you do not use &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; to configure Casual]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;[[#if-you-have-used-use-package-to-configure-casual][If you have used &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; to configure Casual]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[[#a-note-on-package-dependencies][A Note on Package Dependencies]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#customization][Customization]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#asks][Asks]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#common-menu-actions][Common Menu Actions]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#development][Development]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#sponsorship][Sponsorship]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#see-also][See Also]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[#acknowledgments][Acknowledgments]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Supported Modes ** [[file:docs/agenda.org][Agenda]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-agenda&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for Org Agenda to help you plan your day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/agenda.org][file:docs/images/casual-agenda-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/bookmarks.org][Bookmarks]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-bookmarks&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for editing your bookmark collection.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/bookmarks.org][file:docs/images/casual-bookmarks-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/calc.org][Calc]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-calc&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for Emacs Calc, an embarrasingly feature-rich calculator.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/calc.org][file:docs/images/casual-calc-tmenu.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/calendar.org][Calendar]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-calendar&lt;/del&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An interface for [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Calendar_002fDiary.html][Calendar &amp;amp; Diary]].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/images/casual-calendar-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/dired.org][Dired]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-dired&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for the venerable file manager Dired.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/dired.org][file:docs/images/casual-dired-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/editkit.org][EditKit]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-editkit&lt;/del&gt;) A cornucopia of interfaces for the different editing features (e.g. marking, copying, killing, duplicating, transforming, deleting) of Emacs. Included are interfaces for rectangle, register, macro, and project commands.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/editkit.org][file:docs/images/casual-editkit-main-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/ibuffer.org][IBuffer]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-ibuffer&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for the Info documentation system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/info.org][file:docs/images/casual-ibuffer-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/info.org][Info]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-info&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for the Info documentation system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/info.org][file:docs/images/casual-info-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/isearch.org][I-Search]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-isearch&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for the many commands supported by I-Search.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/isearch.org][file:docs/images/casual-isearch-tmenu.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** [[file:docs/re-builder.org][Re-Builder]] (Elisp library: &lt;del&gt;casual-re-builder&lt;/del&gt;) An interface for the Emacs regular expression tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:docs/re-builder.org][file:docs/images/casual-re-builder-screenshot.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users can choose any or all of the user interfaces made available by Casual at their pleasure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Requirements Casual requires usage of&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Emacs ≥ 29.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casual has been verified with the following configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Emacs 29.4 (macOS 14.5, Ubuntu Linux 22.04.4 LTS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install Standard installation of the &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt; package is via MELPA distribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configuration of a particular Casual user interface is performed per mode. Go to the &lt;em&gt;Install&lt;/em&gt; section for a mode of interest below for guidance on its configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/agenda.org::*Install][Agenda]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/bookmarks.org::*Install][Bookmarks]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/calc.org::*Install][Calc]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/calendar.org::*Install][Calendar]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/dired.org::*Install][Dired]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/editkit.org::*Install][EditKit]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/ibuffer.org::*Install][IBuffer]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/info.org::*Install][Info]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/isearch.org::*Install][I-Search]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[file:docs/re-builder.org::*Install][Re-Builder]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** Upgrading to Casual 2.x If you have been using an earlier version 1.x of Casual, thank you. Please use the following guidance:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** If you do not use &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; to configure Casual Before installing Casual, you should update all of your existing Casual packages. This is most easily done via the [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Package-Menu.html][package menu buffer]]. After updating your packages, install the &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Migrate your existing Casual packages from 1.x to 2.x by running the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+BEGIN_SRC elisp M-x load-library casual M-x casual-upgrade-base-to-version-2 #+END_SRC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any Casual v1.x packages that have been superseded by this package will be uninstalled.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While not necessary, it is recommended to run &lt;del&gt;M-x package-autoremove&lt;/del&gt; to purge any dangling dependent packages. Cautious readers can choose to audit any packages that are targeted to be removed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** If you have used &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; to configure Casual For version 2.x going forward, I (Charles Choi) have decided to not offer any documented guidance on using &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; to configure Casual due my lack of expertise in using it. I leave it to more skilled readers to determine how to best use [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/use-package/][use-package]] for their configuration. Please also note that this is not a prohibition on using &lt;del&gt;use-package&lt;/del&gt; with Casual. I am simply admitting that I don&#39;t know how to use it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, if you have used &lt;del&gt;:ensure t&lt;/del&gt; to install a superseded package, you /must/ remove that configuration. After doing so, please follow the above instructions for installing &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;** A Note on Package Dependencies Casual requires a recent installation of Transient 0.6.0+ from either [[https://elpa.gnu.org/packages/transient.html][ELPA]] or [[https://melpa.org/#/transient][MELPA]]. If your version of Emacs is ≤ 30 but also includes Transient as a built-in package, you will need to set the customizable variable &lt;del&gt;package-install-upgrade-built-in&lt;/del&gt; to &lt;del&gt;t&lt;/del&gt; to enable updating it via &lt;del&gt;package.el&lt;/del&gt;. Set this variable and proceed with installing Casual. Alternately invoking &lt;del&gt;package-install&lt;/del&gt; with a prefix (&lt;del&gt;C-u&lt;/del&gt;) will temporarily coerce the update of dependent built-in packages (example: &lt;del&gt;C-u M-x package-install&lt;/del&gt; &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you already have the latest version of Magit installed (via [[https://elpa.nongnu.org/nongnu/magit.html][non-GNU ELPA]] or [[https://melpa.org/#/magit][MELPA]]), you can bypass the above instruction as Magit already includes the Transient package as a dependency.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Customization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users who wish to extend or alter existing Casual menus can do so via the mechanisms offered by the Transient package (see [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_mono/transient.html#Modifying-Existing-Transients][Modifying Existing Transients]]).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Casual menus can also be configured to use Unicode symbols for labels. This is controlled by the variable &lt;del&gt;casual-lib-use-unicode&lt;/del&gt; which can be customized via a mode&#39;s settings menu. If &lt;del&gt;casual-lib-use-unicode&lt;/del&gt; is set to &lt;del&gt;t&lt;/del&gt;, it is also recommended that the variable &lt;del&gt;transient-align-variable-pitch&lt;/del&gt; also be set to &lt;del&gt;t&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Asks As Casual is new, we are looking for early adopters! Your [[https://github.com/kickingvegas/casual/discussions][feedback]] is welcome as it will likely impact Casual&#39;s evolution, particularly with regards to UI.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Common Menu Actions Casual is built using Transient menus and as such adopts its default behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each menu item has a /key/ and a /label/. The /key/ is what is typed by the user to select the menu item. A key can be prefixed with a meta (M-) or control (C-) key.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Transient supports nested menus. Exiting a menu can be done in two ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;C-g&lt;/del&gt; will exit the current sub-menu and return you back to its parent menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;C-q&lt;/del&gt; will exit you completely from a Transient menu stack.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a mouse is available, a menu item can be selected by moving the mouse cursor over its label and pressing down button 1.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pressing the &lt;del&gt;?&lt;/del&gt; key or &lt;del&gt;C-h&lt;/del&gt; will toggle help for all the menu items. Press the key of interest to get help for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When a Transient menu is raised, a prefix argument (&lt;del&gt;C-u&lt;/del&gt;) and an optional argument can be entered before selecting a menu item.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Development For users who wish to help contribute to Casual or personally customize it for their own usage, please read the [[docs/developer.org][developer documentation]].&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sponsorship If you enjoy using Casual, consider making a modest financial contribution to help support its development and maintenance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://www.buymeacoffee.com/kickingvegas][file:docs/images/default-yellow.png]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;See Also While the package &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt; focuses on user interfaces for built-in Emacs modes, there are other third party packages which receive the “Casual” treatment. Two such packages are:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[https://github.com/kickingvegas/casual-avy][Casual Avy]] (Elisp package: &lt;del&gt;casual-avy&lt;/del&gt;) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An interface for the highly capable Avy navigation package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[[https://github.com/kickingvegas/casual-symbol-overlay][Casual Symbol Overlay]] (Elisp package: &lt;del&gt;casual-symbol-overlay&lt;/del&gt;) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An interface for the Symbol Overlay package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users interested in getting all current and future Casual interfaces for both built-in and third party packages should install [[https://github.com/kickingvegas/casual-suite][Casual Suite]], which includes all of the above packages including &lt;del&gt;casual&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Acknowledgments A heartfelt thanks to all the contributors to [[https://github.com/magit/transient][Transient]], [[https://magit.vc][Magit]], [[https://orgmode.org][Org Mode]], and [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/][Emacs]]. This package would not be possible without your efforts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+HTML: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;© 2024-2025 Charles Y. Choi&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>