<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-15T01:27:07Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>manateelazycat/holo-layer</title>
    <updated>2023-08-15T01:27:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-15:/manateelazycat/holo-layer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/manateelazycat/holo-layer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HoloLayer is a multimedia layer plugin designed specifically for Emacs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;English | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/manateelazycat/holo-layer/master/README.zh-CN.md&#34;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HoloLayer is a multimedia layer plugin specifically designed for Emacs. It is developed based on PyQt, aiming to significantly enhance the visual experience of Emacs. The plugin provides a series of visual enhancement features, including modern window borders, window jump prompts, cursor animations, window screenshots, transparent floating terminals, and real-time dictionaries, etc. These features not only make the Emacs interface look more modern, but also ensure that the performance of Emacs will not be affected.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install Emacs 28 or above (For MacOS, please use Emacs without fullscreen)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install Python dependencies: &lt;code&gt;pip3 install epc sexpdata six inflect PyQt6 PyQt6-Qt6 PyQt6-sip&lt;/code&gt; (For ArchLinux, please use pacman to install PyQt6)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;git clone&lt;/code&gt; to download this repository, and replace the load-path path in the configuration below&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the following code to your configuration file ~/.emacs:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-elisp&#34;&gt;(add-to-list &#39;load-path &#34;&amp;lt;path-to-holo-layer&amp;gt;&#34;)&#xA;(require &#39;holo-layer)&#xA;(holo-layer-enable)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: If you are using Conda or other virtual environments, please first set &lt;code&gt;holo-layer-python-command&lt;/code&gt; to the corresponding Python path.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Jelly Cursor Animation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img style=&#34;height: auto; width: 80%; object-fit: contain&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/manateelazycat/holo-layer/master/demo/jelly-cursor.gif&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-active-window-color: The border color of the active window, only displayed when there are more than two windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-inactive-window-color: The border color of the inactive window, only displayed when there are more than two windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-enable-cursor-animation: Whether to enable the animation of the jelly cursor, it is off by default&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-cursor-color: The color of the jelly cursor, by default it is the same as the background color of the Emacs cursor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-cursor-alpha: The Alpha transparency of the jelly cursor, the default is 200, completely transparent is 0, opaque is 255&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-cursor-animation-interval: The interval time of the jelly cursor animation, the default is 10ms, don&#39;t worry about the time interval, because the animation effect is drawn with PyQt multithreading, it does not affect Emacs performance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-cursor-block-commands: If in some cases you do not want to display cursor animations, you can add the command string to this list, for example, after &lt;code&gt;self-insert-command&lt;/code&gt; is added to the list, inserting characters will not produce animations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-place-info-text-color: Text color of the information at the cursor, the default is the foreground color of &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-place-info-background-color: Background color of the information at the cursor, the default is the background color of &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-place-info-font-size: The font size of the information at the cursor, the default is 18&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-show-place-info-p: Displays information at the cursor in the top right corner of the screen, such as the translation of the word at the cursor, default is off&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-window-number-color: The color of the window jump number, used to jump windows with the &lt;code&gt;holo-layer-jump-to-window&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-window-number-font-size: The font size of the window jump number, the default is 40&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;holo-layer-hide-mode-line: Enable this option to hide the mode-line, it is disabled by default&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For other issues, please use the command &lt;code&gt;emacs -q&lt;/code&gt; and only add holo-layer configuration for a comparison test. If &lt;code&gt;emacs -q&lt;/code&gt; can work normally, please check your personal configuration file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the problem still exists under the &lt;code&gt;emacs -q&lt;/code&gt; environment, please go &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/manateelazycat/holo-layer/issues/new&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to provide feedback, and attach the content of the &lt;code&gt;*holo-layer*&lt;/code&gt; window to submit an issue to us. There are many clues in there that can help us troubleshoot the problem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter a crash, please use the following method to collect crash information:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First install gdb and turn on the option &lt;code&gt;(setq holo-layer-enable-debug t)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the command &lt;code&gt;holo-layer-stop-process&lt;/code&gt; to stop the holo-layer process&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reopen holo-layer, and send the content of &lt;code&gt;*holo-layer*&lt;/code&gt; at the next crash&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/manateelazycat/holo-layer/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=manateelazycat/holo-layer&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>