<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PHP Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-01T01:48:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of PHP in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>zabbix/zabbix</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:48:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/zabbix/zabbix</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zabbix/zabbix" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Real-time monitoring of IT components and services, such as networks, servers, VMs, applications and the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zabbix/zabbix/master/misc/images/docs/zabbix_logo.svg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Zabbix logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An enterprise-class, open-source distributed monitoring solution that’s designed to monitor the performance and availability of network devices, servers, services, and other IT resources. Zabbix is a flexible solution that can monitor anything from a simple, standalone application to a large-scale environment, with features including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource discovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Discover network entities, server resources, and onboard/offboard devices. Use out-of-the-box integrations (templates) to monitor anything form a low-level device to a SAAS service.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metric acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; Use an agent or agent-less approach for metric acquisition from any source – devices, sensors, operating systems, virtualization platforms, container platforms like Docker, Kubernetes, cloud infrastructures, databases, webpages, Java ecosystems, application servers, API endpoints, business applications, and many more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Root cause analysis and problem detection:&lt;/strong&gt; Count on high-performance, real-time problem detection that correlates both existing and incoming problems and performs root cause analyses.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incidents, alerts, and notifications:&lt;/strong&gt; Receive an alert when an issue is triggered (proactively or post-mortem) in the ecosystem. Use multiple messaging channels (including Slack, JIRA, Microsoft Teams, email or text messages) to get notified about the different types of events occurring in your environment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Single pane of glass” overview:&lt;/strong&gt; Visualize collected data and monitoring events in graphs, lists, geomaps, and network topology maps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multitenancy and distributed monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; Enjoy the convenience of one monitoring solution for multiple data centers, departments, and organizations, and monitor remote locations behind firewalls with remote command execution capability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unparalleled flexibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Adapt Zabbix to your needs and utilize built-in functionalities, including the ability to stream metrics and events over HTTP, reporting, auditing, security, service SLA calculations, and many more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zabbix.com/download&#34;&gt;Get Zabbix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zabbix.com/documentation/current/en/manual/installation&#34;&gt;Installation manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zabbix documentation is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zabbix.com/documentation/current/en/&#34;&gt;zabbix.com/documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zabbix is distributed under &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zabbix/zabbix/master/COPYING&#34;&gt;AGPL-3.0-only&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anankke/SSPanel-UIM</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:48:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/Anankke/SSPanel-UIM</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Anankke/SSPanel-UIM" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Multi-purpose proxy service management system&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Anankke/SSPanel-UIM/dev/public/images/uim-logo-round_192x192.png&#34; alt=&#34;logo&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;SSPanel UIM&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Across the Great Wall we can reach every corner in the world&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSPanel UIM is a multi-purpose proxy service management system designed for Shadowsocks(2022) / V2Ray / Trojan / TUIC protocol.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integrate multiple payment systems such as Alipay F2F, PayPal, Stripe, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support multiple mail services, built-in mail queue function, no third-party components are required to use&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Built-in tabler theme based on Bootstrap 5, template engine support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support Shadowsocks 2022, TUIC, and other latest proxy protocols&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Universal subscription interface, one-click json/clash/sip008/sing-box format subscription distribution&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom node configuration, modular subscription system, support multiple client-specific subscription formats&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Refactored store system, support billing modes including but not limited to annual/monthly, pay-as-you-go, access type billing, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Refactored scheduled task system, one command can automatically complete all scheduled tasks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deep integration of large language models, support intelligent replies to tickets, document generation, and other functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;One-click access to OpenAI, Google AI, Vertex AI, Hugging Face Hosted API, Cloudflare Workers AI, Anthropic, and other large language model services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSPanel UIM requires the following programs to be installed and run normally:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Git&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nginx（HTTPS is REQUIRED）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PHP 8.2+ （OPcache+JIT is highly recommended）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;MariaDB 10.11+（Disable strict mode）&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Redis 7.0+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jetbrains.com/?from=SSPanel-UIM&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Anankke/SSPanel-UIM/dev/.github/jetbrains.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Anankke/SSPanel-UIM/dev/blob/dev/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PrivateBin/PrivateBin</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:48:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/PrivateBin/PrivateBin</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A minimalist, open source online pastebin where the server has zero knowledge of pasted data. Data is encrypted/decrypted in the browser using 256 bits AES.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://privatebin.info/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.rawgit.com/PrivateBin/assets/master/images/preview/logoSmall.png&#34; alt=&#34;PrivateBin&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Current version: 1.7.3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PrivateBin&lt;/strong&gt; is a minimalist, open source online &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pastebin&#34;&gt;pastebin&lt;/a&gt; where the server has zero knowledge of pasted data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data is encrypted and decrypted in the browser using 256bit AES in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Galois/Counter_Mode&#34;&gt;Galois Counter mode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a fork of ZeroBin, originally developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sebsauvage/ZeroBin&#34;&gt;Sébastien Sauvage&lt;/a&gt;. PrivateBin was refactored to allow easier and cleaner extensions and has many additional features. It is, however, still fully compatible to the original ZeroBin 0.19 data storage scheme. Therefore, such installations can be upgraded to PrivateBin without losing any data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What PrivateBin provides&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a server administrator you don&#39;t have to worry if your users post content that is considered illegal in your country. You have plausible deniability of any of the pastes content. If requested or enforced, you can delete any paste from your system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Pastebin-like system to store text documents, code samples, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Encryption of data sent to server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Possibility to set a password which is required to read the paste. It further protects a paste and prevents people stumbling upon your paste&#39;s link from being able to read it without the password.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What it doesn&#39;t provide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a user you have to trust the server administrator not to inject any malicious code. For security, a PrivateBin installation &lt;em&gt;has to be used over&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;HTTPS&lt;/em&gt;! Otherwise you would also have to trust your internet provider, and any jurisdiction the traffic passes through. Additionally the instance should be secured by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_Strict_Transport_Security&#34;&gt;HSTS&lt;/a&gt;. It can use traditional certificate authorities and/or use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System_Security_Extensions&#34;&gt;DNSSEC&lt;/a&gt; protected &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS-based_Authentication_of_Named_Entities&#34;&gt;DANE&lt;/a&gt; record.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &#34;key&#34; used to encrypt the paste is part of the URL. If you publicly post the URL of a paste that is not password-protected, anyone can read it. Use a password if you want your paste to remain private. In that case, make sure to use a strong password and share it privately and end-to-end-encrypted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A server admin can be forced to hand over access logs to the authorities. PrivateBin encrypts your text and the discussion contents, but who accessed a paste (first) might still be disclosed via access logs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;In case of a server breach your data is secure as it is only stored encrypted on the server. However, the server could be abused or the server admin could be legally forced into sending malicious code to their users, which logs the decryption key and sends it to a server when a user accesses a paste. Therefore, do not access any PrivateBin instance if you think it has been compromised. As long as no user accesses this instance with a previously generated URL, the content can&#39;t be decrypted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Options&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some features are optional and can be enabled or disabled in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/Configuration&#34;&gt;configuration file&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Password protection&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Discussions, anonymous or with nicknames and IP based identicons or vizhashes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Expiration times, including a &#34;forever&#34; and &#34;burn after reading&#34; option&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Markdown format support for HTML formatted pastes, including preview function&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting for source code using prettify.js, including 4 prettify themes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;File upload support, image, media and PDF preview (disabled by default, size limit adjustable)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Templates: By default there are bootstrap CSS, darkstrap and &#34;classic ZeroBin&#34; to choose from and it is easy to adapt these to your own websites layout or create your own.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Translation system and automatic browser language detection (if enabled in browser)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Language selection (disabled by default, as it uses a session cookie)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;QR code for paste URLs, to easily transfer them over to mobile devices&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Further resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/FAQ&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/raw/master/doc/Installation.md#installation&#34;&gt;Installation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/Configuration&#34;&gt;Configuration guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/Templates&#34;&gt;Templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/Translation&#34;&gt;Translation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/wiki/Development&#34;&gt;Developer guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run into any issues? Have ideas for further developments? Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PrivateBin/PrivateBin/issues&#34;&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; them!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>