<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Scala Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-25T01:44:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Scala in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>yanns/play2-scala-DI</title>
    <updated>2022-12-25T01:44:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-25:/yanns/play2-scala-DI</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yanns/play2-scala-DI" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;play2-scala-DI&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technical prototyp to test different dependency injection solutions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The target platform is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Play framework v2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scala&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tested:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cake pattern&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;injection with implicits.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;spring&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>apache/kyuubi</title>
    <updated>2022-12-25T01:44:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-25:/apache/kyuubi</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apache/kyuubi" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apache Kyuubi is a distributed and multi-tenant gateway to provide serverless SQL on data warehouses and lakehouses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Apache Kyuubi (Incubating)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://svn.apache.org/repos/asf/comdev/project-logos/originals/kyuubi-1.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Kyuubi logo&#34; height=&#34;120px&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%202-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/apache/incubator-kyuubi?label=release&#34; alt=&#34;Release&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://tokei.rs/b1/github.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/apache/incubator-kyuubi/branch/master/graph/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;codecov&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/workflow/status/apache/incubator-kyuubi/Kyuubi/master?style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Workflow Status&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.travis-ci.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Travis&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyuubi.apache.org/docs/latest/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://readthedocs.org/projects/kyuubi/badge/?version=latest&#34; alt=&#34;Documentation Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/languages/top/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub top language&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/incubator-kyuubi/graphs/commit-activity&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; alt=&#34;Commit activity&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; title=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/resolution/apache/incubator-kyuubi.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; title=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/open/apache/incubator-kyuubi.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is Kyuubi?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apache Kyuubi™ is a distributed and multi-tenant gateway to provide serverless SQL on data warehouses and lakehouses.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuubi provides a pure SQL gateway through Thrift JDBC/ODBC interface for end-users to manipulate large-scale data with pre-programmed and extensible Spark SQL engines. This &#34;out-of-the-box&#34; model minimizes the barriers and costs for end-users to use Spark at the client side. At the server-side, Kyuubi server and engines&#39; multi-tenant architecture provides the administrators a way to achieve computing resource isolation, data security, high availability, high client concurrency, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/kyuubi/master/docs/imgs/kyuubi_positioning.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; A HiveServer2-like API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Multi-tenant Spark Support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Running Spark in a serverless way&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Target Users&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuubi&#39;s goal is to make it easy and efficient for &lt;code&gt;anyone&lt;/code&gt; to use Spark(maybe other engines soon) and facilitate users to handle big data like ordinary data. Here, &lt;code&gt;anyone&lt;/code&gt; means that users do not need to have a Spark technical background but a human language, SQL only. Sometimes, SQL skills are unnecessary when integrating Kyuubi with Apache Superset, which supports rich visualizations and dashboards.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In typical big data production environments with Kyuubi, there should be system administrators and end-users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;System administrators: A small group consists of Spark experts responsible for Kyuubi deployment, configuration, and tuning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;End-users: Focus on business data of their own, not where it stores, how it computes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the Kyuubi community will continuously optimize the whole system with various features, such as History-Based Optimizer, Auto-tuning, Materialized View, SQL Dialects, Functions, e.t.c.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Usage scenarios&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Port workloads from HiveServer2 to Spark SQL&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In typical big data production environments, especially secured ones, all bundled services manage access control lists to restricting access to authorized users. For example, Hadoop YARN divides compute resources into queues. With Queue ACLs, it can identify and control which users/groups can take actions on particular queues. Similarly, HDFS ACLs control access of HDFS files by providing a way to set different permissions for specific users/groups.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apache Spark is a unified analytics engine for large-scale data processing. It provides a Distributed SQL Engine, a.k.a, the Spark Thrift Server(STS), designed to be seamlessly compatible with HiveServer2 and get even better performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HiveServer2 can identify and authenticate a caller, and then if the caller also has permissions for the YARN queue and HDFS files, it succeeds. Otherwise, it fails. However, on the one hand, STS is a single Spark application. The user and queue to which STS belongs are uniquely determined at startup. Consequently, STS cannot leverage cluster managers such as YARN and Kubernetes for resource isolation and sharing or control the access for callers by the single user inside the whole system. On the other hand, the Thrift Server is coupled in the Spark driver&#39;s JVM process. This coupled architect puts a high risk on server stability and makes it unable to handle high client concurrency or apply high availability such as load balancing as it is stateful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuubi extends the use of STS in a multi-tenant model based on a unified interface and relies on the concept of multi-tenancy to interact with cluster managers to finally gain the ability of resources sharing/isolation and data security. The loosely coupled architecture of the Kyuubi server and engine dramatically improves the client concurrency and service stability of the service itself.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;DataLake/LakeHouse Support&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vision of Kyuubi is to unify the portal and become an easy-to-use data lake management platform. Different kinds of workloads, such as ETL processing and BI analytics, can be supported by one platform, using one copy of data, with one SQL interface.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logical View support via Kyuubi DataLake Metadata APIs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Multiple Catalogs support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SQL Standard Authorization support for DataLake(coming)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Cloud Native Support&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kyuubi can deploy its engines on different kinds of Cluster Managers, such as, Hadoop YARN, Kubernetes, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/kyuubi/master/docs/imgs/kyuubi_migrating_yarn_to_k8s.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Kyuubi Ecosystem(present and future)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The figure below shows our vision for the Kyuubi Ecosystem. Some of them have been realized, some in development, and others would not be possible without your help.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/kyuubi/master/docs/imgs/kyuubi_ecosystem.drawio.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Online Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since Kyuubi 1.3.0-incubating, the Kyuubi online documentation is hosted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyuubi.apache.org/&#34;&gt;https://kyuubi.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;. You can find the latest Kyuubi documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyuubi.apache.org/docs/latest/&#34;&gt;this web page&lt;/a&gt;. For 1.2 and earlier versions, please check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyuubi.readthedocs.io/en/v1.2.0/&#34;&gt;Readthedocs&lt;/a&gt; directly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ready? &lt;a href=&#34;https://kyuubi.apache.org/docs/latest/quick_start/quick_start.html&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt; with Kyuubi.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/kyuubi/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributor over time&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://api7.ai/contributor-graph?chart=contributorOverTime&amp;amp;repo=apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://contributor-graph-api.apiseven.com/contributors-svg?chart=contributorOverTime&amp;amp;repo=apache/incubator-kyuubi&#34; alt=&#34;Contributor over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Aside&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project took its name from a character of a popular Japanese manga - &lt;code&gt;Naruto&lt;/code&gt;. The character is named &lt;code&gt;Kyuubi Kitsune/Kurama&lt;/code&gt;, which is a nine-tailed fox in mythology. &lt;code&gt;Kyuubi&lt;/code&gt; spread the power and spirit of fire, which is used here to represent the powerful &lt;a href=&#34;http://spark.apache.org&#34;&gt;Apache Spark&lt;/a&gt;. Its nine tails stand for end-to-end multi-tenancy support of this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the Apache 2.0 License. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/kyuubi/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Banno/akka-event-handler-flume</title>
    <updated>2022-12-25T01:44:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-25:/Banno/akka-event-handler-flume</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Banno/akka-event-handler-flume" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;flume sink for your akka event handler&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;akka-event-handler-flume&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;akka-event-handler-flume&lt;/code&gt; is an &lt;a href=&#34;http://akka.io&#34;&gt;akka&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;EventHandler&lt;/code&gt; listener that can publish to &lt;a href=&#34;https://cwiki.apache.org/FLUME/&#34;&gt;flume&lt;/a&gt; sinks. It is akin to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://akka.io/docs/akka/1.2/general/slf4j.html&#34;&gt;akka-slf4j&lt;/a&gt; EventHandler. See akka&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://akka.io/docs/akka/1.2/general/event-handler.html&#34;&gt;event-handler&lt;/a&gt; documentation for more information. &lt;a href=&#34;http://grabgrip.com&#34;&gt;T8 Webware&lt;/a&gt; has been using this to great success.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Registration of the listener&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;akka {&#xA;  event-handlers = [&#34;com.banno.akka.event.flume.FlumeSinkEventHandler]&#xA;  flume-event-handler.sink = &#34;console&#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Configuring the Sink&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;FlumeSinkEventHandler&lt;/code&gt; can take in a string as long as it follow the same grammar as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.cloudera.com/cdh/3/flume/UserGuide/index.html#_introducing_sinks&#34;&gt;flume sink spec&lt;/a&gt; This is configured vai the &lt;code&gt;akka.flume-event-handler.sink&lt;/code&gt; config property in the &lt;code&gt;akka.conf&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Please&lt;/em&gt; take the time to familiarize yourself with the different types of decorators and event sinks. There are many durability gurantees that they can give you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Decorating the flume event with semi-structured data&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the greater things about logging to Flume is that you can have semi-structured data instead of just a body text. Some of things you can do with this are: nodes down the line can organize and redirect to a different sink based of an attribute, MapReduce jobs can also take advantage of the structured data instead of tokenizing a string. Due to the way akka&#39;s logging is usually presented, logging a non-string object is a little less iodiomatic, but is still possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way to do this is like:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-scala&#34;&gt;trait Animal&#xA;case class Cat(name: String) extends Animal&#xA;&#xA;FlumeEventDecorators.decorate { (c: Cat, ev: FlumeEvent) =&amp;gt;&#xA;  ev(&#34;catName&#34;) = c.name&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;log.bus.publish(Logging.Info(&#34;me&#34;, classOf[Cat], Cat(&#34;lou&#34;)))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cwiki.apache.org/FLUME/&#34;&gt;flume&lt;/a&gt; event sent will now have a &lt;code&gt;catName&lt;/code&gt; attribute set to the cat&#39;s name. This can also work for superclasses and traits. Multiple decorators can be set.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some standard attributes that the &lt;code&gt;FlumeSinkEventHandlerListener&lt;/code&gt; will set as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sender&lt;/code&gt;: the sender of the log message&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;senderClass&lt;/code&gt;: the sender&#39;s class of the log message&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;threadName&lt;/code&gt;: the thread name that sent the log message&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;exceptionType&lt;/code&gt;: if an error, the type of the throwable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;exceptionMessage&lt;/code&gt;: if an error, the message of the throwable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;exceptionBacktrace&lt;/code&gt;: if an error, the backtrace of the throwable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cwiki.apache.org/FLUME/&#34;&gt;flume&lt;/a&gt; event priority will be the priority of the &lt;code&gt;EventHandler&lt;/code&gt; event.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is licensed under the Apache License Version 2.0&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>