<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TypeScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-19T01:39:19Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TypeScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>OpenDevin/OpenDevin</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T01:39:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-19:/OpenDevin/OpenDevin</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OpenDevin/OpenDevin" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;OpenDevin Logo&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OpenDevin/OpenDevin/main/OpenDevinLogo.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;OpenDevin: Code Less, Make More&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MIT-green&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Mission 🎯&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to OpenDevin, an open-source project aiming to replicate &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cognition-labs.com/introducing-devin&#34;&gt;Devin&lt;/a&gt;, an autonomous AI software engineer who is capable of executing complex engineering tasks and collaborating actively with users on software development projects. This project aspires to replicate, enhance, and innovate upon Devin through the power of the open-source community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤔 What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cognition-labs.com/introducing-devin&#34;&gt;Devin&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Devin represents a cutting-edge autonomous agent designed to navigate the complexities of software engineering. It leverages a combination of tools such as a shell, code editor, and web browser, showcasing the untapped potential of LLMs in software development. Our goal is to explore and expand upon Devin&#39;s capabilities, identifying both its strengths and areas for improvement, to guide the progress of open code models.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🐚 Why OpenDevin?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OpenDevin project is born out of a desire to replicate, enhance, and innovate beyond the original Devin model. By engaging the open-source community, we aim to tackle the challenges faced by Code LLMs in practical scenarios, producing works that significantly contribute to the community and pave the way for future advancements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;⭐️ Research Strategy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Achieving full replication of production-grade applications with LLMs is a complex endeavor. Our strategy involves:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Technical Research:&lt;/strong&gt; Focusing on foundational research to understand and improve the technical aspects of code generation and handling.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialist Abilities:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhancing the effectiveness of core components through data curation, training methods, and more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task Planning:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing capabilities for bug detection, codebase management, and optimization.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing comprehensive evaluation metrics to better understand and improve our models.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🛠 Technology Stack&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandboxing Environment:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensuring safe execution of code using technologies like Docker and Kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend Interface:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing user-friendly interfaces for monitoring progress and interacting with Devin, potentially leveraging frameworks like React or creating a VSCode plugin for a more integrated experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Literature Review:&lt;/strong&gt; Conduct a thorough review of existing literature (1-2 weeks).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Engagement:&lt;/strong&gt; Release the plan to the community, form research groups, and begin collaborative work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenDevin is a community-driven project, and we welcome contributions from everyone. Whether you&#39;re a developer, a researcher, or simply enthusiastic about advancing the field of software engineering with AI, there are many ways to get involved:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Contributions:&lt;/strong&gt; Help us develop the core functionalities, frontend interface, or sandboxing solutions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research and Evaluation:&lt;/strong&gt; Contribute to our understanding of LLMs in software engineering, participate in evaluating the models, or suggest improvements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback and Testing:&lt;/strong&gt; Use the OpenDevin toolset, report bugs, suggest features, or provide feedback on usability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please fill in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/758d5p6Ve8r2nxxq6&#34;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to become a core member of OpenDevin Team. We will reach out shortly if we feel you are a good fit to the current team!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Stay Connected&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join our community to stay updated on OpenDevin&#39;s progress, share your ideas, and collaborate with fellow enthusiasts and experts. Together, we can make significant strides towards simplifying software engineering tasks and creating more efficient, powerful tools for developers everywhere.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🐚 &lt;strong&gt;Code less, make more with OpenDevin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>