<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TypeScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-06T01:35:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TypeScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>langchain-ai/open-canvas</title>
    <updated>2025-01-06T01:35:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-06:/langchain-ai/open-canvas</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/langchain-ai/open-canvas" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;📃 A better UX for chat, writing content, and coding with LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Canvas&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencanvas.langchain.com/&#34;&gt;TRY IT OUT HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langchain-ai/open-canvas/main/public/screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Canvas is an open source web application for collaborating with agents to better write documents. It is inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/index/introducing-canvas/&#34;&gt;OpenAI&#39;s &#34;Canvas&#34;&lt;/a&gt;, but with a few key differences.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt;: All the code, from the frontend, to the content generation agent, to the reflection agent is open source and MIT licensed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Built in memory&lt;/strong&gt;: Open Canvas ships out of the box with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://langchain-ai.github.io/langgraphjs/tutorials/reflection/reflection/&#34;&gt;reflection agent&lt;/a&gt; which stores style rules and user insights in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://langchain-ai.github.io/langgraphjs/concepts/memory/&#34;&gt;shared memory store&lt;/a&gt;. This allows Open Canvas to remember facts about you across sessions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start from existing documents&lt;/strong&gt;: Open Canvas allows users to start with a blank text, or code editor in the language of their choice, allowing you to start the session with your existing content, instead of being forced to start with a chat interaction. We believe this is an ideal UX because many times you will already have some content to start with, and want to iterate on-top of it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memory&lt;/strong&gt;: Open Canvas has a built in memory system which will automatically generate reflections and memories on you, and your chat history. These are then included in subsequent chat interactions to give a more personalized experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom quick actions&lt;/strong&gt;: Custom quick actions allow you to define your own prompts which are tied to your user, and persist across sessions. These then can be easily invoked through a single click, and apply to the artifact you&#39;re currently viewing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-built quick actions&lt;/strong&gt;: There are also a series of pre-built quick actions for common writing and coding tasks that are always available.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artifact versioning&lt;/strong&gt;: All artifacts have a &#34;version&#34; tied to them, allowing you to travel back in time and see previous versions of your artifact.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code, Markdown, or both&lt;/strong&gt;: The artifact view allows for viewing and editing both code, and markdown. You can even have chats which generate code, and markdown artifacts, and switch between them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live markdown rendering &amp;amp; editing&lt;/strong&gt;: Open Canvas&#39;s markdown editor allows you to view the rendered markdown while you&#39;re editing, without having to toggle back and fourth.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Setup locally&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide will cover how to setup and run Open Canvas locally. If you prefer a YouTube video guide, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/sBzcQYPMekc&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Canvas requires the following API keys and external services:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Package Manager&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://yarnpkg.com/&#34;&gt;Yarn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;LLM APIs&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/signup/&#34;&gt;OpenAI API key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://console.anthropic.com/&#34;&gt;Anthropic API key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(optional) &lt;a href=&#34;https://aistudio.google.com/apikey&#34;&gt;Google GenAI API key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(optional) &lt;a href=&#34;https://fireworks.ai/login&#34;&gt;Fireworks AI API key&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Authentication&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://supabase.com/&#34;&gt;Supabase&lt;/a&gt; account for authentication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;LangGraph Server&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://langchain-ai.github.io/langgraph/cloud/reference/cli/&#34;&gt;LangGraph CLI&lt;/a&gt; for running the graph locally&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;LangSmith&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://smith.langchain.com/&#34;&gt;LangSmith&lt;/a&gt; for tracing &amp;amp; observability&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, clone the repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/langchain-ai/open-canvas.git&#xA;cd open-canvas&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, install the dependencies:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;yarn install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After installing dependencies, copy the &lt;code&gt;.env.example&lt;/code&gt; file contents into &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; and set the required values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cp .env.example .env&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, setup authentication with Supabase.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup Authentication&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After creating a Supabase account, visit your &lt;a href=&#34;https://supabase.com/dashboard/projects&#34;&gt;dashboard&lt;/a&gt; and create a new project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, navigate to the &lt;code&gt;Project Settings&lt;/code&gt; page inside your project, and then to the &lt;code&gt;API&lt;/code&gt; tag. Copy the &lt;code&gt;Project URL&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;anon public&lt;/code&gt; project API key. Paste them into the &lt;code&gt;NEXT_PUBLIC_SUPABASE_URL&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;NEXT_PUBLIC_SUPABASE_ANON_KEY&lt;/code&gt; environment variables in the &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After this, navigate to the &lt;code&gt;Authentication&lt;/code&gt; page, and the &lt;code&gt;Providers&lt;/code&gt; tab. Make sure &lt;code&gt;Email&lt;/code&gt; is enabled (also ensure you&#39;ve enabled &lt;code&gt;Confirm Email&lt;/code&gt;). You may also enable &lt;code&gt;GitHub&lt;/code&gt;, and/or &lt;code&gt;Google&lt;/code&gt; if you&#39;d like to use those for authentication. (see these pages for documentation on how to setup each provider: &lt;a href=&#34;https://supabase.com/docs/guides/auth/social-login/auth-github&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://supabase.com/docs/guides/auth/social-login/auth-google&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Test authentication&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To verify authentication works, run &lt;code&gt;yarn dev&lt;/code&gt; and visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000&#34;&gt;localhost:3000&lt;/a&gt;. This should redirect you to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/auth/login&#34;&gt;login page&lt;/a&gt;. From here, you can either login with Google or GitHub, or if you did not configure these providers, navigate to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/auth/signup&#34;&gt;signup page&lt;/a&gt; and create a new account with an email and password. This should then redirect you to a conformation page, and after confirming your email you should be redirected to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000&#34;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup LangGraph Server&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now we&#39;ll cover how to setup and run the LangGraph server locally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://langchain-ai.github.io/langgraph/cloud/reference/cli/#installation&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Installation&lt;/code&gt; instructions in the LangGraph docs&lt;/a&gt; to install the LangGraph CLI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once installed, navigate to the root of the Open Canvas repo and run &lt;code&gt;LANGSMITH_API_KEY=&#34;&amp;lt;YOUR_LANGSMITH_API_KEY&amp;gt;&#34; langgraph up --watch --port 54367&lt;/code&gt; (replacing &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;YOUR_LANGSMITH_API_KEY&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with your LangSmith API key).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once it finishes pulling the docker image and installing dependencies, you should see it log:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Ready!       &#xA;- API: http://localhost:54367&#xA;- Docs: http://localhost:54367/docs&#xA;- LangGraph Studio: https://smith.langchain.com/studio/?baseUrl=http://*********:54367&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After your LangGraph server is running, execute the following command to start the Open Canvas app:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;yarn dev&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, open &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000&#34;&gt;localhost:3000&lt;/a&gt; with your browser and start interacting!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LLM Models&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Canvas is designed to be compatible with any LLM model. The current deployment has the following models configured:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthropic Claude 3 Haiku 👤&lt;/strong&gt;: Haiku is Anthropic&#39;s fastest model, great for quick tasks like making edits to your document. Sign up for an Anthropic account &lt;a href=&#34;https://console.anthropic.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fireworks Llama 3 70B 🦙&lt;/strong&gt;: Llama 3 is a SOTA open source model from Meta, powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://fireworks.ai/&#34;&gt;Fireworks AI&lt;/a&gt;. You can sign up for an account &lt;a href=&#34;https://fireworks.ai/login&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI GPT 4o Mini 💨&lt;/strong&gt;: GPT 4o Mini is OpenAI&#39;s newest, smallest model. You can sign up for an API key &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/signup/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to add a new model, follow these simple steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add to or update the model provider variables in &lt;code&gt;constants.ts&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the necessary package for the provider (e.g. &lt;code&gt;@langchain/anthropic&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update the &lt;code&gt;getModelConfig&lt;/code&gt; function in &lt;code&gt;src/agent/utils.ts&lt;/code&gt; to include an &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; statement for your new model name and provider.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manually test by checking you can:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;4a. Generate a new artifact&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;4b. Generate a followup message (happens automatically after generating an artifact)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;4c. Update an artifact via a message in chat&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;4d. Update an artifact via a quick action&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;4e. Repeat for text/code (ensure both work)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Local Ollama models&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Canvas supports calling local LLMs running on Ollama. This is not enabled in the hosted version of Open Canvas, but you can use this in your own local/deployed Open Canvas instance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use a local Ollama model, first ensure you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://ollama.com&#34;&gt;Ollama&lt;/a&gt; installed, and a model that supports tool calling pulled (the default model is &lt;code&gt;llama3.3&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, start the Ollama server by running &lt;code&gt;ollama run llama3.3&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, set the &lt;code&gt;NEXT_PUBLIC_OLLAMA_ENABLED&lt;/code&gt; environment variable to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;OLLAMA_API_URL&lt;/code&gt; environment variable to the URL of your Ollama server (defaults to &lt;code&gt;http://host.docker.internal:11434&lt;/code&gt;. If you do not set a custom port when starting your Ollama server, you should not need to set this environment variable).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] Open source LLMs are typically not as good at instruction following as proprietary models like GPT-4o or Claude Sonnet. Because of this, you may experience errors or unexpected behavior when using local LLMs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below are some common issues you may run into if running Open Canvas yourself:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have the LangGraph server running successfully, and my client can make requests, but no text is being generated:&lt;/strong&gt; This can happen if you start &amp;amp; connect to multiple different LangGraph servers locally in the same browser. Try clearing the &lt;code&gt;oc_thread_id_v2&lt;/code&gt; cookie and refreshing the page. This is because each unique LangGraph server has its own database where threads are stored, so a thread ID from one server will not be found in the database of another server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&#39;m getting 500 network errors when I try to make requests on the client:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure you have the LangGraph server running, and you&#39;re making requests to the correct port. You can specify the port to use by passing the &lt;code&gt;--port &amp;lt;PORT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; flag to the &lt;code&gt;langgraph up&lt;/code&gt; command, and you can set the URL to make requests to by either setting the &lt;code&gt;LANGGRAPH_API_URL&lt;/code&gt; environment variable, or by changing the fallback value of the &lt;code&gt;LANGGRAPH_API_URL&lt;/code&gt; variable in &lt;code&gt;constants.ts&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&#39;m getting &#34;thread ID not found&#34; error toasts when I try to make requests on the client:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure you have the LangGraph server running, and you&#39;re making requests to the correct port. You can specify the port to use by passing the &lt;code&gt;--port &amp;lt;PORT&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; flag to the &lt;code&gt;langgraph up&lt;/code&gt; command, and you can set the URL to make requests to by either setting the &lt;code&gt;LANGGRAPH_API_URL&lt;/code&gt; environment variable, or by changing the fallback value of the &lt;code&gt;LANGGRAPH_API_URL&lt;/code&gt; variable in &lt;code&gt;constants.ts&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Model name is missing in config.&lt;/code&gt; error is being thrown when I make requests:&lt;/strong&gt; This error occurs when the &lt;code&gt;customModelName&lt;/code&gt; is not specified in the config. You can resolve this by setting the &lt;code&gt;customModelName&lt;/code&gt; field inside &lt;code&gt;config.configurable&lt;/code&gt; to the name of the model you want to use when invoking the graph. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://langchain-ai.github.io/langgraphjs/how-tos/configuration/&#34;&gt;this doc&lt;/a&gt; on how to use configurable fields in LangGraph.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of features we&#39;d like to add to Open Canvas in the near future:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Render React in the editor&lt;/strong&gt;: Ideally, if you have Open Canvas generate React (or HTML) code, we should be able to render it live in the editor. &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: This is in the planning stage now!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple assistants&lt;/strong&gt;: Users should be able to create multiple assistants, each having their own memory store.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give assistants custom &#39;tools&#39;&lt;/strong&gt;: Once we&#39;ve implemented &lt;code&gt;RemoteGraph&lt;/code&gt; in LangGraph.js, users should be able to give assistants access to call their own graphs as tools. This means you could customize your assistant to have access to current events, your own personal knowledge graph, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you have a feature request? Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/langchain-ai/open-canvas/issues/new&#34;&gt;open an issue&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like to continue developing and improving Open Canvas, and want your help!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start, there are a handful of GitHub issues with feature requests outlining improvements and additions to make the app&#39;s UX even better. There are three main labels:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;frontend&lt;/code&gt;: This label is added to issues which are UI focused, and do not require much if any work on the agent(s).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ai&lt;/code&gt;: This label is added to issues which are focused on improving the LLM agent(s).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fullstack&lt;/code&gt;: This label is added to issues which require touching both the frontend and agent code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about contributing, please reach out to me via email: &lt;code&gt;brace(at)langchain(dot)dev&lt;/code&gt;. For general bugs/issues with the code, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/langchain-ai/open-canvas/issues/new&#34;&gt;open an issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo</title>
    <updated>2025-01-06T01:35:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-06:/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Secure, open source and community driven crypto wallet runs on all platforms and trusted by millions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;OneKey - Open Source Crypto Wallet&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/stargazers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo?t&amp;amp;logo=github&amp;amp;style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Github Stars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/release/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors-anon/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/commits/onekey&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Last commit&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-raw/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/pulls?q=is%3Apr+is%3Aopen&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr-raw/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo.svg?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Pull Requests&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/onekey&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/868309113942196295?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OneKeyHQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/OneKeyHQ?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Follow&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/onekey-open-source-wallet/id1609559473&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/rayston92/graph_bed/raw/275d053220d5b54b32b01ce4c4985210951043c5/img/app_store.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Appstore&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=so.onekey.app.wallet&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/rayston92/graph_bed/raw/275d053220d5b54b32b01ce4c4985210951043c5/img/play.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Playstore&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onekey.so/zh_CN/download?client=desktop&#34;&gt;Desktop clients: macOS, Windows &amp;amp; Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onekey.so/zh_CN/download?client=browserExtension&#34;&gt;Browser extensions: Chrome, Firefox, Edge &amp;amp; Brave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onekey.so/zh_CN/download?client=bridge&#34;&gt;Bridge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community &amp;amp; Enterprise Edition&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🏡 🧔🏻‍♂️ For Community Edition. It will always remain FREE FOREVER for open-source projects by individuals and communities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🏦 💼 For Enterprise Edition. We&#39;ve got this plan on the radar, but we&#39;re not quite ready yet. Just star our repo, and you&#39;ll be pinged as soon as we&#39;re all set.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/OneKeyHQ/discussions&#34;&gt;Community Forum&lt;/a&gt;. Best for: help with building, discussion about best practices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt;. Best for: bugs and errors you encounter using OneKey.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/onekey&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;. Best for: sharing your ideas and hanging out with the community.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repo Status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;✅ Public: Production-ready&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We really need your support, star or watch this repo for latest updates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;kbd&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/rayston92/graph_bed/raw/e3b2c938fc5b17d68531f69178908afb16266e6a/img/onekey_monorepo_star.gif?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Star this repo&#34;&gt;&lt;/kbd&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 Getting Onboard&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;node.js LTS version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://yarnpkg.com/&#34;&gt;yarn package management tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-lfs.github.com/&#34;&gt;git lfs&lt;/a&gt; (some binaries are required for pulling and updating)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To start the iOS project, make sure that the local XCode version is greater than or equal to 13.3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To start the Android project, make sure that the local JDK version is greater than or equal to 11&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After pulling the latest code via the git command line tool, install the project dependencies in the root directory via the &lt;code&gt;yarn&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🧑‍💻 Develop&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Execute the following commands in the root directory to develop different business code&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn app:web&lt;/code&gt;: Develop web mode, which starts a static server on port 3000 locally&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn app:ios&lt;/code&gt;: connect to iphone device via USB for development debugging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn app:android&lt;/code&gt;: develop android&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn app:desktop&lt;/code&gt;: development in desktop mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn app:ext&lt;/code&gt;: development in extension mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;💬 Docs in your languages&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Available Languages&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/x/docs/i18n/README.zh-cn.md&#34;&gt;Simplified Chinese / 简体中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/x/docs/i18n/README.de.md&#34;&gt;German / Deutsch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/x/docs/i18n/README.jp.md&#34;&gt;Japanese / 日本語&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/x/docs/i18n/README.fr.md&#34;&gt;French / Français&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/x/docs/i18n/README.it.md&#34;&gt;Italian / Italiano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🪄 Repo Activity&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://repobeats.axiom.co/api/embed/5f8b83656094956b2d6274929f6eaa2e068a6cfb.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Repo Activity&#34; title=&#34;Repobeats analytics image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🔰 Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please read &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/raw/onekey/docs/BUG_RULES.md&#34;&gt;Bug Bunty Rules&lt;/a&gt;, we have detailed the exact plan in this article.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please report suspected security vulnerabilities in private to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dev@onekey.so&#34;&gt;dev@onekey.so&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please do NOT create publicly viewable issues for suspected security vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;As an open source project, although we are not yet profitable, we try to give some rewards to white hat hackers who disclose vulnerabilities to us in a timely manner.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🙋‍♂️We&#39;re Hiring!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th colspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt; We are hiring many roles (Remote) &lt;a href=&#34;https://onekeyhq.atlassian.net/wiki/spaces/OC/overview&#34;&gt;👉 Click here to check all open positions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt; &lt;li&gt;Remote (Live anywhere)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Global Pay (Literally)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;ESOP (For everybody)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Open Source (As you see)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Awesome Colleagues (Hell Yeah!)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt; &lt;li&gt;远程 (生活在哪个城市都可以)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;全球一致的薪酬 (真的)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;全员持股计划 (每个人都有)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;开源 (如你所见)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;超级棒的同事 (爽呆!)&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;✨ Salute!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors-anon/OneKeyHQ/app-monorepo?style=for-the-badge&amp;amp;labelColor=000&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/onekeyhq/app-monorepo/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=onekeyhq/app-monorepo&amp;amp;max=240&amp;amp;columns=24&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>boardgameio/boardgame.io</title>
    <updated>2025-01-06T01:35:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-06:/boardgameio/boardgame.io</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;State Management and Multiplayer Networking for Turn-Based Games&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgame.io/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/docs/logo-optimized.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;boardgame.io&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/boardgame.io&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badge.fury.io/js/boardgame.io.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;npm version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/actions?query=workflow%3ATests&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/workflows/Tests/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveralls.io/github/boardgameio/boardgame.io?branch=main&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/boardgameio/boardgame.io/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/boardgame-io&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.gitter.im/boardgame-io.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Gitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgame.io/documentation/#/&#34;&gt;Read the Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;boardgame.io&lt;/strong&gt; is an engine for creating turn-based games using JavaScript. &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Write simple functions that describe how the game state changes when a particular move is made. This is automatically converted into a playable game complete with online multiplayer features, all without requiring you to write a single line of networking or storage code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Game state is managed seamlessly across clients, server and storage automatically.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer&lt;/strong&gt;: Game state is kept in sync in realtime and across platforms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;: Automatically generated bots that can play your game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Phases&lt;/strong&gt;: with different game rules and turn orders per phase.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lobby&lt;/strong&gt;: Player matchmaking and game creation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototyping&lt;/strong&gt;: Interface to simulate moves even before you render the game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extendable&lt;/strong&gt;: Plugin system that allows creating new abstractions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View-layer Agnostic&lt;/strong&gt;: Use the vanilla JS client or the bindings for React / React Native.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logs&lt;/strong&gt;: Game logs with the ability to time travel (viewing the board at an earlier state).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;npm install boardgame.io&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgame.io/documentation/&#34;&gt;Full Documentation&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to use boardgame.io, and join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/boardgame-io/General&#34;&gt;community on gitter&lt;/a&gt; to ask your questions!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Running examples in this repository&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;npm install&#xA;npm start&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The examples can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/examples/&#34;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Using VS Code?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is ready to run in a dev container in VS Code. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;the contributing guidelines for details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/docs/documentation/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get involved&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions of all kinds! Please take a moment to review our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;🐛 &lt;strong&gt;Found a bug?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Let us know by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;creating an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;❓ &lt;strong&gt;Have a question?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/boardgame-io/General&#34;&gt;Gitter channel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/discussions&#34;&gt;GitHub Discussions&lt;/a&gt; are good places to start.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;⚙️ &lt;strong&gt;Interested in fixing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Abug&#34;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; or adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3Afeature&#34;&gt;feature&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/roadmap.md&#34;&gt;project roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📖 &lt;strong&gt;Can we improve &lt;a href=&#34;https://boardgame.io/documentation/&#34;&gt;our documentation&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; Pull requests even for small changes can be helpful. Each page in the docs can be edited by clicking the “Edit on GitHub” link at the top right.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/boardgameio/boardgame.io/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>