<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TypeScript Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-17T01:47:25Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TypeScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SiaExplains/visa-sponsorship-companies</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T01:47:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-17:/SiaExplains/visa-sponsorship-companies</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SiaExplains/visa-sponsorship-companies" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The aim of this repo is making an updated list of all companies around the world that offer visa sponsorship perk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;visa-sponsorship-companies&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this repo is making an updated list of all companies around the world that offer visa sponsorship perk.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the list here: &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://siaexplains.github.io/visa-sponsorship-companies/&#34;&gt;Demo App&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For now we added +13 countries, but we need your help, it means if you have got any sponsership visa or your company offering it, feel free to create a pull-request and try to contribute.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How can you contribute:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork the project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the &lt;code&gt;/countries/&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the country that you could get the visa-sponsorship offer is not defined yet here, please create it with lowercase name in json format. (and update the index.js file as well)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Search the company name and if it is not exist add it to the end of the list.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send the PR&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please support us with a shinny ⭐&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join us!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SiaExplains/visa-sponsorship-companies/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=SiaExplains/visa-sponsorship-companies&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to run Company-Finder app&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, Install dependecies:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;npm install&#xA;# or&#xA;yarn install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, run the development server:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;npm run dev&#xA;# or&#xA;yarn dev&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📫 Let me know your suggestions &amp;amp; ideas:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/siaexplains&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/twitter/follow/siaexplains?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;Twitter Follow&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🌐 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/siavash-ghanbari/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>langgenius/dify</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T01:47:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-17:/langgenius/dify</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/langgenius/dify" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One API for plugins and datasets, one interface for prompt engineering and visual operation, all for creating powerful AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/images/describe-en.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README.md&#34;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README_CN.md&#34;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dify.ai&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dify_ai&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dify&lt;/strong&gt; is an easy-to-use LLMOps platform designed to empower more people to create sustainable, AI-native applications. With visual orchestration for various application types, Dify offers out-of-the-box, ready-to-use applications that can also serve as Backend-as-a-Service APIs. Unify your development process with one API for plugins and datasets integration, and streamline your operations using a single interface for prompt engineering, visual analytics, and continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applications created with Dify include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out-of-the-box web sites supporting form mode and chat conversation mode A single API encompassing plugin capabilities, context enhancement, and more, saving you backend coding effort Visual data analysis, log review, and annotation for applications Dify is compatible with Langchain, meaning we&#39;ll gradually support multiple LLMs, currently supported:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GPT 3 (text-davinci-003)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GPT 3.5 Turbo(ChatGPT)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GPT-4&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use Cloud Services&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://dify.ai&#34;&gt;Dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install the Community Edition&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before installing Dify, make sure your machine meets the following minimum system requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CPU &amp;gt;= 1 Core&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RAM &amp;gt;= 4GB&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to start the Dify server is to run our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/docker/docker-compose.yaml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file. Before running the installation command, make sure that &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; are installed on your machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd docker&#xA;docker-compose up -d&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After running, you can access the Dify dashboard in your browser at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/install&#34;&gt;http://localhost/install&lt;/a&gt; and start the initialization installation process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to customize the configuration, please refer to the comments in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/docker/docker-compose.yaml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file and manually set the environment configuration. After making the changes, please run &#39;docker-compose up -d&#39; again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Features under development:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasets&lt;/strong&gt;, supporting more datasets, e.g. syncing content from Notion or webpages We will support more datasets, including text, webpages, and even Notion content. Users can build AI applications based on their own data sources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugins&lt;/strong&gt;, introducing ChatGPT Plugin-standard plugins for applications, or using Dify-produced plugins We will release plugins complying with ChatGPT standard, or Dify&#39;s own plugins to enable more capabilities in applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-source models&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g. adopting Llama as a model provider or for further fine-tuning We will work with excellent open-source models like Llama, by providing them as model options in our platform, or using them for further fine-tuning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What can I do with Dify?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: Dify is a simple yet powerful LLM development and operations tool. You can use it to build commercial-grade applications, personal assistants. If you want to develop your own applications, LangDifyGenius can save you backend work in integrating with OpenAI and offer visual operations capabilities, allowing you to continuously improve and train your GPT model.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How do I use Dify to &#34;train&#34; my own model?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: A valuable application consists of Prompt Engineering, context enhancement, and Fine-tuning. We&#39;ve created a hybrid programming approach combining Prompts with programming languages (similar to a template engine), making it easy to accomplish long-text embedding or capturing subtitles from a user-input Youtube video - all of which will be submitted as context for LLMs to process. We place great emphasis on application operability, with data generated by users during App usage available for analysis, annotation, and continuous training. Without the right tools, these steps can be time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What do I need to prepare if I want to create my own application?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: We assume you already have an OpenAI API Key; if not, please register for one. If you already have some content that can serve as training context, that&#39;s great!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What interface languages are available?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: English and Chinese are currently supported, and you can contribute language packs to us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Star History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://star-history.com/#langgenius/dify&amp;amp;Date&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=langgenius/dify&amp;amp;type=Date&#34; alt=&#34;Star History Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, suggestions, or partnership inquiries, feel free to contact us through the following channels:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit an Issue or PR on our GitHub Repo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Join the discussion in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; Community&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@dify.ai&#34;&gt;hello@dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re eager to assist you and together create more fun and useful AI applications!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To ensure proper review, all code contributions - including those from contributors with direct commit access - must be submitted via pull requests and approved by the core development team prior to being merged.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome all pull requests! If you&#39;d like to help, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribution Guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to get started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To protect your privacy, please avoid posting security issues on GitHub. Instead, send your questions to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@dify.ai&#34;&gt;security@dify.ai&lt;/a&gt; and we will provide you with a more detailed answer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software uses the following open-source software:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chase, H. (2022). LangChain [Computer software]. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hwchase17/langchain&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hwchase17/langchain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Liu, J. (2022). LlamaIndex [Computer software]. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.1234.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, please refer to the official website or license text of the respective software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Dify Open Source License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lxfater/BilibiliSummary</title>
    <updated>2023-05-17T01:47:25Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-17:/lxfater/BilibiliSummary</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lxfater/BilibiliSummary" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A chrome extension helps you summary video on bilibili.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;BilibiliSummary&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lxfater/BilibiliSummary/main/screenShot/logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;运行截图&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BilibiliSummary is a Chrome extension that helps you summarize videos on Bilibili.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you ever feel tired when watching long videos and wish you could quickly understand the main content of the video without spending a lot of time watching the whole thing? Then our Chrome extension is designed for you!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Log in to Bilibili, click on a video, and then click the BilibiliSummary icon to start generating a video summary. Our extension will analyze the video content within 5 seconds and generate a short but detailed video summary, telling you the main content and key points of the video. You can choose to watch the entire video or just quickly browse the summary according to your needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chrome store: &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/summary-for-bilibili/hjjdhgophcjfgkempifgiflgekhecnme?hl=ch&#34;&gt;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/summary-for-bilibili/hjjdhgophcjfgkempifgiflgekhecnme?hl=ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not close the ChatGPT tab, as this will interrupt your service.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because we use subtitles for parsing, it is not suitable to use an APIKEY that charges by the number of words. This method will not consume your APIKEY and will not cost you any money, of course, it will not cost me any money either.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the dist.zip from Releases and then unzip and install it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>