<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-14T01:38:14Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>edugca/xlRcode</title>
    <updated>2022-09-14T01:38:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-14:/edugca/xlRcode</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/edugca/xlRcode" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Call R from Excel. Create new Excel functions that make use of R packages. Integrate both tools seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;xlRcode v. 0.1.1&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call R from Excel. Create new Excel functions that make use of R packages. Integrate both tools seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A work in progress...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For documentation, check the spreadsheet file &#34;xlRcode - Main.xlsx&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;New Excel functions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRCODE&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Run R code in a local environment and transfer values from and to Excel. Function memory is cleared after calculation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRCODE_ENV&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Run R code in a pre-specified environment and transfer values from and to Excel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRSCRIPT&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Run R script in a local environment and transfer values from and to Excel. Function memory is cleared after calculation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRSCRIPT_ENV&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Run R script in a pre-specified environment and transfer values from and to Excel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRFUNCTION&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Call an R function in a local environment and transfer values from and to Excel. Function memory is cleared after calculation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLRFUNCTION_ENV&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Call an R function in a pre-specified environment and transfer values from and to Excel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It only works with Windows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This add-in has been tested on Microsoft Excel 365 64-bit. It may work with other versions of Excel for Windows, but it is not guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are going to need that R is installed on your machine. You can download an installer from here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/index.html&#34;&gt;https://cran.r-project.org/index.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This add-in was tested with R v. 4.0.2. It may work with other versions, though.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you already have R installed on your machine, you may wish to make an independent installation just for this add-in. It is up to you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to install for the first time?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;At the top-right corner of this webpage, click on &#34;Code&#34; and then on &#34;Download ZIP&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find on your computer the zip file you have just downloaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract all files in the Release subfolder of the zip file to a folder on your computer. This is where the add-in will be installed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open Excel. Go to File / Options / Add-ins. Then on the drop-down named &#34;Manage&#34;, select &#34;Excel Add-ins&#34; and click on &#34;Go...&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It will pop-up a window named &#34;Add-ins&#34;. Click on &#34;Browse...&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find the folder you have created for installing the add-in. From there access the subfolder &#34;Release&#34; and select the file xlRcode-AddIn64.xll. If your Excel is 32-bits, you should select xlRcode-AddIn.xll instead. Click on the &#34;Open&#34; button.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Back to the &#34;Add-ins&#34; window, click on the &#34;OK&#34; button.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whenever you open Excel, the add-in should be automatically loaded now!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the Ribbon, you should see a new tab named &#34;xlRcode&#34;. Click on it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the button &#34;SetUp&#34;. A window named &#34;xlRcode SetUp&#34; will pop-up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You will need to set the paths for the folders of your R installation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;R Home should be equivalent to &#34;C:\Program Files\R\R-x.x.x&#34;, where x.x.x stands for the version of your R installation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;R Path should be equivalent to &#34;C:\Program Files\R\R-x.x.x\bin\yyy&#34;, where x.x.x stands for the version of your R installation and yyy is either x64 or i386. If your Excel is 32-bits, you should choose i386.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scripts folder could be any folder, but I strongly advise you to create a new folder and copy to it the scripts of the &#34;R Scripts&#34; subfolder located inside the folder you installed xlRcode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You will not be able to pick a packages repository until you restart Excel. Later on, feel free to do it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click on the &#34;Save&#34; button.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Restart Excel!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That should do the trick!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to update from a previous version?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Close Excel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If, by any chance, your Scripts folder is inside the folder you previously installed this addin and you have added or made changes to any of its scripts, make a backup copy of your Scripts folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the folder you previously installed this addin and delete all of its contents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;At the top-right corner of this webpage, click on &#34;Code&#34; and then on &#34;Download ZIP&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Find on your computer the zip file you have just downloaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract all files in the zip file to the same folder in your computer you had previously installed the add-in.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If step-2 advice applies to you, this is the time to bring the backup scripts back to their original folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open Excel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the xlRcode ribbon tab, click on the &#34;About&#34; button and check whether the version displayed matches the version just installed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That should do the trick!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;v. 0.1.1&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Minor improvements and bug handling.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvement: Set-Up form is now displayed above others.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvement: the first time a form is opened, it is now located at the center of the screen of the Excel monitor (multiple monitors issue). Modal forms still remember their position before hiding.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bug fix: an error handler was added to the AutoOpen routine to obtain clearer info on start-up errors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bug fix: trying to select an online packages repository was prompting untretaed error if R was not loaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bug fix: trying to open the Scripts folder from the Console form before it was set by the user prompted an error.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;v. 0.1&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First beta release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;=======&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>