<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-20T01:37:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data</title>
    <updated>2022-10-20T01:37:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-20:/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;CDC FluSight Hospitalization Forecasts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the data repository for CDC FluSight hospitalization forecasts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are a modeling team interested in submitting forecasts to this project, please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data/master/data-forecasts/README.md&#34;&gt;technical README with detailed submission instructions&lt;/a&gt;. Participating teams provide their &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data/master/data-forecasts/&#34;&gt;forecasts&lt;/a&gt; in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data/master/data-forecasts/README.md#Data-formatting&#34;&gt;quantile-based format&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data license and reuse&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are grateful to the teams who have generated these and made their data publicly available under different terms and licenses. By default, forecasts are available under the CC-BY 4.0 license, although teams may specify release under a different license in their metadata. You will find the licenses (when provided) within the metadata contained within model-specific folders in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cdcepi/Flusight-forecast-data/master/data-forecasts/&#34;&gt;data-forecasts&lt;/a&gt; directory. Please consult these licenses before using these data to ensure that you follow the terms under which these data were released.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>seanchrismurphy/A-Psychologists-Guide-to-R</title>
    <updated>2022-10-20T01:37:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-20:/seanchrismurphy/A-Psychologists-Guide-to-R</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanchrismurphy/A-Psychologists-Guide-to-R" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A repository containing the course notes and worked examples for a six week course in the R statistical programming language aimed at helping psychology students and faculty to learn R. This course was taught live at the University of Melbourne, Australia in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;A Psychologist&#39;s Guide to R&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a repository containing the course notes and worked examples for a six week course in the R statistical programming language taught at the University of Melbourne, Australia. It is targeted at graduate students and faculty in psychology (and probably other social sciences) with no programming experience, and covers the use of R from the basics up to multilevel modelling, though it is not exhaustive within that range.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I taught this course live, I also designed it with self-teaching in mind. Starting in Week 1, reading through the Introduction to R handout will get you started using R with no previous experience. From there, each week contains R files that teach the relevant content and then have worked exercises to test it. I suggest downloading this repository and opening each .R file within RStudio (which you&#39;ll understand after reading the Introduction to R handout) to work through.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please let me know if you have any feedback or if you find any errors (or feel free to submit a pull request if you&#39;re technically savvy)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may find &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/doc/contrib/Short-refcard.pdf&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; reference card a useful reminder for common functions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seancmurphy.com/&#34;&gt;http://seancmurphy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Referencing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself wanting to cite this course, the easiest way to do so is to cite the Week 1 introductory guide, which is available as a pre-print on the Open Science Framework, and points to the larger course. You can do so as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Murphy, S. C. (2017, May 3). A Psychologist&#39;s Guide to R. Retrieved from osf.io/v48zr&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would prefer to directly cite the repository, you can do so as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Murphy, S. C. (2017, May 3). A Psychologist&#39;s Guide To R. Retrieved [Insert Date], from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/seanchrismurphy/A-Psychologists-Guide-to-R&#34;&gt;https://github.com/seanchrismurphy/A-Psychologists-Guide-to-R&lt;/a&gt;. DOI: 10.5281/zenodo.570953&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/latestdoi/89973875&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/89973875.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;This work is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>cran-task-views/MixedModels</title>
    <updated>2022-10-20T01:37:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-20:/cran-task-views/MixedModels</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cran-task-views/MixedModels" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CRAN Task View: Mixed, Multilevel, and Hierarchical Models in R&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;CRAN Task View: Mixed, Multilevel, and Hierarchical Models in R&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://CRAN.R-project.org/view=MixedModels&#34;&gt;https://CRAN.R-project.org/view=MixedModels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source file:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cran-task-views/MixedModels/main/MixedModels.md&#34;&gt;MixedModels.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributions:&lt;/strong&gt; Suggestions and improvements for this task view are very welcome and can be made through issues or pull requests here on GitHub or via e-mail to the maintainer address. For further details see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran-task-views/ctv/raw/main/Contributing.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; guide. All contributions must adhere to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cran-task-views/ctv/raw/main/CodeOfConduct.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>