<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-06T01:37:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>MilesMcBain/rmdgh</title>
    <updated>2022-09-06T01:37:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-06:/MilesMcBain/rmdgh</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MilesMcBain/rmdgh" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Put Github in your Rmd and Rmd in your GitHub&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;rmdgh&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if there exists an alternate timeline where (R)markdown is their HTML?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the overbearing richness of the modern web pared back to glorious responsive plain text interfaces... And how the inhabitants of this brave world would interact with their favourite centralised decentralised version control repository?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t yet go to this utopia, but we can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(&#xA;   &#34;rmdgh&#34;, &#xA;   repos = c(mm = &#34;https://milesmcbain.r-universe.dev&#34;, getOption(&#34;repos&#34;)))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get an R &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; GitHub productivity tool powered by Rmarkdown that works in VSCode or RStudio via &lt;code&gt;{rstudioapi}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Search Operations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;my_issues()&lt;/code&gt; issues by author (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issues_with_me()&lt;/code&gt; issues referring to author (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issues_for_me()&lt;/code&gt; issues created on an user&#39;s repositories (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;repo_issues()&lt;/code&gt; issues for a given repo or repos (defaults to current repo)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;my_prs()&lt;/code&gt; pr threads by an author (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;prs_with_me()&lt;/code&gt; pr threads referring to author (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;prs_for_me()&lt;/code&gt; pr threads for user&#39;s repos (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;repo_prs()&lt;/code&gt; prs for a given repo or repos (defaults to current repo)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gh_for_me()&lt;/code&gt; prs and issues for user&#39;s repos (defaults to you)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can change who &#39;me&#39; or &#39;my&#39; is. It defaults to you but if you do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;  my_issues(&#xA;    repos = &#34;tidyverse/dplyr&#34;,&#xA;    author = &#34;hadley&#34;&#xA;  )&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And you&#39;ll get Hadley&#39;s issues for &lt;code&gt;{dplyr}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;repos&lt;/code&gt; accepts multiple repos.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of these are built on top of &lt;code&gt;issues()&lt;/code&gt; which takes various arguments for searching and filtering issues and PRs to return to you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Search with text queries&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All search operations support &lt;code&gt;search_query&lt;/code&gt; which is text to search in the title and body of issues to filter search results. You can use this to find issues relating to problems you may be having. e.g.:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;repo_issues(&#xA;  repos = &#34;rdatatable/data.table&#34;, &#xA;  search_query = &#34;names(DT) reference semantics&#34;&#xA;  )&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Search Options&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issue_search_results_per_page&lt;/code&gt; Defines the search results per page. Defaults to 30. Max is 100.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Navigation Operations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You want to bind most of these to keys:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issue_seach_results_forward()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;get the next page of issue search results&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issue_search_results_backward()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;get the previous page of search results&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;issue_search_results_expand()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;search forward on the current line for the identifier of an issue and if found preview the issue body inline with search results.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;jump_to_issue_thread()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search as per &#39;expand&#39;, but go to the issue thread rendered as an Rmd document. You can submit updates to the issue, comments to the thread, or close the issue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;jump_to_issue_webpage()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search as per &lt;code&gt;expand&lt;/code&gt;, but go to the issue thread on GitHub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;refresh_issue_thread()&lt;/code&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;refresh the issue thread referred to by the current Rmd.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also &lt;code&gt;gh_thread()&lt;/code&gt; to open issue threads as Rmarkdown documents, which is designed for console use. E.g.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;gh_thread(&#34;capsule#12&#34;) &#xA;gh_thread(&#34;milesmcbain/capusle#12&#34;)&#xA;gh_thread() # read url from the clipboard&#xA;gh_thread(1) # issue 1 in the current repo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;GitHub issue thread RMarkdown output&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have an Rmarkdown output format called &lt;code&gt;github_issue&lt;/code&gt; that can be used to submit issues, issue updates, and issue comments to GitHub when the document is rendered with &lt;code&gt;rmarkdown::render()&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code&gt;knit&lt;/code&gt; button in RStudio, or the &lt;code&gt;Knit Rmd&lt;/code&gt; command in VSCode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Drafting issues&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;draft_issue()&lt;/code&gt; Will create a new RMarkdown GitHub issue, defaulting to the current repo. By default issues are created in a temporary directory but this can be set to the current working directory with option &lt;code&gt;draft_issue_in_tempdir = FALSE&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Config you can use looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---&#xA;title: Example&#xA;author: MilesMcBain&#xA;output:&#xA;  rmdgh::github_issue:&#xA;    repo: MilesMcBain/rmdgh&#xA;    number: 8&#xA;    labels: ~&#xA;    action: comment&#xA;    draft: no&#xA;    close_with_comment: no&#xA;---&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;action&lt;/code&gt; is one of &#39;create&#39;, &#39;update&#39;, &#39;comment&#39; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;number&lt;/code&gt; is only valid with &#39;update&#39; or &#39;comment&#39;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;action: update&lt;/code&gt; lets you update the issue title, body, and labels. Comments cannot be updated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;labels&lt;/code&gt; can be a single label or yaml list of labels. Only used on &#39;create&#39; and &#39;update&#39;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Commenting on Issues (and PRs)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can type in the necessary metadata to make a comment in the draft you&#39;re given above. But it&#39;s much nicer to navigate to the issue thread with &lt;code&gt;jump_to_issue_thread()&lt;/code&gt; described above. Metadata is automatically set up for to submit a comment on render in this case.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Making a reprex&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;reprex::reprex()&lt;/code&gt; doesn&#39;t really work well inside a code chunk. You may not even need it though, since rendering a &lt;code&gt;github_issue()&lt;/code&gt; does a similar thing to &lt;code&gt;{reprex}&lt;/code&gt; so long as you render it in a fresh session.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;code&gt;error = TRUE&lt;/code&gt; in the chunk options to display error output instead of stopping.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I decided to make a &lt;code&gt;{reprex}&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;{knitr}&lt;/code&gt; engine, since I think the specific output from the &lt;code&gt;{reprex}&lt;/code&gt; package is expected in some communities, and could cause confusion if it is absent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So with the new engine you can make a code chunk that uses &lt;code&gt;{reprex}&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;{r}&lt;/code&gt;. The output will be as if you had called &lt;code&gt;reprex::reprex()&lt;/code&gt; on the code in that chunk. Code in these chunks is self-contained, as per regular reprexes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why? Why have you done this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I find typing into little text input boxes on GitHub.com a bit of a buzz kill when drafting issues. My text editor feels so much nicer to draft technical communications with.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s also a bit of jankyness that comes from the fact that most of the time when drafting issues I&#39;ll want a reprex, which has to be coded up in R, rendered, and then pasted into the issue. But sometimes as the issue evolves the reprex needs to also, and there&#39;s awkward iterative back and forth involving context switching between applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the kind of source-output synchronisation and context switching pain that &lt;code&gt;{knitr}&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;{rmarkdown}&lt;/code&gt; take away. Why wouldn&#39;t we draft GitHub issues and comments that mash up code and prose in RMarkdown?!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why are you using Rmd instead of Quarto?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never used Quarto! I need to walk before I can run with all this document generation stuff. Also VSCode support for coding in R in Rmd is better than coding in R in Qmd.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And RMarkdown being displaced by Quarto means at some point in the future it&#39;s going to be all old school and vintage hipster cool. I&#39;m just getting ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Will you port this to Quarto at some point?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Possibly. I like the idea of being able to author issues that use multiple languages. However much of this package works via the &lt;code&gt;{rstudioapi}&lt;/code&gt; which means it&#39;s not likely to appeal to quarto users from other languages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably a Quarto version should be implemented as VSCode extension? But then the potential user base is much smaller at present. Let&#39;s see what Posit does with extensions in the stand-alone Quarto editor that must surely be coming.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>