<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-25T03:02:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>sjp/gridSVG</title>
    <updated>2023-08-25T03:02:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-25:/sjp/gridSVG</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sjp/gridSVG" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do not use this version of gridSVG as it is out of date. The version on CRAN is newer and development occurs on R-Forge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#x9;&#x9;R-Forge SVN README&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This file explains the repository structure of your project. A more detailed guide to R-Forge is available by Theußl and Zeileis (2010) [1] and the R-Forge Administration and Development Team (2009) [2].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;R is free software distributed under a GNU-style copyleft. R-Forge is a central platform for the development of R packages, R-related software and further projects. Among many other web-based features it provides facilities for collaborative source code management via Subversion (SVN) [3].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The directory you&#39;re in&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository of your project. It contains two important pre-defined directories namely &#39;pkg&#39; and &#39;www&#39;. These directories must not be deleted otherwise R-Forge&#39;s core functionality will not be available (i.e., daily checking and building of your package or the project websites). &#39;pkg&#39; and &#39;www&#39; are standardized and therefore are going to be described in this README. The rest of your repository can be used as you like.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&#39;pkg&#39; directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make use of the package building and checking feature the package source code has to be put into the &#39;pkg&#39; directory of your repository (i.e., &#39;pkg/DESCRIPTION&#39;, &#39;pkg/R&#39;, &#39;pkg/man&#39;, etc.) or, alternatively, a subdirectory of &#39;pkg&#39;. The latter structure allows for having more than one package in a single project, e.g., if a project consists of the packages foo and bar then the source code will be located in &#39;pkg/foo&#39; and &#39;pkg/bar&#39;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;R-Forge automatically examines the &#39;pkg&#39; directory of every repository and builds the package sources as well as the package binaries on a daily basis for Mac OS X and Windows (if applicable). The package builds are provided in the &#39;R Packages&#39; tab for download or can be installed directly in R from a CRAN-style repository using &#39;install.packages(&#34;foo&#34;, repos=&#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://R-Forge.R-project.org&#34;&gt;http://R-Forge.R-project.org&lt;/a&gt;&#34;)&#39;. Furthermore, in the &#39;R Packages&#39; tab developers can examine logs generated on different platforms by the build and check process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&#39;www&#39; directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developers may present their project on a subdomain of R-Forge, e.g., &#39;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foo.R-Forge.R-project.org&#34;&gt;http://foo.R-Forge.R-project.org&lt;/a&gt;&#39;, or via a link to an external website.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This directory contains the project homepage which gets updated hourly on R-Forge, so please take into consideration that it will not be available right after you commit your changes or additions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Help&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need help don&#39;t hesitate to submit a support request at &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-forge.r-project.org/tracker/?func=add&amp;amp;group_id=34&amp;amp;atid=194&#34;&gt;https://r-forge.r-project.org/tracker/?func=add&amp;amp;group_id=34&amp;amp;atid=194&lt;/a&gt;, search the forum &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-forge.r-project.org/forum/forum.php?forum_id=78&amp;amp;group_id=34&#34;&gt;https://r-forge.r-project.org/forum/forum.php?forum_id=78&amp;amp;group_id=34&lt;/a&gt;, or contact us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:R-Forge@R-project.org&#34;&gt;R-Forge@R-project.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;References&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[1] Stefan Theußl and Achim Zeileis. Collaborative software development using R-Forge. The R Journal, 1(1):9-14, May 2009. URL &lt;a href=&#34;http://journal.r-project.org/2009-1/RJournal_2009-1_Theussl+Zeileis.pdf&#34;&gt;http://journal.r-project.org/2009-1/RJournal_2009-1_Theussl+Zeileis.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[2] R-Forge Administration and Development Team. RForge User’s Manual, 2008. URL &lt;a href=&#34;http://download.R-Forge.R-project.org/R-Forge.pdf&#34;&gt;http://download.R-Forge.R-project.org/R-Forge.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[3] C. M. Pilato, B. Collins-Sussman, and B. W. Fitzpatrick. Version Control with Subversion. O’Reilly, 2004. Full book available online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://svnbook.red-bean.com/&#34;&gt;http://svnbook.red-bean.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>