<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-21T01:37:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-Chapel</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T01:37:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-21:/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-Chapel</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-Chapel" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🧠️🖥️2️⃣️0️⃣️0️⃣️1️⃣️💾️📜️ The sourceCode:Chapel category for AI2001, containing Chapel programming language datasets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/seanpm2001/AI2001/&#34;&gt;AI2001&lt;/a&gt; data sets&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Category: Source Code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Subcategory (SC): Chapel&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dataset is under development/coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌱️ This &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-Chapel/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-Chapel_Main-dev/README.md&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file is a major stub and need significant expansion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File version:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;1 (2023, Wednesday, August 16th at 09:08 pm PST)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>VermeirJellen/AlgorithmicTrading-Cointegration</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T01:37:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-21:/VermeirJellen/AlgorithmicTrading-Cointegration</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/VermeirJellen/AlgorithmicTrading-Cointegration" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Proof of concept Cointegration-Based spread trading strategy applied to the Foreign Exchange market&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cointegration-Based Statistical Arbitrage Trading Strategy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project consists of a proof of concept and conceptual demo of a simple stat-arb trading strategy that is based upon cointegration methods. View &lt;code&gt;./paper/Cointegration-Based spread trading applied to the foreign exchange market.pdf&lt;/code&gt; for a theoretical overview on the relevant statistical methods. The conceptual demo in this project implements the trading strategy that is explained in Chapter 4 of the paper. It is important to note the academic nature of the project: The demo trading results contain a severe lookahead bias because the strategy is executed on in-sample data. Hence, the trading results will most likely not correspond with realistic out of sample trading.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Running the Demo&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The entrance point to the demo is &lt;code&gt;./demo.R&lt;/code&gt; and the functionality is well documented inside the script. Following functionality is executed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A portfolio containing currency pair objects is created from the &lt;code&gt;.csv&lt;/code&gt; files which are provided in the &lt;code&gt;./data&lt;/code&gt; directory. It should be noted that all relevant timeseries are recreated in such a way that the USD currency pair becomes the quoted pair, for consistency reasons.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A particular data window is selected and the individual time series are plotted (line 23)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The timeseries are tested for integration of order 1: I(1)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The I(1) Currency pairs are grouped in smaller cointegrationTestPortfolioCollection objects. Cointegration tests are performed on these subgroups one by one, as follows: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;We obtain the optimal VAR lag length by searching for the VAR model that fits the timeseries data in the portfolio optimally, based upon the SC criterion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;We use this lag length to launch a Johansen cointegration procedure test on the portfolio.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;We use the trace statistic to determine the cointegration properties of the portfolio.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Some additional properties such as the half life of mean reversion are further determined for the cointegrating portfolios.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For this partcular demo run we determine that for 16 out of the 91 tested portfolios, the null hypothesis of no cointegrating vectors is rejected with more than 90% confidence.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For these particular portfolios we use the &#34;optimal&#34; cointegrating vectors with highest eigenvalues and we use the relevant vectorvalues as our hedge ratio&#39;s.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We use the hedge ratio&#39;s to create spreads for these cointegrating portfolios and output some graphs for illustration purposes (line 75)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We execute a simple mean reversion strategy on the cointegrating spread and output the results for Portfolio(AUDUSD/CADUSD) (Line 82)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We execute a simple mean reversion strategy on the cointegrating spread and output the results for Portfolio(AUDUSD/CADUSD/NZDUSD/JPYUSD/ (Line 92). We note that the latter portfolio has stronger cointegrating properties and a lower half life of mean reversion. As expected, The results -as expressed by the Sharpe ratio- for this portfolio are better (Transaction costs / bid-ask spreads are included in the analysis).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Trading Results&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;View the &lt;code&gt;./images&lt;/code&gt; folder for graphical illustrations of the trading results.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the event of problems or errors while running the code, make sure that your R version is up to date and all the required subpackages that are mentioned in &lt;code&gt;./config.r&lt;/code&gt; are installed properly. Uncommenting and executing the first 4 lines in &lt;code&gt;./config.R&lt;/code&gt; should resolve most potential problems that might occur. Also view the extended comments inside the &lt;code&gt;./classes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;./functions&lt;/code&gt; files for additional insight on the technical implementation details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Licensing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2015 Jellen Vermeir. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jellenvermeir@gmail.com&#34;&gt;jellenvermeir@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cointegration-Based Statistical Arbitrage Trading Strategy is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version. Cointegration-Based Statistical Arbitrage Trading Strategy is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public License along with Cointegration-Based Statistical Arbitrage Trading Strategy. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following people are given credit for the co-authoring of the attached paper:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thys Lynsey&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Van Overloop Hans&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Van Drom Karen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vanstreels Dieter&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trippaers Veerle&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-CMake</title>
    <updated>2023-08-21T01:37:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-21:/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-CMake</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-CMake" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🧠️🖥️2️⃣️0️⃣️0️⃣️1️⃣️💾️📜️ The sourceCode:CMake category for AI2001, containing CMake programming language datasets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/seanpm2001/AI2001/&#34;&gt;AI2001&lt;/a&gt; data sets&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Category: Source Code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Subcategory (SC): CMake&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dataset is under development/coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🌱️ This &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/seanpm2001/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-CMake/AI2001_Category-Source_Code-SC-CMake_Main-dev/README.md&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file is a major stub and need significant expansion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File version:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;1 (2023, Sunday, August 13th at 05:30 pm PST)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>