<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:33Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>justinsbenjamin/Egg_Chick_Project</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/justinsbenjamin/Egg_Chick_Project</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/justinsbenjamin/Egg_Chick_Project" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a project I am working on to explore if there are any patterns or relationships between the size of Pūkeko (Porphyrio melanotus melanotus) eggs (i.e. length and width), the order of laying and hatching, and the size of chicks at hatching. I have been putting together a multi-year dataset from 2008, 2010, 2013-19, 2022-23. Some years are missing some egg size data. Otherwise I have data egg size, length from the end of the shield to the tip of the beak, and length of the left outer tarsus at hatching measured in millimeters using digital calipers. I also have the mass of the chicks at hatching using a spring scale. The chicks were placed in small sacs and the mass is the total mass minus the mass of the bag. The laying order is only known when addtional eggs were found in the nest during monitoring. For example, there were 3 eggs when the nest was first found, and 4 eggs the next day, we know which egg was laid 4th. Pūkeko can have varying degrees of hatching synchrony with some clutches all hatching at the same time and other nests that all hatch on different days. The hatching order is only known when there were not synchronous hatching of multiple chicks at the same time. Sometimes we can tell which chick came from which egg based on which eggs are left in the nest when chicks are found, or we observe them actively hatching. When this occurs, we can also tell the hatching order of the chicks. Most of my analyses will be using this complete dataset with known egg size, hatching order, and chick morphometric measurments at hatching.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>infotroph/ggplotTicks</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/infotroph/ggplotTicks</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/infotroph/ggplotTicks" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Copy axes from bottom to top and left to right sides of a ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ggplotTicks&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Provides a single&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt; function &lt;code&gt;mirror_ticks&lt;/code&gt; that puts scale ticks on all four sides on a ggplot by copying axes from bottom to top and left to right. Think of this as a replacement for the panel grid; it is not a way of adding multiple scales to the same plot.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;Plus a helper function or two, but these may or may not ever be useful outside of &lt;code&gt;mirror_ticks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;From R using &lt;code&gt;devtools&lt;/code&gt; (recommended)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;devtools&#34;)&#xA;library(&#34;devtools&#34;)&#xA;install_github(&#34;infotroph/ggplotTicks&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; you can ignore the step of the &lt;code&gt;devtools&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/devtools/README.html&#34;&gt;installation instructions&lt;/a&gt; where it claims you need a full development toolchain (on OS X this involves a multi-gigabyte download of Xcode). If you have any trouble installing on a machine with no developer tools, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current version of ggplotTicks (0.1.0) does not work with versions of ggplot2 older than 2.0. If you are using ggplot2 v. 1.x and can&#39;t upgrade it yet, you&#39;ll need to use ggplotTicks 0.0.2: &lt;code&gt;install_github(&#34;infotroph/ggplotTicks&#34;, ref=&#34;v0.0.2&#34;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;From a command line&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably only necessary if you want to edit the package code. Modify these commands as needed for your system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/infotroph/ggplotTicks.git&#xA;R CMD build ggplotTicks&#xA;R CMD install ggplotTicks_&amp;lt;version.number.here&amp;gt;.tar.gz&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Basic usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The basic idea: make a plot, call mirror_ticks on it, then either plot it as it is or keep modifying.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(ggplot2)&#xA;library(ggplotTicks)&#xA;&#xA;plt = (ggplot(iris, aes(Sepal.Length, Petal.Length))&#xA;&#x9;+geom_point())&#xA;&#xA;plt_m = mirror_ticks(plt)&#xA;plt_m&#xA;plt_m + theme_bw() + geom_smooth(aes(group=Species))&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think mirrored ticks look best with no background grid.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;theme_nogrid = theme_bw() + theme(&#xA;&#x9;panel.grid.major = element_blank(),&#xA;&#x9;panel.grid.minor = element_blank(),&#xA;&#x9;axis.ticks.length = unit(-0.25 , &#34;lines&#34;),&#xA;&#x9;axis.text.x = element_text(margin=margin(t=1, unit=&#34;lines&#34;)),&#xA;&#x9;axis.text.y = element_text(margin=margin(r=1, unit=&#34;lines&#34;)))&#xA;&#xA;plt_m_s + theme_nogrid + geom_smooth(aes(group=Species))&#xA;plt_m_s&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mirroring works within facets too, though you have to think about what you want: Ticks on all the edges of the &lt;em&gt;plot&lt;/em&gt;, or on all edges of &lt;em&gt;each panel&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;carplt = (ggplot(mtcars, aes(wt, mpg))&#xA;&#x9;+geom_point()&#xA;&#x9;+facet_grid(cyl~am)&#xA;&#x9;+theme_nogrid)&#xA;mirror_ticks(carplt)&#xA;mirror_ticks(carplt, allPanels=T)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here both approaches work reasonably well. But when axes differ between panels, you probably ~always want allPanels=TRUE:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dplt = (ggplot(diamonds, aes(z, price, color=cut))&#xA;&#x9;+geom_point()&#xA;&#x9;+theme_nogrid&#xA;&#x9;+facet_wrap(~clarity, scales=&#34;free&#34;))&#xA;mirror_ticks(dplt, allPanels=FALSE) # Almost certainly not what you want&#xA;mirror_ticks(dplt, allPanels=TRUE) # Better&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known limitations:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Changing facets will lose mirroring, because ggplot does all its axis rendering inside the facet functions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; mirror_ticks(plt + facet_wrap(~Species)) # has mirrored ticks&#xA; mirror_ticks(plt) + facet_wrap(~Species) # does not&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you call &lt;code&gt;mirror_ticks&lt;/code&gt; last thing before plotting, this will not affect you. If you prefer to call it earlier and then find you need to refacet an already-mirrored plot, the easiest workaround is to simply wrap another &lt;code&gt;mirror_ticks()&lt;/code&gt; around the result. It&#39;s no problem to call mirror_ticks multiple times on the same object, so if in doubt mirror it again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mirroring fails in the case where one or both axes contain no ticks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A slightly contrived example: Let&#39;s say you have a boxplot with in-panel labels, so you want to remove the x-axis but still mirror the y-axis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; mtlab = aggregate(drat~am, data=mtcars, FUN=mean)&#xA; p = (ggplot(mtcars, aes(factor(am), drat))&#xA; &#x9;+geom_boxplot()&#xA; &#x9;+geom_text(data=mtlab, aes(label=am))&#xA; &#x9;+theme_nogrid)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;One fairly easy way to remove an axis is by setting &lt;code&gt;breaks=NULL&lt;/code&gt;, but that makes mirror_ticks fail:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; p_nox = p + scale_x_discrete(breaks=NULL)&#xA; mirror_ticks(p_nox)&#xA; # Error in match_axes(cur_panel, axis_extents) : Can&#39;t match axes to panel&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;One possible workaround for this case: Remove the x-axis in the theme instead of in the scale.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; p_hidx = p + theme(&#xA; &#x9;&#x9;axis.ticks.x=element_blank(),&#xA; &#x9;&#x9;axis.text.x=element_blank())&#xA; mirror_ticks(p_hidx)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>