<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-23T01:44:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>InsightRX/clinPK</title>
    <updated>2023-01-23T01:44:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-23:/InsightRX/clinPK</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/InsightRX/clinPK" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Equations and tools for clinical pharmacokinetics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;clinPK: Clinical Pharmacokinetics Toolkit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clinPK package provides equations commonly used in clinical pharmacokinetics and clinical pharmacology, such as equations for dose individualization, compartmental pharmacokinetics, drug exposure, anthropomorphic calculations, clinical chemistry, and conversion of common clinical parameters. Where possible and relevant, it provides multiple published and peer-reviewed equations within the respective R function.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The development version of clinPK always has the most up-to-date improvements and bug fixes. We aim to release clinPK on CRAN at least once a year, depending on the number and impact of updates made to the development version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CRAN version of clinPK can be installed using:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;clinPK&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The development version of clinPK can be installed using:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&#34;InsightRX/clinPK&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome input from the community:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you think you have encountered a bug, please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/InsightRX/clinPK/issues&#34;&gt;submit an issue&lt;/a&gt; on the GitHub page. Please include a reproducible example of the unexpected behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/InsightRX/clinPK/pulls&#34;&gt;open a pull request&lt;/a&gt; if you have a fix or updates that would improve the package. If you&#39;re not sure if your proposed changes are useful or within scope of the package, feel free to contact one of the authors of this package.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The functionality in this R package is provided &#34;as is&#34;. While its authors adhere to software development best practices, the software may still contain unintended errors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;InsightRX Inc. and the authors of this package can not be held liable for any damages resulting from any use of this software. By the use of this software package, the user waives all warranties, expressed or implied, including any warranties to the accuracy, quality or suitability of InsightRX for any particular purpose, either medical or non-medical.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;&#xA;  © &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/InsightRX/clinPK/master/man/figures/insightrx_logo_color.png&#34; alt=&#34;InsightRX logo&#34; width=&#34;120&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>cran/grafzahl</title>
    <updated>2023-01-23T01:44:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-23:/cran/grafzahl</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cran/grafzahl" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;❗ This is a read-only mirror of the CRAN R package repository. grafzahl — Supervised Machine Learning for Textual Data Using Transformers and &#39;Quanteda&#39;. Homepage: https://github.com/chainsawriot/grafzahl Report bugs for this package: https://github.com/chainsawriot/grafzahl/issues&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>