<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-09T01:35:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tubanlee/REDS_Nonasymptotic</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T01:35:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-09:/tubanlee/REDS_Nonasymptotic</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubanlee/REDS_Nonasymptotic" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Robust estimations from distribution structures: III. Non-asymptotic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Robust estimations from distribution structures: Non-asymptotic.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the hardness of order statistics, finite sample bias of robust statistics is generally unsolvable. Monte Carlo method can provide approximate solutions, but the convergence rate is very low, so the computational cost to achieve desired accuracy is unaffordable for ordinary users. Here, with a comparametric approach, the distribution structure of order statistics is decomposed. By obtaining a set of quasi-random variables simultaneously consistent for two or more different estimators, the finite sample bias of other related estimators can be approximated with much less computational costs. This article provides a different and prospective approach to integrate two or more parametric assumptions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These works have been publically deposited in this Github since one year ago for a PNAS paper (I hidden some previous versions after updated new versions, e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tubanlee/FiniteSampleBias&#34;&gt;https://github.com/tubanlee/FiniteSampleBias&lt;/a&gt;). I am introducing this work in YouTube and Quora, if you are interested, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&#34;&gt;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&lt;/a&gt; . Also, the manuscript has been deposited in Zenodo. Tuobang Li. (2024). Robust estimations from distribution structures: V. Non-asymptotic. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10616689&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10616689&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974622_Robust_estimations_from_distribution_structures_V_Non-Asymptotic&#34;&gt;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974622_Robust_estimations_from_distribution_structures_V_Non-Asymptotic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to share it or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tl@biomathematics.org&#34;&gt;tl@biomathematics.org&lt;/a&gt;, for more materials available by request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;view counts since 2024, February, 8th &lt;img src=&#34;https://profile-counter.glitch.me/%7Btubanlee%7D.$%7BREDS_Nonasymptotic%7D/count.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Visitor Count&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tubanlee/MM</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T01:35:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-09:/tubanlee/MM</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubanlee/MM" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Infer metabolic directions from moment differences of mass-weighted intensity distributions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Infer metabolic directions from moment differences of mass-weighted intensity distributions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metabolic pathways are fundamental maps in biochemistry that detail how molecules are transformed through various reactions. Metabolomics refers to the large-scale study of small molecules. High-throughput, untargeted, mass spectrometry-based metabolomics experiments typically depend on libraries for structural annotation, which is necessary for pathway analysis. However, only a small fraction of spectra can be matched to known structures in these libraries and only a portion of annotated metabolites can be associated with specific pathways, considering that numerous pathways are yet to be discovered. The complexity of metabolic pathways, where a single compound can play a part in multiple pathways, poses an additional challenge. This study introduces a different concept: mass spectra distribution, which is the empirical distribution of the intensities times their associated m/z values. Analysis of COVID-19 and mouse brain datasets shows that by estimating the differences of the point estimations of these distributions, it becomes possible to infer the metabolic directions and magnitudes without requiring knowledge of the exact chemical structures of these compounds and their related pathways. The overall metabolic momentum map, named as momentome, has the potential to bypass the current bottleneck and provide fresh insights into metabolomics studies. This brief report thus provides a mathematical framing for a classic biological concept.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work was finished two years ago, and later I shared to some professors. I registered the domain, &lt;a href=&#34;http://directome.org&#34;&gt;http://directome.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://biomathematics.org&#34;&gt;http://biomathematics.org&lt;/a&gt; in January, 2022. It is prepared for PNAS. I am introducing this work in YouTube and Quora, if you are interested, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&#34;&gt;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&lt;/a&gt; . Also, the manuscript has been deposited in Zenodo, Tuobang Li. (2024). Infer metabolic momentum from moment differences of mass-weighted intensity distributions. Zenodo. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10616979&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10616979&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974502_Infer_metabolic_directions_from_moment_differences_of_mass-weighted_intensity_distributions&#34;&gt;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974502_Infer_metabolic_directions_from_moment_differences_of_mass-weighted_intensity_distributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to share it or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tl@biomathematics.org&#34;&gt;tl@biomathematics.org&lt;/a&gt;, for more materials available by request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;view counts since 2024, February, 8th &lt;img src=&#34;https://profile-counter.glitch.me/%7Btubanlee%7D.$%7BMM%7D/count.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Visitor Count&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tubanlee/REDS_Invariant_Moments</title>
    <updated>2024-02-09T01:35:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-09:/tubanlee/REDS_Invariant_Moments</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tubanlee/REDS_Invariant_Moments" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Robust estimations from distribution structures: Invariant moments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Robust estimations from distribution structures: Invariant moments.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Descriptive statistics for parametric models are currently highly sensative to departures, gross errors, and/or random errors. Here, leveraging the structures of parametric distributions and their central moment kernel distributions, a class of estimators, consistent si-multanously for both a semiparametric distribution and a distinct parametric distribution, is proposed. These efficient estimators are robust to both gross errors and departures from parametric assumptions , making them ideal for estimating the mean and central moments of common unimodal distributions. This article also illuminates the understanding of the common nature of probability distributions and the measures of them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These works have been publically deposited in this Github since one year ago for a PNAS paper (I hidden some previous versions after updated new versions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tubanlee/NRS3333&#34;&gt;https://github.com/tubanlee/NRS3333&lt;/a&gt;). I am introducing this work in YouTube and Quora, if you are interested, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/@Iobiomathematics&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&#34;&gt;https://www.quora.com/profile/Tuobang-Li-1/answers&lt;/a&gt; . Also, the manuscript has been deposited in Zenodo Tuobang Li. (2022). Robust estimations for semiparametric models: Moments. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8127703&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.8127703&lt;/a&gt; and research gate &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974419_Robust_estimations_from_distribution_structures_III_Invariant_Moments&#34;&gt;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/377974419_Robust_estimations_from_distribution_structures_III_Invariant_Moments&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to share it or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tl@biomathematics.org&#34;&gt;tl@biomathematics.org&lt;/a&gt;, for more materials available by request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;view counts since 2024, February, 8th &lt;img src=&#34;https://profile-counter.glitch.me/%7Btubanlee%7D.$%7BREDS_Invariant_Moments%7D/count.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Visitor Count&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>