<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-16T01:39:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>course-dprep/team-assignment-team-2</title>
    <updated>2022-09-16T01:39:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-16:/course-dprep/team-assignment-team-2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/course-dprep/team-assignment-team-2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;team-assignment-team-2 created by GitHub Classroom&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Most appealing cities in the US to rent an Airbnb during the week&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &#39;most appealing cities in the US to rent an Airbnb during the week&#39; repository. This README provides detailed instructions on how to use the contents in this repository for future use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Airbnb is started in 2007, when two hosts opened their San Francisco home to three guests. Since then, it has expanded to over 4 million hosts and more than 1 billion guest arrivals in practically every nation on earth. Through the internet marketplace Airbnb, homeowners who wish to rent out their properties can connect with travelers looking for accommodation in particular areas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previously, Airbnbs were mostly rented on weekends. While renters still show up on weekends, weekday stays are becoming increasingly popular in the U.S. People who rent out an Airbnb are quickly inclined to lower their prices for renting the Airbnb during the week, while instead, they can increase prices because of the increasing demand. By gathering and analyzing data, it is possible to find out in which U.S. cities there is a higher demand for stays during the week. The general question for this study project is as follows: “&lt;em&gt;Which U.S. cities are most appealing to rent your private room during the week?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example of reproducible research workflow&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a basic example repository using Gnu make for a reproducible research workflow, as described in detail here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tilburgsciencehub.com/&#34;&gt;tilburgsciencehub.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main aim of this to have a basic structure, which can be easily adjusted to use in an actual project. In this example project, the following is done:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download and prepare data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run some analysis&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Present results in a final pdf generated using LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;R&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;R packages: &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;stargazer&#34;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tilburgsciencehub.com/get/make&#34;&gt;Gnu Make&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tilburgsciencehub.com/get/latex/?utm_campaign=referral-short&#34;&gt;TeX distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For the &lt;code&gt;makefile&lt;/code&gt; to work, R, Gnu make and the TeX distribution (specifically &lt;code&gt;pdflatex&lt;/code&gt;) need to be made available in the system path&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Detailed installation instructions can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tilburgsciencehub.com/&#34;&gt;tilburgsciencehub.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;make clean&lt;/code&gt; removes all unncessary temporary files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tested under Linux Mint (should work in any linux distro, as well as on Windows and Mac)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;IMPORTANT: In &lt;code&gt;makefile&lt;/code&gt;, when using &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt; to split code into multiple lines, no space should follow &lt;code&gt;\&lt;/code&gt;. Otherwise Gnu make aborts with error 193.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Many possible improvements remain. Comments and contributions are welcome!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>