<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-12T01:41:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/Azure-TDSP-ProjectTemplate</title>
    <updated>2023-03-12T01:41:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-12:/Azure/Azure-TDSP-ProjectTemplate</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/Azure-TDSP-ProjectTemplate" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;TDSP: Data science project template repository with standardized directory structure and document templates to support efficient project execution and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;TDSP Project Structure, and Documents and Artifact Templates&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a general project directory structure for Team Data Science Process developed by Microsoft. It also contains templates for various documents that are recommended as part of executing a data science project when using TDSP.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/machine-learning/team-data-science-process/overview&#34;&gt;Team Data Science Process (TDSP)&lt;/a&gt; is an agile, iterative, data science methodology to improve collaboration and team learning. It is supported through a lifecycle definition, standard project structure, artifact templates, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Azure-TDSP-Utilities&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; for productive data science.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; In this directory structure, the &lt;strong&gt;Sample_Data folder is NOT supposed to contain LARGE raw or processed data&lt;/strong&gt;. It is only supposed to contain &lt;strong&gt;small and sample&lt;/strong&gt; data sets, which could be used to test the code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The two documents under Docs/Project, namely the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/Azure-TDSP-ProjectTemplate/master/Docs/Project/Charter.md&#34;&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/Azure-TDSP-ProjectTemplate/master/Docs/Project/Exit%20Report.md&#34;&gt;Exit Report&lt;/a&gt; are particularly important to consider. They help to define the project at the start of an engagement, and provide a final report to the customer or client.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; In some projects, e.g. short term proof of principle (PoC) or proof of value (PoV) engagements, it can be relatively time consuming to create and all the recommended documents and artifacts. In that case, at least the Charter and Exit Report should be created and delivered to the customer or client. As necessary, organizations may modify certain sections of the documents. But it is strongly recommended that the content of the documents be maintained, as they provide important information about the project and deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>