<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-03T01:52:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>cbdavis/RSemanticMediaWikiBot</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T01:52:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/cbdavis/RSemanticMediaWikiBot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cbdavis/RSemanticMediaWikiBot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bot for editing Semantic MediaWiki templates, written in R&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;RSemanticMediaWikiBot&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an bot developed in R for editing Semantic MediaWiki templates. This code is very much in development, and it is highly recommended to test it on a few pages before letting it loose on a wiki.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary motivation for &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Creating_a_bot#Programming_languages_and_libraries&#34;&gt;Yet Another MediaWiki Bot Framework&lt;/a&gt; is that this bot is specifically design to help with batch editing of data contained within &lt;a href=&#34;http://semantic-mediawiki.org/wiki/Help:Semantic_templates&#34;&gt;Semantic Templates&lt;/a&gt; that are commonly used with &lt;a href=&#34;http://semantic-mediawiki.org/&#34;&gt;Semantic MediaWiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main idea is that this bot converts templates into data structures in R. For example, it allows you to read from a wiki page a template such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;{{City&#xA;| point=52.015, 4.356667&#xA;| country=Netherlands&#xA;}}&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;...and then convert this data into a list within R. The data contained in the list can be accessed via template$point, template$country, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#39;devtools&#39;) # only if not already installed&#xA;library(devtools)&#xA;install_github(&#34;cbdavis/RSemanticMediaWikiBot&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The functions can then be accessed from within R code by first declaring:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;library(RSemanticMediaWikiBot)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Basic usage - logging in, reading, editing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Logging in&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;#TODO fill these in based on your own configuration&#xA;username=USERNAME&#xA;password=PASSWORD&#xA;apiURL = &#34;http://my.wiki.com/wiki/api.php&#34;&#xA;&#xA;bot = initializeBot(apiURL) #initialize the bot&#xA;login(username, password, bot) #login to the wiki&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Reading page text&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;text = read(title=&#34;MyWikiPage&#34;, bot) &#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Editing and saving page text&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;edit(title=&#34;MyWikiPage&#34;, &#xA;     text=&#34;this is the new page text&#34;, &#xA;     bot, &#xA;     summary=&#34;my edit summary&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Deleting pages&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;delete(pageName, bot, reason=&#34;deleting old page&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Working with template data&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Extracting templates&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming that you are not working with multiple instance templates, you can retrieve and modify the data in a template as such:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;template = getTemplateByName(&#34;MyTemplateName&#34;, &#34;MyWikiPage&#34;, bot)[[1]]&#xA;#[[1]] is needed as a list is returned&#xA;#If using multiple-instance templates, then multiple templates will be returned&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Getting and modifying values of template parameters&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;valueOfTemplate = template$data$NameOfTemplateParameter&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can then modify this value by:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;template$data$NameOfTemplateParameter = newValue&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Removing template parameters&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to completely remove a parameter from a template (i.e. both the key and the value) such as changing this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;{{City&#xA;| point=52.015, 4.356667&#xA;| country=Netherlands&#xA;}}&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;to this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;{{City&#xA;| country=Netherlands&#xA;}}&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;then you can just do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;template$data$point = NULL&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Writing the template back to the wiki page&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The template with its new value can then be written back to the wiki as such:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;writeTemplateToPage(template, bot, editSummary=&#34;testing bot&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The template contains information about the page which it came from, so the name of the page does not need to be specified.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Writing Spreadsheet Data to Multiple Pages&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheet data loaded into a dataframe can be used to make it easy to write data to templates contained on multiple pages. The first column of the data frame specifies the name of the page, while the second column is the name of the template to write to. The headers for the rest of the columns need to correspond to the names of the parameters in that template. The default behavior of this code is to not overwrite existing values unless you explicitly tell it to. A list of pages for which an existing value for a parameter were found are returned.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;# default - will not overwrite existing parameter values that are already set&#xA;errorDFEntries = writeDataFrameToPageTemplates(dataFrame, bot, editSummary=&#34;what the bot is doing&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;# overwrite existing values&#xA;errorDFEntries = writeDataFrameToPageTemplates(dataFrame, bot, overWriteConflicts=TRUE, editSummary=&#34;what the bot is doing&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Writing a Data Frame to a Table on a Single page&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The syntax for a sortable wikitable can be generated from a data frame. The code currently doesn&#39;t figure out how to intelligently put it on a page - it&#39;s up to you to figure out how to paste things together in some useful way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&#xA;# get the wiki table syntax&#xA;wikiTable = getWikiTableTextForDataFrame(df)&#xA;&#xA;# put some text before and after the table&#xA;pageText = paste(someText, &#34;\n\n&#34;, wikiTable, &#34;\n\n&#34;, someMoreText, sep=&#34;&#34;)&#xA;  &#xA;# write this all to some wiki page&#xA;edit(title=pageTitle,&#xA;     text=pageText,&#xA;     bot,&#xA;     summary=&#34;adding a table&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future development/known issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No support yet for multiple-instance templates. There needs to be a way to distinguish if one wants to edit an existing one, or add another. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA; &lt;li&gt;No support yet for adding a new template to a page. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA; &lt;li&gt;When editing a page, no check is done to see if it will create the page. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nested template calls may not be parsed correctly &lt;/li&gt;&#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the code is not able to connect to the wiki API, then it will terminate instead of trying to connect again. In practical experience, this means that you may have to run a script multiple times if you have several thousand edits. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA; &lt;li&gt;There seems to be a memory leak if you read and/or edit around 10,000+ pages. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>marcosci/climate_multiples</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T01:52:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/marcosci/climate_multiples</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/marcosci/climate_multiples" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Small spatial multiples with R&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/marcosci/climate_multiples/main/germany_heating_up.png&#34; alt=&#34;Germany is heating up&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>JGCRI/gcam-core</title>
    <updated>2022-07-03T01:52:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-03:/JGCRI/gcam-core</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/JGCRI/gcam-core" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GCAM -- The Global Change Analysis Model&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Global Change Analysis Model (GCAM)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Joint Global Change Research Institute (JGCRI) is the home and primary development institution for GCAM, an integrated assessment tool for exploring consequences and responses to global change. Climate change is a global issue that impacts all regions of the world and all sectors of the global economy. Thus, any responses to the threat of climate change, such as policies or international agreements to limit greenhouse gas emissions, can have wide ranging consequences throughout the energy system as well as on land use and land cover. Integrated assessment models endeavor to represent all world regions and all sectors of the economy in an economic framework in order to explore interactions between sectors and understand the potential ramifications of climate mitigation actions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GCAM has been developed at PNNL for over 20 years and is now a freely available community model and documented online (See below). The team at JGCRI is comprised of economists, engineers, energy experts, forest ecologists, agricultural scientists, and climate system scientists who develop the model and apply it to a range of science and policy questions and work closely with Earth system and ecosystem modelers to integrate the human decision components of GCAM into their analyses.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Model Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GCAM is a dynamic-recursive model with technology-rich representations of the economy, energy sector, land use and water linked to a climate model that can be used to explore climate change mitigation policies including carbon taxes, carbon trading, regulations and accelerated deployment of energy technology. Regional population and labor productivity growth assumptions drive the energy and land-use systems employing numerous technology options to produce, transform, and provide energy services as well as to produce agriculture and forest products, and to determine land use and land cover. Using a run period extending from 1990 – 2100 at 5 year intervals, GCAM has been used to explore the potential role of emerging energy supply technologies and the greenhouse gas consequences of specific policy measures or energy technology adoption including; CO2 capture and storage, bioenergy, hydrogen systems, nuclear energy, renewable energy technology, and energy use technology in buildings, industry and the transportation sectors. GCAM is an Representative Concentration Pathway (RCP)-class model. This means it can be used to simulate scenarios, policies, and emission targets from various sources including the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). Output includes projections of future energy supply and demand and the resulting greenhouse gas emissions, radiative forcing and climate effects of 16 greenhouse gases, aerosols and short-lived species at 0.5×0.5 degree resolution, contingent on assumptions about future population, economy, technology, and climate mitigation policy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jgcri.github.io/gcam-doc/&#34;&gt;GCAM Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jgcri.github.io/gcam-doc/user-guide.html&#34;&gt;Getting Started with GCAM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.globalchange.umd.edu/models/gcam/gcam-community/&#34;&gt;GCAM Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gcims.pnnl.gov/community&#34;&gt;GCAM Videos and Tutorial Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Selected Publications&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Calvin, K., Patel, P., Clarke, L., Asrar, G., Bond-Lamberty, B., Cui, R. Y., Di Vittorio, A., Dorheim, K., Edmonds, J., Hartin, C., Hejazi, M., Horowitz, R., Iyer, G., Kyle, P., Kim, S., Link, R., McJeon, H., Smith, S. J., Snyder, A., Waldhoff, S., and Wise, M.: GCAM v5.1: representing the linkages between energy, water, land, climate, and economic systems, Geosci. Model Dev., 12, 677–698, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-12-677-2019&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-12-677-2019&lt;/a&gt;, 2019.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edmonds, J., and J. Reilly (1985)Global Energy: Assessing the Future (Oxford University Press, New York) pp.317.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edmonds, J., M. Wise, H. Pitcher, R. Richels, T. Wigley, and C. MacCracken. (1997) “An Integrated Assessment of Climate Change and the Accelerated Introduction of Advanced Energy Technologies”, Mitigation and Adaptation Strategies for Global Change, 1, pp. 311-39&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kim, S.H., J. Edmonds, J. Lurz, S. J. Smith, and M. Wise (2006) “The ObjECTS Framework for Integrated Assessment: Hybrid Modeling of Transportation ” Energy Journal (Special Issue #2) pp 51-80.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jgcri.github.io/gcam-doc/references.html&#34;&gt;Full list of GCAM publications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>