<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-08T01:39:36Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Env-Data-Sci-FA23/Week-4-Geospatial</title>
    <updated>2023-11-08T01:39:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-08:/Env-Data-Sci-FA23/Week-4-Geospatial</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Env-Data-Sci-FA23/Week-4-Geospatial" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Week 4: Geospatial data analysis and visualization&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week is an introduction to working with spatial data in R. You will learn spatial data types, new packages to work with and analyze vector (&lt;code&gt;sf&lt;/code&gt;) and raster (&lt;code&gt;terra&lt;/code&gt;) data and visualize spatial data with the &lt;code&gt;tmap&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will also learn of some new R packages you can use to retrieve spatial data from different databases, such as the &lt;code&gt;rgbif&lt;/code&gt; package which retrieves species occurrence data from the GBIF database and &lt;code&gt;soilDB&lt;/code&gt; to retrieve snow depth data from SNOTEL sites around the U.S.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are more resources on working with geospatial data in R: - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/giswqs/geospatial-data-catalogs&#34;&gt;List of open-source geospatial datasets&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/appsilon-data-science/r-ggmap-how-to-visualize-spatial-data-in-r-c46dcf970095&#34;&gt;Visualize spatial data with &lt;code&gt;ggmap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Material/Assignment&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 2 required lesson plans this week that will count towards your assignment. Remeber to first &lt;strong&gt;Fork&lt;/strong&gt; this repository then &lt;strong&gt;clone your forked repo&lt;/strong&gt;, and save copies of each .Rmd with &lt;em&gt;your name&lt;/em&gt; appended to the file name. Below are descriptions of each assignment with links to the associated video tutorials:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01_spatial_intro.Rmd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02_spatial_analysis.Rmd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To submit your assignment, remember to push all your file edits to GitHub and then submit a pull request by clicking &#39;Contribute&#39; -&amp;gt; &#39;Open a Pull Request&#39; from the home page of your forked repo. The two assignments above will be due &lt;strong&gt;Monday 11/13&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a reminder, it is okay to submit the pull request before you&#39;ve finished all assignments. Any new file changes pushed to GitHub after will just be appended to your existing pull request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bonus Material&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few lessons/challenges that are &lt;strong&gt;not required&lt;/strong&gt; but may be worth your time (and extra credit..). Located in the &#39;bonus/&#39; subfolder, you will find the following files:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;get_spatial_challenge.Rmd&lt;/strong&gt; : Worth up to 3 extra credit points if fully completed&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;spatial_viz.Rmd&lt;/strong&gt; : A fun lesson to explore more visualization techniques&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>