<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-14T01:58:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ParkKyuSeon/Maplestory_DPM</title>
    <updated>2022-06-14T01:58:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-14:/ParkKyuSeon/Maplestory_DPM</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ParkKyuSeon/Maplestory_DPM" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>reichlab/covidData</title>
    <updated>2022-06-14T01:58:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-14:/reichlab/covidData</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/reichlab/covidData" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Versioned covid data&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;covidData&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5208224&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zenodo.org/badge/DOI/10.5281/zenodo.5208224.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;DOI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an R package that provides versioned time series data for COVID-19 from the JHU data repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19/tree/master/csse_covid_19_data/csse_covid_19_time_series&#34;&gt;https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19/tree/master/csse_covid_19_data/csse_covid_19_time_series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation and Updating Data&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this package to be useful, you will need to clone it and install it from your local copy after you have updated the data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To clone the repository, in a terminal you can run &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/reichlab/covidData.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;installation prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need R 3.x or 4.x&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;installation using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We recommend using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; to simplify the updating of data. However, some Windows operating systems do not allow for easy use of the command &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;, so manual installation should be used if &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; does not work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt;, you must complete the following steps once you have cloned the repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In a terminal/shell window, navigate to &lt;code&gt;code/data-processing&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;make all&lt;/code&gt;. (This runs the steps below.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: If you want to only download the most recent JHU data files, for step 2. instead run &lt;code&gt;make recent_data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;manual installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If make does not work for you, you may run the following steps by hand. To update the data, please:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository. If you have previously installed covidData from an existing local clone, pull any updates to the package by running &lt;code&gt;git pull origin master&lt;/code&gt; from the terminal, with the repository folder as your working directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;R CMD INSTALL covidData&lt;/code&gt; from the terminal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;data disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*The names of locations included on the Website correspond with the official designations used by the U.S. Department of State. The presentation of material therein does not imply the expression of any opinion whatsoever on the part of JHU concerning the legal status of any country, area or territory or of its authorities. The depiction and use of boundaries, geographic names and related data shown on maps and included in lists, tables, documents, and databases on this website are not warranted to be error free nor do they necessarily imply official endorsement or acceptance by JHU.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mcompetitions/M4-methods</title>
    <updated>2022-06-14T01:58:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-14:/Mcompetitions/M4-methods</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Mcompetitions/M4-methods" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data, Benchmarks, and methods submitted to the M4 forecasting competition&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;M4-methods&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is dedicated to the M4 forecasting competition, the continuation of the previous three ones organized by Spyros Makridakis (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Makridakis_Competitions&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Makridakis_Competitions&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each folder includes source code that can be used for reproducing the forecasts submitted to the M4 Competition, as well as a short description of the methods utilized. Note that not all of the participants shared their code, meaning that some of the methods might not be available at this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Dataset” folder includes the Train and Test set of the competition, as well as an Info file providing additional information per series, i.e. their ID (M4id), domain (category), frequency (Frequency), number of forecasts requested (Horizon), seasonal periods (SP) and starting date (StartingDate). Note that originally the starting date wasn’t provided to the participants. The “Frequency” variable is used for estimating the MASE evaluation measure (corresponds to the m value of the respective equation).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Point Forecasts” folder includes the point forecasts of all the M4 valid submissions (49), as well as those of the ten benchmarks and two standards of comparison. The “Submission Info” file can be used for matching the submission IDs with the M4 methods.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Prediction Intervals” folder includes the prediction intervals of all the M4 valid submissions (20), as well as those of the one benchmark and two standards of comparison. The “Submission Info” file can be used for matching the submission IDs with the M4 methods.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Benchmarks and Evaluation” file involves the R code used for generating the forecasts of the Statistical benchmarks of the competition. It can be also used for performing the evaluation (sMAPE, MASE and OWA estimation).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “ML_benchmarks” file involves the Python code used for generating the forecasts of the Machine Learning benchmarks of the competition.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “4Theta method” file involves the R code used for generating the forecasts of the 4Theta method. This method, which is a modification of the original Theta method (Assimakopoulos &amp;amp; Nikolopoulos, 2000 – winning method of M3), was submitted by two of the organizers (Spiliotis &amp;amp; Assimakopoulos) and, therefore, wasn’t eligible for a prize.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The “Evaluation and Ranks” file involves the scores and the ranks of the submitted methods, both in terms of Point Forecasts and Prediction Intervals. The results are presented per Frequency, Domain and In Total.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>