<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-11T02:40:03Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>jinworks/CellChat</title>
    <updated>2023-11-11T02:40:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-11:/jinworks/CellChat</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;R toolkit for inference, visualization and analysis of cell-cell communication from single-cell and spatially resolved transcriptomics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/main/CellChat_Logo.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CellChat v2&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CellChat v2 is an updated version that includes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;inference of spatially proximal cell-cell communication between interacting cell groups from spatially resolved transcriptomics&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;expanded database CellChatDB v2 by including more than 1000 protein and non-protein interactions (e.g. metabolic and synaptic signaling) with rich annotations. A function named &lt;code&gt;updateCellChatDB&lt;/code&gt; is also provided for easily updating CellChatDB.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;new functionalities enabling easily interface with other computational tools for single-cell data analysis and cell-cell communication analysis&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;interactive web browser function to allow exploration of CellChat outputs of spatially proximal cell-cell communication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the version history and detailed important changes, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/NEWS.md&#34;&gt;NEWS file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2023.11.05.565674v1&#34;&gt;CellChat v2 paper&lt;/a&gt; for a comprehensive protocol of CellChat v2 that is used for both single-cell and spatially resolved transcriptomic data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Capabilities&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to infer the intercellular communication from any given scRNA-seq data and spatially resolved transcriptomics data, CellChat provides functionality for further data exploration, analysis, and visualization.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It can quantitatively characterize and compare the inferred cell-cell communication networks using an integrated approach by combining social network analysis, pattern recognition, and manifold learning approaches.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It provides an easy-to-use tool for extracting and visualizing high-order information of the inferred networks. For example, it allows ready prediction of major signaling inputs and outputs for all cell populations and how these populations and signals coordinate together for functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It enables comparative analysis of cell-cell communication across different conditions and identification of altered signaling and cell populations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It provides several visualization outputs to facilitate intuitive user-guided data interpretation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CellChat R package can be easily installed from Github using devtools:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&#34;jinworks/CellChat&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please make sure you have installed the correct version of &lt;code&gt;NMF&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;circlize&lt;/code&gt; package&lt;/strong&gt;. See instruction below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installation of other dependencies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;http://renozao.github.io/NMF/devel/PAGE-INSTALLATION.html&#34;&gt;NMF (&amp;gt;= 0.23.0)&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#39;NMF&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;. Please check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChat/issues/16&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for other solutions if you encounter any issue. You might can set &lt;code&gt;Sys.setenv(R_REMOTES_NO_ERRORS_FROM_WARNINGS=TRUE)&lt;/code&gt; if it throws R version error.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jokergoo/circlize&#34;&gt;circlize (&amp;gt;= 0.4.12)&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&#34;jokergoo/circlize&#34;)&lt;/code&gt; if you encounter any issue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jokergoo/ComplexHeatmap&#34;&gt;ComplexHeatmap&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;code&gt;devtools::install_github(&#34;jokergoo/ComplexHeatmap&#34;)&lt;/code&gt; if you encounter any issue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install UMAP python pacakge for dimension reduction: &lt;code&gt;pip install umap-learn&lt;/code&gt;. Please check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lmcinnes/umap&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you encounter any issue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some users might have issues when installing CellChat pacakge due to different operating systems and new R version. Please check the following solutions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation on Mac OX with R &amp;gt; 3.6&lt;/strong&gt;: Please re-install &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.rstudio.com/t/imager-package-does-not-work-in-r-3-6-1/38119&#34;&gt;Xquartz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Installation on Windows, Linux and Centos&lt;/strong&gt;: Please check the solution for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/issues/5&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/issues/131&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please check the tutorial directory of the repo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/CellChat-vignette.html&#34;&gt;Full tutorial for CellChat analysis of a single dataset with detailed explanation of each function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/CellChat_analysis_of_spatial_imaging_data.html&#34;&gt;Brief tutorial for CellChat analysis of a single spatial resolved transcriptomic dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/Comparison_analysis_of_multiple_datasets.html&#34;&gt;Full tutorial for comparison analysis of multiple datasets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/Comparison_analysis_of_multiple_datasets_with_different_cellular_compositions.html&#34;&gt;Comparison analysis of multiple datasets with different cellular compositions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/Interface_with_other_single-cell_analysis_toolkits.html&#34;&gt;Interface with other single-cell analysis toolkits (e.g., Seurat, SingleCellExperiment, Scanpy)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://htmlpreview.github.io/?https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/master/tutorial/Update-CellChatDB.html&#34;&gt;Tutorial for updating ligand-receptor database CellChatDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;700&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/raw/main/overview_CellChat.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Web-based “CellChat Explorer”&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We build a user-friendly web-based “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cellchat.org/&#34;&gt;CellChat Explorer&lt;/a&gt;” that contains two major components:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ligand-Receptor Interaction Explorer&lt;/strong&gt; that allows easy exploration of our novel ligand-receptor interaction database, a comprehensive recapitulation of known molecular compositions including multimeric complexes and co-factors. &lt;em&gt;Our database CellChatDB is a manually curated database of literature-supported ligand-receptor interactions in both &lt;strong&gt;human and mouse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Of note, this Explorer currently only shows the original CellChatDB, but did not include the new interactions in CellChatDB v2.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer&lt;/strong&gt; that allows easy exploration of the cell-cell communication for any given scRNA-seq dataset that has been processed by our R toolkit CellChat.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also developed an Interactive Web Browser that allows exploration of CellChat outputs of spatially proximal cell-cell communication using a built-in function &lt;code&gt;runCellChatApp&lt;/code&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sqjin/CellChatShiny&#34;&gt;standalone CellChat Shiny App&lt;/a&gt; for the above Cell-Cell Communication Atlas Explorer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Help, Suggestion and Contribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any question, comment or suggestion, please use github issue tracker to report coding related &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; of CellChat.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Before reporting an issue&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First &lt;strong&gt;check the GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see if the same or a similar issues has been reported and resolved. This relieves the developers from addressing the same issues and helps them focus on adding new features!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The best way to figure out the issues is &lt;strong&gt;running the sources codes&lt;/strong&gt; of the specific functions by yourself. This will also relieve the developers and helps them focus on the common issues! I am sorry, but I have to say I have no idea on many errors except that I can reproduce the issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minimal and &lt;strong&gt;reproducible example&lt;/strong&gt; are required when filing a GitHub issue. In certain cases, please share your CellChat object and related codes to reproduce the issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users are encouraged to discuss issues and bugs using the github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; instead of email exchanges.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contribution&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CellChat is an open source software package and any contribution is highly appreciated!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use GitHub&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinworks/CellChat/pulls&#34;&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; mechanism for reviewing and accepting submissions of any contribution. Issue a pull request on the GitHub website to request that we merge your branch&#39;s changes into CellChat&#39;s master branch. Be sure to include a description of your changes in the pull request, as well as any other information that will help the CellChat developers involved in reviewing your code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hardware requirements: CellChat package requires only a standard computer with enough RAM to support the in-memory operations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Software requirements: This package is supported for macOS, Windows and Linux. The package has been tested on macOS: Ventura (version 13.5) and Windows 10. Dependencies of CellChat package are indicated in the Description file, and can be automatically installed when installing CellChat pacakge. CellChat can be installed on a normal computer within few mins.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;About CellChat and CellChatDB&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CellChat is an R package designed for inference, analysis, and visualization of cell-cell communication from single-cell and spatially resolved transcriptomics. CellChat aims to enable users to identify and interpret cell-cell communication within an easily interpretable framework, with the emphasis of clear, attractive, and interpretable visualizations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CellChatDB is a manually curated database of literature-supported ligand-receptor interactions in mutiple species, leading to a comprehensive recapitulation of known molecular interaction mechanisms including multi-subunit structure of ligand-receptor complexes and co-factors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use CellChat or CellChatDB in your research, please considering citing our papers:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://biorxiv.org/cgi/content/short/2023.11.05.565674v1&#34;&gt;Suoqin Jin et al., CellChat for systematic analysis of cell-cell communication from single-cell and spatially resolved transcriptomics, bioRxiv 2023&lt;/a&gt; [CellChat v2]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-021-21246-9&#34;&gt;Suoqin Jin et al., Inference and analysis of cell-cell communication using CellChat, Nature Communications 2021&lt;/a&gt; [CellChat v1]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://clustrmaps.com/site/1bpq2&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://clustrmaps.com/map_v2.png?cl=ffffff&amp;amp;w=a&amp;amp;t=n&amp;amp;d=42WqeykSXznN_NSaBlpf6CtSXQxhqmIs6QusUsguFdY&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jinworks/CellChat/main/#&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://api.visitorbadge.io/api/visitors?path=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fjinworks%2FCellChat&amp;amp;labelColor=%233499cc&amp;amp;countColor=%2370c168&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>pharmaverse/falcon</title>
    <updated>2023-11-11T02:40:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-11:/pharmaverse/falcon</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/pharmaverse/falcon" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FDA Safety Tables and Figures&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;falcon&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pharmaverse.github.io/falcon/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pharmaverse/falcon/main/quarto/assets/images/falcon.png&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; height=&#34;139&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 100%;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- start badges --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pharmaverse.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pharmaverse.org/shields/falcon.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Pharmaverse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.repostatus.org/#active&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.repostatus.org/badges/latest/active.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Project Status: Active – The project has reached a stable, usable state and is being actively developed.&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/pharmaverse/falcon/actions/workflows/check.yaml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Check&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pharmaverse/falcon/_xml_coverage_reports/data/main/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Test Coverage&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/pharmaverse/falcon&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/pharmaverse/falcon?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub stars&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/pharmaverse/falcon?style=social&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub forks&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- end badges --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; R package contains table-generating functions to implement standard FDA Safety Tables according to the guidelines published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://downloads.regulations.gov/FDA-2022-N-1961-0046/attachment_1.pdf&#34;&gt;FDA Safety Tables and Figures Integrated Guide&lt;/a&gt;. The falcon project aims to build and open-source a catalog of harmonized templates for generating tables, listings, and graphs (TLGs) in clinical study reporting. Details on package usage and the variety of functions currently available in the package are available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pharmaverse.github.io/falcon/&#34;&gt;the falcon website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can install the latest development version of &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; directly from GitHub and its dependencies from CRAN by running the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;if (!require(&#34;formatters&#34;)) install.packages(&#34;formatters&#34;)&#xA;if (!require(&#34;rtables&#34;)) install.packages(&#34;rtables&#34;)&#xA;if (!require(&#34;rlistings&#34;)) install.packages(&#34;rlistings&#34;)&#xA;if (!require(&#34;tern&#34;)) install.packages(&#34;tern&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;if (!require(&#34;remotes&#34;)) install.packages(&#34;remotes&#34;)&#xA;remotes::install_github(&#34;pharmaverse/falcon&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pharmaverse.github.io/falcon/quarto/getting_started.html&#34;&gt;Getting Started page&lt;/a&gt; on the falcon website for additional details on getting started with the &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the following example, Table 2 (Baseline Demographic and Clinical Characteristics) from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://downloads.regulations.gov/FDA-2022-N-1961-0046/attachment_1.pdf&#34;&gt;FDA Safety Tables and Figures Integrated Guide&lt;/a&gt; is generated using the &lt;code&gt;make_table_02&lt;/code&gt; function from the &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First we will load the &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; package and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/insightsengineering/scda&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;scda&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package to load an example ADSL dataset from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/insightsengineering/scda.2022&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;scda.2022&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; package. The &lt;code&gt;falcon&lt;/code&gt; package works with standard CDISC datasets and variable names while allowing users to set custom variable names &amp;amp; labels where necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;library(falcon)&#xA;adsl &amp;lt;- scda::synthetic_cdisc_dataset(&#34;rcd_2022_10_13&#34;, &#34;adsl&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With data now loaded, the &lt;code&gt;make_table_02&lt;/code&gt; function can be used to generate the FDA standard table.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;make_table_02(&#xA;  df = adsl,&#xA;  vars = c(&#34;SEX&#34;, &#34;AGE&#34;, &#34;RACE&#34;),&#xA;  lbl_vars = c(&#34;Sex&#34;, &#34;Age, years&#34;, &#34;Race&#34;)&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- markdownlint-disable --&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                                                  A: Drug X            B: Placebo         C: Combination      Total Population &#xA;Characteristic                                     (N=134)              (N=134)              (N=132)              (N=400)      &#xA;———————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————————&#xA;Sex                                                                                                                            &#xA;  F                                                79 (59%)            82 (61.2%)            70 (53%)           231 (57.8%)    &#xA;  M                                                55 (41%)            52 (38.8%)            62 (47%)           169 (42.2%)    &#xA;Age, years                                                                                                                     &#xA;  Mean (SD)                                       33.8 (6.6)           35.4 (7.9)           35.4 (7.7)           34.9 (7.4)    &#xA;  Median (Min - Max)                          33.0 (21.0 - 50.0)   35.0 (21.0 - 62.0)   35.0 (20.0 - 69.0)   34.0 (20.0 - 69.0)&#xA;Race                                                                                                                           &#xA;  ASIAN                                           68 (50.7%)            67 (50%)            73 (55.3%)           208 (52%)     &#xA;  BLACK OR AFRICAN AMERICAN                       31 (23.1%)           28 (20.9%)           32 (24.2%)           91 (22.8%)    &#xA;  WHITE                                           27 (20.1%)           26 (19.4%)           21 (15.9%)           74 (18.5%)    &#xA;  AMERICAN INDIAN OR ALASKA NATIVE                  8 (6%)             11 (8.2%)             6 (4.5%)            25 (6.2%)     &#xA;  MULTIPLE                                            0                 1 (0.7%)                0                 1 (0.2%)     &#xA;  NATIVE HAWAIIAN OR OTHER PACIFIC ISLANDER           0                 1 (0.7%)                0                 1 (0.2%)     &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- markdownlint-restore --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information on the &lt;code&gt;make_table_02&lt;/code&gt; function and parameters you can use to customize the output table, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pharmaverse.github.io/falcon/quarto/table-templates/template-table_02.html&#34;&gt;FDA Table 2 page&lt;/a&gt; on the falcon website.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related Packages&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://insightsengineering.github.io/tern/main/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tern&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - analysis functions used to build standard tables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://insightsengineering.github.io/rtables/main/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rtables&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - table engine used for standard tables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://insightsengineering.github.io/rlistings/main/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rlistings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - listing engine used for standard listings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.danieldsjoberg.com/gtsummary/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gtsummary&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - table functions used to build select non-standard tables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/atorus-research/Tplyr&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tplyr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - table functions used to build select non-standard tables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are reachable via the following channels for inquiries and support:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.slack.com/client/T028PB489D3/C04MQS12MND&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; - Use this channel to message the falcon team directly with questions &amp;amp; feedback on the package. If you don&#39;t have access, use this &lt;a href=&#34;https://join.slack.com/t/pharmaverse/shared_invite/zt-yv5atkr4-Np2ytJ6W_QKz_4Olo7Jo9A&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to join the Pharmaverse Slack workspace&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pharmaverse/falcon/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt; - To report a bug, request a new feature or table, or ask a question, open a new issue on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgment&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package is a result of an industry collaboration across several different companies. We would like to thank all of the developers and users who have contributed so far!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Stargazers over time&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starchart.cc/pharmaverse/falcon&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://starchart.cc/pharmaverse/falcon.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;stargazers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>