<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-12-19T01:38:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates</title>
    <updated>2023-12-19T01:38:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-19:/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code and data for Graphic detail on GDP and productivity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;GDP per hour worked&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains the data and code of our analysis of GDP and productivity. The resulting article can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2023/10/04/productivity-has-grown-faster-in-western-europe-than-in-america&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt; To replicate the analysis, please run &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates/main/scripts/01-data-setup.R&#34;&gt;&#39;scripts/01-data-setup.R&#39;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates/main/scripts/02-charts.R&#34;&gt;&#39;scripts/02-charts.R&#39;&lt;/a&gt; in that order.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also contains the data and code behind our ranking of the world&#39;s richest countries, which can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economist.com/graphic-detail/2023/12/15/the-worlds-richest-countries-in-2023&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. To replicate this analysis, please run the two aforementioned scripts, then &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates/main/scripts/03-estimate-gdp-per-hour-for-all-countries.R&#34;&gt;&#39;scripts/03-estimate-gdp-per-hour-for-all-countries.R&#39;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We exclude Ireland from our analysis and data due to issues with its GDP figures explained &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economist.com/the-economist-explains/2023/10/31/whats-weird-about-irelands-gdp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any questions about this work, please email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sondresolstad@economist.com&#34;&gt;sondresolstad@economist.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our latest data can be downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates/raw/main/output-data/gdp_over_hours_worked_with_estimated_hours_worked.csv&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Methodology: Estimating GDP per hour worked&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For OECD countries, we followed guidance from OECD statisticians on how to use their data to calculate total hours worked.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The relevant OECD data was not available for all countries. When missing, we first turned to the Penn World Table. If this source had data available for a country from 2015 or later, we used the most recent value. (We first checked that this was permissible using our OECD data: with the exception of a temporary dip during the early stages of the covid-19 pandemic, values were stable in this interval.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If no such data was available from either source, we estimated it. We here relied on gradient boosted trees as our modelling approach, and used data on countries&#39; demography and economics (including known oil reserves) to train our models. These estimates are uncertain, as we acknowledge, and especially so for poor countries. While our method held up well in cross-validation, our estimates for the very poorest countries, for instance, could be systematically off, and should be approached with care (this would however not greatly affect their rankings).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GDP PPP per hour worked was then calculated by dividing countries&#39; total GDP PPP by their hours worked. GDP adjusted for hours worked (and costs) were calculated by adjusting GDP PPP in a given country by the ratio of their estimated hours worked per person to the average for the world as a whole (i.e. mean of all countries, weighted by population).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those interested can replicate and inspect our calibration plots, other tests, and view all the code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheEconomist/the-economist-gdp-per-hour-estimates/raw/main/output-data/gdp_over_hours_worked_with_estimated_hours_worked.csv&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work shows the latest data available, which at the time of publication, were estimates of 2022 values made in 2023. This means that economic change during 2023 are not captured in the data. Our data also only shows country averages, and does not consider the distribution of income within countries. In some countries high savings rates or other factors may make GDP estimates less reliable as a guide to living standards. Finally, we rely on GDP estimates which are themselves uncertain, and, research suggests, may be especially unreliable for authoritarian countries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data sources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.oecd.org/&#34;&gt;OECD&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://data.worldbank.org/&#34;&gt;World Bank&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://population.un.org/dataportal/&#34;&gt;UN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rug.nl/ggdc/productivity/pwt/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Penn World Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Suggested citation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Economist and Solstad, Sondre (corresponding author), 2023. &#34;All work and no play&#34;, The Economist, October 4th issue, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>