<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-01T01:47:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>zendesk/sdk_messaging_ios</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:47:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/zendesk/sdk_messaging_ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zendesk/sdk_messaging_ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Zendesk Messaging SDK&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Use of this software is subject to important terms and conditions as set forth in the License file&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ZendeskSDKMessaging for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ZendeskSDKMessaging is an SDK that provides customer support through a Messaging interface powered by Zendesk Sunshine Conversations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find our documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables/docs/zendesk-sdk-for-ios/getting_started&#34;&gt;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables/docs/zendesk-sdk-for-ios/getting_started&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;API reference documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zendesk.github.io/sdk_messaging_ios/&#34;&gt;API documentation&lt;/a&gt; for Swift and Objective-C. In addition, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/xcode/distributing-documentation-to-external-developers#Send-a-documentation-archive-directly-to-developers&#34;&gt;DocCArchive&lt;/a&gt; is also attached to every GitHub release. Download the file, open it and Xcode will add it to the Imported Documentation section of the documentation viewer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature requests and issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All feature requests and issues are welcomed. Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zendesk/sdk_messaging_ios/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to find out how to contact us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2020 Zendesk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading or using the Zendesk ZendeskSDKMessaging SDK, You agree to the Zendesk Master Subscription Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and Application Developer and API License Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and acknowledge that such terms govern Your use of and access to the ZendeskSDKHTTPClient SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If You make any Contributions (defined below) to the ZendeskSDKMessaging SDK, You hereby grant Zendesk a royalty-free, worldwide, transferable, sub-licensable, irrevocable and perpetual license to incorporate into the Service or the Zendesk API or otherwise use and commercially exploit any Contributions. “Contribution” shall mean any work of authorship, including any modifications or additions to the Mobile SDK or derivative works thereof, that is submitted to Zendesk by You.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>zendesk/chat_sdk_ios</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:47:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/zendesk/chat_sdk_ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zendesk/chat_sdk_ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zendesk Chat SDK&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Use of this software is subject to important terms and conditions as set forth in the License file&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Zendesk Chat SDK for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zendesk Chat SDK is a quick, convenient way to get live chat into your mobile apps. With just a few lines of code, you can provide your end users with an easy way to get in touch from any mobile app.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find our documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&#34;&gt;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature requests and issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All feature requests and issues are welcomed. Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zendesk/chat_sdk_ios/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to find out how to contact us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2020 Zendesk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading or using the Zendesk Chat SDK, You agree to the Zendesk Master Subscription Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and Application Developer and API License Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and acknowledge that such terms govern Your use of and access to the Chat SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If You make any Contributions (defined below) to the Zendesk Chat SDK, You hereby grant Zendesk a royalty-free, worldwide, transferable, sub-licensable, irrevocable and perpetual license to incorporate into the Service or the Zendesk API or otherwise use and commercially exploit any Contributions. “Contribution” shall mean any work of authorship, including any modifications or additions to the Mobile SDK or derivative works thereof, that is submitted to Zendesk by You.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PerimeterX/px-iOS-Framework</title>
    <updated>2024-06-01T01:47:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-01:/PerimeterX/px-iOS-Framework</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PerimeterX/px-iOS-Framework" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HUMAN iOS framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;About &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humansecurity.com/&#34;&gt;HUMAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HUMAN is a cybersecurity company that protects organizations by disrupting digital fraud and abuse. We leverage modern defense to disrupt the economics of cybercrime by increasing the cost to cybercriminals while simultaneously reducing the cost of collective defense. Today we verify the humanity of more than 20 trillion digital interactions per week across advertising, marketing, e-commerce, government, education and enterprise security, putting us in a position to win against cybercriminals. HUMAN was named one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://time.com/collection/time100-companies-2023/6285152/human-security/&#34;&gt;TIME100 Most Influential Companies of 2023&lt;/a&gt;. Protect your digital business with HUMAN. To Know Who’s Real, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PerimeterX/px-iOS-Framework/master/www.humansecurity.com&#34;&gt;www.humansecurity.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Integration with the SDK&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SDK works by constantly profiling and evaluating device behavior to ensure that the connections to your mobile APIs and services are genuine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This process is complex and detailed yet only requires initialization to manage a set of secure HTTP headers which are added to all HTTP and HTTPS requests made by the mobile application to the origin server. These HTTP headers are refreshed on a regular basis by the SDK as it is profiling the end-user’s mobile device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The full documentation can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.perimeterx.com/pxconsole/docs/sdk-ios&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>