<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub XSLT Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-01T02:26:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of XSLT in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kinkofer/FightClub5eXML</title>
    <updated>2023-02-01T02:26:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-01:/kinkofer/FightClub5eXML</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kinkofer/FightClub5eXML" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Creating XML files of all D&amp;D sources compatible with Fight Club 5e and Game Master 5e apps for iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Fight Club 5e XML&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creating XML files of all official D&amp;amp;D sources compatible with Fight Club 5e and Game Master 5e apps for iOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How-to Use This Repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The files listed in this repository as-is are not compatible with Fight Club 5e. They are instead a collection of individual source files that must be compiled together into a &#34;compendium&#34;. That resulting compendium can then be imported into and used by Fight Club 5e.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document makes a distinction between a &lt;strong&gt;compendium&lt;/strong&gt; file and a &lt;strong&gt;collection&lt;/strong&gt; file. A compendium file is what you ultimately import into Fight Club 5e; it is an XML file that contains all of the source data and is in a format that Fight Club 5e can process. A collection file is the raw source data that exists within this repository, and is not in a format that can be imported into Fight Club 5e. You must first compile a collection file into a compendium file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains several collection files which can be found within the &lt;code&gt;Collections&lt;/code&gt; folder. It&#39;s worth opening some of those files and noting the data found within them along with their basic structure. Each of those collection files contain entries that point to raw source data file found within the &lt;code&gt;Sources&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Download and Extract the Repository to Your Computer&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click on the green &#34;Code&#34; button towards the top of the page, and then click on the &#34;Download ZIP&#34; button on the subsequent modal popup. Extract the ZIP archive to your &lt;code&gt;Documents&lt;/code&gt; folder. On Windows, this will be &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\YOUR_USER_NAME\Documents&lt;/code&gt;; on macOS, this will be &lt;code&gt;/Users/YOUR_USER_NAME/Documents&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The location on your computer that you extract this repository to will be referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;repository root&lt;/strong&gt; folder. The path to the repository root should be something like &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\YOUR_USER_NAME\Documents\FightClub5eXML-main&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;/Users/YOUR_USER_NAME/Documents/FightClub5eXML-main&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need to install the &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt; program in order to compile a collection into a compendium.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Windows&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;chocolatey&lt;/code&gt; by following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org/install&#34;&gt;official instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open up PowerShell with administrative privileges, and execute the following: &lt;code&gt;choco install xsltproc&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;macOS&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;homebrew&lt;/code&gt; by following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;official instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open up Terminal and install &lt;code&gt;libxslt&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;brew install libxslt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Linux&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should be able to use your distro&#39;s official package manager to install either &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;libxslt&lt;/code&gt; if &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt; isn&#39;t available as a standalone package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Compile a Collection Into a Compendium&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open a command-line terminal (such as PowerShell on Windows or Terminal on macOS) and navigate to the repository root. You can do so by executing &lt;code&gt;cd C:\Users\YOUR_USER_NAME\Documents\FightClub5eXML-main&lt;/code&gt; on Windows, or &lt;code&gt;cd /Users/YOUR_USER_NAME/Documents/FightClub5eXML-main&lt;/code&gt; on macOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, execute the &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt; program to compile a collection file into a compendium file. For example, if you wanted to compile the &lt;code&gt;CoreOnly.xml&lt;/code&gt; collection, you would execute the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;xsltproc -o Compendiums/CoreOnly.xml Utilities/merge.xslt Collections/CoreOnly.xml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After that command has completed, you should see a file called &lt;code&gt;Compendium.xml&lt;/code&gt; in the newly created &lt;code&gt;Compendiums&lt;/code&gt; folder. You can then download that file onto your smartphone and import it into Fight Club 5e.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Batching&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The build-collection files are provided for your convenience to compile all collections within your Collections directory into compendiums.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Custom Content&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kinkofer/FightClub5eXML/main/Sources/README.md&#34;&gt;Sources README&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add your own homebrew content or build your own compendium from select source material.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to contribute, feel free to fork the repository and submit pull requests with your changes. We are no longer accepting manual changes to the XML source files because these files are now generated from an external source.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@kinkofer&lt;/code&gt; for XML generation systems to allow github collections to be auto generated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@felix_mil_&lt;/code&gt; for XML creation tools &lt;a href=&#34;https://felixmil.shinyapps.io/compendiumbuildr/&#34;&gt;https://felixmil.shinyapps.io/compendiumbuildr/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@rrgeorge&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;zamrod&lt;/code&gt; for their JSON to XML scripts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@MrFarland&lt;/code&gt; for Artificer Infusions and other XML.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@fightclub5exml&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;@dragonahcas&lt;/code&gt; for carrying the mantle.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@zcdziura&lt;/code&gt; for answering user&#39;s questions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;@sheppe&lt;/code&gt; for the Widows bat file.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Canadensys/E2DCX</title>
    <updated>2023-02-01T02:26:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-01:/Canadensys/E2DCX</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Canadensys/E2DCX" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Create a DataCite XML file from an EML file E2DCX&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;E2DCX&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creates a DataCite XML file from an EML file for DataCite Metadata Store. The resulting XML will respect the &lt;a href=&#34;http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd&#34;&gt;DataCite Metadata Schema 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;What you need&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An assigned DOI prefix, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://mds.datacite.org/&#34;&gt;DataCite Metadata Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A XSLT 2.0 processor, &lt;a href=&#34;http://saxon.sourceforge.net/#F9.4HE&#34;&gt;Saxon&lt;/a&gt; is recommended&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How it works&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the moment, all the data that can&#39;t be found in the EML are taken from a file called config.xml. You need to update this file with your own information in order to generate the right XML file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;java -cp saxon9he.jar net.sf.saxon.Transform -t -s:YOUR_INPUT_FILE.eml -xsl:dataCite.xsl -o:YOUR_OUTPUT_FILE.xml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>