<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub XSLT Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-12-01T02:31:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of XSLT in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>uri-templates/uritemplate-test</title>
    <updated>2023-12-01T02:31:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-12-01:/uri-templates/uritemplate-test</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/uri-templates/uritemplate-test" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tests for URI Template implementations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;URI Template Tests&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a set of tests for implementations of &lt;a href=&#34;https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc6570&#34;&gt;RFC6570&lt;/a&gt; - URI Template. It is designed to be reused by any implementation, to improve interoperability and implementation quality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your project uses Git for version control, you can make uritemplate-tests into a &lt;a href=&#34;http://help.github.com/submodules/&#34;&gt;submodule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Test Format&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each test file is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.ietf.org/html/RFC6627&#34;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt; document containing an object whose properties are groups of related tests. Alternatively, all tests are available in XML as well, with the XML files being generated by transform-json-tests.xslt which uses json2xml.xslt as a general-purpose JSON-to-XML parsing library.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each group, in turn, is an object with three children:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;level - the level of the tests covered, as per the RFC (optional; if absent, assume level 4).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;variables - an object representing the variables that are available to the tests in the suite&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;testcases - a list of testcases, where each case is a two-member list, the first being the template, the second being the result of expanding the template with the provided variables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the result string can be a few different things:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;string - if the second member is a string, the result of expansion is expected to match it, character-for-character.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;list - if the second member is a list of strings, the result of expansion is expected to match one of them; this allows for templates that can expand into different, equally-acceptable URIs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;false - if the second member is boolean false, expansion is expected to fail (i.e., the template was invalid).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&#xA;  &#34;Level 1 Examples&#34; : &#xA;  {&#xA;    &#34;level&#34;: 1,&#xA;    &#34;variables&#34;: {&#xA;       &#34;var&#34;   : &#34;value&#34;,&#xA;       &#34;hello&#34; : &#34;Hello World!&#34;&#xA;     },&#xA;     &#34;testcases&#34; : [&#xA;        [&#34;{var}&#34;, &#34;value&#34;],&#xA;        [&#34;{hello}&#34;, &#34;Hello%20World%21&#34;]&#xA;     ]&#xA;  }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tests Included&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following test files are included:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;spec-examples.json - The complete set of example templates from the RFC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;spec-examples-by-section.json - The examples, section by section&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;extended-tests.json - more complex test cases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;negative-tests.json - invalid templates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For all these test files, XML versions with the names *.xml can be generated with the transform-json-tests.xslt XSLT stylesheet. The XSLT contains the names of the above test files as a parameter, and can be started with any XML as input (i.e., the XML input is ignored).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2011-2012 The Authors&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;); you may not use this file except in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific language governing permissions and limitations under the License.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>