<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub HTML Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-12T01:40:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of HTML in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repo for my &#39;Learning JavaScript Design Patterns&#39; book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gruntjs.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.gruntjs.com/builtwith.png&#34; alt=&#34;Built with Grunt&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns.png&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Learning JavaScript Design Patterns&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.github.com/addyosmani/essential-js-design-patterns/master/cover/cover.jpg&#34; width=&#34;350px&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the source code for Learning JavaScript Design Patterns. It is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial-Share Alike 3.0 license. I hope you enjoy it, I hope it helps you learn, and I hope you&#39;ll support O&#39;Reilly and me by purchasing a print copy of the book at &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920025832.do&#34;&gt;O&#39;Reilly.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Design patterns are reusable solutions to commonly occurring problems in software development and are a very useful tool to have at your disposal. You can read the latest version &lt;a href=&#34;http://addyosmani.com/resources/essentialjsdesignpatterns/book/&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; for free at any time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Why is this book needed?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this book as I felt that patterns were an area a lot of new and intermediate JavaScript developers may not have had a chance to explore just yet and I&#39;m hopeful my book will encourage you to check them out as they can be quite powerful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing and Errata&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m always welcome to feedback on how the book can be improved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Pull requests&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to help improve the project, please feel free to send over a pull request. Some useful notes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All changes should be made against the master branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The source of the book is currently in &lt;code&gt;book/index.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Atomic commits make it easier to review changes. If you can separate changes out in this form, it&#39;ll save us time when trying to land.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Please review the version of the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://addyosmani.com/resources/essentialjsdesignpatterns/book/&#34;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; before requesting a change. It is updated more frequently than the physical version of the book but we do bring changes back in every few months.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Building the project&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install dependencies : &lt;code&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; Build the project: &lt;code&gt;grunt&lt;/code&gt; Preview: &lt;code&gt;grunt serve&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Additional formats&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project is currently authored in HTML, however we do plan on introducing builds for other formats (PDF, ePub) shortly. In the mean time, official releases for other formats can be obtained via O&#39;Reilly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Translations&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to get involved with translating this project to another language, please open up a new issue. O&#39;Reilly have a process for handling translations to ensure that they go through the same review process that the English version goes through.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far, we&#39;ve successfully had the book translated to Japanese. You can find that version on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreilly.co.jp/books/9784873116181/&#34;&gt;O&#39;Reilly Japan&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is released under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial- No Derivative Works 3.0 United States License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;What this means it that the project is free to read and use, but the license does not permit commercial use of the material (i.e you can freely print out the book for your own use, but you can&#39;t sell it). I&#39;m trying to best to publish all of my books in a free + purchased (if you would like to support these projects) form so I would greatly appreciate it if you would respect these terms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright Addy Osmani, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>yoheinakajima/prettygraph</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/yoheinakajima/prettygraph</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yoheinakajima/prettygraph" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An experimental UI for text-to-knowledge-graph generation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;prettygraph&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;prettygraph&lt;/strong&gt; is a Python-based web application developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yoheinakajima&#34;&gt;@yoheinakajima&lt;/a&gt; to demonstrate a new UI pattern for text-to-knowledge graph generation. This project is a quick hack and not intended to be a robust framework, but a simple UI idea for dynamically highlighting the text input when generating knowledge graphs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/prettygraph/raw/main/prettygraph.jpeg?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;prettygraph image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The application uses Flask for the backend, rendering templates for the front end, and LiteLLM for generating predictions which transform text inputs into JSON formatted graph data. This data is then visualized using Cytoscape.js. It&#39;s important to note that the graph regenerates on every period insertion with real-time updates in the UI, providing an interactive experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text-to-Graph Generation:&lt;/strong&gt; Converts user input text into a knowledge graph.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic UI Updates:&lt;/strong&gt; Graph updates with each text input that ends with a period.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Color-Coded Visualization:&lt;/strong&gt; Nodes and edges in the graph are color-coded for better visual distinction.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project uses Poetry for dependency management. To set up the project:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clone the repository:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/yoheinakajima/prettygraph&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Navigate to the project directory:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cd prettygraph&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install dependencies using Poetry:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;poetry install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Run the Flask application:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;poetry run python main.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Configuring Environment Variables&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run this application, you need to set up the &lt;code&gt;OPENAI_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt; environment variable. Create a file named &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory of your project and add the following line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-text&#34;&gt;OPENAI_API_KEY=your_openai_api_key_here&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the application is running and the environment variables are set, open your web browser and navigate to &lt;code&gt;http://localhost/&lt;/code&gt;. Input text into the editable text box, and watch as the knowledge graph updates with each sentence termination (period).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future Improvements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; Enhance the logic for tracking nodes and edges through their flow in the text, moving away from simple keyword matching to a more sophisticated relationship mapping.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual Graph Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduce a manual update button to generate the graph as needed, reducing computational load and API costs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loading Animation:&lt;/strong&gt; Add a loading animation during graph generation to improve user experience by indicating processing is underway.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incremental Graph Building:&lt;/strong&gt; Instead of regenerating the entire graph with each input, modify the existing graph by adding new elements and deduplicating nodes similarly to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/mindgraph&#34;&gt;mindgraph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While &lt;strong&gt;prettygraph&lt;/strong&gt; is not intended to be maintained as a robust framework, contributions are welcome. Feel free to fork the repository and submit pull requests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is open-sourced under the MIT License. See the LICENSE file for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those interested in exploring more about knowledge graphs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/instagraph&#34;&gt;InstaGraph&lt;/a&gt; - Web-based tool for generating knowledge graphs. Or for a web UI, try out &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagraph.ai&#34;&gt;instagraph.ai&lt;/a&gt; - has knowledge graph generation but not the color coded highlights.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yoheinakajima/mindgraph&#34;&gt;mindgraph&lt;/a&gt; - For generating large knowledge graphs with deduping of nodes using an LLM as new graphs are added.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an experimental project and may not handle all edge cases or inputs effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>KingsGambitLab/Lecture_Notes</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:40:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/KingsGambitLab/Lecture_Notes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/KingsGambitLab/Lecture_Notes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository is there to store the combined lecture notes of all the lectures. We are using markdown to write the lecture notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Lecture_Notes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is there to store the combined lecture notes of all the lectures. We are using markdown to write the lecture notes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To render math in the notes, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mathjax-plugin-for-github/ioemnmodlmafdkllaclgeombjnmnbima&#34;&gt;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/mathjax-plugin-for-github/ioemnmodlmafdkllaclgeombjnmnbima&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keep code snippets in Python/Psuedocode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For language specific concepts, make sure to contrast it with other languages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use LaTeX math mode when possible. Quick References: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://math.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/5020/mathjax-basic-tutorial-and-quick-reference&#34;&gt;https://math.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/5020/mathjax-basic-tutorial-and-quick-reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jojozhuang.github.io/blog/2018/09/11/mathjax-cheat-sheet-for-mathematical-notation/&#34;&gt;https://jojozhuang.github.io/blog/2018/09/11/mathjax-cheat-sheet-for-mathematical-notation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Soft resize images to appropriate size (use html img tag with inline style)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use spaces instead of tabs (important, to keep indentation in code blocks consistent)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clearly mark the begin and end of each topic / question by using HR. markdown syntax: &lt;code&gt;-- --&lt;/code&gt; on a new line&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;em&gt;Italics&lt;/em&gt; minimally (hard to detect). Use &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; and headings instead.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t use H1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the following syntax for H2 instead of the usual &lt;code&gt;# heading 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-md&#34;&gt;Heading 2&#xA;---------&#xA;&#xA;content&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>