<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub JavaScript Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-26T01:52:46Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of JavaScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SillyTavern/SillyTavern</title>
    <updated>2023-11-26T01:52:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-26:/SillyTavern/SillyTavern</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LLM Frontend for Power Users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;English | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern/release/readme-zh_cn.md&#34;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern/assets/18619528/c2be4c3f-aada-4f64-87a3-ae35a68b61a4&#34; alt=&#34;SillyTavern-Banner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mobile-friendly layout, Multi-API (KoboldAI/CPP, Horde, NovelAI, Ooba, OpenAI, OpenRouter, Claude, Scale), VN-like Waifu Mode, Stable Diffusion, TTS, WorldInfo (lorebooks), customizable UI, auto-translate, and more prompt options than you&#39;d ever want or need + ability to install third-party extensions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on a fork of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TavernAI/TavernAI&#34;&gt;TavernAI&lt;/a&gt; 1.2.8&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Important news!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have created a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sillytavern.app/&#34;&gt;Documentation website&lt;/a&gt; to answer most of your questions and help you get started.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Missing extensions after the update? Since the 1.10.6 release version, most of the previously built-in extensions have been converted to downloadable add-ons. You can download them via the built-in &#34;Download Extensions and Assets&#34; menu in the extensions panel (stacked blocks icon in the top bar).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Brought to you by Cohee, RossAscends, and the SillyTavern community&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is SillyTavern or TavernAI?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SillyTavern is a user interface you can install on your computer (and Android phones) that allows you to interact with text generation AIs and chat/roleplay with characters you or the community create.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SillyTavern is a fork of TavernAI 1.2.8 which is under more active development and has added many major features. At this point, they can be thought of as completely independent programs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Branches&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SillyTavern is being developed using a two-branch system to ensure a smooth experience for all users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;release -🌟 &lt;strong&gt;Recommended for most users.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most stable and recommended branch, updated only when major releases are pushed. It&#39;s suitable for the majority of users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;staging - ⚠️ &lt;strong&gt;Not recommended for casual use.&lt;/strong&gt; This branch has the latest features, but be cautious as it may break at any time. Only for power users and enthusiasts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not familiar with using the git CLI or don&#39;t understand what a branch is, don&#39;t worry! The release branch is always the preferable option for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What do I need other than Tavern?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On its own Tavern is useless, as it&#39;s just a user interface. You have to have access to an AI system backend that can act as the roleplay character. There are various supported backends: OpenAPI API (GPT), KoboldAI (either running locally or on Google Colab), and more. You can read more about this in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sillytavern.app/usage/faq/&#34;&gt;the FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Do I need a powerful PC to run Tavern?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since Tavern is only a user interface, it has tiny hardware requirements, it will run on anything. It&#39;s the AI system backend that needs to be powerful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Mobile support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This fork can be run natively on Android phones using Termux. Please refer to this guide by ArroganceComplex#2659:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rentry.org/STAI-Termux&#34;&gt;https://rentry.org/STAI-Termux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions or suggestions?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;We now have a community Discord server&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get support, share favorite characters and prompts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RZdyAEUPvj&#34;&gt;Join&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get in touch with the developers directly:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Discord: cohee or rossascends&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reddit: /u/RossAscends or /u/sillylossy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern/issues&#34;&gt;Post a GitHub issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;This version includes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A heavily modified TavernAI 1.2.8 (more than 50% of code rewritten or optimized)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swipes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Group chats: multi-bot rooms for characters to talk to you or each other&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chat bookmarks / branching (duplicates the dialogue in its current state)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Advanced KoboldAI / TextGen generation settings with a lot of community-made presets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;World Info support: create rich lore or save tokens on your character card&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openrouter.ai&#34;&gt;OpenRouter&lt;/a&gt; connection for various APIs (Claude, GPT-4/3.5 and more)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oobabooga/text-generation-webui&#34;&gt;Oobabooga&#39;s TextGen WebUI&lt;/a&gt; API connection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://horde.koboldai.net/&#34;&gt;AI Horde&lt;/a&gt; connection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prompt generation formatting tweaking&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Extensions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SillyTavern has extensibility support, with some additional AI modules hosted via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern-extras&#34;&gt;SillyTavern Extras API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Author&#39;s Note / Character Bias&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Character emotional expressions (sprites)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto-Summary of the chat history&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sending images to chat, and the AI interpreting the content&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stable Diffusion image generation (5 chat-related presets plus &#39;free mode&#39;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Text-to-speech for AI response messages (via ElevenLabs, Silero, or the OS&#39;s System TTS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A full list of included extensions and tutorials on how to use them can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sillytavern.app/extras/extensions/&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;UI/CSS/Quality of Life tweaks by RossAscends&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mobile UI optimized for iOS, and supports saving a shortcut to the home screen and opening in fullscreen mode.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;HotKeys&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Up = Edit last message in chat&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Ctrl+Up = Edit last USER message in chat&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Left = swipe left&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Right = swipe right (NOTE: swipe hotkeys are disabled when the chat bar has something typed into it)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Ctrl+Left = view locally stored variables (in the browser console window)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enter (with chat bar selected) = send your message to AI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Ctrl+Enter = Regenerate the last AI response&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;User Name Changes and Character Deletion no longer force the page to refresh.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Toggle option to automatically connect to API on page load.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Toggle option to automatically load the most recently viewed character on page load.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Better Token Counter - works on unsaved characters, and shows both permanent and temporary tokens.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Better Past Chats View&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New Chat filenames are saved in a readable format of &#34;(character) - (when it was created)&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Chat preview increased from 40 characters to 300.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Multiple options for characters list sorting (by name, creation date, chat sizes).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;By default the left and right settings panel will close when you click away from it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clicking the Lock on the nav panel will hold the panel open, and this setting be remembered across sessions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nav panel status of open or closed will also be saved across sessions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Customizable chat UI:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Play a sound when a new message arrives&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Switch between round or rectangle avatar styles&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Have a wider chat window on the desktop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optional semi-transparent glass-like panels&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Customizable page colors for &#39;main text&#39;, &#39;quoted text&#39;, and &#39;italics text&#39;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Customizable UI background color and blur amount&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: This software is intended for local install purposes, and has not been thoroughly tested on a colab or other cloud notebook service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;DO NOT INSTALL INTO ANY WINDOWS CONTROLLED FOLDER (Program Files, System32, etc).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;DO NOT RUN START.BAT WITH ADMIN PERMISSIONS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing via Git (recommended for easy updating)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An easy-to-follow guide with pretty pictures: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.sillytavern.app/installation/windows/&#34;&gt;https://docs.sillytavern.app/installation/windows/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en&#34;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt; (latest LTS version is recommended)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://central.github.com/deployments/desktop/desktop/latest/win32&#34;&gt;GitHub Desktop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open Windows Explorer (&lt;code&gt;Win+E&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Browse to or Create a folder that is not controlled or monitored by Windows. (ex: C:\MySpecialFolder)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a Command Prompt inside that folder by clicking in the &#39;Address Bar&#39; at the top, typing &lt;code&gt;cmd&lt;/code&gt;, and pressing Enter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once the black box (Command Prompt) pops up, type ONE of the following into it and press Enter:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;for Release Branch: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern -b release&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;for Staging Branch: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern -b staging&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Once everything is cloned, double-click &lt;code&gt;Start.bat&lt;/code&gt; to make NodeJS install its requirements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The server will then start, and SillyTavern will pop up in your browser.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing via ZIP download (discouraged)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en&#34;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt; (latest LTS version is recommended)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the zip from this GitHub repo. (Get the &lt;code&gt;Source code (zip)&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SillyTavern/SillyTavern/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Unzip it into a folder of your choice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;Start.bat&lt;/code&gt; by double-clicking or in a command line.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once the server has prepared everything for you, it will open a tab in your browser.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Linux&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure you have Node.js v18 or higher (the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/download/&#34;&gt;LTS version&lt;/a&gt; is recommended) installed by running &lt;code&gt;node -v&lt;/code&gt;. Alternatively, use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nvm-sh/nvm#installing-and-updating&#34;&gt;Node Version Manager&lt;/a&gt; script to quickly and easily manage your Node installations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the &lt;code&gt;start.sh&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;API keys management&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SillyTavern saves your API keys to a &lt;code&gt;secrets.json&lt;/code&gt; file in the server directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, they will not be exposed to a frontend after you enter them and reload the page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to enable viewing your keys by clicking a button in the API block:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Set the value of &lt;code&gt;allowKeysExposure&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;config.conf&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Restart the SillyTavern server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Remote connections&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most often this is for people who want to use SillyTavern on their mobile phones while their PC runs the ST server on the same wifi network.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, it can be used to allow remote connections from anywhere as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: SillyTavern is a single-user program, so anyone who logs in will be able to see all characters and chats, and be able to change any settings inside the UI.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. Managing whitelisted IPs&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new text file inside your SillyTavern base install folder called &lt;code&gt;whitelist.txt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the file in a text editor, and add a list of IPs you want to be allowed to connect.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both individual IPs and wildcard IP ranges are accepted. Examples:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-txt&#34;&gt;192.168.0.1&#xA;192.168.0.20&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-txt&#34;&gt;192.168.0.*&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(the above wildcard IP range will allow any device on the local network to connect)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;CIDR masks are also accepted (eg. 10.0.0.0/24).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save the &lt;code&gt;whitelist.txt&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Restart your TAI server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now devices which have the IP specified in the file will be able to connect.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: &lt;code&gt;config.conf&lt;/code&gt; also has a &lt;code&gt;whitelist&lt;/code&gt; array, which you can use in the same way, but this array will be ignored if &lt;code&gt;whitelist.txt&lt;/code&gt; exists.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;2. Getting the IP for the ST host machine&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the whitelist has been setup, you&#39;ll need the IP of the ST-hosting device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the ST-hosting device is on the same wifi network, you will use the ST-host&#39;s internal wifi IP:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For Windows: windows button &amp;gt; type &lt;code&gt;cmd.exe&lt;/code&gt; in the search bar &amp;gt; type &lt;code&gt;ipconfig&lt;/code&gt; in the console, hit Enter &amp;gt; look for &lt;code&gt;IPv4&lt;/code&gt; listing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you (or someone else) want to connect to your hosted ST while not being on the same network, you will need the public IP of your ST-hosting device.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;While using the ST-hosting device, access &lt;a href=&#34;https://whatismyipaddress.com/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; and look for &lt;code&gt;IPv4&lt;/code&gt;. This is what you would use to connect from the remote device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;3. Connect the remote device to the ST host machine&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whatever IP you ended up with for your situation, you will put that IP address and port number into the remote device&#39;s web browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A typical address for an ST host on the same wifi network would look like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://192.168.0.5:8000&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use http:// NOT https://&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Opening your ST to all IPs&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We do not recommend doing this, but you can open &lt;code&gt;config.conf&lt;/code&gt; and change &lt;code&gt;whitelist&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You must remove (or rename) &lt;code&gt;whitelist.txt&lt;/code&gt; in the SillyTavern base install folder if it exists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is usually an insecure practice, so we require you to set a username and password when you do this.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The username and password are set in &lt;code&gt;config.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After restarting your ST server, any device will be able to connect to it, regardless of their IP as long as they know the username and password.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Still Unable To Connect?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create an inbound/outbound firewall rule for the port found in &lt;code&gt;config.conf&lt;/code&gt;. Do NOT mistake this for port-forwarding on your router, otherwise, someone could find your chat logs and that&#39;s a big no-no.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable the Private Network profile type in Settings &amp;gt; Network and Internet &amp;gt; Ethernet. This is VERY important for Windows 11, otherwise, you would be unable to connect even with the aforementioned firewall rules.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Performance issues?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try enabling the No Blur Effect (Fast UI) mode on the User settings panel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;I like your project! How do I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;DO&#39;s&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send pull requests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send feature suggestions and issue reports using established templates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read the readme file and built-in documentation before asking anything&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;DONT&#39;s&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Offer monetary donations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send bug reports without providing any context&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask the questions that were already answered numerous times&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Where can I find the old backgrounds?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re moving to a 100% original content only policy, so old background images have been removed from this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find them archived here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://files.catbox.moe/1xevnc.zip&#34;&gt;https://files.catbox.moe/1xevnc.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/18619528/228649245-8061c60f-63dc-488e-9325-f151b7a3ec2d.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/18619528/228649856-fbdeef05-d727-4d5a-be80-266cbbc6b811.png&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License and credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Affero General Public License for more details.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TAI Base by Humi: Unknown license&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cohee&#39;s modifications and derived code: AGPL v3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RossAscends&#39; additions: AGPL v3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Portions of CncAnon&#39;s TavernAITurbo mod: Unknown license&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kingbri&#39;s various commits and suggestions (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bdashore3&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bdashore3&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;city_unit&#39;s extensions and various QoL features (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/city-unit&#34;&gt;https://github.com/city-unit&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;StefanDanielSchwarz&#39;s various commits and bug reports (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StefanDanielSchwarz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/StefanDanielSchwarz&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Waifu mode inspired by the work of PepperTaco (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/peppertaco/Tavern/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/peppertaco/Tavern/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thanks Pygmalion University for being awesome testers and suggesting cool features!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thanks oobabooga for compiling presets for TextGen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;KoboldAI Presets from KAI Lite: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lite.koboldai.net/&#34;&gt;https://lite.koboldai.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Noto Sans font by Google (OFL license)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Icon theme by Font Awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://fontawesome.com&#34;&gt;https://fontawesome.com&lt;/a&gt; (Icons: CC BY 4.0, Fonts: SIL OFL 1.1, Code: MIT License)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AI Horde client library by ZeldaFan0225: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ZeldaFan0225/ai_horde&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ZeldaFan0225/ai_horde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linux startup script by AlpinDale&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thanks paniphons for providing a FAQ document&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;10K Discord Users Celebratory Background by @kallmeflocc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Default content (characters and lore books) provided by @OtisAlejandro, @RossAscends and @kallmeflocc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Korean translation by @doloroushyeonse&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;k_euler_a support for Horde by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Teashrock&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Teashrock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chinese translation by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/XXpE3&#34;&gt;@XXpE3&lt;/a&gt;, 中文 ISSUES 可以联系 @XXpE3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>hakimel/reveal.js</title>
    <updated>2023-11-26T01:52:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-26:/hakimel/reveal.js</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The HTML Presentation Framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://hakim-static.s3.amazonaws.com/reveal-js/logo/v1/reveal-black-text-sticker.png&#34; alt=&#34;reveal.js&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js/actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js/workflows/tests/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://slides.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/static.slid.es/images/slides-github-banner-320x40.png?1&#34; alt=&#34;Slides&#34; width=&#34;160&#34; height=&#34;20&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;reveal.js is an open source HTML presentation framework. It enables anyone with a web browser to create beautiful presentations for free. Check out the live demo at &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/&#34;&gt;revealjs.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The framework comes with a powerful feature set including &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/vertical-slides/&#34;&gt;nested slides&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown support&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/auto-animate/&#34;&gt;Auto-Animate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34;&gt;PDF export&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/speaker-view/&#34;&gt;speaker notes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/math/&#34;&gt;LaTeX typesetting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/code/&#34;&gt;syntax highlighted code&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/api/&#34;&gt;extensive API&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Want to create reveal.js presentation in a graphical editor? Try &lt;a href=&#34;https://slides.com&#34;&gt;https://slides.com&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s made by the same people behind reveal.js.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sponsors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hakim&#39;s open source work is supported by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/hakimel&#34;&gt;GitHub sponsors&lt;/a&gt;. Special thanks to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;table&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;   &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://workos.com/?utm_campaign=github_repo&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=revealjs&amp;amp;utm_source=github&#34;&gt; &#xA;      &lt;div&gt; &#xA;       &lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/629429/151508669-efb4c3b3-8fe3-45eb-8e47-e9510b5f0af1.svg?sanitize=true&#34; width=&#34;290&#34; alt=&#34;WorkOS&#34;&gt; &#xA;      &lt;/div&gt; &lt;b&gt;Your app, enterprise-ready.&lt;/b&gt; &#xA;      &lt;div&gt; &#xA;       &lt;sub&gt;Start selling to enterprise customers with just a few lines of code. Add Single Sign-On (and more) in minutes instead of months. &lt;/sub&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA; &lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🚀 &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/installation&#34;&gt;Install reveal.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;👀 &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/demo&#34;&gt;View the demo presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;📖 &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/markup/&#34;&gt;Read the documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🖌 &lt;a href=&#34;https://slides.com/&#34;&gt;Try the visual editor for reveal.js at Slides.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🎬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/course&#34;&gt;Watch the reveal.js video course (paid)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&#xA;  MIT licensed | Copyright © 2011-2023 Hakim El Hattab, https://hakim.se &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>adrianhajdin/3D_portfolio</title>
    <updated>2023-11-26T01:52:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-26:/adrianhajdin/3D_portfolio</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/adrianhajdin/3D_portfolio" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s build a cool 3D website together! You&#39;ll learn how to make a portfolio with fun interactive parts, like a floating island and a fox that moves when you type. It&#39;ll allow you to show off your skills and get a job!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Build and Deploy an Amazing 3D Developer Portfolio in React with Three.js&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/ryytGVx/Screenshot-2023-11-25-at-11-28-11-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;3D Website&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jsmastery.pro/next14&#34;&gt;🌟 Become a top 1% Next.js 14 developer in only one course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jsmastery.pro/masterclass&#34;&gt;🚀 Land your dream programming job in 6 months&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resource.jsmastery.pro/threejs-cheatsheet&#34;&gt;📙 Free Three.js Cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hostinger.com/javascript10&#34;&gt;🌐 Best Hosting for Your Websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>