<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-08T01:40:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>davidbrewer/tmux-conf</title>
    <updated>2022-09-08T01:40:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-08:/davidbrewer/tmux-conf</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/davidbrewer/tmux-conf" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My tmux configuration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;tmux-conf&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;My tmux configuration. Built upon the excellent foundation provided by Brian P. Hogan&#39;s excellent book &#34;tmux&#34;. Actually. to be perfectly honest there&#39;s not much here yet EXCEPT that foundation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version supports the version of Tmux found in Ubuntu Bionic, which is 2.6. If you want to use it with an older version, check the branches of this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Additional Install Notes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make sure to add the following to the end of .bashrc to get full color support under Linux:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[ -z &#34;$TMUX&#34; ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; export TERM=xterm-256color&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For support for system clipboard on Linux, make sure to install &#34;xclip&#34; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Using on OS X&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This works on OS X in addition to Linux. If installing on OS X, make sure you have Homebrew installed and then:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install tmux&#xA;git clone https://github.com/davidbrewer/tmux-conf.git ~/.tmux-conf&#xA;ln -s ~/.tmux-conf/tmux/conf ~/.tmux.conf&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(It assumes you’re using Linux, but the config works on Mac. You just have to brew install tmux, and then place the file tmux.conf at ~/.tmux.conf ) (edited)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Starting tmux&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll start tmux from the terminal in one of the following ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Start a default session with no special name&#xA;tmux&#xA;&#xA;# Start a new session with a defined name&#xA;tmux new -s SessionName&#xA;&#xA;# Get a list of running sessions&#xA;tmux ls&#xA;&#xA;# Attach to an existing session&#xA;tmux attach -t SessionName&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Keybindings&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&#39;t complete documentation of the keybindings, but to get you started...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All tmux commands start with a &#34;prefix&#34; which you hit to go into &#34;tmux command mode&#34;. You do the prefix, let go of it, and then hit the command listed below You can change this in the configuration, but by default the prefix is &lt;code&gt;control-a&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commands (following prefix):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt;: split a pane into two side by side panes (that&#39;s &#34;prefix-verticalpipe&#34;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt;: split a pane into two vertically stacked panes. (that&#39;s prefix-minus)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;h&lt;/code&gt;: select the pane to the left of the current pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;j&lt;/code&gt;: select the pane under the current pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;: select the pane above the current pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;: select the pane to the right of the current pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;shift-H&lt;/code&gt;: resize panes, moving the vertical divider to the left&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;shift-J&lt;/code&gt;: resize panes, moving the horizontal divider down&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;shift-K&lt;/code&gt;: resize panes, moving the horizontal divider up&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;shift-L&lt;/code&gt;: resize panes, moving the vertical divider to the right&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;c&lt;/code&gt;: create a new &#34;window&#34; inside tmux&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;NUM&lt;/code&gt;: jump to the window indicated by NUM (an integer)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;[&lt;/code&gt;: turn on vertical buffer scrolling in a pane (can use arrows or pageup/pagedown to scroll, ESC then return to exit scrolling)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SPACE&lt;/code&gt;: cycle through layout options for tabs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL-o&lt;/code&gt;: rotate the contents of the panes, moving the contents of the current pane to another pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;,&lt;/code&gt;: rename the current window (adding a label at the bottom)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;d&lt;/code&gt;: &#34;detach&#34; from the current session (going back to the terminal that you launched tmux from)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;: kill the current pane&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;z&lt;/code&gt;: ZOOM into the current pane, enlarging it to the full terminal. Repeat the command to zoom back out&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;w&lt;/code&gt;: display a neat menu of all the panes you have open&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>