<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-03T01:33:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mysociety/fixmystreet</title>
    <updated>2024-06-03T01:33:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-03:/mysociety/fixmystreet</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mysociety/fixmystreet" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is mySociety&#39;s popular map-based reporting platform: easy to install in new countries and regions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to FixMyStreet Platform&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FixMyStreet Platform is an open source project to help people run websites for reporting common street problems such as potholes and broken street lights to the appropriate authority.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users locate problems using a combination of address and sticking a pin in a map without worrying about the correct authority to report it to. FixMyStreet then works out the correct authority using the problem location and type and sends a report, by email or using a web service such as Open311. Reported problems are visible to everyone so they can see if something has already been reported and leave updates. Users can also subscribe to email or RSS alerts of problems in their area.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was created in 2007 by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysociety.org/&#34;&gt;mySociety&lt;/a&gt; for reporting problems to UK councils and has been copied around the world. The FixMyStreet Platform is now at version 5.0; see CHANGELOG.md for a version history.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been working hard to make the FixMyStreet Platform easy to install and re-use in other countries - please see our site at &lt;a href=&#34;https://fixmystreet.org/&#34;&gt;https://fixmystreet.org/&lt;/a&gt; for help and documentation in installing the FixMyStreet Platform.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For development, if you have Vagrant installed, you can clone the repo and run &#39;vagrant up&#39;. We use &lt;a href=&#34;https://githubengineering.com/scripts-to-rule-them-all/&#34;&gt;Scripts to Rule Them All&lt;/a&gt; so &lt;code&gt;script/update&lt;/code&gt; will update your checkout, &lt;code&gt;script/server&lt;/code&gt; will run a dev server, and &lt;code&gt;script/test&lt;/code&gt; will run the tests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution Guidelines&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst many contributions come as part of people setting up their own installation for their area, we of course welcome stand-alone contributions as well. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mysociety/fixmystreet/labels/Suitable%20for%20Volunteers&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suitable for Volunteers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; label in our GitHub issues hopefully labels some potential tasks that might be suitable for that situation, though please do search through the other issues to see if what you&#39;re after has been suggested or discussed - or feel free to add your own issue if not.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Mobile apps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve extracted all of the mobile apps from this repository into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mysociety/fixmystreet-mobile&#34;&gt;fixmystreet-mobile repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.browserstack.com/&#34;&gt;Browserstack&lt;/a&gt; who let us use their web-based cross-browser testing tools for this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fixmystreet.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.fixmystreet.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fiksgatami.no/&#34;&gt;http://www.fiksgatami.no/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fixmystreet.ie/&#34;&gt;http://fixmystreet.ie/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zueriwieneu.ch/&#34;&gt;https://www.zueriwieneu.ch/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mikulely/dotfile</title>
    <updated>2024-06-03T01:33:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-03:/mikulely/dotfile</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mikulely/dotfile" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The notorious dotfiles :-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>