<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-03T01:36:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>centreon/centreon-documentation</title>
    <updated>2023-10-03T01:36:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-03:/centreon/centreon-documentation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/centreon/centreon-documentation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Centreon documentation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Docs @ Centreon&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the repo for our documentation. This is the source for &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.centreon.com/&#34;&gt;https://docs.centreon.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to send us pull requests and file issues. Our docs are completely open source and we deeply appreciate contributions from our community!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/centreon/centreon-documentation/staging/#providing-feedback&#34;&gt;Providing feedback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/centreon/centreon-documentation/staging/#contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/centreon/centreon-documentation/staging/#how-to-build-the-documentation-locally&#34;&gt;How to build the documentation locally&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Providing feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We really want your feedback, and we&#39;ve made it easy. You can edit a page or request changes using the &#34;Edit this page&#34; button at the bottom of each page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only file issues about the documentation in this repository.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One way to think about this is that you should file a bug here if your issue is that you don&#39;t see something that should be in the docs, or you see something incorrect or confusing in the docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If your problem is a general question about how to configure or use Centreon, ask in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://centreon.github.io/register-slack/&#34;&gt;Slack channel&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you have an idea for a new feature or behavior change in a specific aspect of Centreon, or have found a bug in part of Centreon, file that issue in the project&#39;s code repository. You may use the contribution guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/centreon/centreon/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We value your documentation contributions, and we want to make it as easy as possible to work in this repository. One of the first things to decide is which branch to base your work on. If you get confused, just ask and we will help. If a reviewer realizes you have based your work on the wrong branch, we&#39;ll let you know so that you can rebase it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand how the documentation is structured, you may have a look to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docusaurus.io/&#34;&gt;Docusaurus project&lt;/a&gt;. We&#39;re using version 2.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Pull request guidelines&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help us review your PRs more quickly by following these guidelines.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try not to touch a large number of files in a single PR if possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t change whitespace or line wrapping in parts of a file you are not editing for other reasons. Make sure your text editor is not configured to automatically reformat the whole file when saving.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Style guide&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try not to have lines over 80 characters. Use your best judgment, and try to follow the example set by the existing documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to build the documentation locally&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This website is built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docusaurus.io/&#34;&gt;Docusaurus 2&lt;/a&gt;, a modern static website generator.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Which branch should I base my PRs on?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use branch &lt;strong&gt;staging&lt;/strong&gt;. We will merge the PR into production once it has gone through the validation process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install &lt;strong&gt;yarn&lt;/strong&gt;. On Windows: &lt;a href=&#34;https://classic.yarnpkg.com/latest.msi&#34;&gt;https://classic.yarnpkg.com/latest.msi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install &lt;strong&gt;node.js&lt;/strong&gt; (version 14 minimum): &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/download/&#34;&gt;https://nodejs.org/en/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clone the repository :&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/centreon/centreon-documentation.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you need, create and/or check out the branch you want:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git branch &amp;lt;name_of_branch&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout &amp;lt;name_of_branch&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install dependencies:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn install --frozen-lockfile&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Building the documentation website&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Build the EN or FR version of the site (faster)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;EN: &lt;code&gt;yarn start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FR: &lt;code&gt;yarn start --locale=fr&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;The website opens in your browser at the following address: &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000/&lt;/a&gt;. Most changes are reflected live without having to restart the server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you really need to build the whole website, use the following command (but be aware it takes a long time to build):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yarn build&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then use the &lt;code&gt;npm run serve&lt;/code&gt; command to open the website in your browser.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Adding files to the table of contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There is only 1 ToC file per version, in English. ToC files are located in the &lt;strong&gt;versioned_sidebars&lt;/strong&gt; folder. For instance, the EN ToC file for version 21.10 is called &lt;strong&gt;version-21.10-sidebars.json&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For the French ToC, there is no ToC file, but a .json file which contains translated strings for chapter headings, located in the following folder: &lt;strong&gt;i18n\fr\docusaurus-plugin-content-docs&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, the FR translation file for version 21.10 is called &lt;strong&gt;version-21.10.json&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Making changes to the same file in different versions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to make the same change to a file across different versions, you have to copy your change to each version of the doc manually (no cherrypicking).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Docusaurus documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need help with Docusaurus, read their &lt;a href=&#34;https://docusaurus.io/docs&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>