<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-27T01:32:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ryz/dotfiles</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T01:32:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-27:/ryz/dotfiles</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ryz/dotfiles" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;various dotfiles for Unix systems I&#39;m using&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ryz&#39; dotfiles&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are (some of) my personal config files for *NIX systems, tailored to my likes and needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Environment&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am currently using these files mainly on MAC OS X and Arch Linux. I prefer to use zsh (Z shell) and highly encourage you to use this great Unix shell!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;My (g)Vim configuration is included via the git submodule found here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ryz/vim-ryz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ryz/vim-ryz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several other features that i&#39;ll explain in detail at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jchain/quickcd</title>
    <updated>2024-03-27T01:32:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-27:/jchain/quickcd</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jchain/quickcd" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Change directory with less keystrokes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;quickcd&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A rewrite of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/philc/fuzzycd&#34;&gt;fuzzycd&lt;/a&gt; in Perl. You only need to type partial directory names to change directories. It saves you a lot of keystrokes and enhances your productivity, especially when you navigate in many subdirectories with tricky names.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script is inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/philc/fuzzycd&#34;&gt;fuzzycd&lt;/a&gt;. Big thanks to the author for sharing his/her great code. The way of intercepting the system &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; is genius. I recommend you to try both scripts and choose the one you like most.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;quickcd enables you to use cd with partial directory names. For example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd box&#xA;  =&amp;gt; Dropbox&#xA;$ cd ok&#xA;  =&amp;gt; Ebook&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there is more than one directory containing your cd path, you just need to type one more letter to take you to the target folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;~ $ cd D&#xA;Make a choice:&#xA;[a] Desktop  [b] Documents  [c] Downloads  [d] Dropbox&#xA;a&#xA;Desktop $&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Why rewrite?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The differences:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When your cd path contains capital letter quickcd will match case sensitively. This way can result in less matches. fuzzycd seems to do case insensitive match all the time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quickcd prints out a well-formatted candidates&lt;/strong&gt;. It fits the width of the terminal windows and the columns are aligned neatly. I worked really hard on making this right. fuzzycd candidates are not always aligned.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;quickcd doesn&#39;t support multi-level directory nagivation. Its main focus is current directory. fuzzycd supports fuzzy jumps to multi-level directory but I rarely use this feature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;quickcd is written in Perl. Yep, I like Perl! fuzzycd is written in Ruby.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This following instruction are shamelessly copied from fuzzycd&#39;s README.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modify your ~/.profile (or ~/.bashrc, depending your operating system) and add the following lines. This assumes you put quickcd in the ~/scripts/ directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;export PATH=~/scripts/quickcd/:$PATH&#xA;source ~/scripts/quickcd/quickcd_bash_wrapper.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will effectively wrap the builtin bash cd command with the fuzzy cd command. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: If you have any other shell plugins which try to redefine the &#34;cd&#34; function (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://rvm.beginrescueend.com/rvm&#34;&gt;rvm&lt;/a&gt; does this), make sure that the &lt;code&gt;source ... quickcd_bash_wrapper.sh&lt;/code&gt; line comes last in your bash profile. quickcd plays nicely with other bash modification plugins, but it should be loaded last.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>