<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-09T01:37:11Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>binary-com/perl-Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:37:11Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/binary-com/perl-Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/binary-com/perl-Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Math::Business::BlackScholesMerton&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/binary-com/perl-math-business-blackscholesmerton&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/binary-com/perl-math-business-blackscholesmerton.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/binary-com/perl-math-business-blackscholesmerton&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codecov.io/gh/binary-com/perl-math-business-blackscholesmerton/branch/master/graph/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;codecov&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prices options using the GBM model, all closed formulas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important(a): Basically, one_touch, up_or_down and double_touch have two cases of payoff either at end or at hit. We treat them differently. We use parameter $w to differ them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;$w = 0: payoff at hit time. $w = 1: payoff at end.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our current contracts pay rebate at hit time, so we set $w = 0 by default.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important(b) :Furthermore, for all our contracts, we allow a different payout currency (Quantos).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paying domestic currency (JPY if for USDJPY) = correlation coefficient is ZERO. Paying foreign currency (USD if for USDJPY) = correlation coefficient is ONE. Paying another currency = correlation is between negative ONE and positive ONE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install this module, run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perl Makefile.PL&#xA;make&#xA;make test&#xA;make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SUPPORT AND DOCUMENTATION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After installing, you can find documentation for this module with the perldoc command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perldoc Math::Business::BlackScholesMerton&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also look for information at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;RT, CPAN&#39;s request tracker (report bugs here)&#xA;    http://rt.cpan.org/NoAuth/Bugs.html?Dist=Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton&#xA;&#xA;AnnoCPAN, Annotated CPAN documentation&#xA;    http://annocpan.org/dist/Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton&#xA;&#xA;CPAN Ratings&#xA;    http://cpanratings.perl.org/d/Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton&#xA;&#xA;Search CPAN&#xA;    http://search.cpan.org/dist/Math-Business-BlackScholesMerton/&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LICENSE AND COPYRIGHT&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (C) 2014 binary.com&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the the Artistic License (2.0). You may obtain a copy of the full license at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;L&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.perlfoundation.org/artistic_license_2_0&#34;&gt;http://www.perlfoundation.org/artistic_license_2_0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any use, modification, and distribution of the Standard or Modified Versions is governed by this Artistic License. By using, modifying or distributing the Package, you accept this license. Do not use, modify, or distribute the Package, if you do not accept this license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your Modified Version has been derived from a Modified Version made by someone other than you, you are nevertheless required to ensure that your Modified Version complies with the requirements of this license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This license does not grant you the right to use any trademark, service mark, tradename, or logo of the Copyright Holder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This license includes the non-exclusive, worldwide, free-of-charge patent license to make, have made, use, offer to sell, sell, import and otherwise transfer the Package with respect to any patent claims licensable by the Copyright Holder that are necessarily infringed by the Package. If you institute patent litigation (including a cross-claim or counterclaim) against any party alleging that the Package constitutes direct or contributory patent infringement, then this Artistic License to you shall terminate on the date that such litigation is filed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer of Warranty: THE PACKAGE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER AND CONTRIBUTORS &#34;AS IS&#39; AND WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES. THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT ARE DISCLAIMED TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY YOUR LOCAL LAW. UNLESS REQUIRED BY LAW, NO COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTOR WILL BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THE PACKAGE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EquinoxOpenLibraryInitiative/eg-restful-api-experiment</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:37:11Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/EquinoxOpenLibraryInitiative/eg-restful-api-experiment</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/EquinoxOpenLibraryInitiative/eg-restful-api-experiment" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Experimental code for a RESTful API server for Evergreen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Evergreen RESTful API Experiment&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;code&gt;Mojolicious::Lite&lt;/code&gt; application that extends an experiment / proof-of-concept for creating a RESTful API for Evergreen that&#39;s based on&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenAPI 3.0.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mojolicious&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Mojolicious::Plugin::OpenAPI&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install and run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cpan Mojolicious::Plugin::OpenAPI&#xA;./eg-api.pl daemon -m production -l http://localhost:8080&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will also need to add an nginx configuration block within the server section that listens on port 443 to provide HTTPS support / redirection:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; location /openapi3 {&#xA;     proxy_pass http://localhost:8080;&#xA;     proxy_set_header Host $host;&#xA;     proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for;&#xA;     proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-Proto $scheme;&#xA;     proxy_read_timeout 300s;&#xA; }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;eg-api.pl&lt;/code&gt; assumes that it is running on an Evergreen system whose core config is located at &lt;code&gt;/openils/conf/opensrf_core.xml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>