<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-30T01:38:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ggalindezb/vim_colorscheme_template</title>
    <updated>2022-12-30T01:38:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-30:/ggalindezb/vim_colorscheme_template</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ggalindezb/vim_colorscheme_template" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An empty template to create a Vim colorscheme by hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Colorscheme template&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a template to create Vim colorschemes. It includes the most common options used for a filetype independent colorscheme for a terminal Vim with 256 colors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every option is set to default values, to create your colorscheme you should select a background, give the colorscheme a name and fill in the necesary options.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maestro Entheon&#39;s colortest Perl file is included with this template. You&#39;ll likely want to call it like &lt;code&gt;perl colortest -w -r -s&lt;/code&gt; and it will print out every color your terminal supports. It&#39;s helps a lot when developing colorschemes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Highlight format&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every highlight group includes the following (obvious, already known) format:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hi (Group)          ctermfg=none    ctermbg=none    cterm=none&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Group.&lt;/em&gt; The targeted highlight group. If you want to know what&#39;s exactly supposed to do, &lt;code&gt;:help highlight&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;:help hl-(Group)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ctermfg.&lt;/em&gt; The color of the letter of the syntax group.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ctermbg.&lt;/em&gt; The color of the background of each letter in the syntax group.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;cterm.&lt;/em&gt; Formatting options. For a list of options, check &lt;code&gt;highlight-args&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;:help :highlight&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every other colorscheme I came across came with most of the options, but without a real order. It seems that someone did an original template with those options, published it and then everybody else copied it. Being an order-paranoid, I decided to tidy it up a bit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Order of the syntax groups&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editor settings.&lt;/strong&gt; Configuration regarding Vim&#39;s interface, not related to a given programming language. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number column.&lt;/em&gt; The column with the line numbers and folds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Window/Tab delmiters.&lt;/em&gt; The area that shows window splits and opened tabs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;File Navigation / Searching.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prompt/Status.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual aid.&lt;/em&gt; Matching parenthesis, visual block selection...&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variable types.&lt;/strong&gt; Boolean variables, numbers, strings...&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language constructs.&lt;/strong&gt; Conditionals, cycles, keywords, comments... &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;C-Like.&lt;/em&gt; The syntax of some languages is very C-like. This section is for them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diff.&lt;/strong&gt; Colors for vim diff, block is equal, block is different, block doesn&#39;t exists...&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completion Menu.&lt;/strong&gt; Insert mode completion menu, background, scrollbar, selected item, non-selected item.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spelling.&lt;/strong&gt; Useful if you use spelling checking with Vim.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a section labeled &lt;em&gt;Specific settings&lt;/em&gt;. If you want to use specific colors for a given filetype, the highlight rules can be added here to keep them in order.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>