<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-17T01:35:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>libsdl-org/SDL_net</title>
    <updated>2024-06-17T01:35:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-17:/libsdl-org/SDL_net</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/libsdl-org/SDL_net" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A simple, cross-platform wrapper over TCP/IP sockets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;SDL_net 3.0&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version of this library is available from GitHub:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libsdl-org/SDL_net/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/libsdl-org/SDL_net/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a portable network library for use with SDL. It&#39;s goal is to simplify the use of the usual socket interfaces and use SDL infrastructure to handle some portability things (such as threading and reporting errors).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is available under the zlib license, found in the file LICENSE.txt. The API can be found in the file SDL_net.h and online at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.libsdl.org/SDL3_net&#34;&gt;https://wiki.libsdl.org/SDL3_net&lt;/a&gt; This library supports most platforms that offer both SDL3 and networking.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>gugod/App-perlbrew</title>
    <updated>2024-06-17T01:35:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-17:/gugod/App-perlbrew</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/gugod/App-perlbrew" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Manage perl installations in your $HOME&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;NAME&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;App::perlbrew - Manage perl installations in your $HOME&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SYNOPSIS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    # Installation&#xA;    curl -L https://install.perlbrew.pl | bash&#xA;&#xA;    # Initialize&#xA;    perlbrew init&#xA;&#xA;    # See what is available&#xA;    perlbrew available&#xA;&#xA;    # Install some Perls&#xA;    perlbrew install 5.32.1&#xA;    perlbrew install perl-5.28.3&#xA;    perlbrew install perl-5.33.6&#xA;&#xA;    # See what were installed&#xA;    perlbrew list&#xA;&#xA;    # Swith to an installation and set it as default&#xA;    perlbrew switch perl-5.32.1&#xA;&#xA;    # Temporarily use another version only in current shell.&#xA;    perlbrew use perl-5.28.3&#xA;    perl -v&#xA;&#xA;    # Turn it off and go back to the system perl.&#xA;    perlbrew off&#xA;&#xA;    # Turn it back on with &#39;switch&#39;, or &#39;use&#39;&#xA;    perlbrew switch perl-5.32.1&#xA;    perlbrew use perl-5.32.1&#xA;&#xA;    # Exec something with all perlbrew-ed perls&#xA;    perlbrew exec -- perl -E &#39;say $]&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perlbrew is a program to automate the building and installation of perl&#xA;in an easy way. It provides multiple isolated perl environments, and a&#xA;mechanism for you to switch between them.&#xA;&#xA;Everything are installed unter ~/perl5/perlbrew. You then need to&#xA;include a bashrc/cshrc provided by perlbrew to tweak the PATH for you.&#xA;You then can benefit from not having to run sudo commands to install&#xA;cpan modules because those are installed inside your HOME too.&#xA;&#xA;For the documentation of perlbrew usage see perlbrew command on&#xA;MetaCPAN &amp;lt;https://metacpan.org/&amp;gt;, or by running perlbrew help, or by&#xA;visiting perlbrew&#39;s official website &amp;lt;https://perlbrew.pl/&amp;gt;. The&#xA;following documentation features the API of App::perlbrew module, and&#xA;may not be remotely close to what your want to read.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;It is the simplest to use the perlbrew installer, just paste this&#xA;statement to your terminal:&#xA;&#xA;    curl -L https://install.perlbrew.pl | bash&#xA;&#xA;Or this one, if you have fetch (default on FreeBSD):&#xA;&#xA;    fetch -o- https://install.perlbrew.pl | sh&#xA;&#xA;After that, perlbrew installs itself to ~/perl5/perlbrew/bin, and you&#xA;should follow the instruction on screen to modify your shell rc file to&#xA;put it in your PATH.&#xA;&#xA;The installed perlbrew command is a standalone executable that can be&#xA;run with system perl. The minimum required version of system perl is&#xA;5.8.0, which should be good enough for most of the OSes these days.&#xA;&#xA;A fat-packed version of patchperl is also installed to&#xA;~/perl5/perlbrew/bin, which is required to build old perls.&#xA;&#xA;The directory ~/perl5/perlbrew will contain all install perl&#xA;executables, libraries, documentations, lib, site_libs. In the&#xA;documentation, that directory is referred as perlbrew root. If you need&#xA;to set it to somewhere else because, say, your HOME has limited quota,&#xA;you can do that by setting PERLBREW_ROOT environment variable before&#xA;running the installer:&#xA;&#xA;    export PERLBREW_ROOT=/opt/perl5&#xA;    curl -L https://install.perlbrew.pl | bash&#xA;&#xA;As a result, different users on the same machine can all share the same&#xA;perlbrew root directory (although only original user that made the&#xA;installation would have the permission to perform perl installations.)&#xA;&#xA;If you need to install perlbrew using a Perl that isn&#39;t either&#xA;/usr/bin/perl or /usr/local/bin/perl, set and export the environment&#xA;variable PERLBREW_SYSTEM_PERL and then install as described above. Note&#xA;that you must not use a perlbrew-managed perl.&#xA;&#xA;You may also install perlbrew from CPAN:&#xA;&#xA;    cpan App::perlbrew&#xA;&#xA;In this case, the perlbrew command is installed as /usr/bin/perlbrew or&#xA;/usr/local/bin/perlbrew or others, depending on the location of your&#xA;system perl installation.&#xA;&#xA;Please make sure not to run this with one of the perls brewed with&#xA;perlbrew. It&#39;s the best to turn perlbrew off before you run that, if&#xA;you&#39;re upgrading.&#xA;&#xA;    perlbrew off&#xA;    cpan App::perlbrew&#xA;&#xA;You should always use system cpan (like /usr/bin/cpan) to install&#xA;App::perlbrew because it will be installed under a system PATH like&#xA;/usr/bin, which is not affected by perlbrew switch or use command.&#xA;&#xA;The self-upgrade command will not upgrade the perlbrew installed by&#xA;cpan command, but it is also easy to upgrade perlbrew by running cpan&#xA;App::perlbrew again.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PROJECT DEVELOPMENT&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;perlbrew project &amp;lt;https://perlbrew.pl/&amp;gt; uses github&#xA;https://github.com/gugod/App-perlbrew/issues for issue tracking. Issues&#xA;sent to these two systems will eventually be reviewed and handled. To&#xA;participate, you need a github account.&#xA;&#xA;Please briefly read the short instructions about how to get your work&#xA;released to CPAN:&#xA;&#xA;https://github.com/gugod/App-perlbrew/blob/develop/CONTRIBUTING.md&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AUTHOR&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Kang-min Liu &amp;lt;gugod@gugod.org&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;COPYRIGHT&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright (c) 2023 Kang-min Liu &amp;lt;gugod@gugod.org&amp;gt;.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LICENCE&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The MIT License&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;BECAUSE THIS SOFTWARE IS LICENSED FREE OF CHARGE, THERE IS NO WARRANTY&#xA;FOR THE SOFTWARE, TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW. EXCEPT&#xA;WHEN OTHERWISE STATED IN WRITING THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND/OR OTHER&#xA;PARTIES PROVIDE THE SOFTWARE &#34;AS IS&#34; WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,&#xA;EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED&#xA;WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. THE&#xA;ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE SOFTWARE IS WITH&#xA;YOU. SHOULD THE SOFTWARE PROVE DEFECTIVE, YOU ASSUME THE COST OF ALL&#xA;NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR, OR CORRECTION.&#xA;&#xA;IN NO EVENT UNLESS REQUIRED BY APPLICABLE LAW OR AGREED TO IN WRITING&#xA;WILL ANY COPYRIGHT HOLDER, OR ANY OTHER PARTY WHO MAY MODIFY AND/OR&#xA;REDISTRIBUTE THE SOFTWARE AS PERMITTED BY THE ABOVE LICENCE, BE LIABLE&#xA;TO YOU FOR DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY GENERAL, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR&#xA;CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR INABILITY TO USE THE&#xA;SOFTWARE (INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO LOSS OF DATA OR DATA BEING&#xA;RENDERED INACCURATE OR LOSSES SUSTAINED BY YOU OR THIRD PARTIES OR A&#xA;FAILURE OF THE SOFTWARE TO OPERATE WITH ANY OTHER SOFTWARE), EVEN IF&#xA;SUCH HOLDER OR OTHER PARTY HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH&#xA;DAMAGES.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>