<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-09T01:29:17Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>NathanReb/ocaml-api-watch</title>
    <updated>2024-03-09T01:29:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-09:/NathanReb/ocaml-api-watch</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/NathanReb/ocaml-api-watch" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Libraries and tools to keep watch on you OCaml lib&#39;s API changes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;api-watch&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This project is WIP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;api-watch&lt;/code&gt; povides libraries and tools to keep watch on your OCaml&#39;s library&#39;s API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a keystone of an effort to bring semantic versioning to the OCaml libraries ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>munin-monitoring/contrib</title>
    <updated>2024-03-09T01:29:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-09:/munin-monitoring/contrib</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/munin-monitoring/contrib" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contributed stuff for munin (plugins, tools, etc...)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for all user contributed stuff related to &lt;a href=&#34;http://munin-monitoring.org&#34;&gt;munin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;contrib/plugins/ - 3rd-party plugins&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is usually where you want to begin your journey.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here you find a plethora of plugins for the most diverse topics. Please take a look and improve existing or propose new plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/munin-monitoring/contrib/master/plugins#contributed-munin-plugins&#34;&gt;hints for plugin contributions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gallery.munin-monitoring.org/&#34;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt; for a browsable overview of these plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;contrib/templates/ - 3rd-party templates&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to update templates here, or even to create new ones.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bonus points for mobile-friendly ones :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the one named &lt;code&gt;official&lt;/code&gt; is a loose-synced copy of the one distributed with munin. It should serves as a base for small editions that can be merged into munin, so for that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;don&#39;t copy the whole template&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;directly edit files in this directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;contrib/tools/ - 3rd-party tools&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here, you can put just any kind of tool. Please use this directory instead of a random place on the internet. It makes things way more easy to search for others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;contrib/samples/ - 3rd-party examples of configs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This serves as a repository for examples of various configs. You know, the &#39;&#39;learn by example&#39;&#39; way of doing things.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes to contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Commits, Comments &amp;amp; Pull requests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We like to have &lt;em&gt;elementary&lt;/em&gt; commits as it is much easier to manage for reviewing and debugging. So please &lt;strong&gt;don&#39;t&lt;/strong&gt; be afraid to make &lt;strong&gt;as many&lt;/strong&gt; commits as needed. Merging many commits is as easy as merging one, if not easier.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A good rationale is that each commit shall have a one-liner commit comment as its first line. Ideally that first line has a prefix that shows the part the commit is about. It makes it very easy to see grouped changes, and it enable avoiding to look at the &lt;code&gt;--stat&lt;/code&gt;. To know the prefix you should use, you can have a look at already existing commits. Next lines are optional and should only explain the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it is done this particular way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the other side, pull requests can regroup many commits at once. Just try to explain in the pull comment the &#39;&#39;why&#39;&#39; we should merge it (if it&#39;s not obvious).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tim Pope wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tbaggery.com/2008/04/19/a-note-about-git-commit-messages.html&#34;&gt;very nice tuto&lt;/a&gt; on making good commit comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Licenses&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the code here is licensed with the same terms as munin itself (GPLv2), unless specified otherwise inside a file. In all cases the code shall have an OSI-compatible license. Asking for a pull implies that you agree with that fact.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This change was made on Jun 1st 2012. If you wrote some code earlier and you do not agree to the new licensing default, you can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;submit a licensing change pull&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;submit a removal pull&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Building status&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;master: &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/munin-monitoring/contrib&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/munin-monitoring/contrib.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>