<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-23T01:46:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ErSanSan233/latex-translation</title>
    <updated>2023-04-23T01:46:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-23:/ErSanSan233/latex-translation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ErSanSan233/latex-translation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;一本LaTeX图书的中文译本&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ErSanSan233/latex-translation/main/cover.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;偶然间发现了这本名为&lt;a href=&#34;https://archives.framabook.org/tout-sur-latex/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tout ce que vous avez toujours voulu savoir sur LaTeX sans jamais oser le demander&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;的图书，其中涉及了丰富且实用的排版技巧，遂将其翻译为中文，供大家阅读参考。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;编译和阅读&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;本工程采用XeLaTeX编译。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;文件&lt;code&gt;main.pdf&lt;/code&gt;为编译后效果，可直接阅读。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;许可证&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;本书是开放图书，遵循&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.artlibre.org&#34;&gt;开放作品许可&lt;/a&gt;（Licence Art Libre，LAL）。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>grambank/grambank</title>
    <updated>2023-04-23T01:46:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-23:/grambank/grambank</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/grambank/grambank" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Grambank v1.0&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/grambank/grambank/actions?query=workflow%3ACLDF-validation&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/grambank/grambank/workflows/CLDF-validation/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;CLDF validation&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to cite&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use these data please cite&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the original source &#xA;  &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;Skirgård, Hedvig and Haynie, Hannah J. and Blasi, Damián E. and Hammarström, Harald and Collins, Jeremy and Latarche, Jay J. and Lesage, Jakob and Weber, Tobias and Witzlack-Makarevich, Alena and Passmore, Sam and Chira, Angela and Maurits, Luke and Dinnage, Russell and Dunn, Michael and Reesink, Ger and Singer, Ruth and Bowern, Claire and Epps, Patience and Hill, Jane and Vesakoski, Outi and Robbeets, Martine and Abbas, Noor Karolin and Auer, Daniel and Bakker, Nancy A. and Barbos, Giulia and Borges, Robert D. and Danielsen, Swintha and Dorenbusch, Luise and Dorn, Ella and Elliott, John and Falcone, Giada and Fischer, Jana and Ghanggo Ate, Yustinus and Gibson, Hannah and Göbel, Hans-Philipp and Goodall, Jemima A. and Gruner, Victoria and Harvey, Andrew and Hayes, Rebekah and Heer, Leonard and Herrera Miranda, Roberto E. and Hübler, Nataliia and Huntington-Rainey, Biu and Ivani, Jessica K. and Johns, Marilen and Just, Erika and Kashima, Eri and Kipf, Carolina and Klingenberg, Janina V. and König, Nikita and Koti, Aikaterina and Kowalik, Richard G. A. and Krasnoukhova, Olga and Lindvall, Nora L.M. and Lorenzen, Mandy and Lutzenberger, Hannah and Martins, Tônia R.A. and Mata German, Celia and van der Meer, Suzanne and Montoya Samamé, Jaime and Müller, Michael and Muradoglu, Saliha and Neely, Kelsey and Nickel, Johanna and Norvik, Miina and Oluoch, Cheryl Akinyi and Peacock, Jesse and Pearey, India O.C. and Peck, Naomi and Petit, Stephanie and Pieper, Sören and Poblete, Mariana and Prestipino, Daniel and Raabe, Linda and Raja, Amna and Reimringer, Janis and Rey, Sydney C. and Rizaew, Julia and Ruppert, Eloisa and Salmon, Kim K. and Sammet, Jill and Schembri, Rhiannon and Schlabbach, Lars and Schmidt, Frederick W.P. and Skilton, Amalia and Smith, Wikaliler Daniel and de Sousa, Hilário and Sverredal, Kristin and Valle, Daniel and Vera, Javier and Voß, Judith and Witte, Tim and Wu, Henry and Yam, Stephanie and Ye 葉婧婷, Jingting and Yong, Maisie and Yuditha, Tessa and Zariquiey, Roberto and Forkel, Robert and Evans, Nicholas and Levinson, Stephen C. and Haspelmath, Martin and Greenhill, Simon J. and Atkinson, Quentin D. and Gray, Russell D. (in press). Grambank reveals the importance of genealogical constraints on linguistic diversity and highlights the impact of language loss. Science Advances.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the derived dataset using the DOI of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grambank/releases/&#34;&gt;particular released version&lt;/a&gt; you were using&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grambank/grambank/master/map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Distribution of classifier languages&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Global dataset of structural linguistic features, part of Glottobank.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This dataset is licensed under a CC-BY-4.0 license&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Available online at &lt;a href=&#34;https://grambank.clld.org&#34;&gt;https://grambank.clld.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For examples on how to use this datasets, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grambank/grambank/master/recipes/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;recipes&lt;/code&gt; folder in this repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;CLDF Datasets&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following CLDF datasets are available in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grambank/grambank/master/cldf&#34;&gt;cldf&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CLDF &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cldf/cldf/tree/master/modules/StructureDataset&#34;&gt;StructureDataset&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/grambank/grambank/master/cldf/StructureDataset-metadata.json&#34;&gt;cldf/StructureDataset-metadata.json&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>