<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-12T01:59:09Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>fmarotta/kaobook</title>
    <updated>2022-07-12T01:59:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-12:/fmarotta/kaobook</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/fmarotta/kaobook" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A LaTeX class for books, reports or theses based on https://github.com/kenohori/thesis and https://github.com/Tufte-LaTeX/tufte-latex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;kaobook&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This class is based on the work of &lt;a href=&#34;https://3d.bk.tudelft.nl/ken/en/&#34;&gt;Ken Arroyo Ohori&lt;/a&gt; for his doctoral thesis. The main ideas behind the layout can be found in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://3d.bk.tudelft.nl/ken/en/2016/04/17/a-1.5-column-layout-in-latex.html&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Tufte-LaTeX/tufte-latex&#34;&gt;Tufte-LaTeX class&lt;/a&gt; has also been a source of ideas about the layout.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;My gratitude goes also to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vel.nz/&#34;&gt;Vel&lt;/a&gt;, for his patience and his invaluable suggestions about the design, and to all the people who have contributed either on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fmarotta/kaobook/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or by sending e-mails.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The salient features of the class are as follows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wide margin to house captions, small figures or tables, and textual notes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mini table of contents in the margin at the start of each chapter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Easily-customisable chapter headings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Flexible citations with references both in the margin and in the bibliography at the end.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Powered by KOMA-Script.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Many commands have been redefined to ease the life of the user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A better description can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latextemplates.com/template/kaobook&#34;&gt;LaTeX Templates&lt;/a&gt;. If you think that a PDF is worth a thousand words, have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/example_and_documentation.pdf&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Showcase&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/examples&#34;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; directory you can find some sample documents, but here are some more books or reports created with the kaobook class. If you want to add a link to your work, please send me an email or open a pull request!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cyrius.com/foss-foundations/growing-open-source-projects.pdf&#34;&gt;Growing Open Source Projects with a Stable Foundation (short book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://femto-physique.fr/mecanique/pdf/book_meca.pdf&#34;&gt;Cours De Physique - Mécanique Classique (textbook)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bradyneal.com/Introduction_to_Causal_Inference-Dec17_2020-Neal.pdf&#34;&gt;Introduction to Causal Inference (textbook)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheoWinterhalter/phd-thesis/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Formalisation and Meta-Theory of Type Theory (PhD thesis)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tudelft3d/terrainbook/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Computational modelling of terrains (textbook)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anjapetkovic.com/img/doctoralThesis.pdf&#34;&gt;Meta-analysis of Type Theories with an Application to the Design of Formal Proofs (PhD thesis)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with LaTeX, I recommend starting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.overleaf.com/learn/latex/Learn_LaTeX_in_30_minutes&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, which will give you a basic understanding of the language. As you will read in the tutorial, all LaTeX documents, including books, start by defining the so-called &lt;em&gt;class&lt;/em&gt; of the document, for example &#39;article&#39;, or &#39;book&#39;. Thus, the first line of a LaTeX document will be something like&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;\documentclass{book}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each class provides a unique style and set of commands that can be used throughout the document. &lt;code&gt;kaobook&lt;/code&gt; is just another class. The following paragraphs will outline how to use it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;On Overleaf&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Browse to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latextemplates.com/template/kaobook&#34;&gt;latextemplates.com page for kaobook&lt;/a&gt; and start editing the &lt;code&gt;main.tex&lt;/code&gt; file to fill it with your own contents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;On your computer&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the latest release from GitHub. At the root of the repository, create a new &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; file and make sure that the first line reads &lt;code&gt;\documentclass{kaobook}&lt;/code&gt; (for books) or &lt;code&gt;\documentclass{kaohandt}&lt;/code&gt; (for reports). Then, fill the file with your LaTeX contents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Important: when we say &lt;code&gt;\documentclass{kaobook}&lt;/code&gt;, LaTeX needs to know where the &lt;code&gt;kaobook&lt;/code&gt; file is. This means that the &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; file should be in the same folder as the &lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt; file, &lt;em&gt;i.e.&lt;/em&gt; at the root of the repository. (There are exceptions to this rule. For instance, the kaobook files can be placed in a folder that is automatically searched by LaTeX. This, way, the &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; file with your contents can be placed anywhere; check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/instructions&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; directory for hints.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t want to start from scratch, go to the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; directory, and find a template that you like; then, copy the corresponding &lt;code&gt;main.tex&lt;/code&gt; at the root of the repository, and start editing it, filling it with your contents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/instructions&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; directory for additional guidance. There, you can read about setting up your own sharelatex server or integrating kaobook with your local LaTeX installation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The class is documented and exemplified in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/example_and_documentation.pdf&#34;&gt;example_and_documentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt; file. The easiest way to start using the class is to open one of the examples and start editing them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compiling the examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; directory of this repository you can find several documents exemplifying the kaobook class. For the sake of simplicity I shall list the commands to compile only the documentation, but the compilation of the other examples would proceed in the same way. Also, you can replace pdflatex with your favorite engine, like &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; xelatex.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;From the command line (Unix-like operating systems)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the root of the repository, and run&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pdflatex -output-directory examples/documentation main.tex&#xA;biber -output-directory examples/documentation main&#xA;pdflatex -output-directory examples/documentation main.tex&#xA;pdflatex -output-directory examples/documentation main.tex&#xA;pdflatex -output-directory examples/documentation main.tex&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To compile the glossary and nomenclature as well, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt;examples/documentation&lt;/code&gt; directory and run&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;makeindex main.nlo -s nomencl.ist -o main.nls&#xA;makeglossaries main&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; back into the root of the repository and re-run pdflatex.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: sometimes LaTeX needs more than one run to get the correct position of each element; this is true in particular for the positioning of floating elements like figures, tables, and margin notes. Occasionally, LaTeX can need up to four re-runs, so If the alignment of margin elements looks odd, or if they bleed into ther main text, try running pdflatex one more time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Updating kaobook&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To update kaobook you should download the whole repository (or one of the releases) again, and replace all of your old files with the newer ones, &lt;em&gt;except&lt;/em&gt; for the main.tex and the files that you have created, like the chapters of the book. The crucial files that pertain to kaobook and that you should always update are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kaohandt.cls&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kao.sty&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kaobiblio.sty&lt;/code&gt; (optional);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kaorefs.sty&lt;/code&gt; (optional);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;kaotheorems.sty&lt;/code&gt; (optional);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These files should be in the same folder as your &lt;code&gt;main.tex&lt;/code&gt;. Even if a file has not been modified, I would still suggest to replace everything because it is easier.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In practice, I would do as follows. I would have a directory, called for example &#39;my_book&#39;, with all the files necessary for the book: &lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;kaohand.cls&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code&gt;*.sty&lt;/code&gt; files, and the &lt;code&gt;main.tex&lt;/code&gt;. I like to have a separate file for each chapter, so I would also have a directory called &lt;code&gt;chapters&lt;/code&gt;, with all the &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; files with the actual chapters. Then, when I want to update kaobook, I would download the GitHub repository (or one of the releases) into a directory called &#39;kaobook&#39;, and finally copy the &lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;kaohandt.cls&lt;/code&gt;, and the whole &lt;code&gt;styles&lt;/code&gt; directory from &#39;kaobook&#39; to &#39;my_book&#39;. Once the update is completed, the whole &#39;my_book&#39; directory can be uploaded on Overleaf or on a personal ShareLaTeX server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, advanced users can download the repository in their local texmf tree; see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/instructions&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt; directory for hints.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository Schema&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two main class files: &lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt;, used for books, and &lt;code&gt;kaohandt.cls&lt;/code&gt;, used for reports or handouts; both heavily rely on &lt;code&gt;kao.sty&lt;/code&gt;, which contains the bulk of the definitions that are common to both classes. In the future there may be another class for theses.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some examples and templates are listed in the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; directory. The book that documents the class is an example itself, and the pdf has been copied to the root of the repository so that it will be found more easily.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;*.sty&lt;/code&gt; files contain additional packages that are used by the class, but in principle they are independent of it (even though in practice it is still not so).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to do something more peculiar, the &lt;code&gt;instructions&lt;/code&gt; directory may contain what you need.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you like the design, but you found a bug? Is there something you would have done differently? Any contribution is welcome! Moreover, even if you&#39;d rather not tamper with the code it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; forbidden to send me the documents you compiled using the kaobook class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the content of this repository is published at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latextemplates.com/&#34;&gt;LaTeX Templates&lt;/a&gt;, if you wish to contribute by changing the code you must follow the style guidelines of the site: extensive commenting and clear separation of the code into nicely formatted blocks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Supporting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am always happy to help as much as I can, and I am glad if someone uses the &lt;code&gt;kaobook&lt;/code&gt; class for their works, so there is no real need to do anything: the kaobook can be used just like any other LaTeX package (no need to add copyright statements). However, if you want to acknowledge kaobook, adding somewhere a sentence like &#39;This book was typeset with the kaobook class&#39; would suffice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coffee keeps me awake and helps me writing a better LaTeX template. As another way to contribute, you can buy me a coffee through PayPal: &lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/marofede&#34;&gt;https://paypal.me/marofede&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains two independent works. On the one hand, the kaobook class, consisting of &lt;code&gt;kaobook.cls&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;kaohandt.cls&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;kao.def&lt;/code&gt; files plus all of the files listed in the &lt;code&gt;styles&lt;/code&gt; directory; on the other hand, the templates and the examples in the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first work is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latex-project.org/lppl/&#34;&gt;LaTeX Project Public License&lt;/a&gt;, so if you want to modify and/or distribute the &lt;code&gt;*.cls&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;*.sty&lt;/code&gt; files pertaining to this work you have to complain with the terms of the license. However, if you just want to use the class to compile your documents you need not worry about the license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second work is released into the public domain with a Creative Commons Zero License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fmarotta/kaobook/master/MANIFEST.md&#34;&gt;MANIFEST.md&lt;/a&gt; for the details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>michaelt/martin-lof</title>
    <updated>2022-07-12T01:59:09Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-12:/michaelt/martin-lof</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/michaelt/martin-lof" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;papers of Per Martin Löf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The collected works of Per Martin-Löf&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please inform us of any inaccuracies or missing works.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Definition-of-Random-Sequences-1966.pdf&#34;&gt;Definition of Random Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1966&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Algorithms-and-randomness-1969.pdf&#34;&gt;Algorithms and randomness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1969&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Notes on constructive mathematics (Almqvist &amp;amp; Wiksell)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1970&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/martin-loef1971%20-%20A%20Theory%20of%20Types.pdf&#34;&gt;A theory of types (Preprint, Stockholm University)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1971&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Hauptsatz-for-the-intuitionistic-theory-of-iterated-inductive-definitions-1971.pdf&#34;&gt;Hauptsatz for the intuitionistic theory of iterated inductive definitions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1971&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Complexity-Oscillations-in-Infinite-Binary-Sequences-1971.pdf&#34;&gt;Complexity Oscillations in Infinite Binary Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1971&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Infinite-terms-and-a-system-of-natural-deduction-1972.pdf&#34;&gt;Infinite terms and a system of natural deduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1972&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/An-Intuitionistic-Theory-of-Types-1972.pdf&#34;&gt;An Intuitionistic Theory of Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1972&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/The-Notion-of-Redundancy-1974.pdf&#34;&gt;The Notion of Redundancy and Its Use as a Quantitative Measure of the Discrepancy between a Statistical Hypothesis and a Set of Observational Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1974&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/An-Intuitionistic-Theory-of-Types-Predicative-Part-1975.pdf&#34;&gt;An Intuitionistic Theory of Types: Predicative Part&lt;/a&gt; (Proceedings of the logic colloquium Bristol, July 1973)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1975&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/About-Models-for-Intuitionistic-Type-Theories-and-the-notion-of-Definitional-Equality-1975.pdf&#34;&gt;About Models for Intuitionistic Type Theories and the notion of Definitional Equality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1975&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Syntax-and-semantics-of-the-language-of-primitive-recursive-functions-1975.pdf&#34;&gt;Syntax and semantics of the language of primitive recursive functions&lt;/a&gt; (Preprint written with Peter Hancock)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1975&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Reply-to-Sverdrups-Polemical-Article-Tests-without-Power-1975.pdf&#34;&gt;Reply to Sverdrups Polemical Article Tests without Power&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1975&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Note-to-Michael-Dummett-1976.pdf&#34;&gt;A note to Michael Dummett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1976&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Exact-tests-confidence-regions-and-estimates-1977.pdf&#34;&gt;Exact tests, confidence regions and estimates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1977&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Constructive-mathematics-and-computer-programming-1979.pdf&#34;&gt;Constructive mathematics and computer programming&lt;/a&gt; (Tech report)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1979&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/MartinL%C3%B6f1979.pdf&#34;&gt;Constructive mathematics and computer programming (Version 2)&lt;/a&gt; (Tech report)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1979&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Constructive-mathematics-and-computer-programming-1982.pdf&#34;&gt;Constructive mathematics and computer programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1982&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Meanings-of-the-Logical-Constants-1983.pdf&#34;&gt;On the Meanings of the Logical Constants and the Justification of Logical Laws&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1983&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Notes-on-The-Domain-Interpretation-of-Type-Theory-1983.pdf&#34;&gt;Notes on The Domain Interpretation of Type Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1983&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Bibliopolis-Book-1984.pdf&#34;&gt;Intuitionistic Type Theory&lt;/a&gt; (Bibliopolis Book, notes by Giovanni Sambin of a series of lectures given in Padua, June 1980) &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Bibliopolis-Book-retypeset-1984.pdf&#34;&gt;(Re-typeset and searchable version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1984&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/The-logic-of-judgements-1987.pdf&#34;&gt;The logic of Judgements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1987&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/The-logic-of-judgements-typeset-1987.pdf&#34;&gt;The logic of Judgements (typeset)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1987&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Truth-of-a-Proposition-Evidence-of-a-Judgment-1987.pdf&#34;&gt;Truth of a Proposition, Evidence of a Judgment, Validity of a Proof&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1987&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Philosophical implications of type theory (Lectures given at the Facoltà di Lettere e Filosofia, Universitá degli Studi di Firenze, Florence, March 15th - May 15th, Privately circulated notes)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1987&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Mathematics-of-Infinity.pdf&#34;&gt;Mathematics of Infinity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/A-path-from-logic-to-metaphysics-1990-typescript.pdf&#34;&gt;A path from logic to metaphysics (typescript)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1990&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/A-path-from-logic-to-metaphysics-1991.pdf&#34;&gt;A path from logic to metaphysics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1991&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Substitution-calculus-1992.pdf&#34;&gt;Substitution calculus&lt;/a&gt; (Notes from a lecture given in Göteborg)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1992&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Martin-Lof-Analytic-and-Synthetic-Judgements-in-Type-Theory.pdf&#34;&gt;Analytic and Synthetic Judgements in Type Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1994&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Truth-and-Knowability-On-the-Principles-C-and-K-of-Michael-Dummett-1998.pdf&#34;&gt;Truth and Knowability: On the Principles C and K of Michael Dummett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Hilbert-Brouwer-Controversy-Resolved-2008.pdf&#34;&gt;Hilbert Brouwer Controversy Resolved?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2008&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Are-the-objects-of-propositional-attitudes-propositions-in-the-sense-of-propositional-and-predicate-logic-2003.pdf&#34;&gt;Are the objects of propositional attitudes propositions in the sense of propositional and predicate logic?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2003&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Normalization by Evaluation and by the Method of Computability (Talk at JAIST, Kanazawa)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2004&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/One-hundred-years-of-Zermelo-s-axiom-of-choice-what-was-the-problem-with-it-2009.pdf&#34;&gt;One hundred years of Zermelo&#39;s axiom of choice. What was the problem with it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2009&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/michaelt/martin-lof/master/pdfs/Martin-Lof-Verificationism-Then-and-Now-2013.pdf&#34;&gt;Verificationism Then and Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.portal.chalmers.se/cse/pmwiki.php/ProgLog/TypeTheoryAndFormalizationOfMathematics&#34;&gt;Making sense of normalization by evaluation&lt;/a&gt; (Talk given at a workshop on Type theory and formalization of mathematics in Gothenburg, December 11th)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>