<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-08T01:49:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>chenyk1990/reproducible_research</title>
    <updated>2023-06-08T01:49:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-08:/chenyk1990/reproducible_research</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/chenyk1990/reproducible_research" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web versions of these reproducible papers (mostly based on the Madagascar platform: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ahay.org&#34;&gt;www.ahay.org&lt;/a&gt;) are at&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ahay.org/wiki/Reproducible_Documents&#34;&gt;http://www.ahay.org/wiki/Reproducible_Documents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One can access the contents of the papers quickly by searching for the title and author names of each paper in this website.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in a particular paper, for example, reproducible_research/drr3d, you can use the following command (first install subversion in a Linux computer) to download it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;svn co &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chenyk1990/reproducible_research/trunk/drr3d&#34;&gt;https://github.com/chenyk1990/reproducible_research/trunk/drr3d&lt;/a&gt; ./drr3d&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All sub-directories except for &#34;nonMada&#34; correspond to the reproducible packages (for each paper) based on Madagascar, which means that you can use one command &#34;sftour scons lock &amp;amp;&amp;amp; scons paper.pdf&#34; in these sub-directories to reproducible the whole paper in the PDF format.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &#34;nonMada&#34; sub-directory contains reproducible packages that are not based on Madagascar, e.g., based on Matlab, python, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTES&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;sub-directories containing &#34;matfun&#34; require the Matlab-Madagascar interface (to do that, try ./configure API=c++,matlab --prefix=&lt;del&gt;/RSFROOT; scons install -k; add &#34;&lt;/del&gt;/RSFROOT/lib&#34; into the Matlab path directories by &#34;addpath(genpath(&#39;~/RSFROOT/lib&#39;)); savepath;&#34;. The &#34;matfun&#34; directory contains all the Matlab scripts/subroutines to output the data for plotting in SConstruct.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Other sub-directories not containing &#34;matfun&#34; are all based on Madagascar commands and are reproducible after Madagascar is installed successfully.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;These compact reproducible packages only include the python (named as &#34;SConstruct&#34;) scripts that wrap up all the Linux/Madagascar commands, and necessary datasets. Most synthetic data are generated automatically from either &#34;python or matlab scripts&#34;. Small field datasets are also attached with these packages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All C programs that are used to compile the Madagascar commands can be found at &#34;&lt;del&gt;/RSFSRC/user/chenyk&#34; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/user/chenyk&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/user/chenyk&lt;/a&gt;), &#34;&lt;/del&gt;/RSFSRC/user&#34; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/user&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/user&lt;/a&gt;), &#34;&lt;del&gt;/RSFSRC/system&#34; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/system&#34;&gt;https://github.com/ahay/src/tree/master/system&lt;/a&gt;). All Madagascar Application programming interface (API) (written in C programs) can be found at &#34;&lt;/del&gt;/RSFSRC/api/c&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>srush/do-we-need-attention</title>
    <updated>2023-06-08T01:49:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-08:/srush/do-we-need-attention</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/srush/do-we-need-attention" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Do we need Attention?&lt;/h1&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>schoolofdevops/kubernetes-labguide</title>
    <updated>2023-06-08T01:49:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-08:/schoolofdevops/kubernetes-labguide</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/schoolofdevops/kubernetes-labguide" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes Lab Guide 2020&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Kubernetes Lab Guide&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Duration&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2-4 days&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Level&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Intermediate, Advanced&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Modules&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Flipped Class&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Customizable&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course follows a hands on workshop method and builds container orchestration skills on top of existing skills learnt in Docker Fundamentals. Participants learn how to built a production grade resilient, self healing infrastructure with kubernetes. They take the container images built earlier and deploy with the high availability, fault tolerance, scalability provided by kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Flipped Classroom Methodology&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course follows a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flipped_classroom&#34;&gt;Flipped Classroom&lt;/a&gt; methodology, a blended model where participants come prepared with understanding of concepts by going through video/online content. The class time is maximized to perform practical activities to apply the concepts learnt earlier. Practice activities include taking up a use case and solving it by applying the techniques, or performing nano projects etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make it successful, participants need to be prepared in advance, by going through the recommended pre class content to clear the concepts as well as by making sure their systems are prepared with all the software required, before the class. The pre class checklist given below can be handy for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Who is this for ?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This course is for someone who has already taken docker fundamentals course/has equivalent knowledge, and would like to learn how to extend it to &lt;strong&gt;orchestrate container&lt;/strong&gt; deployments at production scale with kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;Operations/Systems&lt;/strong&gt; personnel and would like to learn how scalable, fault tolerant and high available infrastructures are built on or off cloud to orchestrate container based deployments, this course it for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;developer&lt;/strong&gt; and would like to learn how to deploy your application stacks in production, on top of scalable, highly available and leverage features provided by kubernetes, this course is for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;QA&lt;/strong&gt;, and if your organization has a staging/QA environment built on kubernetes, and you would like to understand how to leverage it for setting up automated test workflow and learn the primitives offered by kubernetes, this course is for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You could be developer/operations personnel and be in charge of securing application infrastructure and setup auxiliary services such as monitoring, centralized logging etc. this course is for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Who is this not for ?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a &lt;strong&gt;advanced user of Kubernetes&lt;/strong&gt; already, this course is definitely not for you.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are looking to start with Kubernetes concepts, this course is not for you as it assumes basic understanding of Kubernetes and COEs. There is a free resource &lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes Quick Dive&lt;/strong&gt; which you should go through before attending this workshop.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are interested in learning docker/container orchestration on &lt;strong&gt;windows&lt;/strong&gt;, this course is not ideal for you as it focuses on linux containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you expect to learn a technology which is mainly driven through a &lt;strong&gt;GUI&lt;/strong&gt;, this course is not suitable for you. Using kubernetes requires you to write YAML specifications, use command line tools etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What will you do as part of this course ?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of this course you will,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Design a &lt;strong&gt;scalable, resilient, secure&lt;/strong&gt; solution for deploying microservices application stack in production using primitives offered by kubernetes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install and configure a simple(non HA) multi node kubernetes cluster with &lt;strong&gt;kubeadm&lt;/strong&gt;. You would also have a conceptual understanding of how to build a production quality cluster with high availability, scalability, redundancy and security considerations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Learn how applications from a microservices stack interconnect with &lt;strong&gt;services&lt;/strong&gt; as well as expose public facing services with various options including nodeport, externalIP, ingress etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Achieve &lt;strong&gt;Continuous Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; with different release strategies such as &lt;strong&gt;Zero Downtime, Blue/Green, Canary&lt;/strong&gt; etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Learn how to manage &lt;strong&gt;persistent storage&lt;/strong&gt; in a kubernetes environment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Learn about the network primitives including &lt;strong&gt;CNI&lt;/strong&gt; plugins, service networking and iptables, ingress etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deploy an application which is auto scalable, high available, and resilient to failures.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is not covered ?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though this course covers many concepts related to kubernetes, since its a very vast topic, it still has the following areas uncovered.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Advanced RBAC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cloud specific provisioning and integration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HA deployment of a kubernetes cluster with multi masters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In depth kubernetes administration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Writing Microservices Applications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alternate container runtimes e.g. rocker/rkt, runc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Pre Requisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following are the pre requisite skills to attend this course. Since its a beginner level course, no prior experience with linux containers is assumed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Courses&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have attended the following course, or have demonstrable knowledge with the topics included in the following course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Docker Fundamentals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pre Assessment test will be conducted at the beginning of the course to asses the skills.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Skills&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker Basics&lt;/strong&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Running Containers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Building Images and writing Dockerfiles&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Docker Compose&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Docker Networking and Storage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linux/Unix Systems Fundamentals&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Command Line Interface (&lt;strong&gt;CLI&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fundamental knowledge of editors on linux (any one of vi/nano/emacs)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Understanding of &lt;strong&gt;YAML&lt;/strong&gt; syntax and familiarity with reading/writing basic YAML specifications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Hardware and Software Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the prerequisites for each attendee.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hardware Requirements&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Software Requirements&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Laptop/Desktop with high speed internet connection&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Base Operating System : Windows / Mac OSX&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8 GB RAM&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 CPU Cores&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;20 GB Disk Space available&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ConEmu (Windows Only)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Git for Windows (windows only)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lab Setup : Instructions can be found at xxx&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Supporting Content/Materials&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following is the supporting material which will be provided to you before/during the course&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Slides (online)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Workshop (online link)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Video Course - XXX by School of Devops&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Pre Class Checklist&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All participants should have completed the following checklist before attending the course .&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Successfully Completed &lt;strong&gt;Docker Fundamentals&lt;/strong&gt; Course, or have equivalent skills.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Verify your system meets the hardware pre requisites.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Validate the setup : verify all pre requisite software is installed on your system and is functional.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/schoolofdevops/Kubernetes?utm_source=share-link&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share-link&#34;&gt;kubernetes channel on gitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/schoolofdevops/course-outlines/raw/master/downloads/docker/kubernetes_bootcamp_checklist.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Pre Class Checklist&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Topics&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following are the topics which would be covered as part of this course. Detailed course outline follows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Design Workshop: Mapping Mogambo&#39;s Microservices Architecture to Kubernetes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Design Workshop: Production grade Kubernetes Architecture design&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup Kubernetes Cluster&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Advanced Pod Scheduling&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Publishing Applications with Services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Achieving Application High Availability and creating Release Strategies with Deployments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adding configurations with ConfigMaps and Secrets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto Scaling with Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Storage and persistence&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adding security with Network Policies&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional Topics if time permits&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional Controllers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Centralized Log Management&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cluster Maintenance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Detailed Course Outline&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the detailed course outline with day wise list of contents&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day I&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Introduction and Assessment&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trainer, Class and Course Introduction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pre-Assessment Test&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Formation of Groups: Group of 3/4 participants is formed. Each group will collectively come up with the solutions design, which is then discussed in the class, which is followed by the implementation of a common solution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Module 1: Design Workshop - Mapping Mogambo&#39;s Microservices Architecture to Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduction to the Use Case&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mogambo - The organization and the Application&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Architecture and Problem Statement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Design Workshop &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This is intended for the participants to come up with the strategy to deploy the application stack described with Kubernetes. Participants would come up with the structure of the code, map application deployment to kubernetes components e.g. deployments, services, ingress etc. and come up with the roadmap which is followed through rest of the workshop.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 2: Design Workshop: Production grade Kubernetes Architecture&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Specification of the problem statement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Design Workshop: This is a design workshop where each group formed earlier comes up with a sample design for a high available, fault tolerant, scalable and secure kubernetes cluster using all the primitives they have learnt as part of the pre course exercise. This is followed by a quick discussion/review.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 3: Setup and configure kubernetes Cluster&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup 2/3 nodes with VirtualBox/Vagrant/Cloud&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install kubernetes with kubeadm&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CNI Overview&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Network containers with CNI using weave/flannel/calico plugin&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure kubectl admin client&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup Kubernetes Dashboard&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Overview of kubernetes configurations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kubernetes RBAC overview - contexts, roles, serviceaccounts etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup a project/environment namespace and switch to it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 4: Advanced Pod Scheduling&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defining node/pod affinity and anti affinity&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adding health checks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Why and how to define pod resource limits&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Taints and tolerations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 5: Publishing Applications with Services&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Picking up the right type of a Service &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Cluster IP and DNS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;nodePort&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;externalIP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;loadbalancer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;headless services with Endpoints/ExternalNames&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Labels and Selectors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Service API Specs * Types * Traffic Policy * Selector&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Services vs Ingress&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Creating service resources for applications and backing services&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 6: Achieving Application High Availability and creating Release Strategies with Deployments&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deployments and/vs Replication Controllers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deployment API Specs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defining replication specs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defining Deployment Strategies &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Rolling Update&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Recreate&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Batch Size&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Deployment Operations &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Describe&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Rollouts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Rollbacks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Edit&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Pause/Unpause&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional Release Strategies &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Canary Relases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Blue/Green Deployments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Day II&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 7: Adding configurations with ConfigMaps and Secrets&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ConfigMaps and Secrets Specs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Injecting configurations as &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Environment Variables&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Distributing sensitive data with secrets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 8: Auto Scaling with Horizontal Pod Autoscaler (HPA)&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scaling deployments &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;manually&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;autoscaling&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HPA Specs &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Scaling metrics &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;default&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;custom&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setting up monitoring for kubernetes &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;heapster&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;influxdb&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;gragana&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Creating autoscaling configs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 9: Storage and Persistence&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Persistent Storage Concepts &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Storage Drivers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;PersistentVolumes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;PersistentVolumeClaims&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;StorageClass&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setting up a database with persistent volume&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Module 10: Securing with Network Policies&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Network Policy overview&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Network policy specs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defining network policy for the application stack&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Additional Topics if time permits&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Advanced Controllers&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;daemonSets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;statefulSets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;jobs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;crons&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Centralized Logging&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Centralized logging for kubernetes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setting up a ELK stack&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Cluster Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cluster Upgrade&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OS Upgrade&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Backups and Restore&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Badge: Kubernetes Champion&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Successful completion of this course along with the project work and an assessment at the end of this course would qualify you to receive a Docker Champion badge by School of Devops. This badge is compliant with &lt;a href=&#34;https://openbadges.org/&#34;&gt;Mozilla&#39;s Open Badge Standards&lt;/a&gt; and can be added to your social profiles (e.g. LinkedIn) and is verifiable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example of a badge is as follows,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/schoolofdevops/course-outlines/raw/master/downloads/docker/kubernetes_champion.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;Kubernetes Champion badge by School of Devops&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reading List&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here is the list of curated resources which you could refer to to learn about docker before the training and and get an in depth understanding post training.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Youtube Resources&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HlAXp0-M6SY&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Introduction by Kelsey Hightower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0Omvgd7Hg1I&#34;&gt;Life of a Packet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Video Courses&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://in.udacity.com/course/scalable-microservices-with-kubernetes--ud615&#34;&gt;Scalable Microservices with Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; by Carter Morgan, Kelsey Hightower, Gundega Dekena&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Safaribooks Online&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kubernetes Up and Running - Kelsey Hightower&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Tutorials&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/examples&#34;&gt;Application Example Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/tree/master/examples&#34;&gt;Application Stack Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes-bootcamp&#34;&gt;Official Kubernetes Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.alexellis.io/kubernetes-in-10-minutes/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes in 10 mins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kelseyhightower/kubernetes-the-hard-way&#34;&gt;Kubernetes the Hard Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hobby-kube/guide&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Cluster for the Hobbyist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>