<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-13T01:42:03Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>davidstutz/latex-resources</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:42:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/davidstutz/latex-resources</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/davidstutz/latex-resources" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Collection of LaTeX resources and examples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;LaTeX Resources&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository provides several examples and resources for LaTeX. All examples are tested using MikTeX &amp;gt;=2.9 on Windows 7 and on Ubuntu 12.04/14.04 using &lt;code&gt;texlive-full&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Citing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to cite this repository, use (make sure to fill in the right date!)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@misc{Stutz2022,&#xA;    author = {David Stutz},&#xA;    title = {Collection of LaTeX resources and examples},&#xA;    publisher = {GitHub},&#xA;    journal = {GitHub repository},&#xA;    howpublished = {\url{https://github.com/davidstutz/latex-resources}},&#xA;    note = {Accessed on MM.DD.YYYY}&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several examples have been taken from different places all over the world wide web. This is usually indicated by the corresponding URL within the source code or any copyright statements in file headers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All other examples are licensed under the BSD 3-Clause License:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2015-2022, David Stutz All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Neither the name of David Stutz nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &#34;AS IS&#34; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>glottolog/glottolog</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:42:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/glottolog/glottolog</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/glottolog/glottolog" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Collaborative data curation for Glottolog&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Glottolog Data Repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Glottolog data repository is the place where the data served by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://glottolog.org&#34;&gt;Glottolog web application&lt;/a&gt; is curated. But the repository also provides an alternative way to access Glottolog&#39;s data locally, and possibly even locally customized data by &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/fork-a-repo/&#34;&gt;forking&lt;/a&gt; glottolog/glottolog.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Accessing Glottolog data&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This repository&lt;/strong&gt; is the place where Glottolog data is curated. So it&#39;s the right place to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glottolog/glottolog/issues&#34;&gt;open issues&lt;/a&gt; about errors you identified and to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/glottolog/glottolog/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;propose changes&lt;/a&gt;. A clone of this repository is also the right thing if you need access to &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; of Glottolog&#39;s data, possibly including older versions and the history of changes. Since the format of the data here is tailored towards maintainability - and not towards accessibility - you might want to use the Python package &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glottolog/pyglottolog&#34;&gt;pyglottolog&lt;/a&gt; to access it programmatically.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://glottolog.org&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;glottolog.org&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - the Glottolog website - may be the most convenient place to inspect and browse the latest released version of Glottolog data. It also provides &lt;a href=&#34;https://glottolog.org/meta/downloads&#34;&gt;access to various download formats&lt;/a&gt;, tailored towards various re-use scenarios.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.3260727&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;glottolog as CLDF dataset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best option for accessing all of Glottolog&#39;s languoid data. Due to the format being &lt;a href=&#34;https://cldf.clld.org&#34;&gt;CLDF&lt;/a&gt;, it can be used from all kinds of programming environments such as spreadsheet programs, programming languages like R or python, or the UNIX shell. A description of the files in this datasets is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/glottolog/glottolog-cldf/raw/master/cldf/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How-to cite&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Only released versions of the Glottolog data should be cited. These releases are archived with and available from ZENODO at &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.596479&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.596479&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Types of data in Glottolog&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Languoids&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data about Glottolog languoids (languages, dialects or sub-groups, aka families) is stored in text files (one per languoid) formatted as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/INI_file&#34;&gt;INI files&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;languoids/tree&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory. The directory tree mirrors the Glottolog classification of languages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Glottolog bibliography is curated as a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BibTeX&#34;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt; files in the &lt;code&gt;references/bibtex&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory, which are merged into a single reference database for each release/edition.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Metadata&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metadata - e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Controlled_vocabulary&#34;&gt;controlled vocabularies&lt;/a&gt; for some of the languoid data - are stored as INI files in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/glottolog/glottolog/master/config/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; subdirectory.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Adamnite/Technical-Paper</title>
    <updated>2022-11-13T01:42:03Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-13:/Adamnite/Technical-Paper</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Adamnite/Technical-Paper" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository contains Adamnite&#39;s technical paper. This is analogous to similar technical specifications (namely Ethereum&#39;s Yellow Paper), and contains a formal specification for the Adamnite Protocol. You can find Latex and PDF versions in the files above. The technical paper is still a work in progress and will be updated periodically as the…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Technical-Paper&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains Adamnite&#39;s technical paper. This is analogous to similar technical specifications (namely Ethereum&#39;s Yellow Paper), and contains a formal specification for the Adamnite Protocol. You can find Latex and PDF versions in the files above. The technical paper is still a &lt;strong&gt;work in progress&lt;/strong&gt; and will be updated periodically as the Adamnite Protocol evolves. Namely, a thorough appendix that provides additional context for the specifications described in the paper will be added, and additional details on Adamnite&#39;s programming environment will be added once it has become more formalized. The Adamnite community can expect these changes to be implemented throughout the remainder of 2022 and onward. However, we maintain that the core ideas and formalizations in this work will remain consistient throughout the development of the Adamnite protocol. This is a public work under the Creative Commons licence.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of August 15, 2022, the current version is Version 1. Version 1.1 will include additional changes and clarifications in the appendix for Adamnite&#39;s protocol, paricularly with regards to the execution model and virutal machine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>