<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-07T01:50:59Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-113-Spring-2023/wc04</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T01:50:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-07:/CS-113-Spring-2023/wc04</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-113-Spring-2023/wc04" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Weekly Challenge 04: Logical Inference&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2023&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weekly challenges (WC) invite you to critically engage with the topics covered up to that week. They may take on a variety of formats and be available and attempted through diverse platforms as the semester progresses. They may be attempted individually or in teams as indicated. If in teams, the intention is for the buddies to discuss the solution among themselves, rather than splitting the tasks among themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This WC provides practice on deduction using rules of inference. You may need to spend a good amount of time thinking about the problems and it is unlikely that you will arrive at a solution in a single sitting. Start discussing the problem with your buddy early.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit the task you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to identify atomic propositions in an argument&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to symbolically represent an argument given in natural language&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to apply rules of inference&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to apply deductive reasoning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the time and persistence to think over the problem&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task and Submission&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this WC is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file. Make sure to include any supporting files needed for successful compilation. The same file at the time of the submission deadline will be taken to be your submission.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The score earned by your submission will be assigned to the team assuming that the buddies contributed equally. To confirm, teams will be occasionally called in for a viva on their submission. If any of the members is unable to explain the submission or does not appear for the scheduled viva, &lt;em&gt;the team&lt;/em&gt; will lose marks not only for that WC but for previous WCs in which they were awarded marks based on trust. You are encouraged to report non-contributing buddies through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hulms.instructure.com/courses/2619/quizzes/7186&#34;&gt;appropriate form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deadline&lt;/em&gt;: 2359h on Sun, 5 Feb&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the WC, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tda-in-ml/tda-in-ml.github.io</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T01:50:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-07:/tda-in-ml/tda-in-ml.github.io</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tda-in-ml/tda-in-ml.github.io" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code for the website of the NeurIPS 2020 workshop on &#39;Topological Data Analysis and Beyond&#39;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Topological Data Analysis in Machine Learning (TDA in ML)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for the web page of our NeurIPS 2020 workshop on topological machine learning. Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://tda-in-ml.github.io&#34;&gt;tda-in-ml.github.io&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Licence&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The code of this theme is licensed under a BSD 3-Clause licence. Please see the file &lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt; for more information. The assets of this theme, i.e. all images and logos, are licensed under a &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0)&lt;/a&gt; licence. Please acknowledge either the authors (see &lt;code&gt;AUTHORS&lt;/code&gt; file) or this repository when re-using an asset.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>StarvingMarvin/talks</title>
    <updated>2023-02-07T01:50:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-07:/StarvingMarvin/talks</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/StarvingMarvin/talks" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Slides from the Scalability talk&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Collection of slides from various talks I gave.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>