<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-27T01:45:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>hoelzer/dfg</title>
    <updated>2023-06-27T01:45:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-27:/hoelzer/dfg</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hoelzer/dfg" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A LaTeX template for a basic DFG (Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, German Research Foundation) grant proposal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;LaTeX DFG template&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A LaTeX template for a basic DFG (Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, German Research Foundation) grant proposal. &lt;strong&gt;Attention&lt;/strong&gt;: you need &lt;code&gt;pdflatex&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;biber&lt;/code&gt; (not &lt;code&gt;bibtex&lt;/code&gt;) to compile the document. &lt;strong&gt;Last updated according to the DFG original template listed in the header of the compiled PDF file (or in the &lt;code&gt;*.tex&lt;/code&gt; files). Please check and open an issue if there are any updates to the original template not reflected here!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This template is based on the template of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emtpb/proposal_dfg&#34;&gt;Measurement Engineering Group&lt;/a&gt; and mimicks the RTF template and PDF guidelines provided by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dfg.de/foerderung/programme/einzelfoerderung/sachbeihilfe/formulare_merkblaetter/index.jsp&#34;&gt;DFG with a focus on a &#34;Sachbeihilfe&#34; grant&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nneuss&#34;&gt;@nneuss&lt;/a&gt; a German version is also available. Please use &lt;code&gt;dfg-german.tex&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;dfg.tex&lt;/code&gt; for the German version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dl1chb&#34;&gt;@dl1chb&lt;/a&gt; for better ToDo handling via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/todonotes&#34;&gt;todonotes package&lt;/a&gt; and updates of the template.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mank4&#34;&gt;@mank4&lt;/a&gt; for the implementation of a gantt chart and better handling of subsections for work packages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klb2/dfg-proposal-template&#34;&gt;@klb2&lt;/a&gt; for the implementation of consecutive section numbers for 1.2.1 and 1.2.2. &lt;em&gt;Deprecated&lt;/em&gt; since DFG template version 54.01 09/22 where references are only listed in Section 3.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gituser789&#34;&gt;@gituser789&lt;/a&gt; for the implementation of an own literature feature with separate numbering.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kss-lea&#34;&gt;@kss-lea&lt;/a&gt; for adding separate numbering formats for the first and second (supplement) part.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please let me know if I accidentally forgot a contribution! Thanks all contributors!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compilation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pdflatex&#xA;biber&#xA;pdflatex&#xA;pdflatex&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also change the filename of the &lt;code&gt;${NAME}.tex&lt;/code&gt; file and then run &lt;code&gt;make filename=${NAME}&lt;/code&gt; (thx &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dl1chb&#34;&gt;@dl1chb&lt;/a&gt;). For example, to compile the German version:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;make filename=dfg-german&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Biber&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do not have &lt;code&gt;biber&lt;/code&gt; installed try to install it from the package sources of your system. There is also a &lt;code&gt;conda&lt;/code&gt; install that you can try:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;conda create -n biber -c malramsay biber &#xA;conda activate biber&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also use a Docker container that comes with all dependencies (pdflatex, biber, ...) to compile the template. Thus, no installation of LaTeX, Biber, etc... is needed on your local system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;DOCKER=&#39;nanozoo/pdflatex:3.14159265--6263fbd&#39;&#xA;docker pull $DOCKER&#xA;&#xA;# using the Makefile&#xA;docker run --rm -v $PWD:$PWD -w $PWD $DOCKER make&#xA;&#xA;# using pdflatex, biber, ... &#xA;docker run --rm -v $PWD:$PWD -w $PWD $DOCKER pdflatex dfg.tex&#xA;docker run --rm -v $PWD:$PWD -w $PWD $DOCKER biber dfg&#xA;...&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Optional content&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The template implements some stuff that is not required by the original DFG template (or even needs to be removed when submitting to DFG). This includes a nice title page, as well as sections for a Signature and a List of Attachements. The LaTeX code is still available, just uncomment in the respective &lt;code&gt;dfg.tex&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;dfg-german.tex&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;ToDo-Notes, reference labels and draft mode&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, ToDos and labels are activated (see below) which is considered the &lt;em&gt;draft&lt;/em&gt; mode of the template. To turn both of them off (e.g. for the final version) just change &lt;code&gt;\setboolean{finalcompile}{false}&lt;/code&gt; in dfg.tex to &lt;code&gt;\setboolean{finalcompile}{true}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ToDos are activated by default using the &lt;code&gt;todonotes&lt;/code&gt; package. You can see it working by looking at the &lt;code&gt;\todo[inline]{foo}&lt;/code&gt; statements in the text. It is self-explaining.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition you will see some labels at the margins. These are caused by another plugin which will just print the name of the label stated in &lt;code&gt;\label{}&lt;/code&gt;. This can help by referencing sections and stuff.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Customization&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of customization (citation style, etc.) can be done by changes in the &lt;code&gt;proposal.sty&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deprecated since DFG template version 54.01 09/22. All literature is listed in Section 3 now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add references to different parts of the proposal, you can define categories:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;\DeclareBibliographyCategory{reviewed}&#xA;\addtocategory{reviewed}{Hoelzer:16}&#xA;&#xA;that can be later used in the sections:&#xA;&#xA;```latex&#xA;\printbibliography[category=reviewed, heading=none]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the DFG changed their template to have references in the sections 1.2.1 and 1.2.2 sorted consecutively. For other references in the bibliography, it seems that one can arrange them alphabetically. This was solved by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klb2/dfg-proposal-template&#34;&gt;@klb2&lt;/a&gt; and changes were also included in this repo (thx!). The current default is numeric labels while first the references in sections 1.2.1 and 1.2.2 are numbered followed by all other references in the order how they appear in the text. Changes can be done via the &lt;code&gt;proposal.sty&lt;/code&gt; file. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gituser789&#34;&gt;@gituser789&lt;/a&gt; also implemented a feature to number own references and all other references independently. This is activated by default and will add an &#39;O&#39; or &#39;E&#39; prefix to own (&#34;eigene&#34;) literature in the english or german template, respectively. The user can change the prefix in the tex template. If you want to deactivate this feature, go to the tex template and comment/remove &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;\newrefcontext[labelprefix=]&lt;/code&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bib Style&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To change the style of your bibliography you have to change the following code snippet in the &lt;code&gt;proposal.sty&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;\usepackage[backend = biber,&#xA;    style = numeric, %numeric, alphabetic&#xA;    firstinits = true,&#xA;    natbib = true,&#xA;    hyperref = true,&#xA;    maxbibnames = 11, % number of authors shown&#xA;    sorting=none, % remove this to have things sorted, e.g. use style=alphabetic&#xA;    ]{biblatex}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sum up costs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The environment &lt;code&gt;funds&lt;/code&gt; can be used to automatically sum up all costs specified like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;\begin{funds}[funding for staff]&#xA;&#xA;\positionmul{Research associate, TV-L 13, 36 months}{5375}{36}&#xA;\positionmul{Student assistant, TV-L 13, 12 months}{450}{12}&#xA;&#xA;\end{funds}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Gantt chart&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will find a &lt;code&gt;gantt/gantt.tex&lt;/code&gt; file that can be modified directly to include a gantt chart in your proposal.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I used this template for an actual proposal submission in 2019 to the DFG that was accepted and send out for review (unfortunately, not accepted in the end).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use this template and receive a confirmation, please let me know and I will be happy to reference your successful application here! :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, please be aware that since May 2020 the proposal is split into a more research focused part (sections 1-3, max. 17 pages) and all the supplementary information (starting section 4, max. 8 pages). Please also always check if there are any changes to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dfg.de/foerderung/programme/einzelfoerderung/sachbeihilfe/formulare_merkblaetter/index.jsp&#34;&gt;DFG template&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>