<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-01T01:39:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset04</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T01:39:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-01:/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset04</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset04" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Problem Set 04: Predicates, Quantifiers, and Nested Quantifiers&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2024&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Problem Set (PSet) contains problems on recently covered material for you to practice. These prepare you for upcoming assessments and later topics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This PSet provides practice in predicates and quantifiers, including nested quantifiers, i.e. Sections 1.4 and 1.5.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background and requirement&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit this PSet you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to know the universal and existential quantifiers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to be able to define domains for the variables of a quantifier&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to be able to express natural language and mathematical statements in logical syntax and vice versa&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to apply a quantified statement over a given domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to evaluate the truth value of a quantified statement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to express the negation of a quantified statement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to find counterexamples to universally quantified statements&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to apply methods to determine the equivalence of two quantified statements involving predicates and connectives&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grading is described on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this PSet is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deadline is mentioned on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the PSet, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc04</title>
    <updated>2024-02-01T01:39:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-01:/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc04</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc04" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Weekly Challenge 04: Predicates and Quantifiers&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2024&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Weekly Challenge (WC) invites you to critically engage with the topics covered up to that week. They may take on a variety of formats and be available and attempted through diverse platforms as the semester progresses. They may be attempted individually or in teams as indicated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This WC explores equivalences between some standard statements involving predicates and quantifiers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background and Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit the task you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to understand quantified statements over a domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to be able to evaluate quantified statements over a domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to infer a logical connective from the truth values of its atomic and compound propositions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the willingness to work through the LaTeX source&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grading is as per the rubric shared on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this WC is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deadline is mentioned on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the WC, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>