<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-08-14T01:42:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>monero-project/research-lab</title>
    <updated>2025-08-14T01:42:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-08-14:/monero-project/research-lab</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/monero-project/research-lab" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A general repo for Monero Research Lab work in progress and completed work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Monero Research Lab&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2014-2018, The Monero Project&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Research Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Web: &lt;a href=&#34;https://getmonero.org&#34;&gt;getmonero.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Forum: &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.getmonero.org&#34;&gt;forum.getmonero.org&lt;/a&gt; IRC on Freenode:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webchat.freenode.net/?randomnick=1&amp;amp;channels=%23monero-research-lab&amp;amp;prompt=1&amp;amp;uio=d4&#34;&gt;#monero-research-lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webchat.freenode.net/?randomnick=1&amp;amp;channels=%23monero-dev&amp;amp;prompt=1&amp;amp;uio=d4&#34;&gt;#monero-dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://webchat.freenode.net/?randomnick=1&amp;amp;channels=%23kovri-dev&amp;amp;prompt=1&amp;amp;uio=d4&#34;&gt;#kovri-dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Vulnerability Response&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/monero-project/meta/raw/master/VULNERABILITY_RESPONSE_PROCESS.md&#34;&gt;Vulnerability Response Process&lt;/a&gt; encourages responsible disclosure&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We are also available via &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackerone.com/monero&#34;&gt;HackerOne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About this Project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Research activities performed by members of the Monero Research Lab, and others, are stored here to make collaboration easy, and to allow for other researchers to pick up where someone leaves off.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is covered by the BSD 3-clause license as listed below. Contributors are welcome and warmly invited, but are expected to work in their own forks before submitting pull requests to this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Source Code and Concept License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2014-2017, The Monero Project&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Neither the name of the copyright holder nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &#34;AS IS&#34; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>