<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-20T01:51:27Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook</title>
    <updated>2023-06-20T01:51:27Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-20:/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Textbook created for Harvard&#39;s undergraduate course in Machine Learning, CS181.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Current Version&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A current version of the textbook is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook/raw/master/Textbook.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Build info&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;code&gt;pdflatex&lt;/code&gt; on your machine, then from the &lt;code&gt;master/&lt;/code&gt; directory, run &lt;code&gt;pdflatex master.tex&lt;/code&gt; (which will output the compiled pdf at master.pdf).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Errors, Requests for Further Explanation, and Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Errors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the course of using this textbook, you may come upon small derivational errors or typos. If you notice one of these, please make an issue and tag it with the &lt;code&gt;Error&lt;/code&gt; label, as in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook/issues/1&#34;&gt;example issue&lt;/a&gt;. Please be sure to note where the error is (chapter and page number).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Requests for Further Explanation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There may be topics that are confusing or given insufficient treatment. If you feel this is the case, please make an issue and tag it with the &lt;code&gt;Request for Explanation&lt;/code&gt; label, as in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook/issues/2&#34;&gt;example issue&lt;/a&gt;. Please be sure to indicate the chapter, page, and topic for which you are requesting further explanation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you make an issue for an error or a request for further explanation, you may also wish to fix that problem yourself! If you choose to do this, please make your changes on a new branch off of &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, make a pull request from that new branch back into &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, and reference the issue number in the PR, as in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/harvard-ml-courses/cs181-textbook/pull/3&#34;&gt;example PR&lt;/a&gt;. Please do not commit the compiled PDF after making your changes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>