<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-15T01:56:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>AllenDowney/ThinkDataStructures</title>
    <updated>2022-06-15T01:56:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-15:/AllenDowney/ThinkDataStructures</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AllenDowney/ThinkDataStructures" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LaTeX source and supporting code for Think Data Structures: Algorithms and Information Retrieval in Java&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ThinkDataStructures&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX source and supporting code for &lt;em&gt;Think Data Structures: Algorithms and Information Retrieval in Java&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data structures and algorithms are among the most important inventions of the last 50 years, and they are fundamental tools software engineers need to know. But in my opinion, most of the books on these topics are too theoretical, too big, and too bottom-up:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Too theoretical: Mathematical analysis of algorithms is based on simplifying assumptions that limit its usefulness in practice. Many presentations of this topic gloss over the simplifications and focus on the math. In this book I present the most practical subset of this material and eliminate the rest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Too big: Most books on these topics are at least 500 pages, and some are more than 1000. By focusing on the topics I think are most useful for software engineers, I kept this book under 250 pages.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Too bottom-up: Many data structures books focus on how data structures work (the implementations), with less about how to use them (the interfaces). In this book, I go ``top down&#39;&#39;, starting with the interfaces. Readers learn to use the structures in the Java Collections Framework before getting into the details of how they work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, many present this material out of context and without motivation: it&#39;s just one damn data structure after another!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I try to alleviate the boredom by organizing the topics around an application -- web search -- that uses data structures extensively, and is an interesting and important topic in its own right.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This application also motivates some topics that are not usually covered in an introductory data structures class, including persistent data structures, with Redis, and streaming algorithms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have made difficult decisions about what to leave out, but I have made some compromises. I include a few topics that most readers will never use, but that they might be expected to know, possibly in a technical interview. For these topics, I present both the conventional wisdom as well as my reasons to be skeptical.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book also presents basic aspects of software engineering practice, including version control and unit testing. Each chapter ends with an exercise that allows readers to apply what they have learned. Each exercise includes automated tests that check the solution. And for most exercises, I present my solution at the beginning of the next chapter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is intended for college students in computer science and related fields, as well as professional software engineers, people training in software engineering, and people preparing for technical interviews.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I assume that the reader knows Java at an intermediate level, but I explain some Java features along the way, and provide pointers to supplementary material.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;People who have read &lt;em&gt;Think Java&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Head First Java&lt;/em&gt; are prepared for this book.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet</title>
    <updated>2022-06-15T01:56:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-15:/aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A helpful 5-page machine learning cheatsheet to assist with exam reviews, interview prep, and anything in-between.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Data Science Cheatsheet 2.0&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A helpful 5-page data science cheatsheet to assist with exam reviews, interview prep, and anything in-between. It covers over a semester of introductory machine learning, and is based on MIT&#39;s Machine Learning courses 6.867 and 15.072. The reader should have at least a basic understanding of statistics and linear algebra, though beginners may find this resource helpful as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Maverick&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Data Science Cheatsheet&lt;/em&gt; (hence the 2.0 in the name), located &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ml874/Data-Science-Cheatsheet&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Linear and Logistic Regression&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Decision Trees and Random Forest&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SVM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;K-Nearest Neighbors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clustering&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Boosting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dimension Reduction (PCA, LDA, Factor Analysis)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Natural Language Processing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Neural Networks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Recommender Systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reinforcement Learning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Anomaly Detection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Time Series&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A/B Testing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This cheatsheet will be occasionally updated with new/improved info, so consider a follow or star to stay up to date.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Future additions (ideas welcome):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Time Series&lt;/del&gt; Added!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Statistics and Probability&lt;/del&gt; Added!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Data Imputation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generative Adversarial Networks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Graph Neural Networks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet/raw/main/Data_Science_Cheatsheet.pdf&#34;&gt;Data Science Cheatsheet 2.0 PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are screenshots of a couple pages - the link to the full cheatsheet is above!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet/main/images/page1-1.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aaronwangy/Data-Science-Cheatsheet/main/images/page2-1.png?raw=true&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why is Python/SQL not covered in this cheatsheet?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I planned for this resource to cover mainly algorithms, models, and concepts, as these rarely change and are common throughout industries. Technical languages and data structures often vary by job function, and refreshing these skills may make more sense on keyboard than on paper.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to share this resource in classes, review sessions, or to anyone who might find it helpful :)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under the &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc-sa/4.0/88x31.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Images are used for educational purposes, created by me, or borrowed from my colleagues &lt;a href=&#34;https://stanford.edu/~shervine/teaching/cs-229/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to suggest comments, updates, and potential improvements!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/axw/&#34;&gt;Aaron Wang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to support this cheatsheet, you can buy me a coffee &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.me/aaxw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>gpoore/minted</title>
    <updated>2022-06-15T01:56:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-15:/gpoore/minted</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/gpoore/minted" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;minted is a LaTeX package that provides syntax highlighting using the Pygments library. Highlighted source code can be customized using fancyvrb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://flattr.com/submit/auto?user_id=gpoore&amp;amp;url=https://github.com/gpoore/minted&amp;amp;title=minted&amp;amp;category=software&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.flattr.com/button/flattr-badge-large.png&#34; alt=&#34;flattr&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;minted — highlighted source code for LaTeX&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;minted&lt;/code&gt; is a LaTeX package that facilitates expressive syntax highlighting using the Pygments library. The package also provides options to customize the highlighted source code output using &lt;code&gt;fancyvrb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, this code:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34;&gt;\begin{minted}[mathescape,&#xA;               linenos,&#xA;               numbersep=5pt,&#xA;               gobble=2,&#xA;               frame=lines,&#xA;               framesep=2mm]{csharp}&#xA;string title = &#34;This is a Unicode π in the sky&#34;&#xA;/*&#xA;Defined as $\pi=\lim_{n\to\infty}\frac{P_n}{d}$ where $P$ is the perimeter&#xA;of an $n$-sided regular polygon circumscribing a&#xA;circle of diameter $d$.&#xA;*/&#xA;const double pi = 3.1415926535&#xA;\end{minted}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;will produce the following rendering:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.stack.imgur.com/OLUjl.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gpoore/minted/raw/master/source/minted.pdf&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for examples and installation instructions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Availability&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;minted&lt;/code&gt; is distributed with both TeX Live and MiKTeX. It is also available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctan.org/pkg/minted&#34;&gt;CTAN&lt;/a&gt;. In any case, &lt;a href=&#34;http://python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pygments.org/download/&#34;&gt;Pygments&lt;/a&gt; need to be installed separately.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work may be distributed and/or modified under the conditions of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.latex-project.org/lppl.txt&#34;&gt;LaTeX Project Public License&lt;/a&gt; (LPPL), version 1.3 or later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the project may be distributed under the terms of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://opensource.org/licenses/BSD-3-Clause&#34;&gt;3-Clause (&#34;New&#34;) BSD license&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please use the project&#39;s GitHub site at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gpoore/minted&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gpoore/minted&lt;/a&gt; for suggestions, feature requests, and bug reports.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>