<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-14T01:33:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics</title>
    <updated>2024-05-14T01:33:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-14:/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Better Informatics. The student run website for students in the School of Informatics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Better Informatics&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Add files to one of these folders: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/start&#34;&gt;start&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/inf1&#34;&gt;inf1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/inf2&#34;&gt;inf2&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/inf3&#34;&gt;inf3&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/inf4&#34;&gt;inf4&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections/masters&#34;&gt;masters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Guidelines for contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In order to contribute you will need GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you would like to make a major change, or a change to the overall visual design, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/issues/new&#34;&gt;submit an issue&lt;/a&gt; with your idea proposal first.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Most of the content right now is in the &lt;code&gt;_sections&lt;/code&gt; directory, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/betterinformatics/tree/master/_sections&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; to view the list of sections to edit.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pull requests are accepted, but we encourage you to create an issue to add your GitHub username to the whitelist. Then you can edit this repository yourself (you don&#39;t have to send a PR!) &lt;strong&gt;We trust you!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trust by default.&lt;/em&gt; No pull requests, no &#34;approvals&#34;, just contribute!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Why? To reduce the barrier to entry and to make it so that you can feel like adding whatever you want to add.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maintain history.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Why? Over time we accumulate a lot of knowledge and resources. We shouldn&#39;t lose it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;History also tends to repeat itself (inf1a split into two courses, and merged back into one course)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Avoid deleting courses, just archive them. Sometimes these courses will come back!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share ownership.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t put things in your personal workspace, you won&#39;t be around forever!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every little helps.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Found a page that explained something really well? Add it here, and others will benefit too!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Systems&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two main sources of Information on Better Informatics which are integral:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GitHub: contains the knowledgebase and links &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It means that the timeless content is backed up somewhere on a familiar, easy to use platform (GitHub)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The content is not vendor lock-in. It&#39;s just a Git repo!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Full history is maintained and there&#39;s a standard Git interface to the content.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It&#39;s renderable (using Jekyll) to &lt;a href=&#34;https://betterinformatics.com&#34;&gt;betterinformatics.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;File Collection: contains past papers solutions &amp;amp; other useful documents &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A web service hosted on Tardis infrastructure, dedicated to study collaboration and sharing documents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Displays snippets from this GitHub repo as embedded knowledgebase articles&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.betterinformatics.com&#34;&gt;files.betterinformatics.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Feature requests and contributions to the service itself is accepted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.tardisproject.uk/betterinformatics/edinburgh-community-solutions&#34;&gt;our repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have a third source, which is being phased out and gradually migrated to File Collection where suitable:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Google Shared Drive: contains past paper solutions &amp;amp; other useful documents &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You need to be added to a separate whitelist using your Gmail address to access this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For reasons of the migration to File Collection and how you can help out, see the FAQ in File Collection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other services we have at Better Informatics include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/mapp&#34;&gt;The Marauders App&lt;/a&gt;: an effort to create an interactive map of all university lab machines &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Currently offline, seeking contributors to try to revive it again&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/bi-app/tree/master/courses.yaml&#34;&gt;The Course List Generator&lt;/a&gt;: a script to generate courses.yaml &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Runs every day on this repo&#39;s CI, generating an API of currently-running Informatics courses &lt;a href=&#34;https://betterinformatics.com/courses.json&#34;&gt;available here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Feel free to hack on this API and make interesting projects!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/compsoc-edinburgh/bi-welcome&#34;&gt;Virtual Welcome Pack&lt;/a&gt;: interactive new-student guide &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Runs at welcome.betterinformatics.com&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Originally a student&#39;s undergraduate project, but is now open to contributions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Any project ideas? Feel free to build it and maybe incorporate it into Better Informatics!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Previously (pre-2020) the Better Informatics Jekyll page was hosted on Tardis, and offered some server-side code for automatic addition to Google Drive etc. After Tardis was temporarily shut down while it migrated to a new infrastructure, the Jekyll page has been hosted on GitHub Pages infrastructure with no moving parts (so you might see some code/text that mentions the previous infra -- feel free to update it!).&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Design Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change can be good, but it&#39;s really important not to alienate users. Students are lazy and if it&#39;s hard to find something, they might not bother to find it, especially if they don&#39;t know it exists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An attempt is made to generally stick to the website design originally created in 2012.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do you merge courses?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes two courses become one course. There&#39;s two things you can do.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 1: still keep the cards separate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;2018/19&lt;/em&gt;, when &lt;strong&gt;Informatics 1: Functional Programming (INF1-FP)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Informatics 1: Computation and Logic (INF1-CL)&lt;/strong&gt; merged to become &lt;strong&gt;Informatics 1: Introduction to Computation&lt;/strong&gt;, we just kept them as separate sections in Better Informatics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We did this because even though administratively (system-wise) the course was one course; the lecturers remained distinct, with separate lectures, labs and tutorials.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is OK, because even newer students that never saw INF1-FP and INF1-CL still refer to each half of the course as FP and CL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example 2: actually merge the cards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;2019/20&lt;/em&gt;, when &lt;strong&gt;Computer Architecture (CAR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Computer Design (CD)&lt;/strong&gt; merged to become &lt;strong&gt;Computer Architecture and Design (CARD)&lt;/strong&gt;, we chose to merge them into one section.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is because these two courses were truly merged together to form a new course. (Well, at least qaisjp hopes this is the case.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s worth noting that in this case the lecturers from both courses are now running &lt;strong&gt;CARD&lt;/strong&gt;, which is similar to how the lecturers shared the course in Example 1 (INF1A).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the course content is hidden on Learn to those not taking the course. So qaisjp can&#39;t actually check if they are distinct.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usually actually merging the cards together is the best option. The code doesn&#39;t get confused, and neither do users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To actually merge two files into one, it&#39;s worth referring to this Git article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20190514-00/?p=102493&#34;&gt;Stupid git tricks: Combining two files into one while preserving line history&lt;/a&gt;. This way history is maintained!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>