<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-18T01:44:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tomdjong/MGS-domain-theory</title>
    <updated>2023-03-18T01:44:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-18:/tomdjong/MGS-domain-theory</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tomdjong/MGS-domain-theory" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lecture notes and exercises for the introductory course on domain theory and denotational semantics at the Midlands Graduate School (MGS) 2023&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Domain theory and denotational semantics&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lecture notes with exercises for the introductory course on &lt;em&gt;domain theory and denotational semantics&lt;/em&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.bham.ac.uk/~mhe/events/MGS23/&#34;&gt;Midlands Graduate School (MGS) 2023&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Under active development.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Denotational semantics aims to understand computer programmes by assigning mathematical meaning to the syntax of a programming language. In this course we will study a simple functional programming language called PCF. Notably, this language has general recursion through a fixed point operator. This means a simple denotational semantics based on sets is not suitable. Instead, we interpret the types of PCF as certain partially ordered sets leading to domain theory and Scott&#39;s model of PCF in particular. The central theorems of soundness and computational adequacy, formulated and proved by Plotkin, then tell us that a PCF programme computes to a value if and only if their interpretations in the model are equal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Links to the notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notes are available in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tomdjong/MGS-domain-theory/releases/latest/download/MGS-domain-theory.pdf&#34;&gt;full colour&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tomdjong/MGS-domain-theory/releases/latest/download/MGS-domain-theory_no-colour.pdf&#34;&gt;black and white&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>