<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-19T01:42:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Estheryu991/Analysis</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T01:42:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-19:/Estheryu991/Analysis</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Estheryu991/Analysis" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Simply theories and excercises in Analysis I.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Analysis_I&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply theories and excercises in Analysis I.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://polybox.ethz.ch/index.php/s/9RDWoQmMlU5Jhb1&#34;&gt;Polybox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://metaphor.ethz.ch/x/2022/fs/401-0212-16L/&#34;&gt;Menu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Analysis_II&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to git push and pull according to your own needs. ^^ Bitte zögern Sie nicht, Git nach Ihren eigenen Bedürfnissen zu drücken und zu ziehen. ^^&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ping me a message for contributions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>pelegs/maths_book</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T01:42:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-19:/pelegs/maths_book</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/pelegs/maths_book" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Planning for an entire maths LaTeX book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;A mathematics book for natural science students (i.e. not for mathematicians and engineers).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based on a course I gave in the University of Göttingen (Germany) in 2020 and 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jeremygibbs/nsf-proposal-latex</title>
    <updated>2022-09-19T01:42:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-19:/jeremygibbs/nsf-proposal-latex</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jeremygibbs/nsf-proposal-latex" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An NSF proposal template in LaTeX&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;NSF Proposal in LaTeX&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is your glass of water to the hell that is MS Word. Scientific proposals are daunting and compiling all of the required material is tedious. This goal of this LaTeX template is to construct a proposal according to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/pubs/policydocs/pappg22_1/nsf22_1.pdf&#34;&gt;National Science Foundation guidelines&lt;/a&gt; (as of October 2021). The template uses the reference styling of the American Meteorological Society. You can substitute your own style file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The end product is a visually consistent and beautiful proposal document. I cannot help you with the science, but I can help you present something that does not look like garbage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope that the template is helpful, but I cannot guarantee support for technical issues. Updates may be infrequent, so it is your responsibility to make sure that any document created using this template adheres to the NSF guidelines. However, feel free to submit pull requests and I will do my best to be responsive.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This template is free source code. It comes without any warranty, to the extent permitted by applicable law. You can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the Do What The Fuck You Want To Public License, Version 2, as published by Sam Hocevar. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wtfpl.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.wtfpl.net&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>