<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-04-08T01:40:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>oscarlevin/discrete-book</title>
    <updated>2025-04-08T01:40:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-04-08:/oscarlevin/discrete-book</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/oscarlevin/discrete-book" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open textbook for Discrete Mathematics, as taught at the University of Northern Colorado&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Discrete Mathematics: An Open Introduction&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An open textbook for Discrete Mathematics, as taught at the University of Northern Colorado. More information about the project is available on &lt;a href=&#34;http://discrete.openmathbooks.org&#34;&gt;the book&#39;s main website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch now has the source code for the 3rd edition. Work on the 4th edition is done on the &lt;code&gt;edition&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compilation instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This text is written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretextbook.org&#34;&gt;PreTeXt&lt;/a&gt;, so the primary source files can be found in the &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; directory. These can be compiled into HTML or PDF files (as well as some other formats) using the following directions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Preliminaries&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to build output formats from the source is to use the PreTeXt-CLI. To get this set up, follow the instructions in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretextbook.org/doc/guide/html/quickstart-getting-pretext.html&#34;&gt;PreTeXt guide&lt;/a&gt;. You will need Python, LaTeX, and &lt;code&gt;pdf2svg&lt;/code&gt; (if you wish to compile the html version; this requires an &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretextbook.org/doc/guide/html/section-installing-pdf2svg.html&#34;&gt;extra step&lt;/a&gt; on Windows).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open up a terminal and in your preferred directory, clone &lt;code&gt;discrete-book&lt;/code&gt; repositories:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/oscarlevin/discrete-book.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(If you had previously done this, you will likely want to get the most recent versions of the repository by entering &lt;code&gt;git pull&lt;/code&gt; from the discrete-book folder.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then change to the &lt;code&gt;discrete-book&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd discrete-book&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Compiling&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If everything has been set up properly above, you can now execute the following commands to build the book. To create a PDF, you can enter:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretext build pdf -w&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make the HTML version:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pretext build html -w -d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; flags are only needed the first time you compile, to extract the WeBWorK exercises and create SVGs for the images. Use the flags again only if you edit these elements in the source.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any and all suggestions to improve the text are welcome. Thanks to those who have already pointed out typos/issues they have found. If you would like to make a more substantial contribution, please contact me so we can discuss how best to proceed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Previous editions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The previous editions have branches, and also tags. Feel free to switch to those if you want to grab the source for those editions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>