<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-02T01:33:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>cpecmu/cpe-project-ex</title>
    <updated>2024-03-02T01:33:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-02:/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;example for CPECMU project report&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;cpecmu-report 0.2.1&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package provides a LaTeX document class for producing senior project reports at the Deparment of Computer Engineering, Chiang Mai University, using LaTeX 2e. You can use a sample report, in &#34;sampleReport.tex&#34;, as a template for writing your report.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To prepare your system for using this document, please install the following software as prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LaTeX distribution (e.g., MikTeX on Windows; TeXLive on MacOS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Perl programming language (e.g., ActiveState Perl on Windows; already installed on MacOS)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, make sure the following LaTeX packages are installed with your LaTeX distribution:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;latexmk&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fonts-tlwg&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fonts-arundina&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;tex-gyre&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;tex-gyre-math For MikTeX on Windows, these packages can be installed via the following command: miktex packages require latexmk fonts-tlwg fonts-arundina tex-gyre tex-gyre-math&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For TeXLive on Unix-based distributions, XeLaTeX will look for fonts in system installations even if your TeX distribution contains the packages above. To install these fonts in your system, install the following packages via apt:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fonts-thai-tlwg-otf&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fonts-arundina&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;tex-gyre&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;texlive-fonts-extra This can be done via the following command: sudo apt install fonts-thai-tlwg-otf fonts-arundina tex-gyre texlive-fonts-extra&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detailed (albeit still incomplete in places) documentation for the document class can be found in the file &#34;cpecmu.pdf&#34;. Please read this documentation if you run into any problems, because it explains how to deal with some common errors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways to build the sample report. If you have &#34;make&#34; available, you can type &#34;make&#34; to build the sample report. The supplied Makefile can be used as a starting point for building your own report.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sample report can also be built within Visual Studio Code. To get started, install the &#34;LaTeX Workshop&#34; extension, then add the following entry into &#34;settings.json&#34;: &#34;latex-workshop.latex.tools&#34;: [ { &#34;name&#34;: &#34;latexmk&#34;, &#34;command&#34;: &#34;latexmk&#34;, &#34;args&#34;: [ &#34;-pdfxe&#34;, &#34;-synctex=1&#34;, &#34;-interaction=nonstopmode&#34;, &#34;-file-line-error&#34;, &#34;%DOC%&#34; ] } ] See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/James-Yu/LaTeX-Workshop/wiki/Compile#latex-recipes&#34;&gt;https://github.com/James-Yu/LaTeX-Workshop/wiki/Compile#latex-recipes&lt;/a&gt; for details. This extension allows you to view the PDF file within Visual Studio Code. You can also use SyncTeX to navigate back and forth between source code and PDF output. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/James-Yu/LaTeX-Workshop/wiki/View&#34;&gt;https://github.com/James-Yu/LaTeX-Workshop/wiki/View&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This template and its related files, including the cpecmu document class, may be updated from time to time. To prepare your own report repository for additoinal changes, first clone this template: git clone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex.git&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex.git&lt;/a&gt; Next, create your own private, empty repository, and retarget the origin remote: git remote set-url origin &#xA; &lt;your-repo-remote-url&gt;&#xA;   Finally, add a remote to the template repository: git remote add template &#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex.git&#34;&gt;https://github.com/cpecmu/cpe-project-ex.git&lt;/a&gt; Then, to pull template changes, use this command: git pull template master Note that conflicts may occur at this point; you should check for changes to your own files and perform a merge appropriately before committing.&#xA; &lt;/your-repo-remote-url&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To avoid changes in the template from interfering with your own report, make a copy of sampleReport.tex and keep sampleReport.tex unchanged. cp sampleReport.tex &amp;lt;your-file-name.tex&amp;gt; Then, add the following entry into &#34;settings.json&#34;, under &#34;settings&#34; key: &#34;latex-workshop.latex.search.rootFiles.exclude&#34;: [&#34;**/sampleReport.tex&#34;]&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>