<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-11T01:39:17Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc05</title>
    <updated>2024-02-11T01:39:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-11:/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc05</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc05" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Weekly Challenge 05: Deduction&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2024&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Weekly Challenge (WC) invites you to critically engage with the topics covered up to that week. They may take on a variety of formats and be available and attempted through diverse platforms as the semester progresses. They may be attempted individually or in teams as indicated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This WC sets the ground for inference and deduction before we formally explore logical inference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background and Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit the task you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to understand statements in English&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to be able to infer information from provided clues&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the willingness to work through the LaTeX source&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grading is as per the rubric shared on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this WC is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deadline is mentioned on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the WC, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fourmilab/hackers_diet_online</title>
    <updated>2024-02-11T01:39:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-11:/Fourmilab/hackers_diet_online</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Fourmilab/hackers_diet_online" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository is the development environment and change log of the Web-based tools that accompany “The Hacker&#39;s Diet” book, available for free from Fourmilab. This is a Web application, implemented as a Common Gateway Interface (CGI) program written in the Perl language which provides logging of weight, charting and analysis of trends, plannin…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Hacker&#39;s Diet &lt;em&gt;Online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fourmilab.ch/hackdiet/online/hdo.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hacker&#39;s Diet &lt;em&gt;Online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Web-based application, companion to my book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fourmilab.ch/hackdiet/&#34;&gt;The Hacker&#39;s Diet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which allows you to maintain weight and exercise logs, produce custom charts, analyse trends, and plan diets from any computer with Internet connectivity and a Web browser. Data may be imported from and exported to other versions of the computer tools, or exported as CSV or XML for analysis with other programs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the master source code for the application, implemented as a Common Gateway Interface (CGI) program in the Perl programming language, with browser support in JavaScript. The complete tree of Web documents describing and supporting the application is included.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Structure of the repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is organised into the following directories.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;src&lt;/strong&gt;: Source code for the CGI application and support utilities, written in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate_programming&#34;&gt;Literate Programming&lt;/a&gt; methodology using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nuweb.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;nuweb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; system. Source code and integral documentation is provided in the &lt;code&gt;src/hdiet.pdf&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;webdoc&lt;/strong&gt;: Web pages providing documentation for the application and support files such as style sheets, images, and JavaScript programs. The main user manual is &lt;code&gt;webdoc/hdo.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with any Common Gateway Interface Web application, installation on a Web server will require installing all of the prerequisites (Perl modules, etc.) required by the programs, adapting them to the directory structure of your server, and linking to them from access documents accessible on the server over the Web. This is a complicated process which requires detailed knowledge of both your Web server&#39;s configuration and the requirements of the application, so no cookbook procedure can be supplied.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>