<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-07T01:39:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto</title>
    <updated>2023-09-07T01:39:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-07:/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Bayesian Data Analysis course at Aalto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Bayesian Data Analysis course material&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has course material for Bayesian Data Analysis course at Aalto (CS-E5710). See &lt;a href=&#34;https://avehtari.github.io/BDA_course_Aalto/&#34;&gt;the course web pages for more information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course material in the repo can be used in other courses. Text and videos licensed under CC-BY-NC 4.0. Code licensed under BSD-3.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://users.aalto.fi/~ave/BDA3.pdf&#34;&gt;The electronic version of the course book Bayesian Data Analysis, 3rd ed, by Andrew Gelman, John Carlin, Hal Stern, David Dunson, Aki Vehtari, and Donald Rubin&lt;/a&gt; is available for non-commercial purposes. Hard copies are available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crcpress.com/Bayesian-Data-Analysis/Gelman-Carlin-Stern-Dunson-Vehtari-Rubin/p/book/9781439840955&#34;&gt;the publisher&lt;/a&gt; and many book stores. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/&#34;&gt;home page for the book&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/book/errata_bda3.txt&#34;&gt;errata for the book&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto/master/chapter_notes&#34;&gt;chapter_notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The material will be updated during the course. Exercise instructions and slides will be updated at latest on Monday of the corresponding week. The best way to stay updated is to clone the repo and pull before checking new material. If you don&#39;t want to learn git and can&#39;t find the Download ZIP link, click &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/avehtari/BDA_course_Aalto/archive/master.zip&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course material has been greatly improved by the previous and current course assistants (in alphabetical order): Michael Riis Andersen, Paul B체rkner, Akash Daka, Alejandro Catalina, Kunal Ghosh, Meenal Jhajharia, Andrew Johnson, Noa Kallioinen, Joona Karjalainen, David Kohns, Juho Kokkala, Leevi Lindgren, Yann McLatchie, M책ns Magnusson, Anton Mallasto, Janne Ojanen, Topi Paananen, Markus Paasiniemi, Juho Piironen, Anna Riha, Jaakko Riihim채ki, Niko Siccha, Eero Siivola, Tuomas Sivula, Teemu S채ilynoja, Jarno Vanhatalo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>