<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-18T01:45:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>boazbk/crypto</title>
    <updated>2023-06-18T01:45:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-18:/boazbk/crypto</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/boazbk/crypto" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lecture notes for a course on cryptography&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;An intensive introduction to cryptography&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a git repository for lecture notes accompanying a fast-paced introductory undergraduate/beginning graduate course on cryptography that can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://intensecrypto.org&#34;&gt;http://intensecrypto.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boazbk/crypto/issues&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/boazbk/crypto/pulls&#34;&gt;pull requests&lt;/a&gt; to post any suggestions, comments, typo fixes, etc..&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License. To view a copy of this license, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&lt;/a&gt; or send a letter to Creative Commons, PO Box 1866, Mountain View, CA 94042, USA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While these notes will remain freely and publicly available, I may also create a printed book version of them in the future. By making any contribution to this work, such as a typo fix or any other suggestion or edit, you are assigning me the rights to use your contribution in both the online or any other version of this work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These notes are produced using a set of scripts written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsteurer.org/&#34;&gt;David Steurer&lt;/a&gt;, together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;, and the Tufte &lt;a href=&#34;https://tufte-latex.github.io/tufte-latex/&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://edwardtufte.github.io/tufte-css/&#34;&gt;css&lt;/a&gt; templates. See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://introtcs.org&#34;&gt;introtcs.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sumofsquares.org&#34;&gt;sumofsquares.org&lt;/a&gt; for other lecture notes using (variants of) the same scripts.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>uclathes/uclathes</title>
    <updated>2023-06-18T01:45:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-18:/uclathes/uclathes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/uclathes/uclathes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UCLA Thesis LaTeX style&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;uclathes - UCLA Thesis LaTeX Style&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2017-04-13, release 1.4&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2012-04-16, release 1.3&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS UCLATHES?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package is a LaTeX2e document style to format UCLA dissertations and theses. This style is based on work from Leslie Lamport, Dorab Patel, Eduardo Krell, Richard B. Wales, and John Heidemann.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The UCLA Graduate Division does not recognize &lt;code&gt;uclathes&lt;/code&gt; as a template for a thesis or dissertation. While countless students have used this template and successfully filed their manuscripts, the Graduate Division does not accept the template (or previous submissions) as an excuse for not meeting the filing requirements. If you find any bugs or have issues completing the filing process, let us know in the &lt;code&gt;Issues&lt;/code&gt; section with a solution for future students.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS NEW WITH UCLATHES 1.4?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UCLA has changed the style requirements for theses and dissertations again as of September 2016. These changes make manuscripts more consistent with the new electronic format that was adopted in 2012. Ryan Rosario updated uclathes-1.3 to match the new style and can confirm that it works as his dissertation was approved under the new rules in Spring 2017. Much of these changes were indicated by Sean Lake and Xiaochen Lian, and their dissertations were approved February 2017 and March 2017 respectively. Ryan&#39;s dissertation was approved in April 2017.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifically:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Margins are now 1&#34; on all sides.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Title and author name on title and abstract pages can no longer bold.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The small caps \textsc{..} and \scshape titles for title page headers is no longer permitted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Title and author name on title and abstract pages can no longer larger than the surrounding text.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If footnotes are single spaced, they must be separated by a single blank line.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several other changes were made to make the files less confusing to use:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Some filenames were changed to better reflect their purpose.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extra files required for the demo technical report were renamed and put into an include directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS NEW WITH UCLATHES 1.3?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After many years, UCLA changed the rules and moved away from paper. (They seem to still have the awful information-sparse double spacing, but maybe in 15 more years...) John Colby updated uclathes-1.2 from 1996 to match the new style, and can confirm that it works as his dissertation was approved under the new rules in late March 2012.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS NEW WITH UCLATHES 1.2?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a bug in &lt;code&gt;\degreeyear&lt;/code&gt; handling. The workaround is described below in ``KNOWN PROBLEMS&#39;&#39;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS NEW WITH UCLATHES 1.1?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I slightly shrunk page size to clearly conform to the requirements (problem reported by David Gast).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An example showing dual-mode formatting is present in &lt;code&gt;demo2*.tex&lt;/code&gt;. My dissertation is formatted either with &lt;code&gt;uclathes.cls&lt;/code&gt; (the submission version) and with &lt;code&gt;report.cls&lt;/code&gt; (for my committee and a technical report) because IMHO the thesis requirements are not optimal. See the manual for more details how to dual-format your document.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT IS IN UCLATHES?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enclosed in this package are the following files:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;uclathes.cls, uclath17.clo, uclathti.clo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; These three files implement the LaTeX2e &#34;uclathes&#34; document class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;uclathes.bst&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; This file implements the BibTeX &#34;uclathes&#34; bibliography style.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;thesis_spec.tex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; A document describing the &#34;uclathes&#34; style material with tips for approval. Candidate should read the document &lt;em&gt;UCLA Thesis and Dissertation Filing Requirements&lt;/em&gt; which is the official specification for the filing format.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;demo.tex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; An example first few pages of the thesis. The &#34;demo thesis&#34; described in &lt;code&gt;thesdoc.tex&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;demo_techreport.tex&lt;/code&gt; and all files in the &lt;code&gt;include&lt;/code&gt; directory These files are not necessary for filing, but provide another demonstration thesis that can be formatted as a technical report (latex &lt;code&gt;demo_techreport&lt;/code&gt;),&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; Automates TeX&#39;ing documents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; The file you are now reading.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;HOW TO INSTALL UCLATHES&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to install uclathes is to copy *.cls, *.clo, and *.bst into the directory where you run LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can copy these files into wherever LaTeX looks for its inputs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHERE&#39;S THE REAL DOCUMENTATION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rich Wales has prepared a good manual for uclathes. Read &lt;code&gt;thesdoc.ps&lt;/code&gt; (or format and read &lt;code&gt;thesdoc.tex&lt;/code&gt;) before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, documentation will be centralized on the GitHub wiki at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uclathes/uclathes/wiki&#34;&gt;https://github.com/uclathes/uclathes/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT: The UCLA Graduate Division maintains a document titled &lt;em&gt;UCLA Thesis and Dissertation Filing Requirements&lt;/em&gt;. As of April 2017, the manual is outdated, &lt;strong&gt;but the checklist on page 25 is updated and is used to approve manuscripts.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://grad.ucla.edu/gasaa/etd/filingrequirements.pdf&#34;&gt;https://grad.ucla.edu/gasaa/etd/filingrequirements.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHERE TO GET UCLATHES&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most recent version of this package can always be found at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/uclathes/uclathes/tarball/master&#34;&gt;https://github.com/uclathes/uclathes/tarball/master&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;ISPELL GOBBLYGOOK&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LocalWords: uclathes Dorab Patel Eduardo Krell cls uclath clo uclathti bst ps BibTeX thesdoc tex README vesion URL http www html mac rep ti isi TeX&#39;ing GOBBLYGOOK LocalWords bf rc LaTeX Lamport degreeyear Gast Makefile usepackage newlfont oldlfont&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;KNOWN PROBLEMS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;\bf doesn&#39;t work, I get the error:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ! Undefined control sequence.&#xA;  l.214 \item{\bf&#xA;                 {Air Interface:}}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re running LaTeX2e, and &lt;code&gt;\bf&lt;/code&gt; isn&#39;t enabled by default. You should choose if you want new or old semantics and put &lt;code&gt;\usepackage{newlfont}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;\usepackage{oldlfont}&lt;/code&gt; in your document. I purposely did not include one of these packages in &lt;code&gt;uclathes.cls&lt;/code&gt; to encourage people to convert to the new macros.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you don&#39;t specify a &lt;code&gt;\degreeyear&lt;/code&gt;, the value on the title page may be wrong. (This bug occurs in &lt;code&gt;demo.ps&lt;/code&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Work around: always specify &lt;code&gt;\degreeyear&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternate work around: find a real uclathes maintainer to fix the bug.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WHAT TO DO ABOUT BUGS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a thesis formatted with uclathes is rejected by the Theses and Dissertations Advisor, please let us know so we can update it accordingly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;REPLY-WARE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uclathes is distributed as reply-ware. If you get it and use it and graduate, you&#39;re strongly encouraged to send me some e-mail to let me know that my work was not in vain.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;--John Heidemann, 12 Jan 1996&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:johnh@isi.edu&#34;&gt;mailto:johnh@isi.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>luc-j-bourhis/smtbx-paper</title>
    <updated>2023-06-18T01:45:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-18:/luc-j-bourhis/smtbx-paper</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/luc-j-bourhis/smtbx-paper" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Project of publication about the smtbx a.k.a. Olex2.refine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The typesetting of this article requires the &lt;a href=&#34;ftp://ftp.iucr.org/templates/latex/iucr.cls&#34;&gt;iucr.cls&lt;/a&gt; style class and the &lt;a href=&#34;ftp://ftp.iucr.org/templates/latex/iucr.bst&#34;&gt;iucr.bst&lt;/a&gt; bibliography style that shall first be installed in a place visible by the LaTeX system. For TeXLive on MacOS, those files should go in the directories &lt;code&gt;~/Library/texmf/tex/latex&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;~/Library/texmf/bibtbx/bst&lt;/code&gt; respectively. In order to typeset without the preprint option, fonts such as Adobe zptmcmr are required. Those and all the other packages used in smtbx.tex should be available in a full TexLive installation on MacOS X or Linux as well as in a full MikTeX installation on Windows. MacOS X users relying on MacPorts to install TexLive are referred to the following &lt;a href=&#34;https://trac.macports.org/wiki/TeXLivePackages&#34;&gt;list of packages and their contents&lt;/a&gt; to decide what needs to be installed (the pgf package shall also be installed).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, authors wishing to contribute to this article are advised to read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://journals.iucr.org/d/services/latexstyle.html&#34;&gt;IUCr recommendations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Typesetting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The body of the article is in the file &lt;code&gt;smtbx.tex&lt;/code&gt; which is written so as to be typeset with &lt;code&gt;pdflatex&lt;/code&gt;. In particular, this means that pictures shall only be in the PDF, PNG, JPEG or GIF format. An EPS file shall therefore first be converted to PDF using e.g. the program &lt;code&gt;epstopdf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Ignores LaTeX intermediate files&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We recommend to add the following lines to the global .gitignore, so as to ignore all intermediate files produced by LaTeX (the last 2 are specific to the MacOS program TeXShop).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    # LaTeX&#xA;    *.log&#xA;    *.aux&#xA;    *.bbl&#xA;    *.blg&#xA;    *.out&#xA;    *.fls&#xA;    *.synctex.gz&#xA;    *.fdb_latexmk&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>