<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-20T01:47:52Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SBU-CE/CE079-Graph-Theory</title>
    <updated>2023-02-20T01:47:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-20:/SBU-CE/CE079-Graph-Theory</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SBU-CE/CE079-Graph-Theory" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Graph Theory Course Materials&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Graph Theory (CE079)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/SBU-CE/CE079-Graph-Theory/raw/main/images/banner.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Graph Theory course repository on GitHub! This repository is a central location for all the materials related to the course, including lecture notes, assignments, code samples, and other resources to help you learn the fundamental concepts of graph theory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graph theory is an important field of mathematics that studies the properties of graphs, which are mathematical structures that model relationships between objects. Graphs have applications in a wide range of fields, including computer science, engineering, biology, social networks, and many more. In this course, you will learn the basics of graph theory, including the structure of graphs, algorithms for finding paths and cycles, and techniques for analyzing the properties of graphs. You will also have the opportunity to apply your knowledge to real-world problems, such as analyzing social networks or designing routing algorithms for computer networks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The repository is organized into different folders, each containing resources related to a particular topic or aspect of graph theory. You will find lecture notes, slides, and code samples in the &#34;lectures&#34; folder, while assignments and projects will be located in the &#34;assignments&#34; folder. There is also a &#34;resources&#34; folder that contains additional materials such as books, papers, and links to useful online resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We hope that this repository will be a valuable resource for you throughout the course and beyond. Let&#39;s explore the fascinating world of graphs and graph theory together!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Instructor:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=RyYg7HcAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Dr. Farshad Safaei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current TAs:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mkh2097&#34;&gt;Mohammad Khoddam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zahra-zibzee&#34;&gt;Zahra Hashemi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MRSadeghi78&#34;&gt;Mohammad Reza Sadeghi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ehsansajadi&#34;&gt;Ehsan Sajadi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/b4ym4k&#34;&gt;Kamyab Abedi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Ghazallghe&#34;&gt;Ghazaal Laghaee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>