<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-06T01:44:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>niclejeune/Algorithms-and-Data-Structures-2024</title>
    <updated>2024-02-06T01:44:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-06:/niclejeune/Algorithms-and-Data-Structures-2024</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/niclejeune/Algorithms-and-Data-Structures-2024" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Algorithms and Data Structures - Spring 2024&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compendium for &#34;Algorithms&#34; for Spring 2024 Algorithms and Data Structures at ITU&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a compressed note compendium based on the textbook &#34;Algorithms&#34;, authored by Robert Sedgewick and Kevin Wayne (4th edition, 2011). It is intended for public use by students enrolled in the Spring 2024 Algorithms and Data Structure course at ITU. The compendium written in LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;main.tex&lt;/code&gt;: LaTeX source file for the compendium.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;notebooks/&lt;/code&gt;: Directory containing Jupyter notebooks for python code referenced in the compendium&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overleaf premium comes free with your ITU email. If you sign up for at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.overleaf.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.overleaf.com/&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;verify your email afterwards&lt;/strong&gt;, you should get it for free. Afterwards, you can import this from GitHub/download the main.tex file and import it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to this compendium are welcome! If you have suggestions for improvements or corrections, feel free to open an issue. If you wish to contribute:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make your changes. You can add it to Overleaf by linking your GitHub account and selecting your forked repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit a pull request with a description of your improvements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The contributors of this project reserve all rights.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This compendium is based on the textbook &#34;Algorithms&#34;, by Robert Sedgewick and Kevin Wayne (4th edition, 2011). No content is directly taken from the book.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The contributor &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/palpatine&#34;&gt;https://github.com/palpatine&lt;/a&gt;, contributed directly through the Overleaf share function. He contributed a substantial part of this compendium, but all commits were made through my github.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This compendium is a supplementary resource and is not a replacement for the textbook. Students are encouraged to consult the original text for a comprehensive understanding of the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For inquiries or further assistance, please contact us through our year&#39;s discord.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>