<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-19T01:38:47Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset10</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T01:38:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-19:/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset10</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/pset10" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Problem Set 10: Cardinality of Sets&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2024&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Problem Set (PSet) contains problems on recently covered material for you to practice. These prepare you for upcoming assessments and later topics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This PSet explores the cardinality of sets by proving that given sets have, or do not have, equal cardinality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background and requirement&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit this PSet you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to recall the definition of countabile and uncountable sets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to propose bijections between given sets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to recall various proof methods and select appropriate ones to apply to a given problem&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;to make logical arguments as required for a proof&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grading is described on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this PSet is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deadline is mentioned on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the PSet, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mbuzdalov/latex-styles</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T01:38:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-19:/mbuzdalov/latex-styles</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mbuzdalov/latex-styles" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LaTeX styles for different purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;latex-styles&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX styles for different purposes. Currently the following styles are available:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;itmo-student-thesis.cls&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A class for bachelor&#39;s and master&#39;s theses for students of ITMO University.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge</title>
    <updated>2024-03-19T01:38:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-19:/Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A collection of Modlists and Mods for various games hosted and open-sourced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to the Modding Lounge&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the official Modding Lounge repository, where all of the modlists featured in the Modding Lounge are hosted and shared publicly. All meta data and information provided for each Modlist can be found here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository acts as a hosting database for each modlists download information, providing a cohesive and collective location for each modlist for organization purposes. This helps reduce the clutter for both me, the Wabbajack team and users of the modlists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://moddinglounge.com/&#34;&gt;Modding Lounge&lt;/a&gt; website for a more visual experience to each Modlist.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Modlists&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Find each Modlist below for the corresponding game that you wish to view, as well as a short and brief description of the modlist.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Starfield&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Stellar Synergy&lt;/a&gt; (Soon&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt;) [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An upcoming modlist for Starfield that will feature a unique taste in modding the game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Fallout 4&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge/wiki/AW-Main-Page&#34;&gt;Atomic Warfare&lt;/a&gt; [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Atomic Warfare is an immersive overhauled, hardcore Tarkov/S.T.A.L.K.E.R.-like experience with amazing combat and new gameplay mechanics. With hundreds of hours of new Quests and New Lands to explore, you&#39;re surely to be bound to playing with endless entertainment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallout4experiences.com/stay-frosty&#34;&gt;Stay FROSTy&lt;/a&gt; [By ScreamingLake] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Stay FROSTy is an experience entirely based around attempting to provide a complete and stable FROST experience. As a survival simulator, survival is the goal and several difficult gameplay mechanics are implemented to make that exceptionally difficult.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallout4experiences.com/ground-zero&#34;&gt;Ground Zero&lt;/a&gt; [By ScreamingLake] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Ground Zero focuses on an alternate vision of the Commonwealth that has instead been overtaken by the ramifications of a deadly viral outbreak. It features TWO profiles: Survivalist and Operative.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallout4experiences.com/whispering-chills&#34;&gt;Whispering Chills&lt;/a&gt; [By ScreamingLake] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Whispering Chills is a horror experience unlike any other. It is intended to be entirely standalone in that you don&#39;t need to enjoy or know very well how to play Fallout 4 to be able to enjoy it as a horror fan in general. Perfect for anyone experiencing burnout in their other modded setups.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallout4experiences.com/tale-of-two-commonwealths&#34;&gt;Tale of Two Commonwealths&lt;/a&gt; [By ScreamingLake] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A Tale of Two Commonwealths is an experience based around the concept of transforming the look and feel of Fallout 4 into that of Fallout 3 and New Vegas, respectively. We have compiled nearly every known and publicly available Fallout 3/New Vegas-inspired mod out there and brought them all together through the use of two profiles that allow you to seamlessly transition between the experiences of Fallout 3 and New Vegas with a couple clicks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fallout4experiences.com/lost-world&#34;&gt;Lost World&lt;/a&gt; [By ScreamingLake] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Lost World is an experience featuring TWO profiles: one that offers a STALKER-inspired hardcore survival overhaul for Fallout 4 and another that offers a Metro-inspired hardcore survival overhaul for Fallout 4. After installing, you will be able to switch between both as you please.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Fallout: New Vegas&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge/wiki/WP-Main-Page&#34;&gt;Wasteland Prospects&lt;/a&gt; [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explore Nevada all over again, with a new and invigorating look on the Wasteland. Explore new areas, meet new friends, take on challenging enemies, and see what New Vegas is all about. Featured as just a New Vegas modlist, you won&#39;t be restricted to a complex setup with TTW, but instead focus your travels on Nevada.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;The Badlands&lt;/a&gt; [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open-Beta testing for an upcoming TTW modlist, The Badlands. Featured as the sister modlist to Wasteland Prospects, this aims to bring most of the features from WP to a TTW-based setup.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Skyrim Anniversary Edition&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Rage-GitHub/Modding-Lounge/wiki/FL-Main-Page&#34;&gt;Fable Lore&lt;/a&gt; [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An Anniversary Edition based Modlist, with modernizing combat, a survival focus, lore and content expansion, and more than 4 new major DLC-mods to explore. Maintained to be lightweight, small and non-ENB, this list is perfect for any user looking for an expanded version of Skyrim.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R Anomaly&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Divergent&lt;/a&gt; (Deprecated) [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A modlist focused on improving and increasing the exponetially challenging wasteland of S.T.A.L.K.E.R Anomaly, offering a focus on detailed survival, enhanced combat, fun and exciting new events, and more!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Cyberpunk 2077&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Cyber Runner&lt;/a&gt; (Deprecated) [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A Cyberpunk 2077 QoL Modlist focusing on improving over the base games mechanics, such as police chases, penthouses to buy, improved relationships, more immersive locations, etc., without being too intrusive on the base game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Valheim&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;VALHÖLL&lt;/a&gt; (Deprecated) [By Rage] &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A Valheim+ QoL, feature expansion based modlist, including new systems such as RPG based loot, variety of new building pieces, improved gameplay mechanics such as archery, and more.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>