<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-01T01:38:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>libretro/docs</title>
    <updated>2022-09-01T01:38:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-01:/libretro/docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/libretro/docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a repo of the RetroArch official document page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Contribute to the documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The docs are written in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; if you need help with the syntax use &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&#34;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt;. Mkdocs uses some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mkdocs.org/user-guide/writing-your-docs/#markdown-extensions&#34;&gt;Markdown extensions&lt;/a&gt; that you may have to familiarize with.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The documentation source is maintained via &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Git&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;. For more info on how to use git &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/&#34;&gt;refer to their help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to propose improvements to a document:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libretro/docs&#34;&gt;Clone the repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make the changes and update your clone&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the &#34;Building the docs&#34; section to render the documentation site locally&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Propose your changes using the button &lt;code&gt;New Pull Request&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libretro/docs&#34;&gt;in the docs repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a To-Do list for libretro/docs &lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt; and you can submit suggestions or issues regarding documentation at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libretro/docs/issues&#34;&gt;libretro/docs issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building the docs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pip.pypa.io&#34;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; installed &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;python --version&#xA;pip --version&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;!!! Note &#34;Building in Windows/msys2&#34; If you are using the standard RetroArch msys2 environment, you will need to install python with the command &lt;code&gt;pacman -S python&lt;/code&gt;. Next you will need to download &lt;a href=&#34;https://bootstrap.pypa.io/get-pip.py&#34;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;get-pip.py&lt;/code&gt; script&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt; bootstrap site. Finally, execute the script with the command &lt;code&gt;python get-pip.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install MkDocs&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install mkdocs&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install MkDocs-Material&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install mkdocs-material&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install PyMdown Extensions&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install pymdown-extensions&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Build the site&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdocs build&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The documentation will be built to the &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; directory; preview any changes with MkDocs&#39; built-in dev-server before submitting a pull request&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdocs serve&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mkdocs.org/#installation&#34;&gt;Guide to installing mkdocs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Adding a new core&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are the documents that should be added/updated when a new core is added to the libretro ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/library/ (Follow the latest core template. docs/meta/core-template.md)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to mkdocs.yml&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/meta/core-list.md&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/meta/see-also.md if it&#39;s related to another core in some way&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/development/licenses.md&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/guides/softpatching.md if it supports softpatching&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/guides/retroachievements.md if it supports cheevos&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the core to docs/library/bios.md if it needs a BIOS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>msu/csci-432-fall2022</title>
    <updated>2022-09-01T01:38:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-01:/msu/csci-432-fall2022</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/msu/csci-432-fall2022" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CSCI 432: Advanced Algorithmic Topics, Fall 2022&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CSCI 432: Advanced Algorithm Topics, Fall 2022&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is for class materials for CSCI 432 in Fall 2022, taught by Prof. Fasy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MSU Course Catalog Description: A rigorous examination of advanced algorithms and data structures. Topics include average case analysis, probabilistic algorithms, advanced graph problems and theory, distributed and parallel programming.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the Instructor: This course is NOT a programming class, and is not structured like the 132 and 232 courses that precede it. In this course, we will do many proofs (especially using induction), and will be writing pseudo-code, not code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: CSCI 246 (Discrete) and CSCI 232 (Data Structures and Algorithms) are a prerequisite for this course.&lt;br&gt; In particular, a student enrolled in CSCI 432 should be familiar with: sorting and searching algorithms, big-Oh notation, basic recurrence relations, heaps, queues, lists, hash tables, proof by induction and by contradiction, and discrete probability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Land Acknowledgement&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Living in Montana, we are on the ancestral lands of American Indians, including the 12 tribal nations that call Montana home today: A’aninin (Gros Ventre), Amskapi/Piikani (Blackfeet), Annishinabe (Chippewa/Ojibway), Annishinabe/Métis (Little Shell Chippewa), Apsáalooke (Crow), Ktunaxa/Ksanka (Kootenai), Lakota, Dakota (Sioux), Nakoda (Assiniboine), Ne-i-yah-wahk (Plains Cree), Qíispé (Pend d’Oreille), Seliš (Salish), and Tsétsêhéstâhese/So’taahe (Northern Cheyenne). We honor and respect these tribal nations as we live, work, learn, and play in this state.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about Montana Indians, I suggest starting with the following pamphlet: &lt;a href=&#34;http://opi.mt.gov/Portals/182/Page%20Files/Indian%20Education/Indian%20Education%20101/essentialunderstandings.pdf&#34;&gt;Essential Understandings Regarding Montana Indians&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Outcomes and Objectives&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course introduces students to the analysis and design of computer algorithms. In this course, students will:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Analyze asymptotic time and space complexity of algorithms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Describe algorithmic design paradigms (including dynamic programming, greedy algorithms, divide and conquer) and explain when an algorithmic design situation calls for it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Apply methods of analysis (prove correctness, time/space complexity, termination) to new problems.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use and analyze major graph algorithms and data structures.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;When and Where?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When? MWF 15:10-16:00 Where? Roberts 218&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contact you?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The preferred method to ask questions relating to this class is a public post on the group discussion board, or in my office hours.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Office Location: 363 Barnard Hall&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Office Phone: x4804&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zoom: see email&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Office hours:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prof. Fasy: MW 17:10-18:30, and by appointment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TA: TBD&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: Please email or call (x4804) in advance if you plan to join. This will reduce waiting time for me to wrap up a drop-in appointment that gets there before you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is in this repository?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The folders in this repository contain all materials for this class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Subdirectories:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;hw: Homework assignments, as well as a LaTex template for your submissions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;lec-notes: Copies of lecture notes, slides, and board photos.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Files:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;README.md: The course syllabus.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The course schedule is at the bottom of this Markdown file. If you want to learn more about Markdown, check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdowntutorial.com/&#34;&gt;this tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Creating Your Own Repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The repository is set as public, so you can access all course materials easily. I suggest creating a private repository with this one setup as an upstream git repo, so that you can use your repository to maintain your own materials for this class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To do so, follow these instructions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Going to &amp;lt;https://github.com/new&amp;gt;&#xA;- Enter the name `csci-432-fall2022-name`&#xA;- Select `Private`&#xA;- **DO NOT ADD A README.MD or .gitignore!**&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once your repository is initialized, you can pull it down to your local machine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next, you should add the class repository as an upstream git repo:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ git remote add upstream https://github.com/msu/csci-432-fall2022.git&#xA;$ git pull upstream main&#xA;$ git push&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will synchronize your private repository with the class repository. You only need to run these commands once. Then, when you want to get an update from the public class repository you can run this command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git pull upstream main&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a general workflow on your own repository, I suggest:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git pull upstream master&#xA;[[ do work here ]]&#xA;$ git add [[ list filenames edited ]]&#xA;$ git commit -m &#34;Descriptive message here&#34;&#xA;$ git push origin main&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your grade for this class will be determined by:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;35% Homework (individual and group)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;30% Project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;35% Exams&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Homework: All assignments must be submitted by 23:59 on the due date. Late assignments will not be accepted. The lowest homework grade will be dropped. The submission should be typeset in LaTex using the provided template, and submitted as a PDF both in D2L and Gradescope.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Project: Groups will be assigned. The final product will be a video. More details to come.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Exams: We will have three exams in this course. Each exam will be 10% of the grade, with the best exam counting an additional 5%.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A grade of 70% on exams is required to earn a B- or higher in the class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Class Policies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Policy on Class Attendance&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Class attendance and participation is required and expected. If you consistently miss class, then your final grade may be dropped one letter grade (e.g., from B+ to C+).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Policy on Homework&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not search for answers to the problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; You will learn in this class by solving the problems, not by reading the solutions. Regurgitating solutions you found elsewhere will not help you learn the material. If you feel that you need additional resources, please ask.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Policy on Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Collaboration is encouraged on all aspects of the class, except where explicitly forbidden. Note:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All collaboration (who and what) must be clearly indicated in writing on anything turned in.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Homework may be solved collaboratively except as explicitly forbidden, but solutions must be written up &lt;strong&gt;independently&lt;/strong&gt;. This is best done by writing your solutions when not in a group setting. Groups should be small enough that each member plays a significant role. (Note, if there is a group assignment, each group is treated as an &#39;individual&#39;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Classroom Etiquette&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Except for note taking and group work requiring a computer, please keep electronic devices off during class, as they can be distractions to other students. Disruptions to the class will result in being asked to leave the lecture, and one half-point will be deducted from your final course grade.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Withdrawing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After 15 October 2022, I will only support requests to withdraw from this course with a &#34;W&#34; grade if extraordinary personal circumstances exist. If you are considering withdrawing from this class, discussing this with me as early as possible is advised. Since this class involves a project, the decision to withdraw must also be discussed with your group (after groups are formed).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Special Needs Information&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have a documented disability for which you are or may be requesting an accommodation(s), please contact both me and the office of Disabled Student Services within the first two weeks of class.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Diversity Statement&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Montana State University considers the diversity of its students, faculty, and staff to be a strength and critical to its educational mission. MSU expects every member of the university community to contribute to an inclusive and respectful culture for all in its classrooms, work environments, and at campus events. Dimensions of diversity can include sex, race, age, national origin, ethnicity, gender identity and expression, intellectual and physical ability, sexual orientation, income, faith and non-faith perspectives, socio-economic status, political ideology, education, primary language, family status, military experience, cognitive style, and communication style. The individual intersection of these experiences and characteristics must be valued in our community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there are aspects of the design, instruction, and/or experiences within this course that result in barriers to your inclusion or accurate assessment of achievement, please notify the instructor as soon as possible and/or contact Disability Services or the Office of Institutional Equity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Use of Materials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This syllabus, course lectures and presentations, and any course materials provided throughout this term are protected by U.S. copyright laws. Students enrolled in the course may use them for their own research and educational purposes. However, reproducing, selling or otherwise distributing these materials without written permission of the copyright owner is expressly prohibited, including providing materials (or solutions) to commercial platforms such as Chegg or CourseHero. Doing so constitutes a violation of U.S. copyright law as well as MSU’s Code of Student Conduct. Instructors from other universities are free to borrow the material on this website for use in their own classrooms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Special Remarks and Policies for COVID-19&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please follow the current &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prevent-getting-sick/prevention.html&#34;&gt;CDC guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, which includes wearing a mask or respirator when the &#34;COVID-19 community level&#34; is &#34;high&#34;. If you need to miss class to quarantine or isolate due to COVID-19 (or for any other reason), please communicate with the instructor as soon as possible in order to coordinate a plan for making up the missed classwork. As a reminder, attendance is required. If the instructor is unable to make it to class, either a substitute will be found for those lectures or the class will be held via Zoom.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;MSU Policies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Academic Integrity&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The integrity of the academic process requires that credit be given where credit is due. Accordingly, it is academic misconduct to present the ideas or works of another as one&#39;s own work, or to permit another to present one&#39;s work without customary and proper acknowledgment of authorship. Students may collaborate with other students only as expressly permitted by the instructor. Students are responsible for the honest completion and representation of their work, the appropriate citation of sources and the respect and recognition of others&#39; academic endeavors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Plagiarism will not be tolerated in this course. According to the Merriam-Webster dictionary, plagiarism is &#34;the act of using another person&#39;s words or ideas without giving credit to that person.&#34; Proper credit means describing all outside resources (conversations, websites, etc.), and explaining the extent to which the resource was used. Penalties for plagiarism at MSU include (but are not limited to) failing the assignment, failing the class, or having your degree revoked. This is serious, so do not plagiarize. Even inadvertent or unintentional misuse or appropriation of another&#39;s work (such as relying heavily on source material that is not expressly acknowledged) is considered plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By participating in this class, you agree to abide by the Student Code of Conduct. This includes the following academic expectations:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Be prompt and regular in attending classes;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Be well-prepared for classes;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit required assignments in a timely manner;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Take exams when scheduled, unless rescheduled under 310.01;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Act in a respectful manner toward other students and the instructor and in a way that does not detract from the learning experience; and&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make and keep appointments when necessary to meet with the instructor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;MSU Drug and Alcohol Policies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Per the Code of Conduct for students, no student may come to class under the influence of drugs or alcohol, as that would not be &lt;code&gt;fostering a healthy, safe and productive campus and community.&lt;/code&gt; See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.montana.edu/deanofstudents/alcoholanddrugs.html&#34;&gt;Alcohol and Drug Policies Website&lt;/a&gt; for more information. In particular, note:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Montana State University is tobacco free campus, to include e-cigarettes&#xA;(vaping) and an environment where inappropriate use of alcohol and unlawful&#xA;possession, consumption, use or distribution of illicit drugs or alcohol is&#xA;prohibited. The minimum age to purchase tobacco products in the state of Montana&#xA;is 21.  Despite the fact that medical and recreational marijuana use is legal in&#xA;the state of Montana for individuals over the age of 21, University policy&#xA;prohibits its use and federal and state law prohibit the possession and/or use&#xA;of drug paraphernalia at an educational institution.  The university&#xA;requirements are found in the Tobacco Free Campus Policy and the Campus Alcohol&#xA;and Drug Policy.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Technical Resources&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udacity.com/course/how-to-use-git-and-github--ud775&#34;&gt;Git Udacity Course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/fork-a-repo/&#34;&gt;Forking in Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdowntutorial.com/&#34;&gt;More Markdown&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tavmjong.free.fr/INKSCAPE/MANUAL/html/SoupCan.html&#34;&gt;Inkscape Can Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lib.usm.edu/legacy/plag/pretest_new.php&#34;&gt;Plagiarism Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rob-bell.net/2009/06/a-beginners-guide-to-big-o-notation/&#34;&gt;Big-O, Intuitive Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.cs.duke.edu/spring09/cps102/Lectures/Book.pdf&#34;&gt;Discrete Lecture Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Course Textbook&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Required) &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeffe.cs.illinois.edu/teaching/algorithms/&#34;&gt;Algorithms by Jeff Erickson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Suggested) Introduction to Algorithms, Third Edition by Cormen, Leiserson, Rivest, and Stein (CLRS).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each week, we assign:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Textbook Reading: These are readings from &lt;a href=&#34;https://jeffe.cs.illinois.edu/teaching/algorithms/&#34;&gt;Erickson&#39;s Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;, please skim before class, and fully read after class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional Readings: additional resources that your classmates (current or previous) have found helpful. Skim/read as you find appropriate. If you need more resources, ask!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 1 (24, 26 August)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Intro to Analysis of Algorithms; Induction.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional Reading: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.montana.edu/brittany/teaching/algorithms/15_fall/docs/induction.pdf&#34;&gt;Induction Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 2 (29,31 August; 2 September)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Asymptotic Notation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 3 (7,9 September)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Monday (5 September) is Labor day. No class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Recursion: Correctness, Runtime, Runtime, and Master Theorem&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 4 (12,14,16 September)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Proof of Termination; Backtracking&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 5 (19,21,23 September)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Dynamic Programming&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 6 (25,28,30 September)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: More Dynamic Programming&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 7 (3,5,7 October)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Greedy Algorithms, Loop Invarints&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 4&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional Reading: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@TheGeekiestOne/greedy-algorithms-the-car-fueling-problem-a35ccc9bb011&#34;&gt;Gas Stop Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 8 (10,12,14 October)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Graph Algorithms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapters 5,6&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 9 (17,19,21 October)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Graph Algorithms (cont.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapters 5,6&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 10 (24,26,28 October)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: More Graph Algorithms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 7&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 11 (31 October; 2,4 November)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: MST and SSSP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 8&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 12 (7,9 November)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Friday (11 November) is Veteran&#39;s Day. No class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: APSP and Flows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 9 and 10.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 13 (14,16,18 November)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Flows and Cuts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: Chapter 10-11&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 14 (21,23,25 November)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fall Break (no classes)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 15 (28,30 November; 2 December)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Topics: Randomized Algorithms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reading: TODO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 16 (5,7,9 December)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TBD&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Week 17 (Finals Week)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We meet Mnday, 12 December, 14:00-15:50. (TODO: someone must confirm!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.montana.edu/registrar/Schedules.html&#34;&gt;Finals Week Schedule&lt;/a&gt; for university policies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This syllabus was created, using wording from previous courses taught by myself, as well as my colleagues. Thanks all! If you are teaching an algorithms or related course and wish to use any of the materials, you have permission to do so, as long as solutions to HW questions are not posted online.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OCamlPro/cheat-sheets</title>
    <updated>2022-09-01T01:38:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-01:/OCamlPro/cheat-sheets</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OCamlPro/cheat-sheets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>