<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-05T01:55:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>plk/biblatex</title>
    <updated>2022-07-05T01:55:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-05:/plk/biblatex</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/plk/biblatex" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;biblatex is a sophisticated bibliography system for LaTeX users. It has considerably more features than traditional bibtex and supports UTF-8&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package provides advanced bibliographic facilities for use with LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The package is a complete reimplementation of the bibliographic facilities provided by LaTeX. A custom backend Biber is used by default which processes BibTeX format data files and them performs all sorting, label generation (and a great deal more).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biblatex does not use the backend to format the bibliography information as with traditional BibTeX: instead of being implemented in BibTeX style files, the formatting of the bibliography is entirely controlled by TeX macros.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package supports subdivided bibliographies, multiple bibliographies within one document with different sorting, separate lists of bibliographic information such as abbreviations of various fields. Bibliographies may be subdivided into parts and / or segmented by topics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just like the bibliography styles, all citation commands may be freely defined.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Biber as the backend, features such as customisable sorting, multiple bibliographies with different sorting, customisable labels, dynamic data modification and custom data models are available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The package is completely localised and can interface with the Babel and Polyglossia packages. Read below for how to update and/or add translations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Copyright and Licence&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Authors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Philipp Lehman&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Philip Kime, Joseph Wright, Audrey Boruvka (since 2011)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copyright 2006 --- 2011 Philipp Lehman&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copyright 2011 --- ... Philip Kime&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licence&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work may be distributed and/or modified under the conditions of the LaTeX Project Public License, either version 1.3 of this license or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version of the license is in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latex-project.org/lppl.txt&#34;&gt;https://www.latex-project.org/lppl.txt&lt;/a&gt; and version 1.3 or later is part of all distributions of LaTeX version 2003/06/01 or later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work has the LPPL maintenance status &#34;maintained&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;biblatex is bundled with TeXLive and its variants as well as MikTeX. Normally you can install and update biblatex through your TeX distribution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;biblatex starts life on Github where you can always find development releases:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/plk/biblatex&#34;&gt;https://github.com/plk/biblatex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From here, it is packaged for general consumption to SourceForge:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/biblatex&#34;&gt;https://sourceforge.net/projects/biblatex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;this is where users can download the current development version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest official release is then put onto CTAN, which is where users can get the latest stable version:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ctan.org/pkg/biblatex&#34;&gt;https://ctan.org/pkg/biblatex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation from github&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this you&#39;ll need to be on a UNIX-like system (use &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/plk/biblatex/dev/cygwin&#34;&gt;https://www.cygwin.com&lt;/a&gt; on Windows) that has bash and perl.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should only install from github if you want to check out the bleeding edge of development or if there is absolutely no way to obtain either the official historical releases from &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/biblatex/files/&#34;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt; or the current release from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/biblatex&#34;&gt;CTAN&lt;/a&gt;. Remember that you will need a matching Biber version (the binaries are distributed on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/biblatex-biber/files/biblatex-biber/&#34;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First clone the repo:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/plk/biblatex.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then from the clone root:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;obuild/build.sh install &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;texmf root&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;for example, say the currently released version is 3.3 and you want to try the 3.4 development version. Suppose your personal texmf root is at &lt;code&gt;~/texmf&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;obuild/build.sh install 3.4 ~/texmf&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If this is the first time you are installing &lt;code&gt;biblatex&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;~/texmf&lt;/code&gt;, you will have to tell TeX that it can find the files in this new location with &lt;code&gt;texhash&lt;/code&gt; or the equivalent command from your TeX distribution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the install script does not fetch and install the official biblatex release version corresponding to the version argument supplied. It just takes the files that are currently checked out, moves them and changes their version identifications so that they identify as the version given in the argument. If you want a specific version, you must check out the corresponding tag or obtain the corresponding sources otherwise before running the script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously, its is easier to get the TDS format package from the Sourceforge development folder and just unpack it into your &lt;code&gt;~/texmf&lt;/code&gt; but this might not be quite as recent as the git development branch (but is usually very close).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Translation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The language files (&lt;code&gt;*.lbx&lt;/code&gt;) are located in &lt;code&gt;tex/latex/biblatex/lbx&lt;/code&gt;. To add a new translation copy &lt;code&gt;english.lbx&lt;/code&gt; (or another existing translation that is closer to your language; note that &lt;code&gt;english.lbx&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;german.lbx&lt;/code&gt; are reference translations, all other files are not guaranteed to be complete) to &lt;code&gt;languagename.lbx&lt;/code&gt;, where &lt;code&gt;languagename&lt;/code&gt; is the name used by Babel for the language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To debug or verify that a translation is complete, copy &lt;code&gt;doc/latex/biblatex/examples/03-localization-keys.tex&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;tex/latex/biblatex/lbx&lt;/code&gt;. Edit &lt;code&gt;03-localization-keys.tex&lt;/code&gt; so Babel (and hence Biblatex) uses the language you are translating. Compiling the file will warn you about missing strings, and looking at the generated file will help you to proofread your translation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are translating for an upcoming release, i.e., you have cloned the Git repository, please remember to build and install the package as described above before trying to compile &lt;code&gt;03-localization-keys.tex&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your language inherits from another, you&#39;ll have to take extra care as new strings aren&#39;t reported if they are already translated in the inherited language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Help&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;biblatex comes with example files in the &lt;code&gt;doc/latex/biblatex/examples&lt;/code&gt; directory in the distribution. There are a lot of practical examples here along with comments in the source &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; files which help to explain details not dwelt on in the PDF manual.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tex.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/biblatex&#34;&gt;StackExchange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Debug and feature requests&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suggestions and bug reports are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the Github &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/plk/biblatex/issues&#34;&gt;issues page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open an issue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add a &lt;a href=&#34;https://texfaq.org/FAQ-minxampl&#34;&gt;minimal working example&lt;/a&gt; if possible. This helps a great deal facilitate a swift response.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic</title>
    <updated>2022-07-05T01:55:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-05:/OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An open-source, customizable intermediate logic textbook&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Open Logic Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic/actions/workflows/build.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Open Logic Project is an open source, open access collection of materials on advanced logic, aimed mainly at philosophers, but also suitable for computer scientists and mathematicians. The text can be rearranged and remixed. You can produce custom textbooks from it, so they take the aim of the course and the preferences of the instructor into account. It is written in LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://openlogicproject.org/&#34;&gt;project website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OpenLogicProject/OpenLogic/wiki&#34;&gt;Open Logic wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains LaTeX source files only. Head to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://builds.openlogicproject.org/&#34;&gt;builds site to download PDFs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): The Open Logic Project&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span xmlns:dct=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; property=&#34;dct:title&#34; rel=&#34;dct:type&#34;&gt;The Open Logic Text&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;https://openlogicproject.org/people/&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;The Open Logic Project&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;Permissions beyond the scope of this license may be available at &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;https://openlogicproject.org/&#34; rel=&#34;cc:morePermissions&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://openlogicproject.org/&#34;&gt;https://openlogicproject.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>abntex/abntex2</title>
    <updated>2022-07-05T01:55:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-05:/abntex/abntex2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/abntex/abntex2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;📚 Classe LaTeX e estilo bibliográfico compatíveis com as normas da ABNT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;abntex2&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O &lt;strong&gt;abnTeX2&lt;/strong&gt;, evolução do abnTeX (&lt;em&gt;ABsurd Norms for TeX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt;), é uma suíte para LaTeX que atende os requisitos das normas da ABNT (Associação Brasileira de Normas Técnicas) para elaboração de documentos técnicos e científicos brasileiros, como artigos científicos, relatórios técnicos, trabalhos acadêmicos como teses, dissertações, projetos de pesquisa e outros documentos do gênero.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A suíte abnTeX2 é composta por uma classe, por pacotes de citação e de formatação de estilos bibliográficos, por exemplos, modelos de documentos e por uma ampla documentação.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Compatível com as normas ABNT vigentes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O abnTeX2 é compatível com as seguintes normas vigentes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6022:2018&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Artigo em publicação periódica científica - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6023:2002&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Referência - Elaboração&lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6024:2012&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Numeração progressiva das seções de um documento - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6027:2012&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Sumário - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6028:2003&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Resumo - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6029:2006&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Livros e folhetos - Apresentação &lt;font color=&#34;red&#34;&gt;(novo!)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 6034:2004&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Índice - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 10520:2002&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Citações&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 10719:2015&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Relatório técnico e/ou científico - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 14724:2011&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Trabalhos acadêmicos - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABNT NBR 15287:2011&lt;/strong&gt;: Informação e documentação - Projeto de pesquisa - Apresentação&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Por onde começar?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color=&#34;green&#34;&gt;Não entre em pânico!&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;strong&gt; É iniciante em LaTeX ou em abnTeX2? Consulte a página &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/PorOndeComecar&#34;&gt;Por Onde Começar?&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/abntex2&#34;&gt;Download de modelos canônicos de documentos construídos com abnTeX2&lt;/a&gt;, que incluem (links remetem a exemplos compilados):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Artigo científico;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Trabalho acadêmico (tese, dissertação, trabalho de conclusão de curso e outros do gênero);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Projeto de pesquisa;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Relatório técnico/científico;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Livro e Folheto &lt;font color=&#34;red&#34;&gt;(novo!)&lt;/font&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Documento com Glossários;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Apresentação de slides &lt;font color=&#34;red&#34;&gt;(novo!)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/abntex2&#34;&gt;Download dos manuais de uso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/abntex/abntex2/master/doc/latex/abntex2/README&#34;&gt;Notas de atualização&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instalação&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;O abnTeX2 está disponível no &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/abntex2&#34;&gt;CTAN: Comprehensive TeX Archive Network&lt;/a&gt; e já é integrado às distribuições LaTeX:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.miktex.org/&#34;&gt;MiKTeX&lt;/a&gt; ou &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tug.org/protext/&#34;&gt;proTeXt&lt;/a&gt; para Windows;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tug.org/texlive/&#34;&gt;TeX Live 2013/2014&lt;/a&gt; para Windows e diversos sabores de Linux;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tug.org/mactex/&#34;&gt;MacTeX 2013/2014&lt;/a&gt; para Mac;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Se você usa uma dessas distribuições, nenhuma instalação adicional é necessária. Baixe um dos &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ctan.org/pkg/abntex2&#34;&gt;modelos canônicos&lt;/a&gt;) disponíveis e pronto!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Porém, caso não possa usar as versões mais recentes das distribuições indicadas, instale o abnTeX 2 por meio do &lt;code&gt;Package Manager&lt;/code&gt; da sua distribuição LaTeX. Consulte as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/Instalacao&#34;&gt;instruções de instalação do LaTeX e do abnTeX2&lt;/a&gt;. Há instruções para &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/InstalacaoWindows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/InstalacaoLinux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; e &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/InstalacaoMac&#34;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Como colaborar?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sua ajuda é muito importante! &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/Como-Contribuir&#34;&gt;Você pode ajudar no desenvolvimento e na divulgação&lt;/a&gt; do abnTeX2.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Customizações do abnTeX2&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizações conhecidas&lt;/strong&gt;: já são dezenas de customizações para universidades e instituições. Veja a lista de &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/CustomizacoesConhecidas&#34;&gt;customizações conhecidas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deseja customizar o abnTeX2?&lt;/strong&gt; Caso você pretenda alterar e/ou redistribuir os modelos canônicos do abnTeX2, recomendamos fortemente que leia com atenção as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/ComoCustomizar&#34;&gt;orientações sobre como customizar o abnTeX2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;LyX e abnTeX2&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usa o LyX? O abnTeX2 é compatível! Veja como instalar o arquivo de layout e o modelo de documento do &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki/LyX&#34;&gt;abnTeX2 para LyX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Veja também&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/wiki&#34;&gt;Wiki do abnTeX2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/105202176004387477100&#34;&gt;Comunidade do abnTeX2 no Google Plus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; o abnTeX original era um projeto coordenado por Gerald Weber, Miguel Frasson, Renato Machnievscz e outros.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;**&lt;/code&gt; O abnTeX2 é compatível com a versão corrente da norma ABNT NBR 6023:2002. Porém, até este momento, o manual abnTeX2cite.pdf está atualizado com informações referentes à versão anterior da referida norma, ou seja, com informações sobre a versão 2000. A atualização do manual é uma das &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abntex/abntex2/issues&#34;&gt;atividades em execução&lt;/a&gt; do projeto.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>