<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-09T01:55:34Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>loreabad6/R-CV</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:55:34Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/loreabad6/R-CV</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/loreabad6/R-CV" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My CV created in R&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Lorena Abad - Curriculum Vitae&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;My CV created with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mitchelloharawild/vitae&#34;&gt;vitae&lt;/a&gt; package in R.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To reproduce, please copy the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loreabad6/R-CV/master/awesome-cv.cls&#34;&gt;awesome-cv.cls&lt;/a&gt; file to the directory with your &lt;code&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/loreabad6/R-CV/raw/master/CV.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loreabad6/R-CV/master/preview.png&#34; alt=&#34;CV&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HandsOnDataViz/book</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:55:34Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/HandsOnDataViz/book</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HandsOnDataViz/book" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hands-On Data Visualization: Interactive Storytelling from Spreadsheets to Code is an open-access book-in-progress, under contract with O&#39;Reilly Media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Hands-On Data Visualization: Interactive Storytelling from Spreadsheets to Code&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open-access book-in-progress by Jack Dougherty and Ilya Ilyankou, under contract with O&#39;Reilly Media, Inc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read for free online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://HandsOnDataViz.org&#34;&gt;http://HandsOnDataViz.org&lt;/a&gt;, or purchase print or ebook edition (to come).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;View open-source code for source text and templates at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/handsondataviz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/handsondataviz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please send corrections or suggestions for this book-in-progress to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:handsondataviz@gmail.com&#34;&gt;handsondataviz@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, or open an issue or submit a pull request on the GitHub repository at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/handsondataviz/book&#34;&gt;https://github.com/handsondataviz/book&lt;/a&gt;. If you submit a GitHub pull request, in your commit message, please add the sentence “I assign the copyright of this contribution to Jack Dougherty and Ilya Ilyankou,” so that we can maintain the option of publishing this book in other forms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Built with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bookdown.org&#34;&gt;http://bookdown.org&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;https://www.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About the book&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tell your story and show it with data, using free and easy-to-learn tools on the web. This introductory book teaches you how to design interactive charts and customized maps for your website, beginning with easy drag-and-drop tools, such as Google Sheets and Tableau Public, then gradually working up to editing open-source Chart.js and Leaflet code templates on GitHub. Follow along with the step-by-step tutorials, real-world examples, and online resources. This book is ideal for students, non-profit organizations, small business owners, local governments, journalists, academics, or anyone who wants to tell their story and show the data. No coding experience is required.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hands-On Data Visualization&lt;/em&gt; is copyrighted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://handsondataviz.org/authors&#34;&gt;Jack Dougherty and Ilya Ilyankou&lt;/a&gt; and distributed under a &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0&#34;&gt;Creative Commons BY-NC-ND 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;. You may freely share this content for non-commercial purposes, with a source credit to &lt;a href=&#34;http://HandsOnDataViz.org&#34;&gt;http://HandsOnDataViz.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This open-source repository is provided &#34;as is&#34;, without warranty of any kind, express or implied, including but not limited to the warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and non-infringement. No installation or technical support will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>StatBiomed/BMDS-book</title>
    <updated>2022-07-09T01:55:34Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-09:/StatBiomed/BMDS-book</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/StatBiomed/BMDS-book" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Biomedical Data Science book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the book &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Biomedical Data Science - an introduction with case studies&lt;/a&gt;. Most contents are demonstrated with R programming language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is designed as the lecture notes and textbook for &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;BIOF1001: Introduction to Biomedical Data Science&lt;/a&gt;, an undergraduate course (Year 1) at the University of Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Source files and re-build:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;you can find the source files on GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/StatBiomed/BMDS-book&#34;&gt;StatBiomed/BMDS-book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To build this book from the source files, use the following script in R:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;bookdown::render_book(&#34;index.Rmd&#34;, &#34;bookdown::gitbook&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To release the build, you can simply copy the whole contents in the &lt;code&gt;_book&lt;/code&gt; folder to the &lt;code&gt;docs&lt;/code&gt; folder and push it to this github repository.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>