<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-07-13T01:41:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>julienXX/terminal-notifier</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T01:41:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-13:/julienXX/terminal-notifier</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Send User Notifications on macOS from the command-line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;terminal-notifier&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/release/julienXX/terminal-notifier.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub release&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;terminal-notifier is a command-line tool to send macOS User Notifications, which are available on macOS 10.10 and higher.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/alerter&#34;&gt;alerter&lt;/a&gt; features were merged in terminal-notifier 1.7. This led to some issues and even more issues in the 1.8 release. We decided with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet&#34;&gt;Valère Jeantet&lt;/a&gt; to rollback this merge.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From now on terminal-notifier won&#39;t have the sticky notification feature nor the actions buttons. If you need them please use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/alerter&#34;&gt;alerter&lt;/a&gt;. I also want to follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://semver.org&#34;&gt;semver&lt;/a&gt; hence this latest version starts at 2.0.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sticking to two smaller specialized tools will hopefully make them easier to maintain and less error prone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is currently packaged as an application bundle, because &lt;code&gt;NSUserNotification&lt;/code&gt; does not work from a ‘Foundation tool’. &lt;a href=&#34;radar://11956694&#34;&gt;radar://11956694&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you intend to package terminal-notifier with your app to distribute it on the Mac App Store, please use 1.5.2; version 1.6.0+ uses a private method override, which is not allowed in the App Store Guidelines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re using macOS &amp;lt; 10.10 you should use terminal-notifier 1.6.3.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re looking for sticky notifications or more actions on a notification please use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vjeantet/alerter&#34;&gt;alerter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prebuilt binaries are available from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/releases&#34;&gt;releases section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or if you want to use this from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/tree/master/Ruby&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/a&gt;, you can install it through RubyGems:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ [sudo] gem install terminal-notifier&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also install it via &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mxcl/homebrew&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ brew install terminal-notifier&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ./terminal-notifier.app/Contents/MacOS/terminal-notifier -[message|group|list] [VALUE|ID|ID] [options]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to use terminal-notifier, you have to call the binary &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the application bundle.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Ruby gem, which wraps this tool, &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; have a bin wrapper. If installed you can simply do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terminal-notifier -[message|group|list] [VALUE|ID|ID] [options]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will obviously be a bit slower than using the tool without the wrapper.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like notifications to stay on the screen until dismissed, go to System Preferences -&amp;gt; Notifications -&amp;gt; terminal-notifier and change the style from Banners to Alerts. You cannot do this on a per-notification basis.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Example Uses&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Display piped data with a sound:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ echo &#39;Piped Message Data!&#39; | terminal-notifier -sound default&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/master/assets/Example_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example 1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use a custom icon:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terminal-notifier -title ProjectX -subtitle &#34;new tag detected&#34; -message &#34;Finished&#34; -appIcon http://vjeantet.fr/images/logo.png&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/master/assets/Example_3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example 3&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open an URL when the notification is clicked:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terminal-notifier -title &#39;💰&#39; -message &#39;Check your Apple stock!&#39; -open &#39;http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=AAPL&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/master/assets/Example_4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example 4&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open an app when the notification is clicked:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ terminal-notifier -group &#39;address-book-sync&#39; -title &#39;Address Book Sync&#39; -subtitle &#39;Finished&#39; -message &#39;Imported 42 contacts.&#39; -activate &#39;com.apple.AddressBook&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/julienXX/terminal-notifier/master/assets/Example_5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example 5&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Options&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At a minimum, you must specify either the &lt;code&gt;-message&lt;/code&gt; , the &lt;code&gt;-remove&lt;/code&gt;, or the &lt;code&gt;-list&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-message VALUE&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[required]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The message body of the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you pipe data into terminal-notifier, you can omit this option, and the piped data will become the message body instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-title VALUE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title of the notification. This defaults to ‘Terminal’.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-subtitle VALUE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subtitle of the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-sound NAME&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Play the &lt;code&gt;NAME&lt;/code&gt; sound when the notification appears. Sound names are listed in &lt;code&gt;/System/Library/Sounds&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the special &lt;code&gt;NAME&lt;/code&gt; “default” for the default notification sound.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-group ID&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifies the notification’s ‘group’. For any ‘group’, only &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; notification will ever be shown, replacing previously posted notifications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A notification can be explicitly removed with the &lt;code&gt;-remove&lt;/code&gt; option (see below).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example group IDs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The sender’s name (to scope the notifications by tool).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The sender’s process ID (to scope the notifications by a unique process).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The current working directory (to scope notifications by project).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-remove ID&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[required]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remove a previous notification from the &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; ‘group’, if one exists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the special &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; “ALL” to remove all messages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-list ID&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;[required]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lists details about the specified ‘group’ &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use the special &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; “ALL” to list details about all currently active messages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The output of this command is tab-separated, which makes it easy to parse.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-activate ID&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Activate the application specified by &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; when the user clicks the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the bundle identifier (&lt;code&gt;CFBundleIdentifier&lt;/code&gt;) of an application in its &lt;code&gt;Info.plist&lt;/code&gt; file &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; the application bundle.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Examples application IDs are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;com.apple.Terminal&lt;/code&gt; to activate Terminal.app&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;com.apple.Safari&lt;/code&gt; to activate Safari.app&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-sender ID&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fakes the sender application of the notification. This uses the specified application’s icon, and will launch it when the notification is clicked.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using this option fakes the sender application, so that the notification system will launch that application when the notification is clicked. Because of this it is important to note that you cannot combine this with options like &lt;code&gt;-execute&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-activate&lt;/code&gt; which depend on the sender of the notification to be ‘terminal-notifier’ to perform its work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information on the &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt;, see the &lt;code&gt;-activate&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-appIcon PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specify an image &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; to display instead of the application icon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING: This option is subject to change, since it relies on a private method.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-contentImage PATH&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specify an image &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; to attach inside of the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING: This option is subject to change since it relies on a private method.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-open URL&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;URL&lt;/code&gt; when the user clicks the notification. This can be a web or file URL, or any custom URL scheme.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-execute COMMAND&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run the shell command &lt;code&gt;COMMAND&lt;/code&gt; when the user clicks the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;-ignoreDnD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ignore Do Not Disturb settings and unconditionally show the notification.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING: This option is subject to change since it relies on a private method.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the works are available under the MIT license. &lt;strong&gt;Except&lt;/strong&gt; for ‘Terminal.icns’, which is a copy of Apple’s Terminal.app icon and as such is copyright of Apple.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (C) 2012-2017 Eloy Durán &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:eloy.de.enige@gmail.com&#34;&gt;eloy.de.enige@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, Julien Blanchard &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:julien@sideburns.eu&#34;&gt;julien@sideburns.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &#34;Software&#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &#34;AS IS&#34;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T01:41:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-13:/michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/michaeltyson/TPKeyboardAvoiding" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A drop-in universal solution for moving text fields out of the way of the keyboard in iOS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;TPKeyboardAvoiding&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A drop-in universal solution for moving text fields out of the way of the keyboard in iOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a hundred and one proposed solutions out there for how to move &lt;code&gt;UITextField&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UITextView&lt;/code&gt; out of the way of the keyboard during editing -- usually, it comes down to observing &lt;code&gt;UIKeyboardWillShowNotification&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UIKeyboardWillHideNotification&lt;/code&gt;, or implementing &lt;code&gt;UITextFieldDelegate&lt;/code&gt; delegate methods, and adjusting the frame of the superview, or using &lt;code&gt;UITableView&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s &lt;code&gt;scrollToRowAtIndexPath:atScrollPosition:animated:&lt;/code&gt;, but most proposed solutions tend to be quite DIY, and have to be implemented for each view controller that needs it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively universal, drop-in solution: &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;UITableView&lt;/code&gt; subclasses that handle everything.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the keyboard is about to appear, the subclass will find the subview that&#39;s about to be edited, and adjust its frame and content offset to make sure that view is visible, with an animation to match the keyboard pop-up. When the keyboard disappears, it restores its prior size.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It should work with basically any setup, either a UITableView-based interface, or one consisting of views placed manually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also automatically hooks up &#34;Next&#34; buttons on the keyboard to switch through the text fields.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For use with &lt;code&gt;UITableViewController&lt;/code&gt; classes, drop &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView.m&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView.h&lt;/code&gt; into your project, and make your UITableView a &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingTableView&lt;/code&gt; in the xib. If you&#39;re not using a xib with your controller, I know of no easy way to make its UITableView a custom class: The path of least resistance is to create a xib for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For non-UITableViewControllers, drop the &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView.m&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView.h&lt;/code&gt; source files into your project, pop a &lt;code&gt;UIScrollView&lt;/code&gt; into your view controller&#39;s xib, set the scroll view&#39;s class to &lt;code&gt;TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView&lt;/code&gt;, and put all your controls within that scroll view. You can also create it programmatically, without using a xib - just use the TPKeyboardAvoidingScrollView as your top-level view.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To disable the automatic &#34;Next&#34; button functionality, change the UITextField&#39;s return key type to anything but UIReturnKeyDefault.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These classes currently adjust the contentInset parameter to avoid content moving beneath the keyboard. This is done, as opposed to adjusting the frame, in order to work around an iOS bug that results in a jerky animation where the view jumps upwards, before settling down. In order to facilitate this workaround, the contentSize is maintained to be at least same size as the view&#39;s frame.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licence (Zlib)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2013 Michael Tyson&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is provided &#39;as-is&#39;, without any express or implied warranty. In no event will the authors be held liable for any damages arising from the use of this software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission is granted to anyone to use this software for any purpose, including commercial applications, and to alter it and redistribute it freely, subject to the following restrictions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The origin of this software must not be misrepresented; you must not claim that you wrote the original software. If you use this software in a product, an acknowledgment in the product documentation would be appreciated but is not required.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Altered source versions must be plainly marked as such, and must not be misrepresented as being the original software.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;This notice may not be removed or altered from any source distribution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Michael Tyson, A Tasty Pixel&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:michael@atastypixel.com&#34;&gt;michael@atastypixel.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push</title>
    <updated>2025-07-13T01:41:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-13:/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cordova plugin for CodePush&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Cordova support is retired in App Center&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check our &lt;a href=&#34;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/appcenter/announcing-apache-cordova-retirement/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Apache Cordova Plugin for CodePush&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This plugin provides client-side integration for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoft.github.io/code-push/&#34;&gt;CodePush service&lt;/a&gt;, allowing you to easily add a dynamic update experience to your Cordova app(s).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- Cordova Catalog --&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#supported-cordova-platforms&#34;&gt;Supported Cordova Platforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#deprecating-old-versions&#34;&gt;Deprecating old versions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#plugin-usage&#34;&gt;Plugin Usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#releasing-updates&#34;&gt;Releasing Updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#api-reference&#34;&gt;API Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#phonegap-build&#34;&gt;PhoneGap Build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#example-apps&#34;&gt;Example Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- Cordova Catalog --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Cordova app is composed of HTML, CSS and JavaScript files and any accompanying images, which are bundled together by the Cordova CLI and distributed as part of a platform-specific binary (i.e. an .ipa or .apk file). Once the app is released, updating either the code (e.g. making bug fixes, adding new features) or image assets, requires you to recompile and redistribute the entire binary, which of course, includes any review time associated with the store(s) you are publishing to.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CodePush plugin helps get product improvements in front of your end users instantly, by keeping your code and images synchronized with updates you release to the CodePush server. This way, your app gets the benefits of an offline mobile experience, as well as the &#34;web-like&#34; agility of side-loading updates as soon as they are available. It&#39;s a win-win!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure that your end users always have a functioning version of your app, the CodePush plugin maintains a copy of the previous update, so that in the event that you accidentally push an update which includes a crash, it can automatically roll back. This way, you can rest assured that your newfound release agility won&#39;t result in users becoming blocked before you have a chance to roll back on the server. It&#39;s a win-win-win!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Any product changes which touch native code (e.g. upgrading Cordova versions, adding a new plugin) cannot be distributed via CodePush, and therefore, must be updated via the appropriate store(s).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Supported Cordova Platforms&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cordova 5.0.0+ is fully supported, along with the following associated platforms:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-android&#34;&gt;cordova-android&lt;/a&gt; 4.0.0+) - &lt;em&gt;Including CrossWalk!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Note: Only on TLS 1.2 compatible devices&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;iOS (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-ios&#34;&gt;cordova-ios&lt;/a&gt; 3.9.0+) - please see notes below.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Note: Starting with v2.0.0 &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-code-push&lt;/code&gt; doesn&#39;t support apps using UIWebView due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/news/?id=12232019b&#34;&gt;Apple officially deprecated it and discourage developers from using it&lt;/a&gt;. Prior versions of the plugin still support UIWebView but be aware that the App Store will no longer accept new apps using UIWebView as of April 2020 and app updates using UIWebView as of December 2020.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Note: In order to use CodePush along with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; plugin, you need to install &lt;code&gt;v1.5.1-beta+&lt;/code&gt; version of &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-code-push&lt;/code&gt;, which includes full support for apps using either WebView. Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#using-wkwebview&#34;&gt;Using WKWebView&lt;/a&gt; section for more information of how to confiure your app to use &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To check which versions of each Cordova platform you are currently using, you can run the following command and inspect the &lt;code&gt;Installed platforms&lt;/code&gt; list:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cordova platform ls&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re running an older Android and/or iOS platform than is mentioned above, and would be open to upgrading, you can easily do so by running the following commands (omitting a platform if it isn&#39;t necessary):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cordova platform update android&#xA;cordova platform update ios&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Deprecating old versions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since CodePush is migrating to a new service all versions of cordova-plugin-code-push lower than &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/releases/tag/v1.12.0&#34;&gt;1.12.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will not work in the nearest future.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find more information in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/code-push/raw/master/migration-notice.md&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve followed the general-purpose &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/appcenter/distribution/codepush/&#34;&gt;&#34;getting started&#34;&lt;/a&gt; instructions for setting up your CodePush account, you can start CodePush-ifying your Cordova app by running the following command from within your app&#39;s root directory:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cordova plugin add cordova-plugin-code-push@latest&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the CodePush plugin installed, configure your app to use it via the following steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add your deployment keys to the &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, making sure to include the right key for each Cordova platform:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;platform name=&#34;android&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;preference name=&#34;CodePushDeploymentKey&#34; value=&#34;YOUR-ANDROID-DEPLOYMENT-KEY&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/platform&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;platform name=&#34;ios&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;    &amp;lt;preference name=&#34;CodePushDeploymentKey&#34; value=&#34;YOUR-IOS-DEPLOYMENT-KEY&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/platform&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a reminder, these keys are generated for you when you created your CodePush app via the CLI. If you need to retrieve them, you can simply run &lt;code&gt;appcenter codepush deployment list &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;appName&amp;gt; --displayKeys&lt;/code&gt;, and grab the key for the specific deployment you want to use (e.g. &lt;code&gt;Staging&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Production&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: You &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/appcenter/distribution/codepush/cli#releasing-updates&#34;&gt;must&lt;/a&gt; create a separate CodePush app for iOS and Android, which is why the above sample illustrates declaring separate keys for Android and iOS. If you&#39;re only developing for a single platform, then you only need to specify the deployment key for either Android or iOS, so you don&#39;t need to add the additional &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element as illustrated above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beginning from version &lt;strong&gt;1.10.0&lt;/strong&gt; you can sign your update bundles (for more information about code signing please refer to relevant documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/code-push/raw/master/cli/README.md#code-signing&#34;&gt;section&lt;/a&gt;). In order to enable code signing for Cordova application you should setup public key to verify bundles signature by providing following &lt;code&gt;preference&lt;/code&gt; setting in &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;platform name=&#34;android&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;   ...&#xA;   &amp;lt;preference name=&#34;CodePushPublicKey&#34; value=&#34;YOUR-PUBLIC-KEY&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/platform&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;platform name=&#34;ios&#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;   ...&#xA;   &amp;lt;preference name=&#34;CodePushPublicKey&#34; value=&#34;YOUR-PUBLIC-KEY&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/platform&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can use the same private/public key pair for each platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re using an &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;access origin=&#34;*&#34; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element in your &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, then your app is already allowed to communicate with the CodePush servers and you can safely skip this step. Otherwise, add the following additional &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;access /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;access origin=&#34;https://codepush.appcenter.ms&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;access origin=&#34;https://codepush.blob.core.windows.net&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;access origin=&#34;https://codepushupdates.azureedge.net&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To ensure that your app can access the CodePush server on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Security/CSP/Introducing_Content_Security_Policy&#34;&gt;CSP&lt;/a&gt;-compliant platforms, add &lt;code&gt;https://codepush.appcenter.ms&lt;/code&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;Content-Security-Policy&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;meta&lt;/code&gt; tag in your &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;Content-Security-Policy&#34; content=&#34;default-src https://codepush.appcenter.ms &#39;self&#39; data: gap: https://ssl.gstatic.com &#39;unsafe-eval&#39;; style-src &#39;self&#39; &#39;unsafe-inline&#39;; media-src *&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, double-check that you already have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-plugin-whitelist&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-whitelist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; plugin installed (most apps will). To check this, simply run the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cordova plugin ls&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;If &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-whitelist&lt;/code&gt; is in the list, then you are good to go. Otherwise, simply run the following command to add it:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cordova plugin add cordova-plugin-whitelist&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to use the plugin in the application code. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/samples&#34;&gt;sample applications&lt;/a&gt; for examples and the API documentation for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Using WKWebView&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For cordova-ios v4-v5 there is a possibility to specify WebView engine on the plugin build phase. By default UIWebView engine is used. To use WKWebView engine please do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine#installation&#34;&gt;cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine#required-permissions&#34;&gt;Configure your app&lt;/a&gt; to use WKWebView&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&lt;/code&gt; is just a workaround for cordova-ios v4-v5 users to be able to use WKWebView in their apps to avoid stop accepting updates via AppStore as of December 2020. Cordova-ios v6+ has full support for native WKWebView and doesn&#39;t require &lt;code&gt;cordova-plugin-wkwebview-engine&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Plugin Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the CodePush plugin installed and configured, the only thing left is to add the necessary code to your app to control the following policies:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When (and how often) to check for an update? (e.g. app start, in response to clicking a button in a settings page, periodically at some fixed interval)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When an update is available, how to present it to the end user?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to do this is to perform the following in your app&#39;s &lt;code&gt;deviceready&lt;/code&gt; event handler:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.sync();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an update is available, it will be silently downloaded, and installed the next time the app is restarted (either explicitly by the end user or by the OS), which ensures the least invasive experience for your end users. If an available update is mandatory, then it will be installed immediately, ensuring that the end user gets it as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like your app to discover updates more quickly, you can also choose to call &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; every time the app resumes from the background, by adding the following code (or something equivalent) as part of your app&#39;s startup behavior. You can call &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; as frequently as you would like, so when and where you call it just depends on your personal preference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;document.addEventListener(&#34;resume&#34;, function () {&#xA;    codePush.sync();&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you would like to display an update confirmation dialog (an &#34;active install&#34;), configure when an available update is installed (e.g. force an immediate restart) or customize the update experience in any way, refer to the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; method&#39;s API reference for information on how to tweak this default behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: While &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/programs/ios/information&#34;&gt;Apple&#39;s developer agreement&lt;/a&gt; fully allows performing over-the-air updates of JavaScript and assets (which is what enables CodePush!), it is against their policy for an app to display an update prompt. Because of this, we recommend that App Store-distributed apps don&#39;t enable the &lt;code&gt;updateDialog&lt;/code&gt; option when calling &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt;, whereas Google Play and internally distributed apps (e.g. Enterprise, Fabric, HockeyApp) can choose to enable/customize it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Releasing Updates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once your app has been configured and distributed to your users, and you&#39;ve made some code and/or asset changes, it&#39;s time to instantly release them! The simplest (and recommended) way to do this is to use the &lt;code&gt;release-cordova&lt;/code&gt; command in the App Center CLI, which will handle preparing and releasing your update to the CodePush server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: Before you can start releasing updates, please log into App Center by running the &lt;code&gt;appcenter login&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In it&#39;s the most basic form, this command only requires one parameter: your owner name + &#34;/&#34; + app name.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;appName&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-ios&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-Android&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: When releasing updates to CodePush, you do not need to bump your app&#39;s version in the &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, since you aren&#39;t modifying the binary version at all. You only need to bump this version when you upgrade Cordova and/or one of your plugins, at which point, you need to release an update to the native store(s). CodePush will automatically generate a &#34;label&#34; for each release you make (e.g. &lt;code&gt;v3&lt;/code&gt;) in order to help identify it within your release history.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;release-cordova&lt;/code&gt; command enables such a simple workflow because it understands the standard layout of a Cordova app, and therefore, can generate your update and know exactly which files to upload. Additionally, in order to support flexible release strategies, the &lt;code&gt;release-cordova&lt;/code&gt; command exposes numerous optional parameters that let you customize how the update should be distributed to your end users (e.g. Which binary versions are compatible with it? Should the release be viewed as mandatory?).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# Release a mandatory update with a changelog&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-ios -m --description &#34;Modified the header color&#34;&#xA;&#xA;# Release a dev Android build to just 1/4 of your end users&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-android --rollout 25&#xA;&#xA;# Release an update that targets users running any 1.1.* binary, as opposed to&#xA;# limiting the update to exact version name in the config.xml file&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-android --target-binary-version &#34;~1.1.0&#34;&#xA;&#xA;# Release an update now but mark it as disabled&#xA;# so that no users can download it yet&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-ios -x&#xA;&#xA;# Release an update signed by private key (public key should be configured for application)&#xA;appcenter codepush release-cordova -a &amp;lt;ownerName&amp;gt;/MyApp-android --private-key-path ~/rsa/private_key.pem&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CodePush client supports differential updates, so even though you are releasing your app code on every update, your end users will only actually download the files they need. The service handles this automatically so that you can focus on creating awesome apps and we can worry about optimizing end user downloads.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: for &lt;strong&gt;Ionic&lt;/strong&gt; apps you need to run &lt;code&gt;ionic build&lt;/code&gt; before running &lt;code&gt;cordova-release&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; command in order to build web assets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more details about how the &lt;code&gt;release-cordova&lt;/code&gt; command works, as well as the various parameters it exposes, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/appcenter/distribution/codepush/cli#releasing-updates-cordova&#34;&gt;CLI docs&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, if you would prefer to handle running the &lt;code&gt;cordova prepare&lt;/code&gt; command yourself, and therefore, want an even more flexible solution than &lt;code&gt;release-cordova&lt;/code&gt;, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/appcenter/distribution/codepush/cli#releasing-updates-general&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;release&lt;/code&gt; command&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you run into any issues, or have any questions/comments/feedback, you can &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:codepushfeed@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;e-mail us&lt;/a&gt; and/or open a new issue on this repo and we&#39;ll respond ASAP!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;API Reference&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CodePush API is exposed to your app via the global &lt;code&gt;codePush&lt;/code&gt; object, which is available after the &lt;code&gt;deviceready&lt;/code&gt; event fires. This API exposes the following top-level methods:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushcheckforupdate&#34;&gt;checkForUpdate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Asks the CodePush service whether the configured app deployment has an update available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushgetcurrentpackage&#34;&gt;getCurrentPackage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Retrieves the metadata about the currently installed update (e.g. description, installation time, size).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushgetpendingpackage&#34;&gt;getPendingPackage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Retrieves the metadata for an update (if one exists) that was downloaded and installed, but hasn&#39;t been applied yet via a restart.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushnotifyapplicationready&#34;&gt;notifyApplicationReady&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Notifies the CodePush runtime that an installed update is considered successful. If you are manually checking for and installing updates (i.e. not using the sync method to handle it all for you), then this method &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; be called; otherwise CodePush will treat the update as failed and rollback to the previous version when the app next restarts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushrestartapplication&#34;&gt;restartApplication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Immediately restarts the app. If there is an update pending, it will be immediately displayed to the end user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushsync&#34;&gt;sync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows checking for an update, downloading it and installing it, all with a single call. Unless you need custom UI and/or behavior, we recommend most developers to use this method when integrating CodePush into their apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the following objects and enums are also exposed globally as part of the CodePush API:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#installmode&#34;&gt;InstallMode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Defines the available install modes for updates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#localpackage&#34;&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Contains information about a locally installed package.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#remotepackage&#34;&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Contains information about an update package available for download.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#syncstatus&#34;&gt;SyncStatus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Defines the possible intermediate and result statuses of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushsync&#34;&gt;sync&lt;/a&gt; operation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.checkForUpdate&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.checkForUpdate(onSuccess, onError?, deploymentKey?: String);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Queries the CodePush service to see whether the configured app deployment has an update available. By default, it will use the deployment key that is configured in your &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, but you can override that by specifying a value via the optional &lt;code&gt;deploymentKey&lt;/code&gt; parameter. This can be useful when you want to dynamically &#34;redirect&#34; a user to a specific deployment, such as allowing &#34;Early access&#34; via an easter egg or a user setting switch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the update check completes, it will trigger the &lt;code&gt;onUpdateCheck&lt;/code&gt; callback with one of two possible values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; if there is no update available. This occurs in the following scenarios:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The configured deployment doesn&#39;t contain any releases, and therefore, nothing to update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The latest release within the configured deployment is targeting a different binary version than what you&#39;re currently running (either older or newer).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The currently running app already has the latest release from the configured deployment, and therefore, doesn&#39;t need it again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/code&gt; instance which represents an available update that can be inspected and/or subsequently downloaded.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parameters:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onSuccess&lt;/strong&gt;: Callback that is invoked upon receiving a successful response from the server. The callback receives a single parameter, which is described above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onError&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional callback that is invoked in the event of an error. The callback takes one error parameter, containing the details of the error.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deploymentKey&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional deployment key that overrides the &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; setting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.checkForUpdate(function (update) {&#xA;    if (!update) {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;The app is up to date.&#34;);&#xA;    } else {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;An update is available! Should we download it?&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.getCurrentPackage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.getCurrentPackage(onSuccess, onError?);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Retrieves the metadata about the currently installed &#34;package&#34; (e.g. description, installation time). This can be useful for scenarios such as displaying a &#34;what&#39;s new?&#34; dialog after an update has been applied or checking whether there is a pending update that is waiting to be applied via a resume or restart.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the update retrieval completes, it will trigger the &lt;code&gt;onSuccess&lt;/code&gt; callback with one of two possible values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; if the app is currently running the HTML start page from the binary and not a CodePush update. This occurs in the following scenarios:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The end-user installed the app binary and has yet to install a CodePush update&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The end-user installed an update of the binary (e.g. from the store), which cleared away the old CodePush updates, and gave precedence back to the binary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/code&gt; instance which represents the metadata for the currently running CodePush update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parameters:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onSuccess&lt;/strong&gt;: Callback that is invoked upon receiving the metadata about the currently running update. The callback receives a single parameter, which is described above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onError&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional callback that is invoked in the event of an error. The callback takes one error parameter, containing the details of the error.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.getCurrentPackage(function (update) {&#xA;    if (!update) {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;No updates have been installed&#34;);&#xA;        return;&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    // If the current app &#34;session&#34; represents the first time&#xA;    // this update has run, and it had a description provided&#xA;    // with it upon release, let&#39;s show it to the end user&#xA;    if (update.isFirstRun &amp;amp;&amp;amp; update.description) {&#xA;        // Display a &#34;what&#39;s new?&#34; modal&#xA;    }&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.getPendingPackage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.getPendingPackage(onSuccess, onError?);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gets the metadata for the currently pending update (if one exists). An update is considered &#34;pending&#34; if it has been downloaded and installed, but hasn&#39;t been applied yet via an app restart. An update could only ever be in this state if &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESTART&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME&lt;/code&gt; were specified upon calling &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage.install&lt;/code&gt;, and the app hasn&#39;t yet been restarted or resumed (respectively). This method can be useful if you&#39;d like to determine whether there is a pending update and then prompt the user if they would like to restart now (via &lt;code&gt;codePush.restartApplication&lt;/code&gt;) in order to apply it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the update retrieval completes, it will trigger the &lt;code&gt;onSuccess&lt;/code&gt; callback with one of two possible values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; if the app doesn&#39;t currently have a pending update (e.g. the app is already running the latest available version).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/code&gt; instance which represents the metadata for the currently pending CodePush update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parameters:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onSuccess&lt;/strong&gt;: Callback that is invoked upon receiving the metadata about the currently pending update. The callback receives a single parameter, which is described above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;onError&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional callback that is invoked in the event of an error. The callback takes one error parameter, containing the details of the error.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.getPendingPackage(function (update) {&#xA;    if (update) {&#xA;        // An update is currently pending, ask the&#xA;        // user if they would like to restart&#xA;    }&#xA;});&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.notifyApplicationReady&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.notifyApplicationReady(notifySucceeded?, notifyFailed?);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notifies the CodePush runtime that a freshly installed update should be considered successful, and therefore, an automatic client-side rollback isn&#39;t necessary. It is mandatory to call this function somewhere in the code of the updated bundle. Otherwise, when the app next restarts, the CodePush runtime will assume that the installed update has failed and roll back to the previous version. This behavior exists to help ensure that your end users aren&#39;t blocked by a broken update.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; function, and doing your update check on app start, then you don&#39;t need to manually call &lt;code&gt;notifyApplicationReady&lt;/code&gt; since &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; will call it for you. This behavior exists due to the assumption that the point at which &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; is called in your app represents a good approximation of a successful startup.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parameters:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notifySucceeded&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional callback invoked if the plugin was successfully notified.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;notifyFailed&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional callback invoked in case of an error during notifying the plugin.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.restartApplication&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.restartApplication();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Immediately restarts the app. This method is for advanced scenarios, and is primarily useful when the following conditions are true:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Your app is specifying an install mode value of &lt;code&gt;ON_NEXT_RESTART&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ON_NEXT_RESUME&lt;/code&gt; when calling the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage.install&lt;/code&gt; methods. This has the effect of not applying your update until the app has been restarted (by either the end user or OS) or resumed, and therefore, the update won&#39;t be immediately displayed to the end user.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You have an app-specific user event (e.g. the end user navigated back to the app&#39;s home route) that allows you to apply the update in an unobtrusive way, and potentially gets the update in front of the end user sooner then waiting until the next restart or resume.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;codePush.sync&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;codePush.sync(syncCallback?, syncOptions?, downloadProgress?, syncErrback?);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Synchronizes your app&#39;s code and images with the latest release to the configured deployment. Unlike the &lt;code&gt;checkForUpdate&lt;/code&gt; method, which simply checks for the presence of an update, and let&#39;s you control what to do next, &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; handles the update check, download and installation experience for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This method provides support for two different (but customizable) &#34;modes&#34; to easily enable apps with different requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silent mode&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(the default behavior)&lt;/em&gt;, which automatically downloads available updates, and applies them the next time the app restarts (e.g. the OS or end user killed it, or the device was restarted). This way, the entire update experience is &#34;silent&#34; to the end user, since they don&#39;t see any update prompt and/or &#34;synthetic&#34; app restarts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active mode&lt;/strong&gt;, which when an update is available, prompts the end user for permission before downloading it, and then immediately applies the update. If an update was released using the mandatory flag, the end user would still be notified about the update, but they wouldn&#39;t have the choice to ignore it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;// Fully silent update which keeps the app in&#xA;// sync with the server, without ever&#xA;// interrupting the end user&#xA;codePush.sync();&#xA;&#xA;// Active update, which lets the end user know&#xA;// about each update, and displays it to them&#xA;// immediately after downloading it&#xA;codePush.sync(null, { updateDialog: true, installMode: InstallMode.IMMEDIATE });&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: If you want to decide whether you check and/or download an available update based on the end user&#39;s device battery level, network conditions, etc. then simply wrap the call to sync in a condition that ensures you only call it when desired.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the sync method tries to make it easy to perform silent and active updates with little configuration, it accepts the following optional parameters which allow you to customize numerous aspects of the default behavior mentioned above:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syncCallback&lt;/strong&gt;: Called when the sync process moves from one stage to another in the overall update process. The method is called with a status code which represents the current state, and can be any of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#syncstatus&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SyncStatus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; values.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;syncOptions&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#syncoptions&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;SyncOptions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; parameter configuring the behavior of the sync operation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;downloadProgress&lt;/strong&gt;: Called periodically when an available update is being downloaded from the CodePush server. The method is called with a &lt;code&gt;DownloadProgress&lt;/code&gt; object, which contains the following two properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;totalBytes&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Number)&lt;/em&gt; - The total number of bytes expected to be received for this update (i.e. the size of the set of files which changed from the previous release).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;receivedBytes&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Number)&lt;/em&gt; - The number of bytes downloaded thus far, which can be used to track download progress.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;SyncOptions&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; method tries to make it easy to perform silent and active updates with little configuration, it accepts an &#34;options&#34; object that allows you to customize numerous aspects of the default behavior mentioned above:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deploymentKey&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - Specifies the deployment key you want to query for an update against. By default, this value is derived from the &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, but this option allows you to override it from the script-side if you need to dynamically use a different deployment for a specific call to &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;installMode&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(InstallMode)&lt;/em&gt; - Specifies when you would like to install optional updates (i.e. those that aren&#39;t marked as mandatory). Defaults to &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESTART&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#installmode&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;InstallMode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enum reference for a description of the available options and what they do.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mandatoryInstallMode&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(InstallMode)&lt;/em&gt; - Specifies when you would like to install updates which are marked as mandatory. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.IMMEDIATE&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#installmode&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;InstallMode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; enum reference for a description of the available options and what they do.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;minimumBackgroundDuration&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Number)&lt;/em&gt; - Specifies the minimum number of seconds that the app needs to have been in the background before restarting the app. This property only applies to updates which are installed using &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME&lt;/code&gt;, and can be useful for getting your update in front of end users sooner, without being too obtrusive. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, which has the effect of applying the update immediately after a resume, regardless how long it was in the background.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ignoreFailedUpdates&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt; - Specifies whether an available update should be ignored if it had been previously installed and rolled back on the client (because &lt;code&gt;notifyApplicationReady&lt;/code&gt; wasn&#39;t successfully called). Defaults to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;updateDialog&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(UpdateDialogOptions)&lt;/em&gt; - An &#34;options&#34; object used to determine whether a confirmation dialog should be displayed to the end user when an update is available, and if so, what strings to use. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;, which has the effect of disabling the dialog completely. Setting this to any truthy value will enable the dialog with the default strings, and passing an object to this parameter allows enabling the dialog as well as overriding one or more of the default strings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The following list represents the available options and their defaults:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;appendReleaseDescription&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt; - Indicates whether you would like to append the description of an available release to the notification message which is displayed to the end user. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;descriptionPrefix&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - Indicates the string you would like to prefix the release description with, if any, when displaying the update notification to the end user. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34; Description: &#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mandatoryContinueButtonLabel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;: The text to use for the button the end user must press in order to install a mandatory update. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;Continue&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mandatoryUpdateMessage&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - The text used as the body of an update notification, when the update is specified as mandatory. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;An update is available that must be installed.&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;optionalIgnoreButtonLabel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - The text to use for the button the end user can press in order to ignore an optional update that is available. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;Ignore&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;optionalInstallButtonLabel&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - The text to use for the button the end user can press in order to install an optional update. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;Install&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;optionalUpdateMessage&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - The text used as the body of an update notification, when the update is optional. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;An update is available. Would you like to install it?&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;updateTitle&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt; - The text used as the header of an update notification that is displayed to the end user. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;&#34;Update available&#34;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;// Download the update silently, but install it on&#xA;// the next resume, as long as at least 5 minutes&#xA;// has passed since the app was put into the background.&#xA;codePush.sync(null, { installMode: InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME, minimumBackgroundDuration: 60 * 5 });&#xA;&#xA;// Download the update silently, and install optional updates&#xA;// on the next restart, but install mandatory updates on the next resume.&#xA;codePush.sync(null, { mandatoryInstallMode: InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME });&#xA;&#xA;// Changing the title displayed in the&#xA;// confirmation dialog of an &#34;active&#34; update&#xA;codePush.sync(null, { updateDialog: { updateTitle: &#34;An update is available!&#34; } });&#xA;&#xA;// Displaying an update prompt which includes the&#xA;// description associated with the CodePush release&#xA;codePush.sync(null, {&#xA;   updateDialog: {&#xA;    appendReleaseDescription: true,&#xA;    descriptionPrefix: &#34;\n\nChange log:\n&#34;&#xA;   },&#xA;   installMode: InstallMode.IMMEDIATE&#xA;});&#xA;&#xA;// Silently check for the update, but&#xA;// display a custom downloading UI&#xA;// via the SyncStatus and DownloadProgress callbacks&#xA;codePush.sync(syncStatus, null, downloadProgress);&#xA;&#xA;function syncStatus(status) {&#xA;    switch (status) {&#xA;        case SyncStatus.DOWNLOADING_PACKAGE:&#xA;            // Show &#34;downloading&#34; modal&#xA;            break;&#xA;        case SyncStatus.INSTALLING_UPDATE:&#xA;            // Hide &#34;downloading&#34; modal&#xA;            break;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;function downloadProgress(downloadProgress) {&#xA;    if (downloadProgress) {&#xA;    &#x9;// Update &#34;downloading&#34; modal with current download %&#xA;        //console.log(&#34;Downloading &#34; + downloadProgress.receivedBytes + &#34; of &#34; + downloadProgress.totalBytes);&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; method can be called anywhere you&#39;d like to check for an update. That could be in the &lt;code&gt;deviceready&lt;/code&gt; event handler, the &lt;code&gt;click&lt;/code&gt; event of a button, in the callback of a periodic timer, or whatever else makes sense for your needs. Just like the &lt;code&gt;checkForUpdate&lt;/code&gt; method, it will perform the network request to check for an update in the background, so it won&#39;t impact your UI thread and/or JavaScript thread&#39;s responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Package objects&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;checkForUpdate&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;getCurrentPackage&lt;/code&gt; methods invoke success callbacks, that when triggered, provide access to &#34;package&#34; objects. The package represents your code update as well as any extra metadata (e.g. description, mandatory?). The CodePush API has the distinction between the following types of packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/code&gt;: Represents a downloaded update that is either already running, or has been installed and is pending an app restart.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/code&gt;: Represents an available update on the CodePush server that hasn&#39;t been downloaded yet.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contains details about an update that has been downloaded locally or already installed. You can get a reference to an instance of this object either by calling the &lt;code&gt;codePush.getCurrentPackage&lt;/code&gt; method, or as the value provided to the success callback of the &lt;code&gt;RemotePackage.download&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Properties&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;appVersion&lt;/strong&gt;: The native version of the application this package update is intended for. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;deploymentKey&lt;/strong&gt;: Deployment key of the package. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;description&lt;/strong&gt;: The description of the update. This is the same value that you specified in the CLI when you released the update. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;failedInstall&lt;/strong&gt;: Indicates whether this update has been previously installed but was rolled back. The &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; method will automatically ignore updates which have previously failed, so you only need to worry about this property if using &lt;code&gt;checkForUpdate&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;isFirstRun&lt;/strong&gt;: Flag indicating if the current application run is the first one after the package was applied. &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;isMandatory&lt;/strong&gt;: Indicates whether the update is considered mandatory. This is the value that was specified in the CLI when the update was released. &lt;em&gt;(Boolean)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;label&lt;/strong&gt;: The internal label automatically given to the update by the CodePush server, such as &lt;code&gt;v5&lt;/code&gt;. This value uniquely identifies the update within it&#39;s deployment. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;packageHash&lt;/strong&gt;: The SHA hash value of the update. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;packageSize&lt;/strong&gt;: The size of the code contained within the update, in bytes. &lt;em&gt;(Number)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Methods&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;install(installSuccess, installError, installOptions)&lt;/strong&gt;: Installs this package to the application. The install behavior is dependent on the provided &lt;code&gt;installOptions&lt;/code&gt;. By default, the update package is silently installed and the application is reloaded with the new content on the next application start. On the first run after the update, the application will wait for a &lt;code&gt;codePush.notifyApplicationReady()&lt;/code&gt; call. Once this call is made, the install operation is considered a success. Otherwise, the install operation will be marked as failed, and the application is reverted to its previous version on the next run.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h6&gt;InstallOptions&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;p&gt;Interface defining several options for customizing install operation behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;installMode&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to specify the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#installmode&#34;&gt;InstallMode&lt;/a&gt; used for the install operation. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESTART&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mandatoryInstallMode&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to specify the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#installmode&#34;&gt;InstallMode&lt;/a&gt; used for the install operation if the package is mandatory. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.IMMEDIATE&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;minimumBackgroundDuration&lt;/strong&gt;: If &lt;strong&gt;installMode&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;code&gt;InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME&lt;/code&gt;, used to specify the amount of time the app must be in the background before the update is installed when it is resumed. Defaults to &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;// App version 1 (current version)&#xA;&#xA;var onError = function (error) {&#xA;    console.log(&#34;An error occurred. &#34; + error);&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onInstallSuccess = function () {&#xA;    console.log(&#34;Installation succeeded.&#34;);&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onPackageDownloaded = function (localPackage) {&#xA;    // Install regular updates after someone navigates away from the app for more than 2 minutes&#xA;    // Install mandatory updates after someone restarts the app&#xA;    localPackage.install(onInstallSuccess, onError, { installMode: InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESUME, minimumBackgroundDuration: 120, mandatoryInstallMode: InstallMode.ON_NEXT_RESTART });&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onUpdateCheck = function (remotePackage) {&#xA;    if (!remotePackage) {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;The application is up to date.&#34;);&#xA;    } else {&#xA;        // The hash of each previously reverted package is stored for later use.&#xA;        // This way, we avoid going into an infinite bad update/revert loop.&#xA;        if (!remotePackage.failedInstall) {&#xA;            console.log(&#34;A CodePush update is available. Package hash: &#34; + remotePackage.packageHash);&#xA;            remotePackage.download(onPackageDownloaded, onError);&#xA;        } else {&#xA;            console.log(&#34;The available update was attempted before and failed.&#34;);&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;window.codePush.checkForUpdate(onUpdateCheck, onError);&#xA;&#xA;//------------------------------------------------&#xA;&#xA;// App version 2 (updated version)&#xA;&#xA;var app = {&#xA;    onDeviceReady: function () {&#xA;        // Calling this function is required during the first application run after an update.&#xA;        // If not called, the application will be reverted to the previous version.&#xA;        window.codePush.notifyApplicationReady();&#xA;        // ...&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For an example on how you are protected against a bad update, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushnotifyapplicationready&#34;&gt;notifyApplicationReady() documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contains details about an update that is available for download from the CodePush server. You get a reference to an instance of this object by calling the &lt;code&gt;codePush.checkForUpdate&lt;/code&gt; method when an update is available. If you are using the sync API, you don&#39;t need to worry about the &lt;code&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/code&gt;, since it will handle the download and installation process automatically for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Properties&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;RemotePackage&lt;/code&gt; inherits all of the same properties as the &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/code&gt;, but includes one additional one:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;downloadUrl&lt;/strong&gt;: The URL at which the package is available for download. This property is only needed for advanced usage, since the &lt;code&gt;download&lt;/code&gt; method will automatically handle the acquisition of updates for you. &lt;em&gt;(String)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;Methods&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;abortDownload(abortSuccess, abortError)&lt;/strong&gt;: Aborts the current download session, if any.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;download(downloadSuccess, downloadError, downloadProgress)&lt;/strong&gt;: Downloads the package update from the CodePush service. The &lt;code&gt;downloadSuccess&lt;/code&gt; callback is invoked with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#localpackage&#34;&gt;LocalPackage&lt;/a&gt; argument, representing the downloaded package. The optional &lt;code&gt;downloadProgress&lt;/code&gt; callback is invoked several times during the download progress with one &lt;code&gt;DownloadProgress&lt;/code&gt; parameter.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h6&gt;DownloadProgress&lt;/h6&gt; &lt;p&gt;Defines the format of the DownloadProgress object, used to send periodical update notifications on the progress of the update download.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Properties&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;totalBytes&lt;/strong&gt;: The size of the downloading update package, in bytes. (Number)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;receivedBytes&lt;/strong&gt;: The number of bytes already downloaded. (Number)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;var onError = function (error) {&#xA;    console.log(&#34;An error occurred. &#34; + error);&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onPackageDownloaded = function (localPackage) {&#xA;    console.log(&#34;Package downloaded at: &#34; + localPackage.localPath);&#xA;    // you can now update your application to the downloaded version by calling localPackage.install()&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onProgress = function (downloadProgress) {&#xA;    console.log(&#34;Downloading &#34; + downloadProgress.receivedBytes + &#34; of &#34; + downloadProgress.totalBytes + &#34; bytes.&#34;);&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;var onUpdateCheck = function (remotePackage) {&#xA;    if (!remotePackage) {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;The application is up to date.&#34;);&#xA;    } else {&#xA;        console.log(&#34;A CodePush update is available. Package hash: &#34; + remotePackage.packageHash);&#xA;        remotePackage.download(onPackageDownloaded, onError, onProgress);&#xA;    }&#xA;};&#xA;&#xA;window.codePush.checkForUpdate(onUpdateCheck, onError);&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enums&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CodePush API includes the following &#34;enum&#34; objects which can be used to customize the update experience, and are available globally off of the &lt;code&gt;window&lt;/code&gt; object:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;InstallMode&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This enum specified when you would like an installed update to actually be applied, and can be passed to either the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage.install&lt;/code&gt; methods. It includes the following values:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMMEDIATE&lt;/strong&gt;: The update will be applied to the running application immediately. The application will be reloaded with the new content immediately.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ON_NEXT_RESTART&lt;/strong&gt;: Indicates that you want to install the update, but not forcibly restart the app. When the app is &#34;naturally&#34; restarted (due the OS or end user killing it), the update will be seamlessly picked up. This value is appropriate when performing silent updates, since it would likely be disruptive to the end user if the app suddenly restarted out of nowhere, since they wouldn&#39;t have realized an update was even downloaded. This is the default mode used for both the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;LocalPackage.install&lt;/code&gt; methods.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ON_NEXT_RESUME&lt;/strong&gt;: Indicates that you want to install the update, but don&#39;t want to restart the app until the next time the end user resumes it from the background. This way, you don&#39;t disrupt their current session, but you can get the update in front of them sooner then having to wait for the next natural restart. This value is appropriate for silent installs that can be applied on resume in a non-invasive way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;SyncStatus&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Defines the possible statuses of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/cordova-plugin-code-push/master/#codepushsync&#34;&gt;sync&lt;/a&gt; operation. There are two categories of statuses: intermediate and result (final). The intermediate statuses represent progress statuses of the sync operation, and are not final. The result statuses represent final statuses of the sync operation. Every sync operation ends with only one result status, but can have zero or more intermediate statuses.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UP_TO_DATE&lt;/strong&gt;: The app is fully up-to-date with the configured deployment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE_INSTALLED&lt;/strong&gt;: An available update has been installed and will be run either immediately after the callback function returns or the next time the app resumes/restarts, depending on the &lt;code&gt;InstallMode&lt;/code&gt; specified in &lt;code&gt;SyncOptions&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE_IGNORED&lt;/strong&gt;: The app has an optional update, which the end user chose to ignore. &lt;em&gt;(This is only applicable when the &lt;code&gt;updateDialog&lt;/code&gt; is used)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ERROR&lt;/strong&gt;: An error occurred during the &lt;code&gt;sync&lt;/code&gt; operation. This might be an error while communicating with the server, downloading or unzipping the update. The console logs should contain more information about what happened. No update has been applied in this case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IN_PROGRESS&lt;/strong&gt;: Another sync is already running, so this attempt to sync has been aborted.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CHECKING_FOR_UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: The CodePush server is being queried for an update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWAITING_USER_ACTION&lt;/strong&gt;: An update is available, and a confirmation dialog was shown to the end user. &lt;em&gt;(This is only applicable when the &lt;code&gt;updateDialog&lt;/code&gt; is used)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DOWNLOADING_PACKAGE&lt;/strong&gt;: An available update is being downloaded from the CodePush server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INSTALLING_UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: An available update was downloaded and is about to be installed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;PhoneGap Build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This plugin is compatible with &lt;a href=&#34;https://build.phonegap.com&#34;&gt;PhoneGap Build&lt;/a&gt;, and supports creating Android and iOS builds out-of-the-box. However, in order for CodePush to calculate the hash of your binary contents on Android, PhoneGap Build needs to use Gradle to build your app, which isn&#39;t its default behavior (it uses Ant). To resolve this, simply add the following element to your app&#39;s &lt;code&gt;config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, as a child of the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;platform name=&#34;android&#34;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;preference name=&#34;android-build-tool&#34; value=&#34;gradle&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example Apps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Cordova community has graciously created some awesome open source apps that can serve as examples for developers that are getting started. The following is a list of OSS Cordova apps that are also using CodePush, and can therefore be used to see how others are using the service:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rangle/pgdays-codepush-demo&#34;&gt;PGDay CodePush Demo&lt;/a&gt; - Demo app created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://rangle.io&#34;&gt;Rangle.io&lt;/a&gt; used for &lt;a href=&#34;http://pgday.phonegap.com/eu2016/&#34;&gt;PhoneGap Day Europe 2016&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: If you&#39;ve developed a Cordova app using CodePush, that is also open-source, please let us know. We would love to add it to this list!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>