<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-22T01:57:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HyangZhao/Quicksilver</title>
    <updated>2023-10-22T01:57:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-22:/HyangZhao/Quicksilver</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HyangZhao/Quicksilver" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quicksilver Mac OS X Project Source&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About Quicksilver B5X on Github&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the current source code of Quicksilver. If you&#39;re having issues with the latest Quicksilver version, feel free to log them at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/tiennou/blacktree-alchemy/issues&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The B5X branch contains the source for the currently released Quicksilver. The master branch contains the code for the &#34;next-gen&#34; Quicksilver. Right now it features an updated plugin system, and Catalyst, which aims to provide triggers as a preference pane, and that&#39;s it. It is usable, but all plugins are incompatible without some extra work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want more info about &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quicksilver_%28software%29&#34; title=&#34;Quicksilver Wikipedia article&#34;&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/a&gt; just do a search on YouTube - there&#39;s tons of very helpful instructional and informational video tutorials. Or visit the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/blacktree-quicksilver&#34; title=&#34;Quicksilver Google Group&#34;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; hosted at Google Groups.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Where to find it ?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go look on the download pages around. The &#34;most official&#34; one is &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/tiennou/blacktree-alchemy/downloads&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but there are some &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/andreberg/blacktree-alchemy/downloads&#34;&gt;others&lt;/a&gt;. Choose the one with the biggest number ;-).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Before You Try It Out&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before trying out new Quicksilver versions &lt;strong&gt;ALWAYS BACKUP&lt;/strong&gt; your user data!&lt;br&gt; This is easily done by backing up the following folders&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; stands for your short user name):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/Users/&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;/Library/Application Support/Quicksilver&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;/Users/&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;/Library/Caches/Quicksilver&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;and just to be safe, let&#39;s also backup the present&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/Applications/Quicksilver.app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;before you overwrite it with this version.&lt;br&gt; Now if anything happens you can always restore the exact state Quicksilver was in before your were trying out this version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Facts, Features and Fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest change first and foremost:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Minimum runtime requirement for this version is Mac OS X 10.5 (&#34;Leopard&#34;). &#xA;There are no plans for supporting Mac OS X 10.4 (&#34;Tiger&#34;).&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following is a short, assorted list of facts and enhancements you may find in this version.&lt;br&gt; For a more comprehensive list take a look at the commit messages.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Default compiler changed to Clang, Apple&#39;s and the Open Source community&#39;s next gen compiler.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;By doing that a 20 to 40% increase in runtime speed was gained while managing a catalog library with approx. 13k items. Quicksilver also feels a lot snappier too. This, of course, is mostly subjective (read: YMMV).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Actions should now appear localized again where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;(e.g. &#39;Copy to...&#39; for example in German could also be typed as &#39;Bewegen nach...&#39; or &#39;Open&#39; as &#39;Ouvrir&#39; in French.&lt;br&gt; .lproj folders for English, French, Italian, German, Spanish, Danish, Finish, Norwegian, Polish, and Swedish have been included. Mind you, the end result really depends on how Mac OS X handles this in the target language as Quicksilver just asks the OS for the localized representation of some common actions).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Composed characters like German umlauts (e.g. &#39;ä&#39;) will now show both parts (the letter &#39;a&#39; and the &#39;dots&#39;. Previously only letters would show up).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The broken action menu now shows up with a cross-selection of all enabled actions from the Actions preferences.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Smart Replace and Replace dialog actions no longer crash Quicksilver and will now actually append numbers via a smart numbering system if a file to be copied or moved already exists at the destination.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to use the Smart Replace dialog you will need to set the feature level equal to or higher than 3.To do that enter the following &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; into the Terminal and press Return: &lt;code&gt;defaults write com.blacktree.Quicksilver &#34;Feature Level&#34; 3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;File operation requiring credentials no longer crash QS after providing the password.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Large Type action now keeps the text visible again for prolonged periods.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Icons associated with custom file actions (e.g. like custom AppleScript actions) are now correctly displayed instead of a generic file placeholder icon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;AppleScript actions which return something now cause Quicksilver to reappear again ready to use the result for the next action.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mouse tracking for triggers (&#39;Mouse entered&#39; / &#39;Mouse exited&#39;) now seems to work more reliably.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Extras pref pane no longer has a row spacing issue upon first loading of the associated NIB file.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Excessive log outputs have been silenced to only occur if certain debugging environment variables are set in order to avoid spamming the Console.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Dozens of API upgrades like replacing deprecated methods with safer variants or adding declaration names for the new way of handling informal protocols.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All NIB files were converted to a SCM and collaboration friendly XIB format. A lot of clipping warnings have been fixed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Triggers with wierd keys (like Function keys) are now displayed again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Updated French and German localization.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Various other housekeeping tasks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes Specific to Snow Leopard&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Snow Leopard has a reworked Services system. This is relevant because preferences like &lt;em&gt;&#34;Pull selection from front application instead of Finder&#34;&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;code&gt;Preferences &amp;gt; Extras&lt;/code&gt;) make use of two services called &lt;em&gt;&#34;Get Current Selection&#34;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&#34;Send to Quicksilver&#34;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It appears that these services will not register properly when the pasteboard server (&lt;code&gt;/System/Library/CoreServices/pbs&lt;/code&gt;) sees multiple Quicksilver.app packages each with their very own Info.plist file defining the same services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The result is that none of the services for any Quicksilver.app will register and thus the default Cmd + Esc hotkey combo won&#39;t do anything much no matter which application is currrently frontmost. The solution to this is to zip any old Quicksilver.app packages you want to keep around and delete every Quicksilver.app package except the one you want to run. Also do not forget to empty your trash after you deleted the older Quicksilver.app packages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should be able to build Quicksilver by opening the project file with Xcode and pressing &#34;Build&#34;. Be aware that the build system &lt;strong&gt;will overwrite&lt;/strong&gt; the Quicksilver located in your /Applications folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;A Few Notes on Working With Git&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following (non-exhaustive) list shows files which need to be treated specially within git:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/Bezel/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/Finder/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/PrimerInterface/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/QSHotKeyPlugIn/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is because they change each time the project is built (e.g. the hexadecimal build number is updated by &#39;bltrversion&#39; for each plugin).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t just remove them from the project and add them to the repository-wide .gitignore file because we still need to push those files up to the remote so that another developer will get them when he/she clones the project. Also because this project was converted from SVN we can&#39;t just tell everyone to add those files to their personal repository-wide exclude file (in .git/info/exclude) and be done with it. If the file is already tracked adding it to any ignore file won&#39;t keep git from tracking it (gitignore(5) has more info on that).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;What we need is to tell git to just keep the initial version in the repository but not track any changes.&lt;br&gt; The following commands seem to do just that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git update-index --assume-unchanged Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/Bezel/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;git update-index --assume-unchanged Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/Finder/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;git update-index --assume-unchanged Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/PrimerInterface/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;git update-index --assume-unchanged Quicksilver/PlugIns-Main/QSHotKeyPlugIn/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will keep git from noticing any changes but will still keep it (do a &lt;code&gt;git-ls-files | grep QSHotKeyPlugIn/Info.plist&lt;/code&gt; to confirm).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to make changes to any of those files and you need these changes visible for others to clone then you must revert the commands issued above before commiting.&lt;br&gt; To do so just run the commands again but this time with &lt;code&gt;--no-assume-unchanged&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PS.: If any of the git veterans has a better way of handling this please send me a message to my (andreberg) github inbox.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Legal Stuff&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading and/or using this software you agree to the following terms of use:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;);&#xA;you may not use this software except in compliance with the License.&#xA;You may obtain a copy of the License at&#xA;&#xA;  http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#xA;&#xA;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software&#xA;distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS,&#xA;WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.&#xA;See the License for the specific language governing permissions and&#xA;limitations under the License.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which basically means: whatever you do, I can&#39;t be held accountable if something breaks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>frijole/gifbook</title>
    <updated>2023-10-22T01:57:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-22:/frijole/gifbook</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/frijole/gifbook" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;a rough gif viewer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder</title>
    <updated>2023-10-22T01:57:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-22:/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A SVG coder plugin for SDWebImage, using Apple&#39;s built-in framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/travis/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;CI Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org/pods/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/cocoapods/v/SDWebImageSVGCoder.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org/pods/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/cocoapods/l/SDWebImageSVGCoder.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org/pods/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/cocoapods/p/SDWebImageSVGCoder.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Platform&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Carthage-compatible-4BC51D.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Carthage compatible&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently SDWebImage org provide 3 kinds of SVG Coder Plugin support, here is comparison:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Plugin Name&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Vector Image&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Bitmap Image&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Platform&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Compatibility&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Dependency&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGNativeCoder&#34;&gt;SVGNativeCoder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;iOS 9+&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Best and W3C standard&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;adobe/svg-native-viewer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&gt;SVGCoder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;iOS 13+&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;OK but buggy on some SVG&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Apple CoreSVG(Private)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&#34;&gt;SVGKitPlugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;YES&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NO&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;iOS 9+&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Worst, no longer maintain&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;SVGKit/SVGKit&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s for&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder is a SVG coder plugin for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rs/SDWebImage/&#34;&gt;SDWebImage&lt;/a&gt; framework, which provide the image loading support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scalable_Vector_Graphics&#34;&gt;SVG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SVG rendering is done using Apple&#39;s framework CoreSVG.framework (introduced in iOS 13/macOS 10.15).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Note for SVGKit user&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previously before 1.0.0 version, this SVG Coder is powered by third party library &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SVGKit/SVGKit&#34;&gt;SVGKit&lt;/a&gt;. Which support iOS 8+(macOS 10.10+) as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, due to the lack support of that third party library, which contains massive issues without community&#39;s help, no clarity of version release, makes a pain for us to maintain. So, We decide to deprecate SVGKit support and move it into another repo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&#34;&gt;SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;User who use SVGKit or have to support iOS 8+(macOS 10.10+) can still use that SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin instead. You can also mix these two SVG coders at the same time. But since Apple already provide a built-in framework support, we prefer to use that instead, which can reduce complicated dependency, code size, and get polished from Apple&#39;s system upgrade.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Note for CoreSVG framework&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So far (Xcode 11.4 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; iOS 13.4), the CoreSVG.framework is still in private framework. I&#39;ve already send the feedback radar to ask for the public for this framework. If you want, please help us to fire radars and request to Apple as well: &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedbackassistant.apple.com/&#34;&gt;https://feedbackassistant.apple.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CoreSVG.framework API is stable and match the same concept as CoreGraphics&#39;s PDF API, so it&#39;s no reason to keep private. And we&#39;ve already submitted Apps which use the CoreSVG to render the vector images on App Store.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the SPI access here we use the runtime access and early check, even if future OS upgrade break the function, this framework will not crash your App and just load failed. I&#39;ll keep update to the latest changes for each firmware update.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you still worry about the SPI usage, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&#34;&gt;SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&lt;/a&gt;. But we may not response to any parser or rendering issue related to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SVGKit/SVGKit&#34;&gt;SVGKit&lt;/a&gt;, because it&#39;s already no longer maintained.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also another solution: &lt;a href=&#34;https://w3c.github.io/svgwg/specs/svg-native/index.html&#34;&gt;SVG-Native&lt;/a&gt;, a new W3C standard from Adobe, which is a subset of SVG/1.1. Both Apple/Google/Microsoft already join the agreement for this standard, you can try to write your own coder using code from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adobe/svg-native-viewer/raw/master/svgnative/example/testCocoaCG/SVGNSView.mm&#34;&gt;SVG-native-viewer&lt;/a&gt; and adopt SVG-native for vector images.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Warning: Some user report that Apple&#39;s CoreSVG has compatible issue for some SVGs (like using non-system Font, gradient), from v1.7.0 we protect some cases, but other exceptions are un-catchable. For these crashes, either use &lt;code&gt;Render SVG as bitmap image&lt;/code&gt; (see below) or edit your SVG source file to make Apple&#39;s CoeSVG compatible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run the example project, clone the repo, and run &lt;code&gt;pod install&lt;/code&gt; from the Example directory first.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can modify the code or use some other SVG files to check the compatibility.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;iOS 13+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;tvOS 13+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;macOS 10.15+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;watchOS 6+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder is available through &lt;a href=&#34;https://cocoapods.org&#34;&gt;CocoaPods&lt;/a&gt;. To install it, simply add the following line to your Podfile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;pod &#39;SDWebImageSVGCoder&#39;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Carthage&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder is available through &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Carthage/Carthage&#34;&gt;Carthage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;github &#34;SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Swift Package Manager&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder is available through &lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/package-manager&#34;&gt;Swift Package Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;let package = Package(&#xA;    dependencies: [&#xA;        .package(url: &#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder.git&#34;, from: &#34;1.4.0&#34;)&#xA;    ]&#xA;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Render SVG as vector image&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use SVG coder, you should firstly add the &lt;code&gt;SDImageSVGCoder&lt;/code&gt; to the coders manager. Then you can call the View Category method to start load SVG images. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImage/wiki/Advanced-Usage#coder-usage&#34;&gt;Wiki - Coder Usage&lt;/a&gt; here for these steps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note SVG is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_graphics&#34;&gt;vector image&lt;/a&gt; format, and UIImageView/NSImageView support rendering vector image as well. Which means you can change the size without losing any details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Objective-C&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objectivec&#34;&gt;// register coder, on AppDelegate&#xA;SDImageSVGCoder *SVGCoder = [SDImageSVGCoder sharedCoder];&#xA;[[SDImageCodersManager sharedManager] addCoder:SVGCoder];&#xA;// load SVG url&#xA;UIImageView *imageView;&#xA;[imageView sd_setImageWithURL:url]&#xA;// Changing size&#xA;CGRect rect = imageView.frame;&#xA;rect.size.width = 200;&#xA;rect.size.height = 200;&#xA;imageView.frame = rect;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swift&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;// register coder, on AppDelegate&#xA;let SVGCoder = SDImageSVGCoder.shared&#xA;SDImageCodersManager.shared.addCoder(SVGCoder)&#xA;// load SVG url&#xA;let imageView: UIImageView&#xA;imageView.sd_setImage(with: url)&#xA;// Changing size&#xA;var rect = imageView.frame&#xA;rect.size.width = 200&#xA;rect.size.height = 200&#xA;imageView.frame = rect&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note since UIImageView/NSImageView support this vector rendering, it means this coder plugin can be compatible for &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/xcode/swiftui/&#34;&gt;SwiftUI&lt;/a&gt;. Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSwiftUI/issues/50&#34;&gt;SDWebImageSwiftUI&lt;/a&gt; for usage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: for watchOS, which does not support UIKit, so you can not use vector image format. (including both SVG and PDF)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Render SVG as bitmap image&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In most cases, vector SVG is preferred. But however, sometimes you may want the bitmap form of SVG, used for image processing or watchOS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default it use the SVG viewBox size. You can also specify a desired size during image loading using &lt;code&gt;.imageThumbnailPixelSize&lt;/code&gt; context option. And you can specify whether or not to keep aspect ratio during scale using &lt;code&gt;.imagePreserveAspectRatio&lt;/code&gt; context option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: When using &lt;code&gt;imageThumbnailPixelSize&lt;/code&gt;, pass 0 for width or height will remove the limit of this length. For example, given a SVG image which original size is &lt;code&gt;(40,50)&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;preserve aspect ratio&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;width&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;height&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;effect&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(40,50)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(80,100)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(20,25)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;true&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(40,50)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;50&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(50,50)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(40,100)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(20,50)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;false&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;(40,50)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: Once you pass the &lt;code&gt;imageThumbnailPixelSize&lt;/code&gt;, we will always generate the bitmap representation. If you do want the vector format, do not pass them, let &lt;code&gt;UIImageView&lt;/code&gt; to dynamically stretch the SVG.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Objective-C&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objectivec&#34;&gt;UIImageView *imageView;&#xA;CGSize bitmapSize = CGSizeMake(500, 500);&#xA;[imageView sd_setImageWithURL:url placeholderImage:nil options:0 context:@{SDWebImageContextThumbnailPixelSize: @(bitmapSize)];&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swift&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;let imageView: UIImageView&#xA;let bitmapSize = CGSize(width: 500, height: 500)&#xA;imageView.sd_setImage(with: url, placeholderImage: nil, options: [], context: [.imageThumbnailPixelSize : bitmapSize])&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Export SVG data&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder&lt;/code&gt; provide an easy way to export the SVG image generated by this coder plugin, to the original SVG data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: The bitmap form of SVG does not support SVG data export.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Objective-C&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objectivec&#34;&gt;UIImage *svgImage; // UIImage with vector image, or NSImage contains `NSSVGImageRep`&#xA;if (svgImage.sd_isVector) { // This API available in SDWebImage 5.6.0&#xA;    NSData *svgData = [svgImage sd_imageDataAsFormat:SDImageFormatSVG];&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swift&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-swift&#34;&gt;let svgImage: UIImage // UIImage with vector image, or NSImage contains `NSSVGImageRep`&#xA;if svgImage.sd_isVector { // This API available in SDWebImage 5.6.0&#xA;    let svgData = svgImage.sd_imageData(as: .SVG)&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compatibility for CoreSVG framework&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;The CSS &lt;code&gt;opacity&lt;/code&gt; can not been applied when &lt;code&gt;fill&lt;/code&gt; color exists&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Example&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;path d=&#34;M399.8,68.2c77.3,3.1,160.6,32.1&#34; opacity=&#34;0.15&#34; fill=&#34;rgb(29,36,60)&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Behavior&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;App Crash.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Workaround: Use CSS &lt;code&gt;rgba&lt;/code&gt; to set the opacity instead.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;path d=&#34;M399.8,68.2c77.3,3.1,160.6,32.1&#34; fill=&#34;rgba(29,36,60,0.15)&#34; /&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Backward Deployment&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This framework supports backward deployment on iOS 12-/macOS 10.14-. And you can combine both &lt;code&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder&lt;/code&gt; for higher firmware version, use &lt;code&gt;SDWebImageSVGKitPlugin&lt;/code&gt; for lower firmware version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For CocoaPods user, you can skip the platform version validation in Podfile with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;platform :ios, &#39;13.0&#39; # This does not effect your App Target&#39;s deployment target version, just a hint for CocoaPods&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pay attention, you should always use the runtime version check to ensure those symbols are available, you should mark all the classes use public API with &lt;code&gt;API_AVAILABLE&lt;/code&gt; annotation as well. See below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-objective-c&#34;&gt;if (@available(iOS 13, *)) {&#xA;    [SDImageCodersManager.sharedCoder addCoder:SDImageSVGCoder.sharedCoder];&#xA;} else {&#xA;    [SDImageCodersManager.sharedCoder addCoder:SDImageSVGKCoder.sharedCoder];&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshot&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder/master/Example/Screenshot/SVGDemo.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SDWebImage/SDWebImageSVGCoder/master/Example/Screenshot/SVGDemo-macOS.png&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These SVG images are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34;&gt;wikimedia&lt;/a&gt;, you can try the demo with your own SVG image as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Author&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DreamPiggy&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SDWebImageSVGCoder is available under the MIT license. See the LICENSE file for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>