<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Objective-C Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-14T01:55:52Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Objective-C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>zendesk/messaging_sdk_ios</title>
    <updated>2024-04-14T01:55:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-14:/zendesk/messaging_sdk_ios</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zendesk/messaging_sdk_ios" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zendesk Messaging SDK&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Use of this software is subject to important terms and conditions as set forth in the License file&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span&gt;⚠&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Zendesk Messaging SDK for iOS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zendesk Messaging SDK for mobile. The Messaging SDK is a shared library among the Zendesk product SDKs. It is used to share the Messaging UI components among our product SDKs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find our documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&#34;&gt;https://developer.zendesk.com/embeddables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature requests and issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All feature requests and issues are welcomed. Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zendesk/messaging_sdk_ios/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to find out how to contact us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright and license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2020 Zendesk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By downloading or using the Zendesk Messaging SDK, You agree to the Zendesk Master Subscription Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#master-subscription-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and Application Developer and API License Agreement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&#34;&gt;https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/#application-developer-api-license-agreement&lt;/a&gt; and acknowledge that such terms govern Your use of and access to the Messaging SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If You make any Contributions (defined below) to the Zendesk Messaging SDK, You hereby grant Zendesk a royalty-free, worldwide, transferable, sub-licensable, irrevocable and perpetual license to incorporate into the Service or the Zendesk API or otherwise use and commercially exploit any Contributions. “Contribution” shall mean any work of authorship, including any modifications or additions to the Mobile SDK or derivative works thereof, that is submitted to Zendesk by You.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>