<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub CSS Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-22T01:40:40Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of CSS in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>nakov/Practical-Cryptography-for-Developers-Book</title>
    <updated>2024-12-22T01:40:40Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-22:/nakov/Practical-Cryptography-for-Developers-Book</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/nakov/Practical-Cryptography-for-Developers-Book" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Practical Cryptography for Developers: Hashes, MAC, Key Derivation, DHKE, Symmetric and Asymmetric Ciphers, Public Key Cryptosystems, RSA, Elliptic Curves, ECC, secp256k1, ECDH, ECIES, Digital Signatures, ECDSA, EdDSA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: this book is &lt;strong&gt;not finished&lt;/strong&gt;! I am still working on some of the chapters. Once it is completed, I will publish it as PDF and EPUB. Be patient.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptobook.nakov.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nakov/Practical-Cryptography-for-Developers-Book/master/.gitbook/assets/practical-cryptography-for-developers-book-nakov-front-cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;Practical Cryptography for Developers - Free Book by Svetlin Nakov - front cover&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A modern &lt;strong&gt;practical book&lt;/strong&gt; about &lt;strong&gt;cryptography for developers&lt;/strong&gt; with code examples, covering core concepts like: &lt;strong&gt;hashes&lt;/strong&gt; (like SHA-3 and BLAKE2), &lt;strong&gt;MAC codes&lt;/strong&gt; (like HMAC and GMAC), &lt;strong&gt;key derivation functions&lt;/strong&gt; (like Scrypt, Argon2), &lt;strong&gt;key agreement protocols&lt;/strong&gt; (like DHKE, ECDH), &lt;strong&gt;symmetric ciphers&lt;/strong&gt; (like AES and ChaCha20, cipher block modes, authenticated encryption, AEAD, AES-GCM, ChaCha20-Poly1305), &lt;strong&gt;asymmetric ciphers&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;public-key cryptosystems&lt;/strong&gt; (RSA, ECC, ECIES), &lt;strong&gt;elliptic curve cryptography&lt;/strong&gt; (ECC, secp256k1, curve25519), &lt;strong&gt;digital signatures&lt;/strong&gt; (ECDSA and EdDSA), &lt;strong&gt;secure random numbers&lt;/strong&gt; (PRNG, CSRNG) and &lt;strong&gt;quantum-safe cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;, along with crypto &lt;strong&gt;libraries&lt;/strong&gt; and developer tools, with a lots of &lt;strong&gt;code examples&lt;/strong&gt; in Python and other languages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author: &lt;strong&gt;Svetlin Nakov&lt;/strong&gt;, PhD - &lt;a href=&#34;https://nakov.com&#34;&gt;https://nakov.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributors: Milen Stefanov, Marina Shideroff&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sponsor: &lt;strong&gt;SoftUni&lt;/strong&gt; (Software University) - &lt;a href=&#34;https://softuni.org&#34;&gt;https://softuni.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ISBN: &lt;strong&gt;978-619-00-0870-5&lt;/strong&gt; (9786190008705)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book is free and open-source, published under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIT license&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Official Web site: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cryptobook.nakov.com&#34;&gt;https://cryptobook.nakov.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Official &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; repo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nakov/practical-cryptography-for-developers-book&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nakov/practical-cryptography-for-developers-book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sofia, November 2018&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tags: cryptography, free, book, Nakov, Svetlin Nakov, hashes, hash function, SHA-256, SHA3, BLAKE2, RIPEMD, MAC, message authentication code, HMAC, KDF, key derivation, key derivation function, PBKDF2, Scrypt, Bcrypt, Argon2, password hashing, random generator, pseudo-random numbers, CSPRNG, secure random generator, key exchange, key agreement, Diffie-Hellman, DHKE, ECDH, symmetric ciphers, asymmetric ciphers, public key cryptosystems, symmetric cryptography, AES, Rijndael, cipher block mode, AES-CTR, AES-GCM, ChaCha20-Poly1305, authenticated encryption, encryption scheme, public key cryptography, RSA, ECC, elliptic curves, secp256k1, curve25519, EC points, EC domain parameters, ECDH key agreement, asymmetric encryption scheme, hybrid encryption, ECIES, digital signature, RSA signature, DSA, ECDSA, EdDSA, ElGammal signature, Schnorr signature, quantum-safe cryptography, digital certificates, TLS, OAuth, multi-factor authentication, crypto libraries, Python cryptography, JavaScript cryptography, C# cryptography, Java cryptography, C++ cryptography, PHP cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>