<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-08-01T01:56:28Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>libsdl-org/SDL_shadercross</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T01:56:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-08-01:/libsdl-org/SDL_shadercross</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/libsdl-org/SDL_shadercross" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shader translation library for SDL&#39;s GPU API.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;SDL_shadercross&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a library for translating shaders to different formats, intended for use with SDL&#39;s GPU API. It takes SPIRV or HLSL as the source and outputs DXBC, DXIL, SPIRV, MSL, or HLSL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library can perform runtime translation and conveniently returns compiled SDL GPU shader objects from HLSL or SPIRV source. This library also provides a command line interface for offline translation of shaders.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For SPIRV translation, this library depends on SPIRV-Cross: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KhronosGroup/SPIRV-Cross&#34;&gt;https://github.com/KhronosGroup/SPIRV-Cross&lt;/a&gt; spirv-cross-c-shared.dll (or your platform&#39;s equivalent) can be obtained in the Vulkan SDK: &lt;a href=&#34;https://vulkan.lunarg.com/&#34;&gt;https://vulkan.lunarg.com/&lt;/a&gt; For compiling to DXIL, dxcompiler.dll and dxil.dll (or your platform&#39;s equivalent) are required. DXIL dependencies can be obtained here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/DirectXShaderCompiler/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/microsoft/DirectXShaderCompiler/releases&lt;/a&gt; It is strongly recommended that you ship SPIRV-Cross and DXIL dependencies along with your application. For compiling to DXBC, d3dcompiler_47 is shipped with Windows. Other platforms require vkd3d-utils.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library is under the zlib license, see LICENSE.txt for details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>awsdocs/aws-cdk-guide</title>
    <updated>2025-08-01T01:56:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-08-01:/awsdocs/aws-cdk-guide</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/awsdocs/aws-cdk-guide" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;User guide for the AWS Cloud Development Kit (CDK).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to the AWS CDK Developer Guide&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the GitHub repository for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/latest/guide/home.html&#34;&gt;AWS CDK Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;. You&#39;re welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/awsdocs/aws-cdk-guide/issues/new&#34;&gt;report issues&lt;/a&gt; with the documentation here or, if you have a moment, to submit a Pull Request with your suggested changes. PRs should target the main branch, not master, which has been deprecated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;v2&lt;/code&gt; - contains the Markdown files for the CDK v2 Developer Guide&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to make a Pull Request against only one of these content sets (we&#39;ll make sure it gets into both).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Issues reported through the Feedback link at the bottom of the individual pages of the AWS CDK Developer Guide go to an internal Amazon issue tracker and may not appear here. However, we try to track most substantive AWS CDK Developer Guide work on GitHub so the community can see, comment, and contribute.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Other Documentation Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Issues with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/api/latest/docs/aws-construct-library.html&#34;&gt;API Reference&lt;/a&gt; should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-cdk/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;filed&lt;/a&gt; against the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-cdk/&#34;&gt;AWS CDK repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Issues with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cdkworkshop.com/&#34;&gt;CDK Workshop&lt;/a&gt; should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cdk-intro-workshop/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;filed&lt;/a&gt; against the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws-samples/aws-cdk-intro-workshop&#34;&gt;CDK Workshop repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributor Grant of License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By submitting a Pull Request against this repo, you grant Amazon the right to use use, modify, copy, and redistribute your contribution under any license we choose.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>