<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Perl Monthly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-01T01:54:30Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Monthly Trending of Perl in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lm-sensors/lm-sensors</title>
    <updated>2025-01-01T01:54:30Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-01:/lm-sensors/lm-sensors</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lm-sensors/lm-sensors" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;lm-sensors repository&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;OVERVIEW OF THE LM-SENSORS PACKAGE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lm-sensors package, version 3, provides user-space support for the hardware monitoring drivers in Linux 2.6.5 and later. For older kernel versions, you have to use lm-sensors version 2.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The directories within this package:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;doc Documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;etc A sample configuration file for libsensors, and a script to convert lm-sensors version 2 configuration files to work with version 3.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;lib The user-space sensors support library code (libsensors).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;prog Several supporting programs. The most important ones are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;sensors-detect: A stand-alone program for detecting installed hardware and recommending specific modules to load.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;sensors: A console tool to report sensor readings and set new sensor limits.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;sensord: A daemon to watch sensor values and log problems. It includes RRD support.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;configs This directory contains sample configurations of various boards, contributed by users of lm-sensors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All configuration files should now be imported from the old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lm-sensors.org&#34;&gt;www.lm-sensors.org&lt;/a&gt; website, however additional information about the origin of the configuration files can be found on the old site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20150901092438/http://www.lm-sensors.org:80/wiki/Configurations&#34;&gt;http://web.archive.org/web/20150901092438/http://www.lm-sensors.org:80/wiki/Configurations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Please contribute back a configuration of your board so other users with the same hardware won&#39;t need to recreate it again and again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;INSTALLING LM-SENSORS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the INSTALL file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;HARDWARE SUPPORT&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To find out what hardware you have, just run &#39;sensors-detect&#39; as root.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most modern mainboards incorporate some form of hardware monitoring chips. These chips read things like chip temperatures, fan rotation speeds and voltage levels. There are quite a few different chips which can be used by mainboard builders for approximately the same results.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Laptops, on the other hand, rarely expose any hardware monitoring chip. They often have some BIOS and/or ACPI magic to get the CPU temperature value, but that&#39;s about it. For such laptops, the lm-sensors package is of no use (sensors-detect will not find anything), and you have to use acpi instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package doesn&#39;t contain chip-specific knowledge. It will support all the hardware monitoring chips your kernel has drivers for. In other words, if you find out that you have unsupported hardware (e.g. sensors-detect told you so) then it means that you need a more recent kernel, or you even need to wait for a new kernel driver to be written. Updating the lm-sensors package itself will not help.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LIBSENSORS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kernel drivers communicate their information through the /sys interface. Because every motherboard is different, the drivers always advert the measurements at their pins. This means that the values they report are not always immediately relevant to you. They have to be labelled properly, and sometimes they must be scaled to correspond to real-world values.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;libsensors is a (shared or static) library of access functions. It offers a simple-to-use interface for applications to access the sensor chip readings and configure them as you like. It has a configuration file where you can put all the motherboard-specific labels and conversion rules. That way, all applications do not need to duplicate the effort and can simply link with libsensors and work out of the box.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;APPLICATIONS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package contains an example console program that reports all current sensors values. This program is called &#39;sensors&#39;. You can use it as a reference implementation for more intricate programs. It also contains a daemon watching for sensor values, logging alarms and feeding an RRD database with the sensor measurements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This package does not contain a nice graphical monitor. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://sensors-applet.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;http://sensors-applet.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://01.org/powertop/&#34;&gt;https://01.org/powertop/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://wpitchoune.net/psensor/&#34;&gt;https://wpitchoune.net/psensor/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://amanusk.github.io/s-tui/&#34;&gt;https://amanusk.github.io/s-tui/&lt;/a&gt; for such programs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;lm-sensors is blamed for all kinds of problems on a regular basis. While it is always possible that lm-sensors does in fact have a problem, almost everytime the problem will be elsewhere. The most likely culprit for a problem is one of the kernel drivers prividing data to lm-sensors or, rather, the sensors command (and libsensors). If you encounter problems, the following tests are recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check enabled sensors with the &#39;sensors&#39; command. Observe and, if there are errors, write down your test steps and report.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If any problems are observed while running the &#39;sensors&#39; command, disable (unload) kernel drivers one after another. After unloading a driver, run the &#39;sensors&#39; command again and observe if the error is gone. If it is, you found the problematic driver. Record your tests and report to the driver maintainer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If problems are observed while using libsensors from another application, the same procedure applies (though it is recommended to perform the test with the sensors command first). Again, after identifying the offending driver, record and report your results to the driver maintainer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If this does not help, try to run ptrace on the sensors command and/or the application using libsensors. If you find any anormalies, record your results and report.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;OTHER INFORMATION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lm_sensors website can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://hwmon.wiki.kernel.org/lm_sensors&#34;&gt;https://hwmon.wiki.kernel.org/lm_sensors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The developers of this package can be reached using&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;a mailing list lm-sensors &#xA;  &lt;at&gt;&#xA;    vger &#xA;   &lt;dot&gt;&#xA;     kernel &#xA;    &lt;dot&gt;&#xA;      org (you can get information on how to subscribe, unsubscribe, and the list of archives at &#xA;     &lt;a href=&#34;http://vger.kernel.org/vger-lists.html#lm-sensors&#34;&gt;http://vger.kernel.org/vger-lists.html#lm-sensors&lt;/a&gt;; you do not need to be subscribed to post to the list)&#xA;    &lt;/dot&gt;&#xA;   &lt;/dot&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/at&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GitHub (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lm-sensors/lm-sensors&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lm-sensors/lm-sensors&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not hesitate to contact us if you have questions, suggestions, problems, want to contribute, or just want to report it works for you. But please try to read the documentation before you ask any questions! It&#39;s all under doc/.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version of this package can always be found at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lm-sensors/lm-sensors&#34;&gt;https://github.com/lm-sensors/lm-sensors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The library (libsensors) is released under the GNU Lesser General Public License (LGPL), as included in the file COPYING.LGPL. The rest of this package may be distributed according to the GNU General Public License (GPL), as included in the file COPYING.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>