<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-16T01:46:35Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>wch/r-source</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:46:35Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/wch/r-source</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/wch/r-source" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Read-only mirror of R source code from https://svn.r-project.org/R/, updated hourly. See the build instructions on the wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#x9;&#x9;THE BASIC R README&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;   (See &#34;doc/FAQ&#34; and &#34;doc/RESOURCES&#34; for more detailed information&#xA;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;      - these files are only in the tarballs)&#xA;   (See &#34;INSTALL&#34;             for help on installation)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This directory contains the source code tree for R, which is a language which is not entirely unlike (versions 3 and 4 of) the S language developed at AT&amp;amp;T Bell Laboratories by Rick Becker, John Chambers and Allan Wilks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;R is free software distributed under a GNU-style copyleft.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The core of R is an interpreted computer language with a syntax superficially similar to C, but which is actually a &#34;functional programming language&#34; with capabilities similar to Scheme. The language allows branching and looping as well as modular programming using functions. Most of the user-visible functions in R are written in R, calling upon a smaller set of internal primitives. It is possible for the user to interface to procedures written in C or Fortran languages for efficiency, and also to write additional primitives.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The R distribution contains functionality for a large number of statistical procedures. Among these are: linear and generalized linear models, nonlinear regression models, time series analysis, classical parametric and nonparametric tests, clustering and smoothing. There is also a large set of functions which provide a flexible graphical environment for creating various kinds of data presentations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A package specification allows the production of loadable modules for specific purposes, and several thousand contributed packages are made available through the CRAN sites (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://CRAN.R-project.org/mirrors.html&#34;&gt;https://CRAN.R-project.org/mirrors.html&lt;/a&gt; for the current members).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HISTORY&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;R was initially written by Robert Gentleman and Ross Ihaka of the Statistics Department of the University of Auckland. In addition, a large group of individuals has contributed to R by sending code and bug reports.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since mid-1997 there has been a core group who can modify the R source code archive, listed in file doc/AUTHORS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;R 1.0.0 was released on 29 February 2000 and 2.0.0 on 4 October 2004. R 3.0.0 came out on 3 April 2013.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This file has been minimally revised since the release of R 1.0.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PRESENT STATUS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The present version implements most of the functionality in the 1988 book &#34;The New S Language&#34; (the &#34;Blue Book&#34;) and many of the applications. In addition, we have implemented a large part of the functionality from the 1992 book &#34;Statistical Models in S&#34; (the &#34;White Book&#34;) and the 1998 book &#34;Programming with Data&#34; (the &#34;Green Book&#34;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the R functions have been documented in the form of help pages in an &#34;output independent&#34; form which can be used to create versions for HTML, PDF, text etc. A 1900+ page Reference Index (a collection of most of the help pages: there is also a 3300+ page version with all the help pages, including recommended packages) can be obtained in PDF. The manual &lt;code&gt;An Introduction to R&#39; provides a more user-friendly starting point, and there is an FAQ, a draft &lt;/code&gt;R Language Definition&#39; manual and more specialized manuals on admininstration, data import/export and extending R. See INSTALL for instructions on how to generate these documents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GOALS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our aim at the start of this project was to demonstrate that it was possible to produce an S-like environment which did not suffer from the memory-demands and performance problems which S has. Somewhat later, we started to turn R into a &#34;real&#34; system, but unfortunately we lost a large part of the efficiency advantage in the process, so have revised the memory management mechanism and implemented delayed loading of R objects. A lot of performance tuning has been done, including the ability to use tuned linear-algebra libraries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Longer-term goals include to explore new ideas: e.g. virtual objects and component-based programming, and expanding the scope of existing ones like formula-based interfaces. Further, we wish to get a handle on a general approach to graphical user interfaces (preferably with cross-platform portability), and to develop better 3-D and dynamic graphics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sincerely, The R Core Team.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>vegandevs/vegan</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:46:35Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/vegandevs/vegan</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/vegandevs/vegan" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;R package for community ecologists: popular ordination methods, ecological null models &amp; diversity analysis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;vegan: an R package for community ecologists&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ordination methods, diversity analysis and other functions for community and vegetation ecologists.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: start --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vegandevs/vegan/actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/vegandevs/vegan/workflows/R-CMD-check/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;R build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/package=vegan&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.r-pkg.org/badges/version/vegan&#34; alt=&#34;CRAN_Status_Badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://cran.rstudio.com/web/packages/vegan/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://cranlogs.r-pkg.org/badges/grand-total/vegan&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: end --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Website for the development version of the &lt;strong&gt;vegan&lt;/strong&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install the development version of &lt;strong&gt;vegan&lt;/strong&gt; you can use the usual &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;R CMD build -&amp;gt; R CMD INSTALL&lt;/code&gt; dance on the cloned repo (or downloaded sources). You&#39;ll need to be able to install packages from source for that to work; if you don&#39;t have the relevant developer tools, you won&#39;t be able to install &lt;strong&gt;vegan&lt;/strong&gt; this way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using &lt;strong&gt;remotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do have the developer tools installed but don&#39;t want the hassle of keeping a local source code tree up-to-date, use the &lt;strong&gt;remotes&lt;/strong&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;install.packages(&#34;remotes&#34;)&#xA;remotes::install_github(&#34;vegandevs/vegan&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing binaries from R Universe&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you just want to install a binary version of the packages, just as you would from CRAN, you can install from our R Universe repository. Run the following in your R session:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;# Enable repository from vegandevs&#xA;options(repos = c(&#xA;  vegandevs = &#39;https://vegandevs.r-universe.dev&#39;,&#xA;  CRAN = &#39;https://cloud.r-project.org&#39;))&#xA;# Download and install vegan in R&#xA;install.packages(&#39;vegan&#39;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make this permanent, you&#39;ll need to include the &lt;code&gt;options()&lt;/code&gt; part of that in your person R settings file, typically a &lt;code&gt;.Rprofile&lt;/code&gt; profile in your home drive. See &lt;code&gt;?Startup&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions</title>
    <updated>2022-10-16T01:46:35Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-16:/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Exercise solutions to &#34;R for Data Science&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidyverse.org/lifecycle/#stable&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/lifecycle-stable-brightgreen.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Lifecycle: stable&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Exercise Solutions to R for Data Science&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the code and text behind the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jrnold.github.io/r4ds-exercise-solutions/&#34;&gt;Solutions for R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt;, which, as its name suggests, has solutions to the the exercises in &lt;a href=&#34;https://r4ds.had.co.nz/&#34;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt; by Garrett Grolemund and Hadley Wickham.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The R packages used in this book can be installed via&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;devtools::install_github(&#34;jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions&#34;)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions welcome! Notice a wrong answer, typo, bug, or have an alternative/better solution, open a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions/issues&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions/pulls&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that the &#39;R4DSSolutions&#39; project is released with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jrnold/r4ds-exercise-solutions/master/.github/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Contributor Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. By contributing to this project, you agree to abide by its terms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The site is built using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/bookdown/&#34;&gt;bookdown&lt;/a&gt; package and pandoc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>