<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub R Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-12T02:03:36Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of R in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>JaneSullivan-NOAA/shortspine_thornyhead_2023</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T02:03:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-12:/JaneSullivan-NOAA/shortspine_thornyhead_2023</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/JaneSullivan-NOAA/shortspine_thornyhead_2023" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2023 West Coast stock assessment for shortspine thornyhead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;2023 Shortspine Thornyhead Stock Assessment&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;File Structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data/&lt;/code&gt; - This directory holds any and all data that is direct requested from state/federal agencies or pulled from NOAA servers (ie. survey data). Data that gets output from other analyses (ie. a lot of the SS inputs) are stored somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data/raw/&lt;/code&gt; - Completely raw, unedited, data from various data sources. This folder is untracked and is safe to place confidential data in.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;data/processed/&lt;/code&gt; - Processed data from available data sources. This folder IS tracked, so no confidential data, only cleaned datasets ready for analysis. Every file in this directory should have an equivalent &#34;raw&#34; data file in data/raw.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;R/&lt;/code&gt; - This directory should hold R scripts and analyses. These can take the form of either runnable .R scripts or .Rmd Rmarkdown documents/notebooks. Note that data outputs/plots should not be stored in this directory. This directory is further broken down into subdirectories based on data type (&#39;bio/&#39;, &#39;comps/&#39;, &#39;discards/&#39;, &#39;landings/&#39;, and &#39;survey/&#39;). Data type specific analyses and script should live in their relevant subdirectories rather than the root R/ directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;R/utils/&lt;/code&gt; - Any utility functions that may be of use across R analyses can go here. For example, plotting code, or helpful data cleaning functions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;model/&lt;/code&gt; - This directory will (in the future) hold the stock synthesis model code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;outputs/&lt;/code&gt; - Send all outputs (including plots and potential SS input files) generated by other analyses to this directory. There is no defined directory structure for this directory at this time, so be thoughtful as to directory and file names when you send outputs here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Useful Packages / Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pfmc-assessments&#34;&gt;PFMC assessments org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcouncil.org&#34;&gt;Pacific Fishery Management Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Packages&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;repository&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;use&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pfmc-assessments.github.io/nwfscSurvey/&#34;&gt;nwfscSurvey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Analysis of the NWFSC trawl surveys&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pfmc-assessments.github.io/PacFIN.Utilities/&#34;&gt;PacFIN.Utilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Manipulate data from the PacFIN database for assessments&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Other resources&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copper Rockfish pre-assessment meeting report &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pfmc-assessments/copper_rockfish_2023/raw/main/documents/pre-assessment_data_workshop/report.Rmd&#34;&gt;Rmd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pfmc-assessments.github.io/copper_rockfish_2023/&#34;&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; (can use this structure as an example for our pre-assessment workshop)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is a scientific product and is not official communication of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the United States Department of Commerce. All NOAA GitHub project code is provided on an ‘as is’ basis and the user assumes responsibility for its use. Any claims against the Department of Commerce or Department of Commerce bureaus stemming from the use of this GitHub project will be governed by all applicable Federal law. Any reference to specific commercial products, processes, or services by service mark, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise, does not constitute or imply their endorsement, recommendation or favoring by the Department of Commerce. The Department of Commerce seal and logo, or the seal and logo of a DOC bureau, shall not be used in any manner to imply endorsement of any commercial product or activity by DOC or the United States Government.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>medavoodi/BIS-244-Spring-2023</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T02:03:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-12:/medavoodi/BIS-244-Spring-2023</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/medavoodi/BIS-244-Spring-2023" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Course Materials BIS 244 Spring 2023&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;BIS-244-Spring-2023&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Course Materials BIS 244 Spring 2023&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kjhealy/socviz</title>
    <updated>2023-02-12T02:03:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-12:/kjhealy/socviz</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kjhealy/socviz" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Support files for a data visualization course and book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;socviz &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kjhealy/socviz/master/man/figures/logo.png&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; width=&#34;120&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: start --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kjhealy/socviz/actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/kjhealy/socviz/workflows/R-CMD-check/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;R build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- badges: end --&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an R package of datasets, functions, and course materials to go along with the book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2vfAixM&#34;&gt;Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Princeton University Press, 2019).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://socviz.co/assets/dv-cover-pupress.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s in this Package&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;socviz&lt;/code&gt; package contains about twenty five datasets and a number of utility and convenience functions. Most of them are used in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2vfAixM&#34;&gt;Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;code&gt;http://socviz.co&lt;/code&gt;), and there are also a few others as well for self-learners and students to practice their skills on.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A course packet is also included. This is a zipped file containing an &lt;a href=&#34;http://rstudio.com&#34;&gt;R Studio&lt;/a&gt; project consisting of a nine &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/a&gt; documents that parallel the chapters in the book. They contain the code for almost all the figures in the book (and a few more besides). Some support files are also included, to help demonstrate things like reading in your own data locally in R.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install the package, you can follow the instructions in the Preface to the book. Alternatively, first download and install R for &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/bin/macosx/&#34;&gt;MacOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/bin/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/bin/linux/&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;, as appropriate. Then download and install &lt;a href=&#34;http://rstudio.com/download/&#34;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt;. Launch RStudio and then type the following code at the Console prompt (&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;/code&gt;), hitting return at the end of each line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;my_packages &amp;lt;- c(&#34;tidyverse&#34;, &#34;fs&#34;, &#34;devtools&#34;)&#xA;install.packages(my_packages)&#xA;&#xA;install.packages(&#34;socviz&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install the development version of &lt;code&gt;socviz&lt;/code&gt;, instead of &lt;code&gt;install.packages(&#34;socviz&#34;)&lt;/code&gt; do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;&#xA;devtools::install_github(&#34;kjhealy/socviz&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once everything has downloaded and been installed (which may take a little while), load the &lt;code&gt;socviz&lt;/code&gt; package:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;library(socviz)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The Course Packet&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The supporting materials are contained in a compressed &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;/code&gt; file. To extract them to your Desktop, make sure the &lt;code&gt;socviz&lt;/code&gt; package is loaded as described above. Then do something like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;&#xA;setup_course_notes(folder = &#34;~/Desktop&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can choose the destination folder, but you must supply one. Here, the &lt;code&gt;dataviz_course_notes.zip&lt;/code&gt; file will be copied to your Desktop, and uncompressed there into a folder called &lt;code&gt;dataviz_course_notes&lt;/code&gt;. Open the folder, and double-click the file named &lt;code&gt;dataviz.Rproj&lt;/code&gt; to launch the project as a new RStudio session. If you want to uncompress the file somewhere other than your Desktop, e.g. your Documents folder, you can do this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34;&gt;&#xA;setup_course_notes(folder = &#34;~/Documents&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;More about the Datasets and Functions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The included datasets and functions are documented at &lt;a href=&#34;http://kjhealy.github.io/socviz/reference/&#34;&gt;http://kjhealy.github.io/socviz/reference/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>