<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Python Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-02-20T01:37:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Python in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>getzep/graphiti</title>
    <updated>2025-02-20T01:37:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-02-20:/getzep/graphiti</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/getzep/graphiti" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Build and query dynamic, temporally-aware Knowledge Graphs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;Graphiti&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;Temporal Knowledge Graphs for Agentic Applications&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;br&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/W8Kw6bsgXQ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dcbadge.vercel.app/api/server/W8Kw6bsgXQ?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/lint.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/lint.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Lint&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/unit_tests.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/unit_tests.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Unit Tests&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/typecheck.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/getzep/Graphiti/actions/workflows/typecheck.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;MyPy Check&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://codespaces.new/getzep/Graphiti&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/codespaces/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Open in GitHub Codespaces&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti builds dynamic, temporally aware Knowledge Graphs that represent complex, evolving relationships between entities over time. Graphiti ingests both unstructured and structured data, and the resulting graph may be queried using a fusion of time, full-text, semantic, and graph algorithm approaches.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/getzep/graphiti/main/images/graphiti-graph-intro.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Graphiti temporal walkthrough&#34; width=&#34;700px&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti helps you create and query Knowledge Graphs that evolve over time. A knowledge graph is a network of interconnected facts, such as &lt;em&gt;“Kendra loves Adidas shoes.”&lt;/em&gt; Each fact is a “triplet” represented by two entities, or nodes (&lt;em&gt;”Kendra”&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;“Adidas shoes”&lt;/em&gt;), and their relationship, or edge (&lt;em&gt;”loves”&lt;/em&gt;). Knowledge Graphs have been explored extensively for information retrieval. What makes Graphiti unique is its ability to autonomously build a knowledge graph while handling changing relationships and maintaining historical context.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Graphiti, you can build LLM applications such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Assistants that learn from user interactions, fusing personal knowledge with dynamic data from business systems like CRMs and billing platforms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Agents that autonomously execute complex tasks, reasoning with state changes from multiple dynamic sources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti supports a wide range of applications in sales, customer service, health, finance, and more, enabling long-term recall and state-based reasoning for both assistants and agents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Graphiti and Zep Memory&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti powers the core of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getzep.com&#34;&gt;Zep&#39;s memory layer&lt;/a&gt; for LLM-powered Assistants and Agents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Graphiti, we&#39;ve demonstrated Zep is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.getzep.com/state-of-the-art-agent-memory/&#34;&gt;State of the Art in Agent Memory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read our paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13956&#34;&gt;Zep: A Temporal Knowledge Graph Architecture for Agent Memory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re excited to open-source Graphiti, believing its potential reaches far beyond memory applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.13956&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/getzep/graphiti/main/images/arxiv-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zep: A Temporal Knowledge Graph Architecture for Agent Memory&#34; width=&#34;700px&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why Graphiti?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were intrigued by Microsoft’s GraphRAG, which expanded on RAG text chunking by using a graph to better model a document corpus and making this representation available via semantic and graph search techniques. However, GraphRAG did not address our core problem: It&#39;s primarily designed for static documents and doesn&#39;t inherently handle temporal aspects of data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti is designed from the ground up to handle constantly changing information, hybrid semantic and graph search, and scale:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temporal Awareness:&lt;/strong&gt; Tracks changes in facts and relationships over time, enabling point-in-time queries. Graph edges include temporal metadata to record relationship lifecycles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Episodic Processing:&lt;/strong&gt; Ingests data as discrete episodes, maintaining data provenance and allowing incremental entity and relationship extraction.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hybrid Search:&lt;/strong&gt; Combines semantic and BM25 full-text search, with the ability to rerank results by distance from a central node e.g. “Kendra”.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable:&lt;/strong&gt; Designed for processing large datasets, with parallelization of LLM calls for bulk processing while preserving the chronology of events.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supports Varied Sources:&lt;/strong&gt; Can ingest both unstructured text and structured JSON data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/getzep/graphiti/main/images/graphiti-intro-slides-stock-2.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Graphiti structured + unstructured demo&#34; width=&#34;700px&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Python 3.10 or higher&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Neo4j 5.21 or higher&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenAI API key (for LLM inference and embedding)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optional:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Anthropic or Groq API key (for alternative LLM providers)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!TIP] The simplest way to install Neo4j is via &lt;a href=&#34;https://neo4j.com/download/&#34;&gt;Neo4j Desktop&lt;/a&gt;. It provides a user-friendly interface to manage Neo4j instances and databases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pip install graphiti-core&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;poetry add graphiti-core&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT] Graphiti uses OpenAI for LLM inference and embedding. Ensure that an &lt;code&gt;OPENAI_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt; is set in your environment. Support for Anthropic and Groq LLM inferences is available, too. Other LLM providers may be supported via OpenAI compatible APIs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from graphiti_core import Graphiti&#xA;from graphiti_core.nodes import EpisodeType&#xA;from datetime import datetime, timezone&#xA;&#xA;# Initialize Graphiti&#xA;graphiti = Graphiti(&#34;bolt://localhost:7687&#34;, &#34;neo4j&#34;, &#34;password&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;# Initialize the graph database with Graphiti&#39;s indices. This only needs to be done once.&#xA;graphiti.build_indices_and_constraints()&#xA;&#xA;# Add episodes&#xA;episodes = [&#xA;    &#34;Kamala Harris is the Attorney General of California. She was previously &#34;&#xA;    &#34;the district attorney for San Francisco.&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;As AG, Harris was in office from January 3, 2011 – January 3, 2017&#34;,&#xA;]&#xA;for i, episode in enumerate(episodes):&#xA;    await graphiti.add_episode(&#xA;        name=f&#34;Freakonomics Radio {i}&#34;,&#xA;        episode_body=episode,&#xA;        source=EpisodeType.text,&#xA;        source_description=&#34;podcast&#34;,&#xA;        reference_time=datetime.now(timezone.utc)&#xA;    )&#xA;&#xA;# Search the graph&#xA;# Execute a hybrid search combining semantic similarity and BM25 retrieval&#xA;# Results are combined and reranked using Reciprocal Rank Fusion&#xA;results = await graphiti.search(&#39;Who was the California Attorney General?&#39;)&#xA;[&#xA;    EntityEdge(&#xA;│   uuid = &#39;3133258f738e487383f07b04e15d4ac0&#39;,&#xA;│   source_node_uuid = &#39;2a85789b318d4e418050506879906e62&#39;,&#xA;│   target_node_uuid = &#39;baf7781f445945989d6e4f927f881556&#39;,&#xA;│   created_at = datetime.datetime(2024, 8, 26, 13, 13, 24, 861097),&#xA;│   name = &#39;HELD_POSITION&#39;,&#xA;# the fact reflects the updated state that Harris is&#xA;# no longer the AG of California&#xA;│   fact = &#39;Kamala Harris was the Attorney General of California&#39;,&#xA;│   fact_embedding = [&#xA;│   │   -0.009955154731869698,&#xA;│       ...&#xA;│   │   0.00784289836883545&#xA;│],&#xA;│   episodes = [&#39;b43e98ad0a904088a76c67985caecc22&#39;],&#xA;│   expired_at = datetime.datetime(2024, 8, 26, 20, 18, 1, 53812),&#xA;# These dates represent the date this edge was true.&#xA;│   valid_at = datetime.datetime(2011, 1, 3, 0, 0, tzinfo= &amp;lt; UTC &amp;gt;),&#xA;│   invalid_at = datetime.datetime(2017, 1, 3, 0, 0, tzinfo= &amp;lt; UTC &amp;gt;)&#xA;)&#xA;]&#xA;&#xA;# Rerank search results based on graph distance&#xA;# Provide a node UUID to prioritize results closer to that node in the graph.&#xA;# Results are weighted by their proximity, with distant edges receiving lower scores.&#xA;await graphiti.search(&#39;Who was the California Attorney General?&#39;, center_node_uuid)&#xA;&#xA;# Close the connection&#xA;graphiti.close()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Graph Service&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; directory contains an API service for interacting with the Graphiti API. It is built using FastAPI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/getzep/graphiti/main/server/README.md&#34;&gt;server README&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Optional Environment Variables&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Neo4j and OpenAi-compatible credentials, Graphiti also has a few optional environment variables. If you are using one of our supported models, such as Anthropic or Voyage models, the necessary environment variables must be set.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;USE_PARALLEL_RUNTIME&lt;/code&gt; is an optional boolean variable that can be set to true if you wish to enable Neo4j&#39;s parallel runtime feature for several of our search queries. Note that this feature is not supported for Neo4j Community edition or for smaller AuraDB instances, as such this feature is off by default.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.getzep.com/graphiti&#34;&gt;Guides and API documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.getzep.com/graphiti/graphiti/quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.getzep.com/graphiti/graphiti/lang-graph-agent&#34;&gt;Building an agent with LangChain&#39;s LangGraph and Graphiti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Status and Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphiti is under active development. We aim to maintain API stability while working on:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Supporting custom graph schemas: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Allow developers to provide their own defined node and edge classes when ingesting episodes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enable more flexible knowledge representation tailored to specific use cases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Enhancing retrieval capabilities with more robust and configurable options&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Expanding test coverage to ensure reliability and catch edge cases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We encourage and appreciate all forms of contributions, whether it&#39;s code, documentation, addressing GitHub Issues, or answering questions in the Graphiti Discord channel. For detailed guidelines on code contributions, please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/getzep/graphiti/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/W8Kw6bsgXQ&#34;&gt;Zep Discord server&lt;/a&gt; and make your way to the &lt;strong&gt;#Graphiti&lt;/strong&gt; channel!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>