<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Python Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-26T01:35:14Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Python in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>d2l-ai/d2l-en</title>
    <updated>2022-12-26T01:35:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-26:/d2l-ai/d2l-en</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interactive deep learning book with multi-framework code, math, and discussions. Adopted at 400 universities from 60 countries including Stanford, MIT, Harvard, and Cambridge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/logo-with-text.png&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;D2L.ai: Interactive Deep Learning Book with Multi-Framework Code, Math, and Discussions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ci.d2l.ai/job/d2l-en/job/master/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://ci.d2l.ai/job/d2l-en/job/master/badge/icon&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://d2l.ai/&#34;&gt;Book website&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://courses.d2l.ai/berkeley-stat-157/index.html&#34;&gt;STAT 157 Course at UC Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The best way to understand deep learning is learning by doing.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/frontpage/_images/eq.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/frontpage/_images/figure.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/frontpage/_images/code.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;200&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/frontpage/_images/notebook.gif&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This open-source book represents our attempt to make deep learning approachable, teaching you the concepts, the context, and the code. The entire book is drafted in Jupyter notebooks, seamlessly integrating exposition figures, math, and interactive examples with self-contained code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to offer a resource that could&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;be freely available for everyone;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;offer sufficient technical depth to provide a starting point on the path to actually becoming an applied machine learning scientist;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;include runnable code, showing readers how to solve problems in practice;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;allow for rapid updates, both by us and also by the community at large;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;be complemented by a forum for interactive discussion of technical details and to answer questions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Universities Using D2L&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;600&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/static/frontpage/_images/map.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Cool Papers Using D2L&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.01547.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descending through a Crowded Valley--Benchmarking Deep Learning Optimizers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. R. Schmidt, F. Schneider, P. Hennig. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Machine Learning, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2002.04664.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Average-Case Optimality of Polyak Momentum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. D. Scieur, F. Pedregosan. &lt;em&gt;International Conference on Machine Learning, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/1996-1944/13/16/3527/pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2D Digital Image Correlation and Region-Based Convolutional Neural Network in Monitoring and Evaluation of Surface Cracks in Concrete Structural Elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. M. Słoński, M. Tekieli. &lt;em&gt;Materials, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jmlr.org/papers/volume21/19-429/19-429.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GluonCV and GluonNLP: Deep Learning in Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. J. Guo, H. He, T. He, L. Lausen, M. Li, H. Lin, X. Shi, C. Wang, J. Xie, S. Zha, A. Zhang, H. Zhang, Z. Zhang, Z. Zhang, S. Zheng, and Y. Zhu. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Machine Learning Research, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=9107077&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detecting Human Driver Inattentive and Aggressive Driving Behavior Using Deep Learning: Recent Advances, Requirements and Open Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. M. Alkinani, W. Khan, Q. Arshad. &lt;em&gt;IEEE Access, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt;&#xA; &lt;summary&gt;more&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-981-15-6325-6_5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diagnosing Parkinson by Using Deep Autoencoder Neural Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. U. Kose, O. Deperlioglu, J. Alzubi, B. Patrut. &lt;em&gt;Deep Learning for Medical Decision Support Systems, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-981-15-6325-6_2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Learning Architectures for Medical Diagnosis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. U. Kose, O. Deperlioglu, J. Alzubi, B. Patrut. &lt;em&gt;Deep Learning for Medical Decision Support Systems, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.01754.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ControlVAE: Tuning, Analytical Properties, and Performance Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. H. Shao, Z. Xiao, S. Yao, D. Sun, A. Zhang, S. Liu, T. Abdelzaher.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reader.elsevier.com/reader/sd/pii/S0952197620301184?token=7261E56B97513C5D621B9B5F43CAABEC2860AE3036278C3E5264707C32DCB658077B2AFA6ED6D5CD0FB7B16770828080&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potential, challenges and future directions for deep learning in prognostics and health management applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. O. Fink, Q. Wang, M. Svensén, P. Dersin, W-J. Lee, M. Ducoffe. &lt;em&gt;Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence, 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2011.05742.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning User Representations with Hypercuboids for Recommender Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. S. Zhang, H. Liu, A. Zhang, Y. Hu, C. Zhang, Y. Li, T. Zhu, S. He, W. Ou. &lt;em&gt;ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining, 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find this book useful, please star (★) this repository or cite this book using the following bibtex entry:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@article{zhang2021dive,&#xA;    title={Dive into Deep Learning},&#xA;    author={Zhang, Aston and Lipton, Zachary C. and Li, Mu and Smola, Alexander J.},&#xA;    journal={arXiv preprint arXiv:2106.11342},&#xA;    year={2021}&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Endorsements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&#34;In less than a decade, the AI revolution has swept from research labs to broad industries to every corner of our daily life. Dive into Deep Learning is an excellent text on deep learning and deserves attention from anyone who wants to learn why deep learning has ignited the AI revolution: the most powerful technology force of our time.&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;b&gt;— Jensen Huang, Founder and CEO, NVIDIA&lt;/b&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&#34;This is a timely, fascinating book, providing with not only a comprehensive overview of deep learning principles but also detailed algorithms with hands-on programming code, and moreover, a state-of-the-art introduction to deep learning in computer vision and natural language processing. Dive into this book if you want to dive into deep learning!&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;b&gt;— Jiawei Han, Michael Aiken Chair Professor, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign&lt;/b&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&#34;This is a highly welcome addition to the machine learning literature, with a focus on hands-on experience implemented via the integration of Jupyter notebooks. Students of deep learning should find this invaluable to become proficient in this field.&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;b&gt;— Bernhard Schölkopf, Director, Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems&lt;/b&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing (&lt;a href=&#34;https://d2l.ai/chapter_appendix-tools-for-deep-learning/contributing.html&#34;&gt;Learn How&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This open source book has benefited from pedagogical suggestions, typo corrections, and other improvements from community contributors. Your help is valuable for making the book better for everyone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;D2L contributors&lt;/a&gt;, please email your GitHub ID and name to d2lbook.en AT gmail DOT com so your name will appear on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://d2l.ai/chapter_preface/index.html#acknowledgments&#34;&gt;acknowledgments&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License Summary&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This open source book is made available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sample and reference code within this open source book is made available under a modified MIT license. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/LICENSE-SAMPLECODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-SAMPLECODE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/d2l-ai/d2l-zh&#34;&gt;Chinese version&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.d2l.ai/&#34;&gt;Discuss and report issues&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/d2l-ai/d2l-en/master/INFO.md&#34;&gt;Other Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>openai/gpt-discord-bot</title>
    <updated>2022-12-26T01:35:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-26:/openai/gpt-discord-bot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/openai/gpt-discord-bot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Example Discord bot written in Python that uses the completions API to have conversations with the `text-davinci-003` model, and the moderations API to filter the messages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Example Discord bot written in Python that uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.openai.com/docs/api-reference/completions&#34;&gt;completions API&lt;/a&gt; to have conversations with the &lt;code&gt;text-davinci-003&lt;/code&gt; model, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.openai.com/docs/api-reference/moderations&#34;&gt;moderations API&lt;/a&gt; to filter the messages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This bot uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openai/openai-python&#34;&gt;OpenAI Python Library&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://discordpy.readthedocs.io/&#34;&gt;discord.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo is not accepting pull requests. Please fork this repo if you want to add or change features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;/chat&lt;/code&gt; starts a public thread, with a &lt;code&gt;message&lt;/code&gt; argument which is the first user message passed to the bot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The model will generate a reply for every user message in any threads started with &lt;code&gt;/chat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The entire thread will be passed to the model for each request, so the model will remember previous messages in the thread&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;when the context limit is reached, or a max message count is reached in the thread, bot will close the thread&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;you can customize the bot instructions by modifying &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;you can change the model, the hardcoded value is &lt;code&gt;text-davinci-003&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy &lt;code&gt;.env.example&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; and start filling in the values as detailed below&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://beta.openai.com/account/api-keys&#34;&gt;https://beta.openai.com/account/api-keys&lt;/a&gt;, create a new API key, and fill in &lt;code&gt;OPENAI_API_KEY&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create your own Discord application at &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/developers/applications&#34;&gt;https://discord.com/developers/applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the Bot tab and click &#34;Add Bot&#34; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Click &#34;Reset Token&#34; and fill in &lt;code&gt;DISCORD_BOT_TOKEN&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Disable &#34;Public Bot&#34; unless you want your bot to be visible to everyone&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enable &#34;Message Content Intent&#34; under &#34;Privileged Gateway Intents&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to the OAuth2 tab, copy your &#34;Client ID&#34;, and fill in &lt;code&gt;DISCORD_CLIENT_ID&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy the ID the server you want to allow your bot to be used in by right clicking the server icon and clicking &#34;Copy ID&#34;. Fill in &lt;code&gt;ALLOWED_SERVER_IDS&lt;/code&gt;. If you want to allow multiple servers, separate the IDs by &#34;,&#34; like &lt;code&gt;server_id_1,server_id_2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install dependencies and run the bot &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install -r requirements.txt&#xA;python -m src.main&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; You should see an invite URL in the console. Copy and paste it into your browser to add the bot to your server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Optional configuration&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want moderation messages, create and copy the channel id for each server that you want the moderation messages to send to in &lt;code&gt;SERVER_TO_MODERATION_CHANNEL&lt;/code&gt;. This should be of the format: &lt;code&gt;server_id:channel_id,server_id_2:channel_id_2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want to change the personality of the bot, go to &lt;code&gt;src/config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; and edit the instructions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want to change the moderation settings for which messages get flagged or blocked, edit the values in &lt;code&gt;src/constants.py&lt;/code&gt;. A lower value means less chance of it triggering.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Why isn&#39;t my bot responding to commands?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the channels your bots have access to allow the bot to have these permissions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send Messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send Messages in Threads&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create Public Threads&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manage Messages (only for moderation to delete blocked messages)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Manage Threads&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read Message History&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use Application Commands&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lazyprogrammer/machine_learning_examples</title>
    <updated>2022-12-26T01:35:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-26:/lazyprogrammer/machine_learning_examples</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lazyprogrammer/machine_learning_examples" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A collection of machine learning examples and tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;machine_learning_examples&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A collection of machine learning examples and tutorials.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Find associated tutorials at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lazyprogrammer.me&#34;&gt;https://lazyprogrammer.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Find associated courses at &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that not all code from all courses will be found in this repository. Some newer code examples (e.g. most of Tensorflow 2.0) were done in Google Colab. Therefore, you should check the instructions given in the lectures for the course you are taking.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to I find the code for a particular course?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The code for each course is separated by folder. You can determine which folder corresponds with which course by watching the &#34;Where to get the code&#34; lecture inside the course (usually Lecture 2 or 3).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remember: one folder = one course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Why you should not fork this repo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve noticed that many people have out-of-date forks. Thus, I recommend not forking this repository if you take one of my courses. I am constantly updating my courses, and your fork will soon become out-of-date. You should clone the repository instead to make it easy to get updates (i.e. just &#34;git pull&#34; randomly and frequently).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Where is the code for your latest courses?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beginning with Tensorflow 2, I started to use Google Colab. For those courses, unless otherwise noted, the code will be on Google Colab. Links to the notebooks are provided in the course. See the lecture &#34;Where to get the code&#34; for further details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;VIP Course Links&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Science: Transformers for Natural Language Processing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-transformers-nlp&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-transformers-nlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine Learning: Natural Language Processing in Python (V2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/natural-language-processing-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/natural-language-processing-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Series Analysis, Forecasting, and Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/time-series-analysis&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/time-series-analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Engineering and Artificial Intelligence in Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/ai-finance&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/ai-finance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PyTorch: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/pytorch-deep-learning&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/pytorch-deep-learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tensorflow 2.0: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; (VIP Version)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-tensorflow-2&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-tensorflow-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deep Learning Courses Exclusives&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science: Bayesian Linear Regression in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-linear-regression-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-linear-regression-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science: Bayesian Classification in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-classification-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-classification-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Classical Statistical Inference and A/B Testing in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/statistical-inference-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/statistical-inference-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linear Programming for Linear Regression in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/linear-programming-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/linear-programming-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MATLAB for Students, Engineers, and Professionals in STEM &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/matlab&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/matlab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Other Course Links&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science &amp;amp; Machine Learning: Naive Bayes in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-machine-learning-naive-bayes-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-machine-learning-naive-bayes-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cutting-Edge AI: Deep Reinforcement Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/cutting-edge-artificial-intelligence&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/cutting-edge-artificial-intelligence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recommender Systems and Deep Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/recommender-systems&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/recommender-systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Machine Learning and AI: Support Vector Machines in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/support-vector-machines-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/support-vector-machines-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning: Advanced Computer Vision &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/advanced-computer-vision&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/advanced-computer-vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning: Advanced NLP and RNNs &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-advanced-nlp&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-advanced-nlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning: GANs and Variational Autoencoders &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-gans-and-variational-autoencoders&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-gans-and-variational-autoencoders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Advanced AI: Deep Reinforcement Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-reinforcement-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-reinforcement-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence: Reinforcement Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/artificial-intelligence-reinforcement-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/artificial-intelligence-reinforcement-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/natural-language-processing-with-deep-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/natural-language-processing-with-deep-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning: Recurrent Neural Networks in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-recurrent-neural-networks-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-recurrent-neural-networks-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unsupervised Machine Learning: Hidden Markov Models in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/unsupervised-machine-learning-hidden-markov-models-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/unsupervised-machine-learning-hidden-markov-models-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning Prerequisites: The Numpy Stack in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-prerequisites-the-numpy-stack-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-prerequisites-the-numpy-stack-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning Prerequisites: Linear Regression in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-linear-regression-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-linear-regression-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning Prerequisites: Logistic Regression in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-logistic-regression-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-logistic-regression-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science: Deep Learning and Neural Networks in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-deep-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-deep-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cluster Analysis and Unsupervised Machine Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/cluster-analysis-unsupervised-machine-learning-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/cluster-analysis-unsupervised-machine-learning-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science: Supervised Machine Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-supervised-machine-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-supervised-machine-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bayesian Machine Learning in Python: A/B Testing &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-machine-learning-in-python-ab-testing&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/bayesian-machine-learning-in-python-ab-testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data Science: Natural Language Processing in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-natural-language-processing-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-natural-language-processing-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern Deep Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-deep-learning-in-theano-tensorflow&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/data-science-deep-learning-in-theano-tensorflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensemble Machine Learning in Python: Random Forest and AdaBoost &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/machine-learning-in-python-random-forest-adaboost&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/machine-learning-in-python-random-forest-adaboost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deep Learning: Convolutional Neural Networks in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-convolutional-neural-networks-theano-tensorflow&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/deep-learning-convolutional-neural-networks-theano-tensorflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unsupervised Deep Learning in Python &lt;a href=&#34;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/unsupervised-deep-learning-in-python&#34;&gt;https://deeplearningcourses.com/c/unsupervised-deep-learning-in-python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>