<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Python Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:24Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Python in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>stooged/PI-Pwn</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/stooged/PI-Pwn</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/stooged/PI-Pwn" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;pppwn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PI Pwn&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a script to setup &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheOfficialFloW/PPPwn&#34;&gt;PPPwn&lt;/a&gt; on the raspberry pi and run &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GoldHEN/GoldHEN&#34;&gt;GoldHen&lt;/a&gt; on the PS4 fw 11.0&lt;br&gt; It aso supports internet access after pwn and access to ftp, klog and binloader servers launched by goldhen.&lt;br&gt; A dns blocker is also installed and used to prevent updates.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tested PI Models&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Listed fastest to slowest&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-5/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-4-model-b/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 4 Model B&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-400/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 400&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-3-model-b-plus/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi 3B+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These work but are slow and not really recommended.&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-zero-2-w/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi Zero 2 W&lt;/a&gt; with usb to ethernet adapter&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-zero-w/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi Zero W&lt;/a&gt; with usb to ethernet adapter&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You need to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/software/operating-systems/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi OS Lite&lt;/a&gt; onto a sd card.&lt;br&gt; Place the sd card into your computer and copy the PPPwn folder to the sd card.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Place the sd card into the raspberry pi, boot it and run the following commands&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;sudo chmod 777 /boot/firmware/PPPwn/install.sh&#xA;sudo bash /boot/firmware/PPPwn/install.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the install process you will be asked to set some options.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using a &lt;b&gt;usb to ethernet adapter&lt;/b&gt; for the connection to the console you need to select yes&lt;br&gt; If your pi has an ethernet port and you are using a usb to ethernet adapter your interface for the usb adapter should be eth1&lt;br&gt; If you are using something like a pi zero 2 the interface will be eth0&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the pi reboots pppwn will run automatically.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;On your PS4:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; and then &lt;code&gt;Network&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;Set Up Internet connection&lt;/code&gt; and choose &lt;code&gt;Use a LAN Cable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;code&gt;Custom&lt;/code&gt; setup and choose &lt;code&gt;PPPoE&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;IP Address Settings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;ppp&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;PPPoE User ID&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PPPoE Password&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NOTE if you enable internet access you must match the username and password entered during the install or use the default &lt;code&gt;ppp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;code&gt;Automatic&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;DNS Settings&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;MTU Settings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Choose &lt;code&gt;Do Not Use&lt;/code&gt; for &lt;code&gt;Proxy Server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For GoldHen you need to place the goldhen.bin file onto the root of a usb drive and plug it into the console.&lt;br&gt; Once goldhen has been loaded for the first time it will be copied to the consoles internal hdd and the usb is no longer required.&lt;br&gt; To update goldhen just repeat the above process and the new version will be copied to the internal hdd&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FTP / Binload&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the pi pwn was setup to allow internet access you can use the ftp, klog, and binloader servers on the console&lt;br&gt; Your pi must be also connected to your home network via wifi or a second ethernet connection&lt;br&gt; To connect to the servers from your pc just connect to the raspberry pi ip on your network and all requests will be forwarded to the console&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For ftp make sure you set the transfer mode on your ftp client software to &lt;code&gt;Active&lt;/code&gt; not passive.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What it does&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once everything is setup and the ethernet cable is plugged in between the pi and the console the pi should automatically try and pwn the console.&lt;br&gt; The exploit may fail many times but the pi will continue to purge the console to keep trying to pwn itself.&lt;br&gt; Once pwned the process will stop and the pi will shut down if you are not using internet access. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need to restart the pi if you wish to pwn the console again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea is you boot the console and the pi together and the pi will keep trying to pwn the console without any input from you, just wait on the home screen until the process completes&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Updating&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can edit the exploit scripts by putting the sd card in your computer and going to the PPPwn folder.&lt;br&gt; The install.sh script can also be run again to install changes or change the PPPoE user/password&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;install video&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/945141797?autoplay=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.vimeocdn.com/video/1850373616-93857870e2a0e3974e00b8e53991557af388fc14b13f305998b8757bc11407f7-d&#34; alt=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/945141797?autoplay=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;internet settings follow up video&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/945142322?autoplay=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.vimeocdn.com/video/1850373112-c392e1538902fb22bb8c98558100943e7b8390c029f9e54cb9f27c22da1d6c42-d&#34; alt=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/945142322?autoplay=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mustafaaljadery/gemma-2B-10M</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/mustafaaljadery/gemma-2B-10M</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mustafaaljadery/gemma-2B-10M" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gemma 2B with 10M context length using Infini-attention.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Gemma 2B - 10M Context&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gemma 2B with recurrent local attention with context length of up to 10M. Our implementation uses &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;32GB&lt;/strong&gt; of memory!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/mustafaaljadery/gemma-2B-10M/main/images/graphic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Graphic of our implementation context&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;10M sequence length on Gemma 2B.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runs on less than 32GB of memory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Native inference optimized for cuda.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Recurrent local attention for O(N) memory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a very early checkpoint of the model. Only 200 steps. We plan on training for a lot more tokens!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pip install -r requirements.txt&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the model from huggingface - &lt;a href=&#34;https://huggingface.co/mustafaaljadery/gemma-10M-safetensor&#34;&gt;Huggingface Model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;python main.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change the &lt;code&gt;main.py&lt;/code&gt; inference code to the specific prompt you desire.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;model_path = &#34;./models/gemma-2b-10m&#34;&#xA;tokenizer = AutoTokenizer.from_pretrained(model_path)&#xA;model = GemmaForCausalLM.from_pretrained(&#xA;    model_path,&#xA;    torch_dtype=torch.bfloat16&#xA;)&#xA;&#xA;prompt_text = &#34;Summarize this harry potter book...&#34;&#xA;&#xA;with torch.no_grad():&#xA;    generated_text = generate(&#xA;        model, tokenizer, prompt_text, max_length=512, temperature=0.8&#xA;    )&#xA;&#xA;    print(generated_text)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How does this work?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The largest bottleneck (in terms of memory) for LLMs is the KV cache. It grows quadratically in vanilla multi-head attention, thus limiting the size of your sequence length.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our approach splits the attention in local attention blocks as outlined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.07143&#34;&gt;InfiniAttention&lt;/a&gt;. We take those local attention blocks and apply recurrance to the local attention blocks for the final result of 10M context global atention.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of the inspiration for our ideas comes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.02860&#34;&gt;Transformer-XL&lt;/a&gt; paper.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;More details&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more context about our motivations, implementation details, and the theory behind the work, check out our technical overview on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@akshgarg_36829/gemma-10m-technical-overview-900adc4fbeeb&#34;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was built by:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxaljadery.com/&#34;&gt;Mustafa Aljadery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stanford.edu/~sidshr/&#34;&gt;Siddharth Sharma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/aksh-garg/&#34;&gt;Aksh Garg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jgravelle/AutoGroq</title>
    <updated>2024-05-12T01:35:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-12:/jgravelle/AutoGroq</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jgravelle/AutoGroq" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The PDF file...&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;...contains all the code for this project. It&#39;s handy for uploading to Claude.AI or ChatGPT if you want to make your own modifications. I create those sorts of PDFs with: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgravelle/GetCodeAsPdf&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jgravelle/GetCodeAsPdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s new?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customizable agents!&lt;/strong&gt; They&#39;re now manually editable, and &lt;strong&gt;NOW&lt;/strong&gt;, they can &#39;evolve&#39; with your project! We&#39;ll have a new video out soon! &lt;strong&gt;Temperature control&lt;/strong&gt; Careful setting it too low. It can hose up your agent generations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the heck is...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;AutoGroq?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s how I wish Autogen worked: quickly, simply, and automatically. In the time it takes you to read this file, AutoGroq could have made dozens (if not hundreds) of specialized Autogen agents for you!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/jgravelle/AutoGroq/assets/3400540/0462400b-5584-4ffa-afc4-cd96eed8da77&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FREE, WORKING, HANDS-ON LIVE DEMO:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://autogroq.streamlit.app/&#34;&gt;https://autogroq.streamlit.app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATED&lt;/strong&gt; video tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JkYzuL8V_4g&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JkYzuL8V_4g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Autogroq creates your team of AutoGen compatible agent assistants AND workflows on the fly. Just type in your request!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoGroq&lt;/strong&gt; is an AI-powered conversational assistant designed to revolutionize the way users interact with AI tools. Built with the goal of addressing the limitations of existing solutions, AutoGroq offers a user-friendly, powerful, and configuration-free experience. Our platform focuses on providing immediate and relevant assistance by automatically generating expert agents tailored to help you with any question, problem, or project, regardless of its complexity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Expert Agent Generation&lt;/strong&gt;: AutoGroq&#39;s core functionality lies in its ability to dynamically create expert agents specialized in various domains or topics, ensuring you receive the most relevant support for your inquiries.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Workflow Generation&lt;/strong&gt;: Watch the video. With Autogroq, you&#39;re about ten minutes away from having a custom team of experts hammering out a project for you. But don&#39;t take my word for it. Try it yourself!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural Conversation Flow&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage in intuitive and contextually aware conversations with AutoGroq&#39;s expert agents, facilitating a seamless exchange of information.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Snippet Extraction&lt;/strong&gt;: AutoGroq intelligently extracts and presents code snippets within a dedicated &#34;Whiteboard&#34; section, making it convenient to reference, copy, or modify code during your interaction.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexible Agent Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Customize your panel of expert agents according to your evolving project needs. Add new agents, modify their expertise, or remove them as required.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Prompt Rephrasing&lt;/strong&gt;: AutoGroq employs sophisticated natural language processing techniques to rephrase user inputs, enhancing clarity and ensuring accurate responses from expert agents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experience AutoGroq&#39;s capabilities firsthand by accessing our online beta version: &lt;a href=&#34;https://autogroq.streamlit.app/&#34;&gt;https://autogroq.streamlit.app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that AutoGroq is currently under active development, and you may encounter occasional instability as we continue to refine our platform.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or install it locally:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a step-by-step guide on how to install and set up AutoGroq based on the provided codebase:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python 3.x installed on your system An API key for the Groq API (replace the placeholder in the code with your actual API key)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone the AutoGroq repository or download the source code files. Open a terminal or command prompt and navigate to the AutoGroq project directory. Create a virtual environment (optional but recommended): python -m venv autogroq_venv&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Activate the virtual environment:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Windows: autogroq_venv\Scripts\activate&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For macOS and Linux: source autogroq_venv/bin/activate&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install the required dependencies:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pip install -r requirements.txt&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Set up the necessary environment variables:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Replace the placeholder API key in the code with your actual Groq API key. Set any other required environment variables mentioned in the code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Run the AutoGroq application:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;streamlit run AutoGroq/main.py&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The application will open in your default web browser. If it doesn&#39;t open automatically, you can access it by navigating to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8501&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8501&lt;/a&gt; in your browser. Enter your request in the &#34;Enter your request&#34; text input field and press Enter or click outside the field to trigger the processing. AutoGroq will generate agents and create workflow files based on your request. The generated files will be available for download as ZIP archives. You can interact with the generated agents using the provided user interface. Enter additional input, view the discussion and whiteboard, and reset the application if needed. To exit the application, stop the Streamlit server by pressing Ctrl+C in the terminal or command prompt where you started the application.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Note:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the necessary permissions to install packages and run the application. If you encounter any issues during the installation or setup process, please refer to the troubleshooting guide or seek further assistance. That&#39;s it! You should now have AutoGroq installed and ready to use on your system. Enjoy exploring and utilizing the powerful features of AutoGroq for your projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How It Works&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initiation&lt;/strong&gt;: Begin by entering your query or request in the designated input area.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;: Click the &#34;Begin&#34; button to initiate the interaction. AutoGroq will rephrase your request and generate the appropriate expert agents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interaction&lt;/strong&gt;: Select an expert agent to receive specialized assistance tailored to your needs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;: Continue the conversation by providing additional input or context as required, guiding the flow of information.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review&lt;/strong&gt;: The &#34;Discussion&#34; section will display your dialogue history, while the &#34;Whiteboard&#34; section will showcase any extracted code snippets.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reset&lt;/strong&gt;: Use the &#34;Reset&#34; button to clear the current conversation and start a new one whenever needed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AutoGroq Architecture&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The AutoGroq codebase is structured into the following main components:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;main.py&lt;/code&gt;: The core Streamlit application responsible for managing the user interface and user interactions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;auto_groq_utils.py&lt;/code&gt;: A utility module containing functions for API interactions, prompt refinement, code extraction, and agent management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;agents_management.py&lt;/code&gt;: A module dedicated to the lifecycle management of expert agents, including creation, modification, and deletion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AutoGroq leverages the Streamlit library and integrates with various APIs to enable natural language processing, code extraction, and dynamic agent generation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We value your feedback and contributions in shaping the future of AutoGroq. If you encounter any issues or have ideas for new features, please share them with us on our GitHub repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AutoGroq is proudly open-source and released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for choosing AutoGroq as your AI-powered conversational assistant. We are committed to redefining the boundaries of what AI can achieve and empowering you to tackle any question, problem, or project with ease and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>