<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Python Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-04-30T01:34:54Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Python in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>carykh/jes</title>
    <updated>2025-04-30T01:34:54Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-04-30:/carykh/jes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/carykh/jes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jelly Evolution Simulator&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Jelly Evolution Simulator&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run this program, run this command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmd python jes.py&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: This project, like all my projects, are not meant to be consumer products with perfect QA. Rather, it&#39;s just me, as one person, coding a casual experiment to the point that it works well enough on my computer to make a video from it! No more, no less. (I used to not put my code online, just like when you create a Minecraft world with your friends, you don&#39;t have to share the world with everyone. I just started posting code here because I wanted to make it easier for eager devs to make mods.) Long story short, I won&#39;t be doing bug-fixing or tech support on this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Key-controls&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ESC: Close the program&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;X: Toggle whether or not X&#39;s show up over killed jellies&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;S: Store the species you&#39;re highlighting in memory. (Press S a 2nd time to unstore.) Why do this? Well, say you notice there&#39;s a creature who got #1 in a certain generation, but you can&#39;t find any trace of it elsewhere. Now, you can highlight the creature, press S, and their species bubble will show up in the upper-left. Then, roll your mouse over the species bubble, and there&#39;s all the species info!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;C: Change the color of the species you&#39;re highlighting. Do this when 2 species are annoyingly close in color, and you want a better way to tell them apart.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Q: Open/close the creature mosaic (can also be done by clicking &#34;Show creatures&#34; button)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LEFT/RIGHT: Scroll through forward/backward through the timeline (can also be done by scrolling the scroll bar)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Updates (2025-01-11)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Mutation-finding-bug fixed (I think)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There used to be a bug where, late in the simulation, big mutations would take forever to find. That has been resolved. (It was the 0.5+ rigidity-forcing)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Added all those key controls&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Allowed the user to change the number of creatures in the simulation (first user input)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-Fixed but where, when you click &#34;Watch sample&#34;, it ONLY shows you a sampling of 8 creatures from the recent-est generation. Now, it always shows you a sampling of the generation your scroll bar is currently at.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>