<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-04T01:29:04Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT</title>
    <updated>2025-01-04T01:29:04Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-04:/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open CASCADE Technology (OCCT) is an open-source software development platform for 3D CAD, CAM, CAE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open CASCADE Technology&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open CASCADE Technology (OCCT) is a software development platform providing services for 3D surface and solid modeling, CAD data exchange, and visualization. Most of OCCT functionality is available in the form of C++ libraries. OCCT is ideal for developing software dealing with 3D modeling (CAD), manufacturing/measuring (CAM), or numerical simulation (CAE).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open CASCADE Technology is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License version 2.1 as published by the Free Software Foundation, with a special exception defined in the file &lt;code&gt;OCCT_LGPL_EXCEPTION.txt&lt;/code&gt;. Consult the file &lt;code&gt;LICENSE_LGPL_21.txt&lt;/code&gt; included in the OCCT distribution for the complete text of the license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, Open CASCADE Technology may be used under the terms of the Open CASCADE commercial license or a contractual agreement.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Open CASCADE Technology is provided on an &#34;AS IS&#34; basis, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND. The entire risk related to any use of the OCCT code and materials is on you. See the license text for a formal disclaimer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Packaging&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can receive certified versions of OCCT code in different packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snapshot of Git repository:&lt;/strong&gt; Contains C++ header and source files of OCCT, documentation sources, build scripts, and CMake project files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complete source archive:&lt;/strong&gt; Contains all sources of OCCT, generated HTML and PDF documentation, and ready-to-use projects for building on all officially supported platforms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary package (platform-specific):&lt;/strong&gt; In addition to the complete source archive, it includes binaries of OCCT and third-party libraries built on one platform. This package allows using OCCT immediately after installation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certified versions of OCCT can be downloaded from:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/release&#34;&gt;Open CASCADE Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT/releases&#34;&gt;GitHub Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also find OCCT pre-installed on your system or install it from packages provided by a third party. Note that packaging and functionality of such versions can be different from certified releases. Please consult the documentation accompanying your version for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documentation is available at the following links:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/doc/overview&#34;&gt;Latest version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/doc/occt-7.8.0/overview&#34;&gt;Version 7.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documentation can be part of the package. To preview documentation as part of the package, open the file &lt;code&gt;doc/html/index.html&lt;/code&gt; to browse HTML documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If HTML documentation is not available in your package, you can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generate it from sources:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have Tcl and Doxygen 1.8.4 (or above) installed on your system and accessible in your environment (check the environment variable PATH). Use the batch file &lt;code&gt;adm/gendoc.bat&lt;/code&gt; on Windows or the Bash script &lt;code&gt;adm/gendoc&lt;/code&gt; on Linux or OS X to (re)generate documentation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generate together with sources:&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have CMake and 1.8.4 (or above) installed on your system. Enable &lt;code&gt;BUILD_DOC_Overview&lt;/code&gt; CMake parameter and set the path to Doxygen &lt;code&gt;3RDPARTY_DOXYGEN_EXECUTABLE&lt;/code&gt;. Then build ALL or only &lt;code&gt;Overview&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read documentation in source plain text (Markdown) format&lt;/strong&gt; found in the subfolder &lt;code&gt;dox&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT/wiki&#34;&gt;GitHub Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;code&gt;dox/dev_guides/documentation/documentation.md&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/doc/occt-7.8.0/overview/html/build_upgrade__building_documentation.html&#34;&gt;Building Documentation&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In most cases, you need to rebuild OCCT on your platform (OS, compiler) before using it in your project to ensure binary compatibility.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consult the file &lt;code&gt;dox/dev_guides/building/building.md&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/doc/overview/html/build_upgrade__building_occt.html&#34;&gt;Building OCCT&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT/wiki/build_upgrade&#34;&gt;Building OCCT Wiki&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on building OCCT from sources on supported platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current version of OCCT can be found in the file &lt;code&gt;src/Standard/Standard_Version.hxx&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug Tracker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tracker.dev.opencascade.org/&#34;&gt;OCCT Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information regarding OCCT code development, please consult the official OCCT Collaborative Development Portal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dev.opencascade.org&#34;&gt;OCCT Development Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Forum and Discussions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.opencascade.org/forums&#34;&gt;OCCT Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Open-Cascade-SAS/OCCT/discussions&#34;&gt;GitHub Discussions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>