<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-19T01:25:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>kevinbentley/Descent3</title>
    <updated>2024-04-19T01:25:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-19:/kevinbentley/Descent3</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kevinbentley/Descent3" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Descent 3 by Outrage Entertainment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Descent 3&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Update 04/17/2024&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your contributions after only a little over 24 hours! The current short-term roadmap is code cleanup and build verification. As described below, the original release includes the &#39;1.5&#39; patch that never made it to retail. At the time it was written, it worked--this may or may not be the case at present. We are aiming to clean up the source for improved readability and standards, as well as playability. In short: we&#39;d like to reach a good baseline &#34;vanilla&#34; source.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve had several contributions towards this end already. Please remember to check for duplicate issues and pull requests before submitting!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Update 04/16/2024&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m so happy to see the amount of interest and participation here!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please join the Descent Developer Discord, there&#39;s an active community there already.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/GNy5CUQ&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/GNy5CUQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can expect some big commits coming soon. We&#39;ll be merging in some code that other developers did in parallel and/or after this code was archived.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Direction and Decisions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We will support c++17 going forward&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We are using clang in LLVM mode for code formatting. Please run clang-format before submitting a PR&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Original Release&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the latest version of the Descent 3 source code. This includes the &#39;1.5&#39; patch that Jeff Slutter and Kevin Bentley wrote several years ago. At the time, it worked for Windows, Linux, and Mac.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some proprietary sound and video libraries from Interplay have been stripped out (the ACM and MVE format). I have that code if someone wants to help make a converter so the old cutscenes work. It&#39;ll take some effort to stub out that code so it compiles.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I want to do is get everything compiling again, and ideally some CI/CD actions. After that, the code needs to be cleaned up some, to remove old version control comments, etc. A lot of this code was written by a really great team, but keep in mind we were much younger and less experienced back then.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in helping maintain it, please send me a message. Otherwise, I&#39;m happy to take pull requests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the last update I put out there showing different architectures playing along. Yikes, that was a long time ago, sorry we never released a 1.5 patch. Some logistics got in the way!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oasEAoPHk7I&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.youtube.com/vi/oasEAoPHk7I/0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Descent3 1.5 Patch Development update&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Jeff Slutter, who did most of the work modernizing the code from the 90&#39;s. I&#39;m looking forward to seeing what the community does with it!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>