<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-02-21T01:31:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>panda3d/panda3d</title>
    <updated>2023-02-21T01:31:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-21:/panda3d/panda3d</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/panda3d/panda3d" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Powerful, mature open-source cross-platform game engine for Python and C++, developed by Disney and CMU&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/panda3d/panda3d/actions?query=branch%3Amaster+workflow%3A%22Continuous+Integration%22&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/panda3d/panda3d/workflows/Continuous%20Integration/badge.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d/backers/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCollective&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d/sponsors/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;OpenCollective&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://avatars2.githubusercontent.com/u/590956?v=3&amp;amp;s=500&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Panda3D&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Panda3D is a game engine, a framework for 3D rendering and game development for Python and C++ programs. Panda3D is open-source and free for any purpose, including commercial ventures, thanks to its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/license/&#34;&gt;liberal license&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about Panda3D&#39;s capabilities, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/gallery/&#34;&gt;gallery&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/features/&#34;&gt;feature list&lt;/a&gt;. To learn how to use Panda3D, check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/documentation/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; resources. If you get stuck, ask for help from our active &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.panda3d.org&#34;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Panda3D is licensed under the Modified BSD License. See the LICENSE file for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installing Panda3D&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest Panda3D SDK can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/download/sdk-1-10-13/&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;. If you are familiar with installing Python packages, you can use the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pip install panda3d&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install the latest development build of Panda3D into an existing Python installation is using the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pip install --pre --extra-index-url https://archive.panda3d.org/ panda3d&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If this command fails, please make sure your version of pip is up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer to install the full SDK with all tools, the latest development builds can be obtained from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/download.php?version=devel&amp;amp;sdk&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are automatically kept up-to-date with the latest GitHub version of Panda.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Building Panda3D&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Windows&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can build Panda3D with the Microsoft Visual C++ 2015, 2017, 2019 or 2022 compiler, which can be downloaded for free from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/downloads/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio site&lt;/a&gt;. You will also need to install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/downloads/windows-sdk&#34;&gt;Windows SDK&lt;/a&gt;, and if you intend to target Windows Vista, you will also need the &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/p/?LinkId=323507&#34;&gt;Windows 8.1 SDK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will also need the thirdparty dependency libraries available for the build scripts to use. These are available from one of these two URLs, depending on whether you are on a 32-bit or 64-bit system, or you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rdb/panda3d-thirdparty&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on building them from source.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/download/panda3d-1.10.13/panda3d-1.10.13-tools-win64.zip&#34;&gt;https://www.panda3d.org/download/panda3d-1.10.13/panda3d-1.10.13-tools-win64.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/download/panda3d-1.10.13/panda3d-1.10.13-tools-win32.zip&#34;&gt;https://www.panda3d.org/download/panda3d-1.10.13/panda3d-1.10.13-tools-win32.zip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After acquiring these dependencies, you can build Panda3D from the command prompt using the following command. Change the &lt;code&gt;--msvc-version&lt;/code&gt; option based on your version of Visual C++; 2022 is 14.3, 2019 is 14.2, 2017 is 14.1, and 2015 is 14. Remove the &lt;code&gt;--windows-sdk=10&lt;/code&gt; option if you need to support Windows Vista, which requires the Windows 8.1 SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;makepanda\makepanda.bat --everything --installer --msvc-version=14.3 --windows-sdk=10 --no-eigen --threads=2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the build succeeds, it will produce an .exe file that you can use to install Panda3D on your system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; you may choose to remove &lt;code&gt;--no-eigen&lt;/code&gt; and build with Eigen support in order to improve runtime performance. However, this will cause the build to take hours to complete, as Eigen is a heavily template-based library, and the MSVC compiler does not perform well under those circumstances.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Linux&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building Panda3D on Linux is easy. All you need is to invoke the makepanda script using the version of Python that you want Panda3D to be built against.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run makepanda.py with the --help option to see which options are available. Usually, you will want to specify the --everything option (which builds with support for all features for which it detects the prerequisite dependencies) and the --installer option (which produces an installable .deb or .rpm file for you to install, depending on your distribution).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following command illustrates how to build Panda3D with some common options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;python3 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --installer --no-egl --no-gles --no-gles2 --no-opencv&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will probably see some warnings saying that it&#39;s unable to find several dependency packages. You should determine which ones you want to include in your build and install the respective development packages. You may visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.panda3d.org/1.11/python/distribution/thirdparty-licenses&#34;&gt;this manual page&lt;/a&gt; for an overview of the various dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are on Ubuntu, this command should cover the most frequently used third-party packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install build-essential pkg-config fakeroot python3-dev libpng-dev libjpeg-dev libtiff-dev zlib1g-dev libssl-dev libx11-dev libgl1-mesa-dev libxrandr-dev libxxf86dga-dev libxcursor-dev bison flex libfreetype6-dev libvorbis-dev libeigen3-dev libopenal-dev libode-dev libbullet-dev nvidia-cg-toolkit libgtk-3-dev libassimp-dev libopenexr-dev&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once Panda3D has built, you can either install the .deb or .rpm package that is produced, depending on which Linux distribution you are using. For example, to install the package on Debian or Ubuntu, use this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo dpkg -i panda3d*.deb&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are not using a Linux distribution that supports .deb or .rpm packages, you may have to use the installpanda.py script instead, which will directly copy the files into the appropriate locations on your computer. You may have to run the &lt;code&gt;ldconfig&lt;/code&gt; tool in order to update your library cache after installing Panda3D.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can add the &lt;code&gt;--wheel&lt;/code&gt; option, which will produce a .whl file that can be installed into a Python installation using &lt;code&gt;pip&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;macOS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On macOS, you will need to download a set of precompiled thirdparty packages in order to compile Panda3D, which can be acquired from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/download/panda3d-1.10.14/panda3d-1.10.14-tools-mac.tar.gz&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After placing the thirdparty directory inside the panda3d source directory, you may build Panda3D using a command like the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;python makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --installer&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may target a specific minimum macOS version using the --osxtarget flag followed by the release number, eg. 10.9 or 10.14.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the build was successful, makepanda will have generated a .dmg file in the source directory containing the installer. Simply open it and run the package file in order to install the SDK onto your system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building on FreeBSD is very similar to building on Linux. You will need to install the requisite packages using the system package manager. To install the recommended set of dependencies, you can use this command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pkg install pkgconf bison png jpeg-turbo tiff freetype2 harfbuzz eigen squish openal opusfile libvorbis libX11 mesa-libs ode bullet assimp openexr&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will also need to choose which version of Python you want to use. Install the appropriate package for it (such as &lt;code&gt;python37&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;python38&lt;/code&gt;) and run the makepanda script with your chosen Python version:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;python3.7 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --installer --no-egl --no-gles --no-gles2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If successful, this will produce a .pkg file in the root of the source directory which you can install using &lt;code&gt;pkg install&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Android&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it&#39;s possible to build Panda3D on an Android device using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://termux.com/&#34;&gt;termux&lt;/a&gt; shell, the recommended route is to cross-compile .whl files using the SDK and NDK, which can then be used by the &lt;code&gt;build_apps&lt;/code&gt; command to build a Python application into an .apk or .aab bundle. You will need to get the latest thirdparty packages, which can be obtained from the artifacts page of the last successful run here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rdb/panda3d-thirdparty/actions?query=branch%3Amain+is%3Asuccess+event%3Apush&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rdb/panda3d-thirdparty/actions?query=branch%3Amain+is%3Asuccess+event%3Apush&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This does not include Python at the moment, which can be extracted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://rdb.name/thirdparty-android.tar.gz&#34;&gt;this archive&lt;/a&gt; instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These commands show how to compile wheels for the supported Android ABIs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;export ANDROID_SDK_ROOT=/home/rdb/local/android&#xA;python3.8 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --outputdir built-droid-arm64 --arch arm64 --target android-21 --threads 6 --wheel&#xA;python3.8 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --outputdir built-droid-armv7a --arch armv7a --target android-19 --threads 6 --wheel&#xA;python3.8 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --outputdir built-droid-x86_64 --arch x86_64 --target android-21 --threads 6 --wheel&#xA;python3.8 makepanda/makepanda.py --everything --outputdir built-droid-x86 --arch x86 --target android-19 --threads 6 --wheel&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to use the generated wheels with &lt;code&gt;build_apps&lt;/code&gt;, as explained on this page:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.panda3d.org/t/deployment-for-android/28226&#34;&gt;https://discourse.panda3d.org/t/deployment-for-android/28226&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Running Tests&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.pytest.org/en/latest/getting-started.html#installation&#34;&gt;PyTest&lt;/a&gt; and run the &lt;code&gt;pytest&lt;/code&gt; command. If you have not installed Panda3D, you will need to configure your environment by pointing the &lt;code&gt;PYTHONPATH&lt;/code&gt; variable at the &lt;code&gt;built&lt;/code&gt; directory. On Linux, you will also need to point the &lt;code&gt;LD_LIBRARY_PATH&lt;/code&gt; variable at the &lt;code&gt;built/lib&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a convenience, you can alternatively pass the &lt;code&gt;--tests&lt;/code&gt; option to makepanda.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter any bugs when using Panda3D, please report them in the bug tracker. This is hosted at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/panda3d/panda3d/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/panda3d/panda3d/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make sure to first use the search function to see if the bug has already been reported. When filling out a bug report, make sure that you include as much information as possible to help the developers track down the issue, such as your version of Panda3D, operating system, architecture, and any code and models that are necessary for the developers to reproduce the issue.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re not sure whether you&#39;ve encountered a bug, feel free to ask about it in the forums or the IRC channel first.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Supporting the Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to support the project financially, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d&#34;&gt;our campaign on OpenCollective&lt;/a&gt;. Your contributions help us accelerate the development of Panda3D.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the list of backers, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/panda3d/panda3d/master/BACKERS.md&#34;&gt;BACKERS.md&lt;/a&gt; file or visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.panda3d.org/sponsors&#34;&gt;Sponsors page&lt;/a&gt; on our web site. Thank you to everyone who has donated!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/panda3d/contribute/button@2x.png?color=blue&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tomlooman/ActionRoguelike</title>
    <updated>2023-02-21T01:31:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-21:/tomlooman/ActionRoguelike</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tomlooman/ActionRoguelike" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Third-person Action Roguelike made in Unreal Engine C++. Project for Unreal Engine Pro C++ Course &amp; Stanford University (CS193U)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Action Roguelike Game (Course Project)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is part of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.tomlooman.com/p/unrealengine-cpp?coupon_code=COMMUNITY15&amp;amp;src=github&#34;&gt;Professional Game Development in C++ and Unreal Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Course where we build this entire game project step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tomlooman.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/actionroguelike_ue4_combatsample5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Course Header&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engine Version: 5.1&lt;/strong&gt; (UE4.X Available under &#39;Branches&#39; dropdown)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Branch &#34;Lecture29-FinishedProject&#34; for course-only code.&lt;/strong&gt; (UE 4.25, &#39;Main branch&#39; includes additional polish and features)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tomlooman.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/github_branchesinfo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Branch Selection Info&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Project Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Third-person Action Character Movement&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action System&lt;/strong&gt; (similar to Gameplay Ability System in design) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dash Ability (Teleporting via projectile)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Blackhole Ability&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Magic Projectile Attack&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&#34;Thorns&#34; buff (reflecting damage)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Burning Damage-over-time effect&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AttributeComponent (Holding health etc.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SaveGame System&lt;/strong&gt; for persisting progress of character and world state.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Heavy use of Events to drive UI and gameplay reactions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Mix of C++ &amp;amp; Blueprint and how to combine these effectively.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GameplayTags&lt;/strong&gt; to mark-up Actors, Buffs, Actions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer support&lt;/strong&gt; for all features&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GameMode Logic &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;EQS for binding bot/powerup spawn locations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Bot spawning system (bots cost points to spawn, gamemode gains points over time to spend)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;DataTable holds bot information&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;DataAssets to hold enemy configurations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Manager:&lt;/strong&gt; Async loading of data assets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Async loading of UI icons&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AI &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Minion AI with Behavior Trees (Roam, See, Chase, Attack, Flee/Heal)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;C++ Custom Behavior Trees Nodes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;EQS for attack/cover locations by AI Powerups&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Powerup pickups to heal, gain credits/actions. UMG&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Main menu to host/join game&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UI elements for player attributes and projected widgets for powerups and enemy health.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;C++ Localized Text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is part of the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.tomlooman.com/p/unrealengine-cpp?coupon_code=COMMUNITY15&amp;amp;src=github&#34;&gt;Professional Game Development in C++ and Unreal Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Course where we build this entire game project step-by-step.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.tomlooman.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/ue_course_herobanner_split_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Combat Example Still&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Unreal Engine 5.0&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the release of UE5, some new rendering features have been enabled. For lower end machines it may be required to turn these off. You can do so via the Project Settings or the config INI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;DefaultEngine.ini&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-[/Script/Engine.RendererSettings]&#34;&gt;r.ReflectionMethod=1 ;lumen reflection&#xA;r.GenerateMeshDistanceFields=True&#xA;r.DynamicGlobalIlluminationMethod=1 ;lumen global illumination&#xA;r.Shadow.Virtual.Enable=1 ;virtual shadow maps&#xA;&#xA;[/Script/WindowsTargetPlatform.WindowsTargetSettings]&#xA;DefaultGraphicsRHI=DefaultGraphicsRHI_DX12 // Forcing to use DX12 for improved performance&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stanford University CS193U Reference Project (Fall &#39;20) &lt;strong&gt;Details: &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.tomlooman.com/p/unrealengine-cpp?coupon_code=COMMUNITY15&amp;amp;src=github&#34;&gt;Course Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Assets:&lt;/strong&gt; Licensed for use with the Unreal Engine only. Without a custom license you cannot use to create sequels, remasters, or otherwise emulate the original game or use the original game’s trademarks, character names, or other IP to advertise or name your game. (Unreal Engine EULA applies) (Please note this applies to the Game Assets that refer to Epic&#39;s Paragon, you can still use the project code and content to build your own Unreal Engine game)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>qTox/qTox</title>
    <updated>2023-02-21T01:31:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-02-21:/qTox/qTox</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/qTox/qTox" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;qTox is a chat, voice, video, and file transfer IM client using the encrypted peer-to-peer Tox protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;This repository and qTox are unmaintained!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to a lack of resources, qTox is no longer maintained.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If someone with provable C++ experience and sufficient resources to maintain qTox wants to take over I&#39;m happy to discuss that. Meanwhile &lt;strong&gt;be careful about &#34;official forks&#34; of qTox&lt;/strong&gt; unless you read it here, they are probably not official.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to take the time and thank all &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt; and especially the long term contributors and founders:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anthonybilinski&#34;&gt;anthonybilinski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Diadlo&#34;&gt;Diadlo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iphydf&#34;&gt;iphydf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nurupo&#34;&gt;nurupo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tux3&#34;&gt;tux3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zetok&#34;&gt;zetok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was fun working with all of you and I learned a lot!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;So long, and thanks for all the fish!&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sudden6&#34;&gt;sudden6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a name=&#34;qtox&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://qtox.github.io/assets/imgs/logo_head.png&#34; alt=&#34;qTox&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-GPLv3%2B-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GPLv3+&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/engage/tox/?utm_source=widget&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://hosted.weblate.org/widgets/tox/-/svg-badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Translate on Weblate&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/qtox/qTox?utm_source=badge&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.gitter.im/Join Chat.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Gitter&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/release-schedule/raw/master/README.md&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://qtox.github.io/release-schedule/status.svg?sanitize=true&#34; title=&#34;Week of Merges: population of Merges increases!&#xA;Week of Testing: Your mana regenerates!&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt; qTox is a chat, voice, video, and file transfer instant messaging client using the encrypted peer-to-peer Tox protocol. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/doc/user_manual_en.md&#34;&gt;User Manual&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md&#34;&gt;Install/Build&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/milestones&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/wiki/Writing-Useful-Bug-Reports&#34;&gt;Report bugs&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://build.tox.chat/&#34;&gt;Jenkins builds&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.tox.chat&#34;&gt;Mailing list&lt;/a&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;IRC:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.libera.chat/#qtox&#34;&gt;#qtox@libera.chat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Windows&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Linux&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;OS X&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/v1.17.6/setup-qtox-x86_64-release.exe&#34;&gt;64 bit release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#arch&#34;&gt;Arch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://packages.debian.org/search?keywords=qtox&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#fedora&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#gentoo&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#opensuse&#34;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://packages.ubuntu.com/search?keywords=qtox&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/v1.17.6/qTox.dmg&#34;&gt;Latest release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#freebsd-easy&#34;&gt;Package &amp;amp; Port&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/v1.17.6/setup-qtox-i686-release.exe&#34;&gt;32 bit release&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/v1.17.6/qTox-v1.17.6.x86_64.AppImage&#34;&gt;AppImage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/v1.17.6/qTox-v1.17.6.x86_64.flatpak&#34;&gt;Flatpak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#os-x&#34;&gt;Building instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/nightly/qtox-nightly-x86_64-release.exe&#34;&gt;64 bit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/nightly/qtox-nightly-i686-release.exe&#34;&gt;32 bit&lt;/a&gt; nightly&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/INSTALL.md#linux&#34;&gt;From Source&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/nightly/qTox-nightly.flatpak&#34;&gt;Flatpak nightly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/nightly/qTox-nightly.x86_64.AppImage&#34;&gt;AppImage nightly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/releases/download/nightly/qTox-nightly.dmg&#34;&gt;Latest nightly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bold&lt;/strong&gt; options are recommended.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Builds other than installer/packages don&#39;t receive updates automatically, so make sure you get back to this site and regularly download the latest version of qTox.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Help us&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re wondering how could you help, fear not, there are plenty of ways &lt;span&gt;😄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of them are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Spread the good word about qTox to make it more popular &lt;span&gt;😄&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Have an opinion? Make sure to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/labels/I-feedback-wanted&#34;&gt;voice it in the issues that need it&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/labels/E-easy&#34;&gt;easy issues&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/labels/help%20wanted&#34;&gt;issues that need help&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/CONTRIBUTING.md#how-to-start-contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; first though &lt;span&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/wiki/Testing&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/wiki/Writing-Useful-Bug-Reports&#34;&gt;reporting bugs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/translations/README.md&#34;&gt;Translating, it&#39;s easy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/qTox/qTox/master/CONTRIBUTING.md#reviews&#34;&gt;Reviewing and testing pull requests&lt;/a&gt; – you don&#39;t need to be able to code to do that &lt;span&gt;😉&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Take a task from our Roadmap below&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently qTox is under a feature freeze to clean up our codebase and tools. During this time we want to prepare qTox for upcoming new features of toxcore.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next steps are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;move all toxcore abstractions into their own subproject&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;write basic tests for this Core&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;format the code base&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;rethink our Issue tracker&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current state is tracked in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qTox/projects/3?fullscreen=true&#34;&gt;Code cleanup&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: The screenshots may not always be up to date, but they should give a good idea of the general look and features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/olb89CN.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 01&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/tmX8z9s.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 02&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;One to one chat with friends&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Group chats&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;File transfers, with previewing of images&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Audio calls, including group calls&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Video calls&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ToxMe and Tox URI support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Translations in over 30 languages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Avatars&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Faux offline messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;History&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Screenshots&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Emoticons&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto-updates on Windows and packages on Linux&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And many more options!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Organizational stuff&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happens in both IRC channel &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.libera.chat/#qtox&#34;&gt;#qtox@libera.chat&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.tox.chat/listinfo/qtox-dev&#34;&gt;qTox-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in participating, &lt;strong&gt;join the channel&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;subscribe to the mailing list&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qTox/qtox-irc-logs&#34;&gt;IRC logs&lt;/a&gt; available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;GPG fingerprints&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;List of GPG fingerprints used by qTox developers to sign commits, merges, tags, and possibly other stuff.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Active qTox maintainers:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;7EB3 39FE 8817 47E7 01B7  D472 EBE3 6E66 A842 9B99      - Anthony Bilinski&#xA;3103 9166 FA90 2CA5 0D05  D608 5AF9 F2E2 9107 C727      – Diadlo&#xA;CA92 21C5 389B 7C50 AA5F  7793 52A5 0775 BE13 DF17      - noavarice&#xA;DA26 2CC9 3C0E 1E52 5AD2  1C85 9677 5D45 4B8E BF44      – sudden6&#xA;141C 880E 8BA2 5B19 8D0F  850F 7C13 2143 C1A3 A7D4      – tox-user&#xA;2880 C860 D95C 909D 3DA4  5C68 7E08 6DD6 6126 3264      – tux3&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Past qTox maintainers:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;C7A2 552D 0B25 0F98 3827  742C 1332 03A3 AC39 9151      – initramfs&#xA;BA78 83E2 2F9D 3594 5BA3  3760 5313 7C30 33F0 9008      – zetok&#xA;F365 8D0A 04A5 76A4 1072  FC0D 296F 0B76 4741 106C      – agilob&#xA;1157 616B BD86 0C53 9926  F813 9591 A163 FF9B E04C      – antis81&#xA;1D29 8BC7 25B7 BE82 65BA  EAB9 3DB8 E053 15C2 20AA      – Dubslow&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Windows updates, managed by &lt;code&gt;tux3&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;AED3 1134 9C23 A123 E5C4  AA4B 139C A045 3DA2 D773&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>