<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-02T01:24:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>TheScienceElf/Blocks-TI-84</title>
    <updated>2023-09-02T01:24:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-02:/TheScienceElf/Blocks-TI-84</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TheScienceElf/Blocks-TI-84" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Minecraft-esque game for the TI 84 CE calculator.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Blocks for the TI 84 CE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Minecraft-esque game for the TI 84 CE calculator. In it you can generate natural-looking worlds, place up to 24 different kinds of blocks, keep up to 5 saves, and enjoy real-time shadow effects, transparent water, and a 10 FPS framerate!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bj9CiMO66xk&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; to see it running on real hardware, and for more implementation details.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TheScienceElf/Blocks-TI-84/main/Screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some sample gameplay captured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ce-programming.github.io/CEmu/&#34;&gt;CEmu&lt;/a&gt;. Note that the triangular screen-tearing is an artifact of the emulator, and doesn&#39;t show up when running on real hardware.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Try It Yourself&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to reliance on some eZ80 hardware instructions, this program can only be run on CE or later model calculators from the Ti84 family.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the binary &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/TheScienceElf/Blocks-TI-84/main/bin/BLOCKS.8xp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CE-Programming/libraries/releases/tag/v11.2&#34;&gt;CE C Standard Libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Load both onto your calculator using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://education.ti.com/en/products/computer-software/ti-connect-ce-sw&#34;&gt;TI Connect™ CE software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the ASM program either with &lt;code&gt;Asm(prgmBLOCKS)&lt;/code&gt; or your favorite graphical shell.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The world select menu should appear. Select an empty save slot and press enter to generate a new world.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; This program takes up a lot of RAM on the calculator, and doesn&#39;t always do so gracefully. It doesn&#39;t happen very often, but in the case where you get it to crash &lt;strong&gt;you will need to reset your calculator&lt;/strong&gt;, which will clear any unarchived data in RAM. It&#39;s best to just archive anything you wouldn&#39;t want to lose before running this. Not only does it protect that data from crashes, but it frees up more memory for the game.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigating a 3D world is tricky, but I&#39;ve tried my best to make the controls manageable. To control this program, use the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Move the cursor with the outer numpad (&lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;code&gt;9&lt;/code&gt; except for &lt;code&gt;5&lt;/code&gt;) to move in that direction (i.e. 6 to move to the right)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Move straight up and straight down (in 3D) with &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; respectively&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scroll the view with the arrow keys (it will return to the player automatically if it gets too far away)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Place or remove blocks at the current cursor position with &lt;code&gt;5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open the block select screen with &lt;code&gt;enter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save and quit to the world select menu with &lt;code&gt;2nd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sharing Worlds&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to technical limitations the world format is a bit strange. Each world is composed of 17 files on your calculator, for example in the case of &#34;World A&#34; the files will be&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WORLDA&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WORLDA00 - WORLDA15&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to transfer a world onto or off of your calculator, make sure you all of these files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOT AN OFFICIAL MINECRAFT PRODUCT. NOT APPROVED BY OR ASSOCIATED WITH MOJANG OR MICROSOFT.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>