<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-21T01:32:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T01:32:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-21:/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open RV&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open RV is an image and sequence viewer for VFX and animation artists. Open RV is high-performant, hardware accelerated, and pipeline-friendly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV/main/doc/rv-manuals.md&#34;&gt;RV Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Build Instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can build Open RV for Linux, Windows, and macOS. You build it from scratch using the instructions specific to each OS:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV/main/doc/build_system/config_linux_centos7.md&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV/main/doc/build_system/config_windows.md&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AcademySoftwareFoundation/OpenRV/main/doc/build_system/config_macos.md&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Building Tips&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Build Aliases&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;code&gt;source rvmds.sh&lt;/code&gt; to add common build aliases into your shell. After the first download following the installation of the required dependencies, use &lt;code&gt;rvbootstrap&lt;/code&gt; to set up, configure, and build Open RV with the default options.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the setup, you can use &lt;code&gt;rvmk&lt;/code&gt; to build.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Compile in Parallel&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start the compilation in parallel by adding &lt;code&gt;--parallel[=threadCound]&lt;/code&gt; to the build command. This is the same as using &lt;code&gt;-j&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;3rd Parties Outside Of Repository&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you desire to keep your third-party builds between build cleanups, set &lt;code&gt;-DRV_DEPS_BASE_DIR=/path/to/third/party&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Expert Mode&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can always go to the build directory and call the generator directly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Running Open RV&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the build ends, you can execute (or debug!) Open RV from the cmake-build directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The path to the build is &lt;code&gt;cmake-build/stage/app&lt;/code&gt;. The Open RV cmake options set up the environment so you can start the build without RPATH issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recommended method to install Open RV is to invoke the install build step tool using cmake.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The build system allows you to prepackage Open RV using cmake&#39;s install command and a prefix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, it&#39;s up to you to either sign or package the result, or to do both. It should contain the minimum required to have a full Open RV.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cmake --install cmake-build --prefix /Absolute/path/to/a/destination/folder&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Run Tests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You invoke Open RV tests with the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;ctest --test-dir cmake-build --extra-verbose&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Tests Tips&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Run The Tests In Parallel&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can run the tests in parallel by specifying &lt;code&gt;--parallel X&lt;/code&gt;, where X is the number of tests to run in parallel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Run A Subset Of The Tests&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can apply a filter with the &lt;code&gt;-R&lt;/code&gt; flag to specify a regex.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Run The Tests Verbose&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can run the tests with extra verbosity with the flag &lt;code&gt;--extra-verbose&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; You cannot use &lt;code&gt;--extra-verbose&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;--parallel&lt;/code&gt;. It&#39;s one or the other, not both.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing to Open RV&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository uses pre-commit to have formatting executed before a commit. To install the hooks:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;pre-commit install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; When the hooks reformat a file, you need to re-add them to git to have your &lt;code&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt; command executed. Also, you can skip the hook execution by using &lt;code&gt;git commit -n&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TigerVNC/tigervnc</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T01:32:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-21:/TigerVNC/tigervnc</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TigerVNC/tigervnc" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;High performance, multi-platform VNC client and server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About TigerVNC&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Virtual Network Computing (VNC) is a remote display system which allows you to view and interact with a virtual desktop environment that is running on another computer on the network. Using VNC, you can run graphical applications on a remote machine and send only the display from these applications to your local machine. VNC is platform-independent and supports a wide variety of operating systems and architectures as both servers and clients.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TigerVNC is a high-speed version of VNC based on the RealVNC 4 and X.org code bases. TigerVNC started as a next-generation development effort for TightVNC on Unix and Linux platforms, but it split from its parent project in early 2009 so that TightVNC could focus on Windows platforms. TigerVNC supports a variant of Tight encoding that is greatly accelerated by the use of the libjpeg-turbo JPEG codec.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Legal&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Incomplete and generally out of date copyright list::&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Copyright (C) 1999 AT&amp;amp;T Laboratories Cambridge&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2002-2005 RealVNC Ltd.&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2000-2006 TightVNC Group&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2005-2006 Martin Koegler&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2005-2006 Sun Microsystems, Inc.&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2006 OCCAM Financial Technology&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2000-2008 Constantin Kaplinsky&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2004-2017 Peter Astrand for Cendio AB&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2010 Antoine Martin&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2010 m-privacy GmbH&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2009-2011 D. R. Commander&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2009-2011 Pierre Ossman for Cendio AB&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2004, 2009-2011 Red Hat, Inc.&#xA;    Copyright (C) 2009-2022 TigerVNC Team&#xA;    All Rights Reserved.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is distributed under the GNU General Public Licence as published by the Free Software Foundation. See the file LICENCE.TXT for the conditions under which this software is made available. TigerVNC also contains code from other sources. See the Acknowledgements section below, and the individual source files, for details of the conditions under which they are made available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;All Platforms&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All versions of TigerVNC contain the following programs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;vncviewer - the cross-platform TigerVNC Viewer, written using FLTK. vncviewer connects to a VNC server and allows you to interact with the remote desktop being displayed by the VNC server. The VNC server can be running on a Windows or a Unix/Linux machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Windows-Specific&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Windows version of TigerVNC contains the following programs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;winvnc - the TigerVNC Server for Windows. winvnc allows a Windows desktop to be accessed remotely using a VNC viewer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WARNING: winvnc is currently unmaintained and and may not function correctly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;winvnc may not work if the Fast User Switching or Remote Desktop features are in use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Unix/Linux-Specific (not Mac)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Unix/Linux version of TigerVNC contains the following programs:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Xvnc - the TigerVNC Server for Unix. Xvnc is both a VNC server and an X server with a &#34;virtual&#34; framebuffer. You should normally use the vncserver service to start Xvnc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;vncpasswd - a program which allows you to change the VNC password used to access your VNC server sessions (assuming that VNC authentication is being used.) This command must be run to set a password before using VNC authentication with any of the servers or services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;vncconfig - a program which is used to configure and control a running instance of Xvnc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;x0vncserver - an inefficient VNC server which continuously polls any X display, allowing it to be controlled via VNC. It is intended mainly as a demonstration of a simple VNC server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also contains the following systemd service:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:vncserver@.service&#34;&gt;vncserver@.service&lt;/a&gt; - a service to start a user session with Xvnc and one of the desktop environments available on the system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This distribution contains public domain DES software by Richard Outerbridge. This is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Copyright (c) 1988,1989,1990,1991,1992 by Richard Outerbridge.&#xA;(GEnie : OUTER; CIS : [71755,204]) Graven Imagery, 1992.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This distribution contains software from the X Window System. This is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 1987, 1988, 1998 The Open Group&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute, and sell this software and its documentation for any purpose is hereby granted without fee, provided that the above copyright notice appear in all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission notice appear in supporting documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &#34;AS IS&#34;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE OPEN GROUP BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Except as contained in this notice, the name of The Open Group shall not be used in advertising or otherwise to promote the sale, use or other dealings in this Software without prior written authorization from The Open Group.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 1987, 1988 by Digital Equipment Corporation, Maynard, Massachusetts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                     All Rights Reserved&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and its documentation for any purpose and without fee is hereby granted, provided that the above copyright notice appear in all copies and that both that copyright notice and this permission notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name of Digital not be used in advertising or publicity pertaining to distribution of the software without specific, written prior permission.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DIGITAL DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS SOFTWARE, INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS, IN NO EVENT SHALL DIGITAL BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>apache/brpc</title>
    <updated>2023-01-21T01:32:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-21:/apache/brpc</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apache/brpc" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;brpc is an Industrial-grade RPC framework using C++ Language, which is often used in high performance system such as Search, Storage, Machine learning, Advertisement, Recommendation etc. &#34;brpc&#34; means &#34;better RPC&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/README_cn.md&#34;&gt;中文版&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/brpc/actions/workflows/ci-linux.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/apache/brpc/actions/workflows/ci-linux.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Linux Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/brpc/actions/workflows/ci-macos.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/apache/brpc/actions/workflows/ci-macos.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;MacOs Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/images/logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;brpc&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;brpc is an Industrial-grade RPC framework using C++ Language, which is often used in high performance system such as Search, Storage, Machine learning, Advertisement, Recommendation etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&#34;brpc&#34; means &#34;better RPC&#34;.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use it to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build a server that can talk in multiple protocols (&lt;strong&gt;on same port&lt;/strong&gt;), or access all sorts of services &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;restful http/https, &lt;a href=&#34;https://http2.github.io/http2-spec&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://grpc.io&#34;&gt;gRPC&lt;/a&gt;. using http/h2 in brpc is much more friendly than &lt;a href=&#34;https://curl.haxx.se/libcurl/&#34;&gt;libcurl&lt;/a&gt;. Access protobuf-based protocols with HTTP/h2+json, probably from another language.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/redis_client.md&#34;&gt;redis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/memcache_client.md&#34;&gt;memcached&lt;/a&gt;, thread-safe, more friendly and performant than the official clients.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brpc/brpc/raw/master/src/brpc/rtmp.h&#34;&gt;rtmp&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_Video&#34;&gt;flv&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_Live_Streaming&#34;&gt;hls&lt;/a&gt;, for building &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brpc/media-server&#34;&gt;streaming services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;hadoop_rpc (may be opensourced)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Remote_direct_memory_access&#34;&gt;rdma&lt;/a&gt; support (will be opensourced)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/thrift.md&#34;&gt;thrift&lt;/a&gt; support, thread-safe, more friendly and performant than the official clients.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;all sorts of protocols used in Baidu: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/baidu_std.md&#34;&gt;baidu_std&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/streaming_rpc.md&#34;&gt;streaming_rpc&lt;/a&gt;, hulu_pbrpc, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/baidu/sofa-pbrpc&#34;&gt;sofa_pbrpc&lt;/a&gt;, nova_pbrpc, public_pbrpc, ubrpc and nshead-based ones.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Build &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High_availability&#34;&gt;HA&lt;/a&gt; distributed services using an industrial-grade implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://raft.github.io&#34;&gt;RAFT consensus algorithm&lt;/a&gt; which is opensourced at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brpc/braft&#34;&gt;braft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Servers can handle requests &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/server.md&#34;&gt;synchronously&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/server.md#asynchronous-service&#34;&gt;asynchronously&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clients can access servers &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/client.md#synchronus-call&#34;&gt;synchronously&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/client.md#asynchronous-call&#34;&gt;asynchronously&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/client.md#semi-synchronous-call&#34;&gt;semi-synchronously&lt;/a&gt;, or use &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/combo_channel.md&#34;&gt;combo channels&lt;/a&gt; to simplify sharded or parallel accesses declaratively.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Debug services &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/builtin_service.md&#34;&gt;via http&lt;/a&gt;, and run &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/cpu_profiler.md&#34;&gt;cpu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/heap_profiler.md&#34;&gt;heap&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/contention_profiler.md&#34;&gt;contention&lt;/a&gt; profilers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/overview.md#better-latency-and-throughput&#34;&gt;better latency and throughput&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/new_protocol.md&#34;&gt;Extend brpc&lt;/a&gt; with the protocols used in your organization quickly, or customize components, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/load_balancing.md#%E5%91%BD%E5%90%8D%E6%9C%8D%E5%8A%A1&#34;&gt;naming services&lt;/a&gt; (dns, zk, etcd), &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/load_balancing.md#%E8%B4%9F%E8%BD%BD%E5%9D%87%E8%A1%A1&#34;&gt;load balancers&lt;/a&gt; (rr, random, consistent hashing)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Try it!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/overview.md&#34;&gt;overview&lt;/a&gt; to know where brpc can be used and its advantages.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/getting_started.md&#34;&gt;getting started&lt;/a&gt; for building steps and play with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brpc/brpc/tree/master/example/&#34;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Docs: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/benchmark.md&#34;&gt;Performance benchmark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/bvar.md&#34;&gt;bvar&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/bvar_c++.md&#34;&gt;bvar_c++&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/bthread.md&#34;&gt;bthread&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/bthread_or_not.md&#34;&gt;bthread or not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/thread_local.md&#34;&gt;thread-local&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/execution_queue.md&#34;&gt;Execution Queue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Client &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/client.md&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/error_code.md&#34;&gt;Error code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/combo_channel.md&#34;&gt;Combo channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/http_client.md&#34;&gt;Access http/h2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/http_derivatives.md#h2grpc&#34;&gt;Access gRPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/thrift.md#client-accesses-thrift-server&#34;&gt;Access thrift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/ub_client.md&#34;&gt;Access UB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/streaming_rpc.md&#34;&gt;Streaming RPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/redis_client.md&#34;&gt;Access redis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/memcache_client.md&#34;&gt;Access memcached&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/backup_request.md&#34;&gt;Backup request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/dummy_server.md&#34;&gt;Dummy server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Server &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/server.md&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/http_service.md&#34;&gt;Serve http/h2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/http_derivatives.md#h2grpc&#34;&gt;Serve gRPC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/thrift.md#server-processes-thrift-requests&#34;&gt;Serve thrift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/nshead_service.md&#34;&gt;Serve Nshead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/server_debugging.md&#34;&gt;Debug server issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/server_push.md&#34;&gt;Server push&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/avalanche.md&#34;&gt;Avalanche&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/auto_concurrency_limiter.md&#34;&gt;Auto ConcurrencyLimiter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brpc/media-server&#34;&gt;Media Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/json2pb.md&#34;&gt;json2pb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/builtin_service.md&#34;&gt;Builtin Services&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/status.md&#34;&gt;status&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/vars.md&#34;&gt;vars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/connections.md&#34;&gt;connections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/flags.md&#34;&gt;flags&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/rpcz.md&#34;&gt;rpcz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/cpu_profiler.md&#34;&gt;cpu_profiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/heap_profiler.md&#34;&gt;heap_profiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/contention_profiler.md&#34;&gt;contention_profiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Tools &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/rpc_press.md&#34;&gt;rpc_press&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/rpc_replay.md&#34;&gt;rpc_replay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/rpc_view.md&#34;&gt;rpc_view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/benchmark_http.md&#34;&gt;benchmark_http&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/parallel_http.md&#34;&gt;parallel_http&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Others &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/iobuf.md&#34;&gt;IOBuf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/streaming_log.md&#34;&gt;Streaming Log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/flatmap.md&#34;&gt;FlatMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/brpc_intro.pptx&#34;&gt;brpc introduction&lt;/a&gt;(training material)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/tutorial_on_building_services.pptx&#34;&gt;A tutorial on building large-scale services&lt;/a&gt;(training material)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/brpc_internal.pptx&#34;&gt;brpc internal&lt;/a&gt;(training material)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;RPC in depth &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/new_protocol.md&#34;&gt;New Protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/atomic_instructions.md&#34;&gt;Atomic instructions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/io.md&#34;&gt;IO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/en/threading_overview.md&#34;&gt;Threading Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/load_balancing.md&#34;&gt;Load Balancing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/lalb.md&#34;&gt;Locality-aware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/consistent_hashing.md&#34;&gt;Consistent Hashing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/memory_management.md&#34;&gt;Memory Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/timer_keeping.md&#34;&gt;Timer keeping&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/docs/cn/bthread_id.md&#34;&gt;bthread_id&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Use cases &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/community/cases.md&#34;&gt;User cases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contribute code&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/brpc/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Feedback and Getting involved&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Report bugs, ask questions or give suggestions by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/apache/brpc/issues&#34;&gt;Github Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Subscribe mailing list(&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dev-subscribe@brpc.apache.org&#34;&gt;dev-subscribe@brpc.apache.org&lt;/a&gt;) to get updated with the project&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We follow the code of conduct from Apache Software Foundation, please refer it here &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/foundation/policies/conduct&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>