<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-28T01:31:05Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HexRaysSA/goomba</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T01:31:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-28:/HexRaysSA/goomba</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HexRaysSA/goomba" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;gooMBA is a Hex-Rays Decompiler plugin to simplify Mixed Boolean-Arithmetic (MBA) expressions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;gooMBA&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;gooMBA is a Hex-Rays Decompiler plugin that simplifies Mixed Boolean-Arithmetic (MBA) expressions. It achieves this using several heuristics and algorithms to achieve orders-of-magnitude better performance than existing state-of-the-art solutions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;More information on the inner workings of this tool is available in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://hex-rays.com/blog/deobfuscation-with-goomba/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Core Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Full integration with the Hex-Rays Decompiler&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Simplifies linear MBAs, including opaque predicates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Handles sign extension for linear functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Verifies soundness of simplifications using the z3 SMT solver&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Simplifies non-linear MBAs with the use of a function fingerprint oracle&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, the plugin does not run automatically. You can invoke the plugin by right clicking in the pseudocode view and selecting &#34;Run gooMBA Optimizer&#34;. In addition, you can set up a keyboard shortcut in IDA by opening Options -&amp;gt; Shortcuts... and adding a shortcut for the &lt;code&gt;goomba:run&lt;/code&gt; action.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several options for usage are available within &lt;code&gt;goomba.cfg&lt;/code&gt;. You can set up a fingerprint oracle, configure the z3 proof timeout time, choose the desired behavior when timeouts occur, and choose to make the plugin run automatically without needing to be invoked from the right-click menu.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The sample database &lt;code&gt;tests/idb/mba_challenge.i64&lt;/code&gt; was created from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrphrazer/msynth/raw/main/samples/mba_challenge&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mba_challenge&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; binary. The functions &lt;code&gt;mba1&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mba2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mba3&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;mba&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;solve_me&lt;/code&gt; contain MBA expressions of varying complexity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, the &lt;code&gt;mba1&lt;/code&gt; function&#39;s initial pseudocode: &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/HexRaysSA/goomba/main/images/mba1_before.png&#34; alt=&#34;mba1 initial pseudocode&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And after running gooMBA optimization: &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/HexRaysSA/goomba/main/images/mba1_after.png&#34; alt=&#34;mba1 pseudocode optimized&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Fingerprint oracle&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The oracle can be used for simplifying non-linear MBAs. The input for generaring it is a list of candidate expressions in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrphrazer/msynth&#34;&gt;msynth&lt;/a&gt; syntax. You can use &lt;code&gt;generate_oracle.sh&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;generate_oracle.bat&lt;/code&gt; to generate a binary oracle file which can then be used by the plugin by specifying the path to it in &lt;code&gt;goomba.cfg&lt;/code&gt; (parameter &lt;code&gt;MBA_ORACLE_PATH&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A large pre-computed oracle is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://hex-rays.com/products/ida/support/freefiles/goomba-oracle.7z&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: oracle files generated with IDA 8.2 can only be used with 64-bit binaries, otherwise you may hit internal error 30661.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>upx/upx</title>
    <updated>2023-01-28T01:31:05Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-28:/upx/upx</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/upx/upx" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;UPX - the Ultimate Packer for eXecutables&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;             ooooo     ooo  ooooooooo.  ooooooo  ooooo&#xA;             `888&#39;     `8&#39;  `888   `Y88. `8888    d8&#39;&#xA;              888       8    888   .d88&#39;   Y888..8P&#xA;              888       8    888ooo88P&#39;     `8888&#39;&#xA;              888       8    888           .8PY888.&#xA;              `88.    .8&#39;    888          d8&#39;  `888b&#xA;                `YbodP&#39;     o888o       o888o  o88888o&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;                The Ultimate Packer for eXecutables&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 1996-2023 Markus Oberhumer, Laszlo Molnar &amp;amp; John Reiser &lt;a href=&#34;https://upx.github.io&#34;&gt;https://upx.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;WELCOME&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to UPX !&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX is a free, secure, portable, extendable, high-performance executable packer for several executable formats.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX is an advanced executable file compressor. UPX will typically reduce the file size of programs and DLLs by around 50%-70%, thus reducing disk space, network load times, download times and other distribution and storage costs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Programs and libraries compressed by UPX are completely self-contained and run exactly as before, with no runtime or memory penalty for most of the supported formats.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX supports a number of different executable formats, including Windows programs and DLLs, macOS apps and Linux executables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX is free software distributed under the term of the GNU General Public License. Full source code is available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX may be distributed and used freely, even with commercial applications. See the UPX License Agreements for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;SECURITY CONTEXT&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT NOTE: UPX inherits the security context of any files it handles.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This means that packing, unpacking, or even testing or listing a file requires the same security considerations as actually executing the file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use UPX on trusted files only!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;SHORT DOCUMENTATION&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#39;upx program.exe&#39; will compress a program or DLL. For best compression results try &#39;upx --best program.exe&#39; or &#39;upx --brute program.exe&#39;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the file UPX.DOC for the full documentation. The files NEWS and BUGS also contain various tidbits of information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;THE FUTURE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stay up-to-date with ongoing OS and executable format changes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;RISC-V 64 for Linux&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;ARM64 for Windows (help wanted)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We will &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; add any sort of protection and/or encryption. This only gives people a false feeling of security because all &#34;protectors&#34; can be broken by definition.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix all remaining bugs - please report any issues &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/upx/upx/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/upx/upx/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;COPYRIGHT&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (C) 1996-2023 Markus Franz Xaver Johannes Oberhumer Copyright (C) 1996-2023 Laszlo Molnar Copyright (C) 2000-2023 John F. Reiser&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;UPX is distributed with full source code under the terms of the GNU General Public License v2+; either under the pure GPLv2+ (see the file COPYING), or (at your option) under the GPLv+2 with special exceptions and restrictions granting the free usage for all binaries including commercial programs (see the file LICENSE).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the UPX License Agreements along with this program; see the files COPYING and LICENSE. If not, visit the UPX home page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Share and enjoy, Markus &amp;amp; Laszlo &amp;amp; John&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Markus F.X.J. Oberhumer Laszlo Molnar &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:markus@oberhumer.com&#34;&gt;markus@oberhumer.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ezerotven+github@gmail.com&#34;&gt;ezerotven+github@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;John F. Reiser &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jreiser@BitWagon.com&#34;&gt;jreiser@BitWagon.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[ The term UPX is a shorthand for the Ultimate Packer for eXecutables and holds no connection with potential owners of registered trademarks or other rights. ]&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>