<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Emacs Lisp Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-10-09T01:42:07Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Emacs Lisp in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>meow-edit/meow</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:42:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/meow-edit/meow</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/meow-edit/meow" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yet another modal editing on Emacs / 猫态编辑&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;#+title: Meow&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[https://melpa.org/#/meow][file:https://melpa.org/packages/meow-badge.svg]] [[https://stable.melpa.org/#/meow][file:https://stable.melpa.org/packages/meow-badge.svg]] [[https://github.com/meow-edit/meow/actions/workflows/action.yml][https://github.com/meow-edit/meow/actions/workflows/action.yml/badge.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:meow.svg]]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#+begin_quote Less is more #+end_quote&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meow is yet another modal editing mode for Emacs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meow aims to blend modal editing into Emacs with minimal interference with its original key-bindings, avoiding most of the hassle introduced by key-binding conflicts. This leads to lower necessary configuration and better integration. More is achieved with fewer commands to remember.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key features compared to existing solutions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minimal configuration -- build your own modal editing system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No third-party dependencies ([[file:GET_STARTED.org][try it without touching your configuration]])&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Doesn&#39;t occupy too many keys &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Much easier to remember for people trying modal editing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;More keys available for your own key-bindings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Most of the time, you don&#39;t even need to hold shift!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lightning fast (unlike Evil)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minimizes modifier usage (e.g. =SPC x f= for =C-x C-f=) inspired by [[https://github.com/emacsorphanage/god-mode][god-mode]]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Better workflow for [[https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Keyboard-Macros.html][kmacro]] application at multiple locations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Interactive selection manipulation and expansion inspired by avy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Selection as top-tier object, and keybindings built around selection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compatible with the vanilla Emacs keymap (or any other keymap from any package)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Effortless uniform keymaps across modes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Key-binding conflict handling made easy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Community&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to ask questions and share ideas in the [[https://github.com/meow-edit/meow/discussions][Discussion]].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Documents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:GET_STARTED.org][Get started]] - Installation and configuration&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:TUTORIAL.org][Tutorial]] - Learn Meow in 15 minutes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:FAQ.org][FAQ]] - Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:COMMANDS.org][Commands]] - Documentation for commands&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:CUSTOMIZATIONS.org][Customizations]] - Helper functions and variables&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:EXPLANATION.org][Explanation]] - Ideas and concepts behind Meow&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[file:CHANGELOG.md][Changelog]] - Changes, releases, and news&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;License&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under GPLv3.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>leahneukirchen/nb</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:42:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/leahneukirchen/nb</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/leahneukirchen/nb" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nota Bene, a quick note-taking tool for Emacs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;= nb - Nota Bene, a quick note-taking tool for Emacs&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;nb---Nota Bene---is a note-taking application with Emacs integration akin to Notational Velocity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Installation&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir ~/NB&#xA;cp nb.el ~/.emacs.d&#xA;cp nb ~/bin&#xA;cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt;EOF &amp;gt;&amp;gt;~/.emacs&#xA;(require &#39;nb) &#xA;(global-set-key [f11] &#39;nb)&#xA;EOF&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Usage&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Type M-x nb or the bound key to search for notes: each search term is a grep(1) regular expression that has to appear somewhere in the note.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use M-x nb-new-note to create a new note.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes are kept in ~/NB and are named based on the first line of the note. It is a good idea to place a title there.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Copying&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To the extent possible under law, Christian Neukirchen &lt;a href=&#34;http://purl.org/net/chneukirchen&#34;&gt;http://purl.org/net/chneukirchen&lt;/a&gt; has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;== Links&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Github page:: &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/chneukirchen/nb&#34;&gt;http://github.com/chneukirchen/nb&lt;/a&gt; Christian Neukirchen:: &lt;a href=&#34;http://chneukirchen.org/&#34;&gt;http://chneukirchen.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>emacs-mirror/emacs</title>
    <updated>2022-10-09T01:42:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-10-09:/emacs-mirror/emacs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/emacs-mirror/emacs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mirror of GNU Emacs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (C) 2001-2022 Free Software Foundation, Inc. See the end of the file for license conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This directory tree holds version 29.0.50 of GNU Emacs, the extensible, customizable, self-documenting real-time display editor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file INSTALL in this directory says how to build and install GNU Emacs on various systems, once you have unpacked or checked out the entire Emacs file tree.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the file etc/NEWS for information on new features and other user-visible changes in recent versions of Emacs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file etc/PROBLEMS contains information on many common problems that occur in building, installing and running Emacs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file CONTRIBUTE contains information on contributing to Emacs as a developer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may encounter bugs in this release. If you do, please report them; your bug reports are valuable contributions to the FSF, since they allow us to notice and fix problems on machines we don&#39;t have, or in code we don&#39;t use often. Please send bug reports to the mailing list &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bug-gnu-emacs@gnu.org&#34;&gt;bug-gnu-emacs@gnu.org&lt;/a&gt;. If possible, use M-x report-emacs-bug.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &#34;Bugs&#34; section of the Emacs manual for more information on how to report bugs. (The file &#39;BUGS&#39; in this directory explains how you can find and read that section using the Info files that come with Emacs.) For a list of mailing lists related to Emacs, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://savannah.gnu.org/mail/?group=emacs&#34;&gt;https://savannah.gnu.org/mail/?group=emacs&lt;/a&gt;. For the complete list of GNU mailing lists, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://lists.gnu.org/&#34;&gt;https://lists.gnu.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &#39;etc&#39; subdirectory contains several other files, named in capital letters, which you might consider looking at when installing GNU Emacs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file &#39;configure&#39; is a shell script to acclimate Emacs to the oddities of your processor and operating system. It creates the file &#39;Makefile&#39; (a script for the &#39;make&#39; program), which automates the process of building and installing Emacs. See INSTALL for more detailed information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file &#39;configure.ac&#39; is the input used by the autoconf program to construct the &#39;configure&#39; script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shell script &#39;autogen.sh&#39; generates &#39;configure&#39; and other files by running Autoconf (which in turn uses GNU m4), and configures files in the .git subdirectory if you are using Git. If you want to use it, you will need to install recent versions of these build tools. This should be needed only if you edit files like &#39;configure.ac&#39; that specify Emacs&#39;s autobuild procedure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file &#39;Makefile.in&#39; is a template used by &#39;configure&#39; to create &#39;Makefile&#39;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The file &#39;make-dist&#39; is a shell script to build a distribution tar file from the current Emacs tree, containing only those files appropriate for distribution. If you make extensive changes to Emacs, this script will help you distribute your version to others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several subdirectories:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#39;src&#39; holds the C code for Emacs (the Emacs Lisp interpreter and its primitives, the redisplay code, and some basic editing functions). &#39;lisp&#39; holds the Emacs Lisp code for Emacs (most everything else). &#39;leim&#39; holds the original source files for the generated files in lisp/leim. These form the library of Emacs input methods, required to type international characters that can&#39;t be directly produced by your keyboard. &#39;lib&#39; holds source code for libraries used by Emacs and its utilities &#39;lib-src&#39; holds the source code for some utility programs for use by or with Emacs, like movemail and etags. &#39;lwlib&#39; holds the sources of the Lucid Widget Library used on X. &#39;oldXMenu&#39; source files from X11R2 XMenu library, used in non-toolkit builds. &#39;etc&#39; holds miscellaneous architecture-independent data files Emacs uses, like the tutorial text and tool bar images. The contents of the &#39;lisp&#39;, &#39;leim&#39;, &#39;info&#39;, and &#39;doc&#39; subdirectories are architecture-independent too. &#39;info&#39; holds the Info documentation tree for Emacs. &#39;doc/emacs&#39; holds the source code for the Emacs Manual. If you modify the manual sources, you will need the &#39;makeinfo&#39; program to produce an updated manual. &#39;makeinfo&#39; is part of the GNU Texinfo package; you need a suitably recent version of Texinfo. &#39;doc/lispref&#39; holds the source code for the Emacs Lisp reference manual. &#39;doc/lispintro&#39; holds the source code for the Introduction to Programming in Emacs Lisp manual. &#39;msdos&#39; holds configuration files for compiling Emacs under MS-DOS. &#39;nextstep&#39; holds instructions and some other files for compiling the Nextstep port of Emacs, for GNUstep and macOS Cocoa. &#39;nt&#39; holds code and documentation for building Emacs on MS-Windows. &#39;test&#39; holds tests for various aspects of Emacs&#39;s functionality. &#39;modules&#39; holds the modhelp.py helper script. &#39;admin&#39; holds files used by Emacs developers, and Unicode data files. &#39;build-aux&#39; holds auxiliary files used during the build. &#39;m4&#39; holds Autoconf macros used for generating the configure script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building Emacs on non-Posix platforms requires tools that aren&#39;t part of the standard distribution of the OS. The platform-specific README files and installation instructions should list the required tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; NOTE ON COPYRIGHT YEARS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In copyright notices where the copyright holder is the Free Software Foundation, then where a range of years appears, this is an inclusive range that applies to every year in the range. For example: 2005-2008 represents the years 2005, 2006, 2007, and 2008.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt; This file is part of GNU Emacs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU Emacs is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU Emacs is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with GNU Emacs. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>