<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-04T01:40:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>pygame/pygame</title>
    <updated>2022-07-04T01:40:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-04:/pygame/pygame</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/pygame/pygame" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;pygame (the library) is a Free and Open Source python programming language library for making multimedia applications like games built on top of the excellent SDL library. C, Python, Native, OpenGL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;.. image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pygame/pygame/main/docs/reST/_static/pygame_logo.svg&#34;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/pygame/pygame/main/docs/reST/_static/pygame_logo.svg&lt;/a&gt; :alt: pygame :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;|AppVeyorBuild| |PyPiVersion| |PyPiLicense| |Python3| |GithubCommits| |LGTMAlerts| |LGTMGradePython| |LGTMGradeC| |BlackFormatBadge|&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pygame_ is a free and open-source cross-platform library for the development of multimedia applications like video games using Python. It uses the &lt;code&gt;Simple DirectMedia Layer library&lt;/code&gt;_ and several other popular libraries to abstract the most common functions, making writing these programs a more intuitive task.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;We need your help&lt;/code&gt;_ to make pygame the best it can be! New contributors are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;::&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pip install pygame&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are just getting started with pygame, you should be able to get started fairly quickly. Pygame comes with many tutorials and introductions. There is also full reference documentation for the entire library. Browse the documentation on the &lt;code&gt;docs page&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The online documentation stays up to date with the development version of pygame on github. This may be a bit newer than the version of pygame you are using. To upgrade to the latest full release, run &lt;code&gt;pip install pygame --upgrade&lt;/code&gt; in your terminal.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Best of all, the examples directory has many playable small programs which can get you started playing with the code right away.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building From Source&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use features that are currently in development, or you want to contribute to pygame, you will need to build pygame locally from its source code, rather than pip installing it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing from source is fairly automated. The most work will involve compiling and installing all the pygame dependencies. Once that is done, run the &lt;code&gt;setup.py&lt;/code&gt; script which will attempt to auto-configure, build, and install pygame.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much more information about installing and compiling is available on the &lt;code&gt;Compilation wiki page&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who has helped contribute to this library. Special thanks are also in order.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Marcus Von Appen: many changes, and fixes, 1.7.1+ freebsd maintainer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lenard Lindstrom: the 1.8+ windows maintainer, many changes, and fixes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Brian Fisher for svn auto builder, bug tracker and many contributions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rene Dudfield: many changes, and fixes, 1.7+ release manager/maintainer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Phil Hassey for his work on the pygame.org website&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DR0ID for his work on the sprite module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Richard Goedeken for his smoothscale function&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ulf Ekström for his pixel perfect collision detection code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pete Shinners: original author&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;David Clark for filling the right-hand-man position&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ed Boraas and Francis Irving: Debian packages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maxim Sobolev: FreeBSD packaging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bob Ippolito: MacOS and OS X porting (much work!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Jan Ekhol, Ray Kelm, and Peter Nicolai: putting up with early design ideas&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nat Pryce for starting our unit tests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dan Richter for documentation work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TheCorruptor for his incredible logos and graphics&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nicholas Dudfield: many test improvements&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Alex Folkner for pygame-ctypes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to those sending in patches and fixes: Niki Spahiev, Gordon Tyler, Nathaniel Pryce, Dave Wallace, John Popplewell, Michael Urman, Andrew Straw, Michael Hudson, Ole Martin Bjoerndalen, Herve Cauwelier, James Mazer, Lalo Martins, Timothy Stranex, Chad Lester, Matthias Spiller, Bo Jangeborg, Dmitry Borisov, Campbell Barton, Diego Essaya, Eyal Lotem, Regis Desgroppes, Emmanuel Hainry, Randy Kaelber Matthew L Daniel, Nirav Patel, Forrest Voight, Charlie Nolan, Frankie Robertson, John Krukoff, Lorenz Quack, Nick Irvine, Michael George, Saul Spatz, Thomas Ibbotson, Tom Rothamel, Evan Kroske, Cambell Barton.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And our bug hunters above and beyond: Angus, Guillaume Proux, Frank Raiser, Austin Henry, Kaweh Kazemi, Arturo Aldama, Mike Mulcheck, Michael Benfield, David Lau&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s many more folks out there who&#39;ve submitted helpful ideas, kept this project going, and basically made our life easier. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many thank you&#39;s for people making documentation comments, and adding to the pygame.org wiki.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also many thanks for people creating games and putting them on the pygame.org website for others to learn from and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lots of thanks to James Paige for hosting the pygame bugzilla.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also a big thanks to Roger Dingledine and the crew at SEUL.ORG for our excellent hosting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pygame is obviously strongly dependent on SDL and Python. It also links to and embeds several other smaller libraries. The font module relies on SDL_ttf, which is dependent on freetype. The mixer (and mixer.music) modules depend on SDL_mixer. The image module depends on SDL_image, which also can use libjpeg and libpng. The transform module has an embedded version of SDL_rotozoom for its own rotozoom function. The surfarray module requires the Python NumPy package for its multidimensional numeric arrays. Dependency versions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CPython &amp;gt;= 3.6 or PyPy3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL &amp;gt;= 2.0.1&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_mixer &amp;gt;= 2.0.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_image &amp;gt;= 2.0.2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_ttf &amp;gt;= 2.0.11&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL_gfx (optional, vendored in)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NumPy &amp;gt;= 1.6.2 (optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This library is distributed under &lt;code&gt;GNU LGPL version 2.1&lt;/code&gt;_, which can be found in the file &lt;code&gt;docs/LGPL.txt&lt;/code&gt;. We reserve the right to place future versions of this library under a different license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This basically means you can use pygame in any project you want, but if you make any changes or additions to pygame itself, those must be released with a compatible license (preferably submitted back to the pygame project). Closed source and commercial games are fine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The programs in the &lt;code&gt;examples&lt;/code&gt; subdirectory are in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See docs/licenses for licenses of dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |AppVeyorBuild| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/x4074ybuobsh4myx?svg=true&#34;&gt;https://ci.appveyor.com/api/projects/status/x4074ybuobsh4myx?svg=true&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/pygame/pygame&#34;&gt;https://ci.appveyor.com/project/pygame/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |PyPiVersion| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/pygame.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/pypi/v/pygame.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&#34;&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |PyPiLicense| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/pygame.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/pypi/l/pygame.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&#34;&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/pygame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |Python3| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3-blue.svg?v=1&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/badge/python-3-blue.svg?v=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |GithubCommits| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commits-since/pygame/pygame/2.1.2.svg&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/github/commits-since/pygame/pygame/2.1.2.svg&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pygame/pygame/compare/2.1.2...main&#34;&gt;https://github.com/pygame/pygame/compare/2.1.2...main&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMAlerts| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/alerts/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/alerts/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/alerts/&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/alerts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMGradePython| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/python/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/python/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:python&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |LGTMGradeC| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/cpp/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/lgtm/grade/cpp/g/pygame/pygame.svg?logo=lgtm&amp;amp;logoWidth=18&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:cpp&#34;&gt;https://lgtm.com/projects/g/pygame/pygame/context:cpp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. |BlackFormatBadge| image:: &lt;a href=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/code%20style-black-000000.svg&#34;&gt;https://img.shields.io/badge/code%20style-black-000000.svg&lt;/a&gt; :target: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/psf/black&#34;&gt;https://github.com/psf/black&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;.. _pygame: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org&lt;/a&gt; .. _Simple DirectMedia Layer library: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libsdl.org&#34;&gt;https://www.libsdl.org&lt;/a&gt; .. _We need your help: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/contribute.html&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/contribute.html&lt;/a&gt; .. _Compilation wiki page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/wiki/Compilation&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/wiki/Compilation&lt;/a&gt; .. _docs page: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pygame.org/docs/&#34;&gt;https://www.pygame.org/docs/&lt;/a&gt; .. _GNU LGPL version 2.1: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/lesser.html&#34;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/copyleft/lesser.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tihmstar/jbinit</title>
    <updated>2022-07-04T01:40:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-04:/tihmstar/jbinit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tihmstar/jbinit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;iOS booter ramdisk creator for checkm8 based jailbreaks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;jbinit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;iOS booter ramdisk creator for checkm8 based jailbreaks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tested on iOS 15.1, should work on all iOS 15&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kernelpatches not included, make sure to bring your own ;P&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mit-pdos/xv6-riscv</title>
    <updated>2022-07-04T01:40:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-04:/mit-pdos/xv6-riscv</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mit-pdos/xv6-riscv" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Xv6 for RISC-V&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;xv6 is a re-implementation of Dennis Ritchie&#39;s and Ken Thompson&#39;s Unix Version 6 (v6). xv6 loosely follows the structure and style of v6, but is implemented for a modern RISC-V multiprocessor using ANSI C.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACKNOWLEDGMENTS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;xv6 is inspired by John Lions&#39;s Commentary on UNIX 6th Edition (Peer to Peer Communications; ISBN: 1-57398-013-7; 1st edition (June 14, 2000)). See also &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/6.828/&#34;&gt;https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/6.828/&lt;/a&gt;, which provides pointers to on-line resources for v6.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following people have made contributions: Russ Cox (context switching, locking), Cliff Frey (MP), Xiao Yu (MP), Nickolai Zeldovich, and Austin Clements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are also grateful for the bug reports and patches contributed by Takahiro Aoyagi, Silas Boyd-Wickizer, Anton Burtsev, Ian Chen, Dan Cross, Cody Cutler, Mike CAT, Tej Chajed, Asami Doi, eyalz800, Nelson Elhage, Saar Ettinger, Alice Ferrazzi, Nathaniel Filardo, flespark, Peter Froehlich, Yakir Goaron,Shivam Handa, Matt Harvey, Bryan Henry, jaichenhengjie, Jim Huang, Matúš Jókay, Alexander Kapshuk, Anders Kaseorg, kehao95, Wolfgang Keller, Jungwoo Kim, Jonathan Kimmitt, Eddie Kohler, Vadim Kolontsov , Austin Liew, l0stman, Pavan Maddamsetti, Imbar Marinescu, Yandong Mao, , Matan Shabtay, Hitoshi Mitake, Carmi Merimovich, Mark Morrissey, mtasm, Joel Nider, OptimisticSide, Greg Price, Jude Rich, Ayan Shafqat, Eldar Sehayek, Yongming Shen, Fumiya Shigemitsu, Cam Tenny, tyfkda, Warren Toomey, Stephen Tu, Rafael Ubal, Amane Uehara, Pablo Ventura, Xi Wang, Keiichi Watanabe, Nicolas Wolovick, wxdao, Grant Wu, Jindong Zhang, Icenowy Zheng, ZhUyU1997, and Zou Chang Wei.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The code in the files that constitute xv6 is Copyright 2006-2020 Frans Kaashoek, Robert Morris, and Russ Cox.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ERROR REPORTS&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please send errors and suggestions to Frans Kaashoek and Robert Morris (kaashoek,&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rtm@mit.edu&#34;&gt;rtm@mit.edu&lt;/a&gt;). The main purpose of xv6 is as a teaching operating system for MIT&#39;s 6.S081, so we are more interested in simplifications and clarifications than new features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BUILDING AND RUNNING XV6&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need a RISC-V &#34;newlib&#34; tool chain from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-gnu-toolchain&#34;&gt;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-gnu-toolchain&lt;/a&gt;, and qemu compiled for riscv64-softmmu. Once they are installed, and in your shell search path, you can run &#34;make qemu&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>