<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-09T01:21:06Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>MadMax1960/Femc-Reloaded-Project</title>
    <updated>2024-03-09T01:21:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-09:/MadMax1960/Femc-Reloaded-Project</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MadMax1960/Femc-Reloaded-Project" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repo for Femc Reloaded Project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Persona 3 Reload Mod Project: Femc Reloaded Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MadMax1960/Femc-Reloaded-Project/main/img/readmelogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;logo in Pink&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ⓒAtlus ⓒSega All Rights reserved, this mod is not associated with Sega or Atlus, all rights reserved, read the full Readme before any contributions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;&#34;Femc True&#34;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MadMax1960/Femc-Reloaded-Project/main/img/readmeimg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Kotone in Pink&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA; &lt;foo style=&#34;color:pink;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Step into the world of Persona 3 Reload, where we&#39;re on a mission to bring Kotone to the forefront, drenched in an authentic pink aura. This mod is crafted for the PC version and is available as &#xA;  &lt;strong&gt;english first&lt;/strong&gt;, all languages are welcome tho.&#xA; &lt;/foo&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA; &lt;foo style=&#34;color:pink;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Within these digital pages lies your roadmap to contributing to a grand vision. This document will evolve, staying in step with our journey. &#xA; &lt;/foo&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Links&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trello&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/b/jxq6wO79/femc-reloaded-project&#34;&gt;Femc Reloaded Project Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discord&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/yxtDmX7qXd&#34;&gt;Join our community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona Modding Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamebanana.com/tuts/17156&#34;&gt;Get started with modding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions come in all shapes and sizes, and here, all are welcome. If your masterpiece isn&#39;t quite ready for the main stage, your fork awaits. It&#39;s a place for refinement and creativity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Key Quests&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our quests span across different assets - from 3D modeling to UI design, from rewriting texts to reanimating cutscenes. Each task is a notch in the pathway for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Document your 3D modeling escapades, breathing life into Kotone&#39;s character.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Paint the UI with Kotone&#39;s essence, making every pixel count.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rewrite dialogues, bestowing Kotone with a voice that echoes and differentiates her from Makoto.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Craft cutscenes that captivate, placing Kotone at the heart of the narrative.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Weave animations with finesse, bringing fluidity to Kotone&#39;s every move.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you venture forth:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chronicle your journey, detailing every artistic conquest and technical triumph.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Attune your senses to the harmony of voices, ensuring they resonate with our narrative.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Herald your achievements, signaling the audio alchemists to concoct their aural elixirs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Archive anomalies and curiosities, for some enigmas require a collective wit to unravel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Clone the Repository&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your first step is to mirror our repository into your own creative enclave using GitHub Desktop or VSCode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Make Your Changes&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Immerse yourself in the cloned repository, transforming Makoto into Kotone with your &lt;strong&gt;unique talents&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Update the trello&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are tracking all progress, so you have to ask for a ticket so we can have your name on it and we can help you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Share Your Changes&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Broadcast your achievements using GitHub Desktop or VSCode, sharing your branch with the world.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Create a Pull Request&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forge a pull request on GitHub, inviting others to witness your work. If you find yourself at a crossroads, our Discord sanctuary offers guidance. (Update the trello.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 6: Once Merged&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please contact the Discord so we can align on where this is in the mod for proper accreditation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Leadership&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead/Director&lt;/strong&gt;: A Mudkip (@MadMax1960), orchestrating it all, decisions, 3D Lead.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Producer/Manager&lt;/strong&gt;: Fernando Holguin (@Fernhw), Tasks management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(More to come)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;br&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;IMPORTANT: Copyright and License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is a fanmade mod (modification) created as a homage to the Persona series. Some things to note include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;Not for Sale&lt;/strong&gt;: This mod does not, and will never, go up on sale. It’s just fans making something for fellow fans out of pure love for the original game, Persona 3, and its developers. Nothing monetary is being sought from it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;License&lt;/strong&gt;: This project and all contents thereof are licensed under Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License (BY-NC-SA 4.0). This means:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attribution (BY)&lt;/strong&gt;: You must give appropriate credit, provide a link to the license, and indicate if changes were made. You may do so in any reasonable manner, but not in any way that suggests the licensor endorses you or your use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NonCommercial (NC)&lt;/strong&gt;: You may not utilize this material for commercial purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ShareAlike (SA)&lt;/strong&gt;: If you remix, transform, or build upon the material, you must distribute your contributions under the same license as the original ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-&lt;strong&gt;Respect for Original Copyright Holders&lt;/strong&gt;: Any rights involving characters such as logos or trademarks associated with Atlus’ franchise known as Persona remain their property or that of other respective copyright holders whether they are Sega or Atlus themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This mod is a labor of love, created to celebrate the Persona series and share our collective creativity within the fan community, not to infringe on the rights of the original creators.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Make It Pink!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA; &lt;foo style=&#34;color:pink;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Your participation in the Femc Reloaded Project showcases the power of community and passion for Persona 3. Together, we&#39;re not merely altering a game; we&#39;re &#xA;  &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;painting it pink&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; or so they say.&#xA; &lt;/foo&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>