<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-28T01:29:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>KartKrewDev/RingRacers</title>
    <updated>2024-04-28T01:29:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-28:/KartKrewDev/RingRacers</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/KartKrewDev/RingRacers" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Dr. Robotnik&#39;s Ring Racers&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kartkrew.org&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/KartKrewDev/RingRacers/master/docs/logo.png&#34; width=&#34;404&#34; style=&#34;image-rendering:pixelated&#34; alt=&#34;Dr. Robotnik&#39;s Ring Racers logo&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Robotnik&#39;s Ring Racers is a kart racing video game originally based on the 3D Sonic the Hedgehog fangame &lt;a href=&#34;https://srb2.org/&#34;&gt;Sonic Robo Blast 2&lt;/a&gt;, itself based on a modified version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://doomlegacy.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Doom Legacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ring Racers&#39; source code is available to users under the GNU General Public License version 2.0 or higher.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kartkrew.org/&#34;&gt;Kart Krew Dev Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kartkrew.org/discord&#34;&gt;Kart Krew Dev Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mb.srb2.org/&#34;&gt;SRB2 Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Robotnik&#39;s Ring Racers is a work of fan art made available for free without intent to profit or harm the intellectual property rights of the original works it is based on. Kart Krew Dev is in no way affiliated with SEGA Corporation. We do not claim ownership of any of SEGA&#39;s intellectual property used in Dr. Robotnik&#39;s Ring Racers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Development&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building from Source&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ring Racers is built using a compatible C++ toolchain (GCC, MinGW, Clang and Apple Clang as of this writing), CMake, and Microsoft vcpkg. The compiler and runtime libraries must support the ISO C++17 standard and ISO C11 standard.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Linux platforms, you will need the following libraries available on the system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libcurl&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;zlib&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libpng&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libogg&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libvorbis&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libvpx&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libyuv&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SDL2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Windows and macOS, you will need to install &lt;a href=&#34;https://vcpkg.io/en/&#34;&gt;vcpkg&lt;/a&gt; instead to build these dependencies alongside the game.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To configure and build the game, there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://cmake.org/cmake/help/latest/manual/cmake-presets.7.html&#34;&gt;CMake presets&lt;/a&gt; (declared in &lt;code&gt;CMakePresets.json&lt;/code&gt;). These presets require the ninja build script tool in addition to cmake and your C++ toolchain. Here is a non-exhaustive list of them:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-debug: non-optimized, assertions enabled&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-develop: optimized, assertions enabled&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-release: optimized&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x86_mingw_static_vcpkg-debug&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x86_mingw_static_vcpkg-develop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x86_mingw_static_vcpkg-release&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x64_osx_vcpkg-debug&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x64_osx_vcpkg-develop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-x64_osx_vcpkg-release&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-arm64_osx_vcpkg-debug&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-arm64_osx_vcpkg-develop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ninja-arm64_osx_vcpkg-release&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These presets depend on the &lt;code&gt;VCPKG_ROOT&lt;/code&gt; environment variable being specified before the first run of the &lt;code&gt;cmake&lt;/code&gt; command. Their build directories are pre-configured as subdirectories of &lt;code&gt;build/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After all prerequisites are set-up, configure and build using the following commands, adjusting according to your target system:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cmake --preset ninja-x86_mingw_static_vcpkg-develop&#xA;cmake --build --preset ninja-x86_mingw_static_vcpkg-develop&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome external contributions from the community. If you are planning on making a large feature you intend to contribute to the project, please consider reaching out to us in the Kart Krew Dev public Discord server so we can coordinate with you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our primary source repository is &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.do.srb2.org/KartKrew/RingRacers&#34;&gt;hosted on the SRB2 Gitlab&lt;/a&gt;. The Github repository is a mirror of this. If you submit a Pull Request to the Github repository, please keep in mind that we do not consistently monitor that mirror and may not see your request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All contributions must be made available under the GPL General Public License version 2.0, or public domain. Integrations for third party code must be made to code which is compatibly licensed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PhysicsDptAngers/polyUAnalog</title>
    <updated>2024-04-28T01:29:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-28:/PhysicsDptAngers/polyUAnalog</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PhysicsDptAngers/polyUAnalog" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open source, analog and polyphonic synthesizer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;polyUAnalog: A Polyphonic Analogic and &lt;em&gt;Open Source&lt;/em&gt; Synth&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The architecture of polyUAnalog centers around a simple design: a &lt;em&gt;conductor board&lt;/em&gt; orchestrating multiple &lt;em&gt;voice boards&lt;/em&gt;. This modular approach allows each board to function independently as a monophonic synthesizer. When combined under the guidance of the conductor board, they form a versatile polyphonic synthesizer capable of operating in various modes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polyphonic Mode&lt;/strong&gt;: Achieve polyphony with up to virtually 120 voices. Our current configuration supports 10 voices of polyphony, tested and functioning seamlessly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monophonic with Unison and Spread Mode&lt;/strong&gt;: For those moments when a single, powerful voice is needed, enhanced with unison and spread capabilities for added depth.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-timbral Mode&lt;/strong&gt; (Under development as of April 2024): Expanding the synth&#39;s versatility by allowing multiple timbres to be played simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PhysicsDptAngers/polyUAnalog/main/resources/synth_archi.png&#34; alt=&#34;PolyUAnalog Synth&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository Structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;polyUAnalog&lt;/code&gt; repository is organized into two main directories, &lt;code&gt;firmware&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hardware&lt;/code&gt;, each containing subdirectories dedicated to different components of the synth:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Firmware&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contains all necessary code to bring the polyUAnalog to life. This includes the microcontroller programming for voice and conductor boards, as well as the controller interface.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Board&lt;/strong&gt;: The soul of the polyUAnalog&#39;s sound, each voice board is an independent monophonic synthesizer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conductor Board&lt;/strong&gt;: The brain behind the operation, orchestrating the voice boards to work in harmony.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller&lt;/strong&gt;: Interface and panel design for hands-on control of the polyUAnalog.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Hardware&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detailed schematics, PCB designs, and everything required to physically construct the polyUAnalog synth.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voice Board&lt;/strong&gt;: Designs and instructions to build each monophonic voice board.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conductor Board&lt;/strong&gt;: The blueprint for constructing the central conductor board.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controller&lt;/strong&gt;: Panel design and schematics for the physical user interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For specific details on each component, please refer to the corresponding &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; file within its directory. Our aim is to make the assembly and understanding of the polyUAnalog as accessible as possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;polyUAnalog thrives on community input and collaboration. Whether you&#39;re a seasoned electrical engineer, a software developer with a knack for DSP, or an enthusiast eager to learn and explore, your contributions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Academic Research and Publications&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have documented our journey and findings in a comprehensive academic paper. This paper delves into the theoretical underpinnings, design choices, and technical challenges encountered during the development of polyUAnalog. While the paper is currently in draft form and distributed as-is, we believe it provides valuable insights into the project&#39;s scientific and engineering aspects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A DOI and access to the official publication will be provided upon acceptance. Additionally, a pre-print version of the paper will be made available to ensure our findings are accessible to the community, fostering further research and development in the field of analog synthesis.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Sound Examples&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are currently compiling a diverse range of audio samples to showcase the versatility and musicality of polyUAnalog. This is a work in progress, and we appreciate your patience as we curate a collection that truly represents the essence of this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for a SoundCloud link, which will be shared here soon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;polyUAnalog is open source and distributed under the MIT License.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>