<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-06-14T01:29:38Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PostHog/DeskHog</title>
    <updated>2025-06-14T01:29:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-06-14:/PostHog/DeskHog</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PostHog/DeskHog" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend for your desk, a dedicated terminal for numbers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;DeskHog: A developer toy for sparking developer joy&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;992&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 2025-04-18 at 1 31 29 AM&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/6e5d1fe6-1887-4d66-8497-4b582eb0391a&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is DeskHog?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeskHog is an open-source, 3D printed, palm-sized developer toy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a toy to tinker with, adapt, and to get curious with. We&#39;ll be folding in a library of simple example games and apps, including a pomodoro timer and versions of Pong, Rogue, Flappy Bird. You can see PRs for these in this repo now for inspiration!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We think that sounds like fun and, if you do too, then DeskHog is for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;OK, but what is it?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeskHog packs an Adafruit ESP32-S3 Reverse TFT Feather in a custom-made 3D printed case. It comes complete with a 240x135 color TFT display, a 10-hour battery life, WiFi, and a cute little LED so you can find it in the dark.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/merch&#34;&gt;plug-and-play DeskHog hardware kit&lt;/a&gt; is coming soon (so you can get everything in one box). In the meantime, here’s what you’ll need if you want to make DeskHog yourself right now.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ESP32-S3 Reverse TFT Feather – &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.adafruit.com/esp32-s3-reverse-tft-feather&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adafruit 5691&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – buy: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/5691&#34;&gt;Adafruit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digikey.com/en/products/detail/adafruit-industries-llc/5691/18627502?s=N4IgjCBcoLQBxVAYygMwIYBsDOBTANCAPZQDa4ArAEwIC6AvvYVWSBQGwCcEDQA&#34;&gt;DigiKey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mouser.com/ProductDetail/Adafruit/5691?qs=mELouGlnn3eeALy2e3r3sw%3D%3D&#34;&gt;Mouser&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://botland.store/arduino-compatible-boards-adafruit/22891-feather-esp32-s3-reverse-with-tft-display-wifi-module-4mb-flash-2mb-psram-compatible-with-arduino-adafruit-5691.html&#34;&gt;Botland (EU)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://coolcomponents.co.uk/products/esp32-s2-reverse-tft-feather?_pos=1&amp;amp;_psq=reverse+tft+fea&amp;amp;_ss=e&amp;amp;_v=1.0&#34;&gt;Cool Components (UK)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.electromaker.io/shop/product/adafruit-esp32-s3-reverse-tft-feather-4mb-flash-2mb-psram-stemma-qt?srsltid=AfmBOorFfshQCLVi9EDKfmKFKMNC_cE3Ww0NaY0U0evm5ZU2OEM2Yn_B&#34;&gt;Electromaker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.berrybase.de/en/adafruit-esp32-s3-reverse-tft-feather&#34;&gt;BerryBase (EU)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optional: PKCell 552035 350mAh 3.7V LiPoly battery – buy: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adafruit.com/product/2750&#34;&gt;Adafruit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tinytronics.nl/en/power/batteries/li-po/pkcell-li-po-battery-3.7v-350mah-jst-ph-lp552035&#34;&gt;Tinytronics (EU)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.berrybase.de/en/lp-552035-lithium-polymer-lipo-akku-3-7v-350mah-mit-2-pin-jst-stecker&#34;&gt;BerryBase (EU)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;3D printed enclosure – print: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PostHog/DeskHog/main/3d-printing&#34;&gt;3mf file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What can DeskHog do?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DeskHog can do a couple of things by default, but the real joy lies in expanding the capabilities by adding them yourself.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Out of the box functionality&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A couple of basic &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PostHog/DeskHog/main/#card-stack&#34;&gt;cards&lt;/a&gt; (screens) are included on the firmware and were built by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/31731&#34;&gt;Danilo Campos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ProvisioningCard&lt;/strong&gt;: Displays a QR code to connect to the device and shows connection stats.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InsightCard&lt;/strong&gt;: Visualizes PostHog data. Still a bit of a WIP, so contributions welcome!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FriendCard&lt;/strong&gt;: Lets Max the hedgehog visit with you and provide encouragement.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Available games and apps&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re working on adding some of the following games to an &lt;code&gt;/examples&lt;/code&gt; folder which will include a selection of games and apps for you to play with. If you can&#39;t see them in the &lt;code&gt;/examples&lt;/code&gt; folder it&#39;s probably because they exist as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PostHog/DeskHog/pulls&#34;&gt;unapproved PRs&lt;/a&gt; while we work on them. No problem, just checkout the branch!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example games include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pog&lt;/strong&gt;: A Pong clone by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/30833&#34;&gt;Leon Daly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IdleHog&lt;/strong&gt;: An idle clicker by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/33534&#34;&gt;Chris McNeill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Button Dungeon&lt;/strong&gt;: An idle Roguelike by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/29070&#34;&gt;Joe Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dictator or Techbro: DeskHog Edition&lt;/strong&gt;: A quiz game by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/33534&#34;&gt;Chris McNeill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notchagotchi&lt;/strong&gt;: A virtual pet by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/33385&#34;&gt;Sophie Payne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flappy Hog&lt;/strong&gt;: A Flappy Bird clone by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/29070&#34;&gt;Joe Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hog Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: A reaction game by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/33534&#34;&gt;Chris McNeill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pineapple Reflex&lt;/strong&gt;: A pizza-based game by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/33385&#34;&gt;Sophie Payne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three Button Dungeon&lt;/strong&gt;: An Ultima-like by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/29070&#34;&gt;Joe Martin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example apps include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awkwardness Avoider&lt;/strong&gt;: A smalltalk prompter by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/28619&#34;&gt;Annika Schmid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pomodoro&lt;/strong&gt;: A productivity timer by &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/community/profiles/28619&#34;&gt;Annika Schmid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the example apps were built in 24 hours at &lt;a href=&#34;https://posthog.com/handbook/company/offsites&#34;&gt;a PostHog hackathon&lt;/a&gt; by people who hadn&#39;t coded before at all. These example cards are a testament to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PostHog/DeskHog/main/#-vibe-coding-with-ai-agents&#34;&gt;what&#39;s possible when vibe coding on DeskHog&lt;/a&gt;, but some lack polish - so make sure you know &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PostHog/DeskHog/main/#buttons-and-reset-sequences&#34;&gt;how to reset DeskHog&lt;/a&gt;. Just in case.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Developing for DeskHog&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Review &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PostHog/DeskHog/main/tech-details.md&#34;&gt;tech-details.md&lt;/a&gt; for info on architecture, libraries and key components used in this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;No matter what I do, flashing the board doesn&#39;t change anything! wtf??&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re actually cutting the storage space in half so that over the air updates can be loaded to the unused half of storage. You can end up in a place where the board just won&#39;t boot to the correct partition.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To fix this, choose &lt;strong&gt;Erase Flash and Upload&lt;/strong&gt; from the PlatformIO Project Tasks menu.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤖 Vibe Coding with AI Agents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We couldn&#39;t have built DeskHog without Cursor&#39;s help, and we encourage agent-driven development with a few caveats.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LLMs often struggle with multi-threaded embedded systems. DeskHog’s firmware has strict rules for core/task roles; AI might overlook them unless you guide it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re looking to get started, we recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cursor.com/en&#34;&gt;Cursor&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://platformio.org/install/ide?install=vscode&#34;&gt;PlatformIO extension&lt;/a&gt;. They work well together and you can use Cursor&#39;s chat function to start building all sorts of things with natural language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;tech-details.md&lt;/code&gt; to give your agent broad context on the device. Still, even with that you should bear in mind the following advice:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You should encourage AI to follow existing patterns: use&lt;code&gt;EventQueue&lt;/code&gt; for cross-core messaging and update the UI only on the UI task.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flag any AI suggestions that touch the UI from the wrong core.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Review and test thoroughly—watch for “LLM slop” (unused vars, odd delays) and clean it up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of your AI as a speedy junior dev: brilliant but prone to mistakes. You’re the senior dev keeping it on track. With that balance, AI can boost productivity while keeping DeskHog reliable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Power off&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to turn the device off, hold ● + ▼ for two seconds. The device will enter deep sleep mode.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To wake the device, press the reset tab on the left.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;UI progress&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Status card: working&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;WiFi provisioning card with QR Code: working&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Friend card to give you (mild) reassurance: working&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Numeric card for Big Number insights: working&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Funnel card: needs a redesign; probably should be horizontal layout instead, won&#39;t display more than three steps right now&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Line graph card: broken, not properly scaling larger data sets, probably fine if you have an insight scoped between 7-30 days&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Other insights: not yet supported&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Request for PRs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following PRs would be interesting, and may earn you a free DeskHog kit or other merch:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional insight parsing and visualizations for Insight Card&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More games and apps! We think limiting things to one available button prompts creativity&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for other boards and displays&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enhance the web UI and &lt;code&gt;ConfigManger&lt;/code&gt; to allow re-ordering of insights, set custom titles per-insight&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LLM slop mitigation: if you see anything obviously stupid in this code that hasn&#39;t yet been caught and cleaned up&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DX improvements around task isolation: if your experience with embedded code says there&#39;s a better way to architect this, happy to follow your lead&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved C++: not my preferred language, feel free to suggest idiomatic and architectural improvements&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Desk utilities, like a pomodoro timer; also constrained: center button only. Be creative!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PlatformIO config improvements: flashing builds causes a reboot that seems unnecessary, maybe you know a better configuration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OTA update mechanisms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PRs over issues, but if you&#39;ve got any trouble, feel free to open an issue. You can also contact the maintainer, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:danilo@posthog.com&#34;&gt;danilo@posthog.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>