<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-27T01:32:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>zmap/zmap</title>
    <updated>2023-06-27T01:32:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-27:/zmap/zmap</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zmap/zmap" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ZMap is a fast single packet network scanner designed for Internet-wide network surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;ZMap: The Internet Scanner&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/zmap/zmap/actions/workflows/cmake.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ZMap is a fast single packet network scanner designed for Internet-wide network surveys. On a typical desktop computer with a gigabit Ethernet connection, ZMap is capable scanning the entire public IPv4 address space in under 45 minutes. With a 10gigE connection and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ntop.org/products/packet-capture/pf_ring/&#34;&gt;PF_RING&lt;/a&gt;, ZMap can scan the IPv4 address space in under 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ZMap operates on GNU/Linux, Mac OS, and BSD. ZMap currently has fully implemented probe modules for TCP SYN scans, ICMP, DNS queries, UPnP, BACNET, and can send a large number of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zmap/zmap/raw/master/examples/udp-probes/README&#34;&gt;UDP probes&lt;/a&gt;. If you are looking to do more involved scans, e.g., banner grab or TLS handshake, take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zmap/zgrab2&#34;&gt;ZGrab 2&lt;/a&gt;, ZMap&#39;s sister project that performs stateful application-layer handshakes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest stable release of ZMap is version 3.0.0 and supports Linux, macOS, and BSD.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions on building ZMap from source&lt;/strong&gt; can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zmap/zmap/main/INSTALL.md&#34;&gt;INSTALL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A guide to using ZMap is found in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zmap/zmap/wiki&#34;&gt;GitHub Wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License and Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ZMap Copyright 2017 Regents of the University of Michigan&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;); you may not use this file except in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#34;&gt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See LICENSE for the specific language governing permissions and limitations under the License.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>