<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-23T01:25:39Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>sleirsgoevy/ps4jb-payloads</title>
    <updated>2023-10-23T01:25:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-23:/sleirsgoevy/ps4jb-payloads</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sleirsgoevy/ps4jb-payloads" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Extracted payloads from the main repo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>wine-mirror/wine</title>
    <updated>2023-10-23T01:25:39Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-23:/wine-mirror/wine</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/wine-mirror/wine" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wine is a program which allows running Microsoft Windows programs (including DOS, Windows 3.x, Win32, and Win64 executables) on Unix. It consists of a program loader which loads and executes a Microsoft Windows binary, and a library (called Winelib) that implements Windows API calls using their Unix, X11 or Mac equivalents. The library may also be used for porting Windows code into native Unix executables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wine is free software, released under the GNU LGPL; see the file LICENSE for the details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;QUICK START&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the top-level directory of the Wine source (which contains this file), run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;./configure make&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then either install Wine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;make install&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or run Wine directly from the build directory:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;./wine notepad&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run programs as &#34;wine program&#34;. For more information and problem resolution, read the rest of this file, the Wine man page, and especially the wealth of information found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org&#34;&gt;https://www.winehq.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;REQUIREMENTS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To compile and run Wine, you must have one of the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux version 2.0.36 or later FreeBSD 12.4 or later Solaris x86 9 or later NetBSD-current Mac OS X 10.8 or later&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As Wine requires kernel-level thread support to run, only the operating systems mentioned above are supported. Other operating systems which support kernel threads may be supported in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FreeBSD info: See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.freebsd.org/Wine&#34;&gt;https://wiki.freebsd.org/Wine&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Solaris info: You will most likely need to build Wine with the GNU toolchain (gcc, gas, etc.). Warning : installing gas does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; ensure that it will be used by gcc. Recompiling gcc after installing gas or symlinking cc, as and ld to the gnu tools is said to be necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NetBSD info: Make sure you have the USER_LDT, SYSVSHM, SYSVSEM, and SYSVMSG options turned on in your kernel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mac OS X info: You need Xcode/Xcode Command Line Tools or Apple cctools. The minimum requirements for compiling Wine are clang 3.8 with the MacOSX10.10.sdk and mingw-w64 v8. The MacOSX10.14.sdk and later can only build wine64.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Supported file systems: Wine should run on most file systems. A few compatibility problems have also been reported using files accessed through Samba. Also, NTFS does not provide all the file system features needed by some applications. Using a native Unix file system is recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basic requirements: You need to have the X11 development include files installed (called xorg-dev in Debian and libX11-devel in Red Hat).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course you also need &#34;make&#34; (most likely GNU make).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You also need flex version 2.5.33 or later and bison.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optional support libraries: Configure will display notices when optional libraries are not found on your system. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.winehq.org/Recommended_Packages&#34;&gt;https://wiki.winehq.org/Recommended_Packages&lt;/a&gt; for hints about the packages you should install. On 64-bit platforms, you have to make sure to install the 32-bit versions of these libraries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;COMPILATION&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To build Wine, do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;./configure make&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will build the program &#34;wine&#34; and numerous support libraries/binaries. The program &#34;wine&#34; will load and run Windows executables. The library &#34;libwine&#34; (&#34;Winelib&#34;) can be used to compile and link Windows source code under Unix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To see compile configuration options, do ./configure --help.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.winehq.org/Building_Wine&#34;&gt;https://wiki.winehq.org/Building_Wine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SETUP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once Wine has been built correctly, you can do &#34;make install&#34;; this will install the wine executable and libraries, the Wine man page, and other needed files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t forget to uninstall any conflicting previous Wine installation first. Try either &#34;dpkg -r wine&#34; or &#34;rpm -e wine&#34; or &#34;make uninstall&#34; before installing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once installed, you can run the &#34;winecfg&#34; configuration tool. See the Support area at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.winehq.org/&lt;/a&gt; for configuration hints.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RUNNING PROGRAMS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When invoking Wine, you may specify the entire path to the executable, or a filename only.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example: to run Notepad:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wine notepad            (using the search Path as specified in&#xA;wine notepad.exe         the registry to locate the file)&#xA;&#xA;wine c:\\windows\\notepad.exe      (using DOS filename syntax)&#xA;&#xA;wine ~/.wine/drive_c/windows/notepad.exe  (using Unix filename syntax)&#xA;&#xA;wine notepad.exe readme.txt          (calling program with parameters)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wine is not perfect, so some programs may crash. If that happens you will get a crash log that you should attach to your report when filing a bug.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;GETTING MORE INFORMATION&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WWW: A great deal of information about Wine is available from WineHQ at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/&#34;&gt;https://www.winehq.org/&lt;/a&gt; : various Wine Guides, application database, bug tracking. This is probably the best starting point.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FAQ: The Wine FAQ is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/FAQ&#34;&gt;https://www.winehq.org/FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wiki: The Wine Wiki is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.winehq.org&#34;&gt;https://wiki.winehq.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gitlab: Wine development is hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.winehq.org&#34;&gt;https://gitlab.winehq.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mailing lists: There are several mailing lists for Wine users and developers; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winehq.org/forums&#34;&gt;https://www.winehq.org/forums&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bugs: Report bugs to Wine Bugzilla at &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.winehq.org&#34;&gt;https://bugs.winehq.org&lt;/a&gt; Please search the bugzilla database to check whether your problem is already known or fixed before posting a bug report.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;IRC: Online help is available at channel #WineHQ on irc.libera.chat.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-- Alexandre Julliard &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:julliard@winehq.org&#34;&gt;julliard@winehq.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>