<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-14T01:30:47Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>H4K6/CVE-2023-0179-PoC</title>
    <updated>2023-04-14T01:30:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-14:/H4K6/CVE-2023-0179-PoC</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/H4K6/CVE-2023-0179-PoC" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;针对（CVE-2023-0179）漏洞利用 该漏洞被分配为CVE-2023-0179，影响了从5.5到6.2-rc3的所有Linux版本，该漏洞在6.1.6上被测试。 漏洞的细节和文章可以在os-security上找到。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Needle (CVE-2023-0179) exploit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the exploit for my recently discovered vulnerability in the nftables subsystem that was assigned CVE-2023-0179, affecting all Linux versions from 5.5 to 6.2-rc3, although the exploit was tested on 6.1.6.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vulnerability details and writeup can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2023/01/13/2&#34;&gt;oss-security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just invoke the &lt;code&gt;make needle&lt;/code&gt; command to generate the corresponding executable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;libmnl&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;libnftnl&lt;/code&gt; are required for the build to succeed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;sudo apt-get install libmnl-dev libnftnl-dev&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Infoleak&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The exploit will enter an unprivileged user and network namespace and add an &lt;code&gt;nft_payload&lt;/code&gt; expression via the &lt;code&gt;rule_add_payload&lt;/code&gt; function which, when evaluated, will trigger the stack buffer overflow and overwrite the registers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The content is then retrieved with the following nft command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;nft list map netdev mytable myset12&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The output will leak several shuffled addresses relative to kernel data structures, among which we find a kernel instruction address and the regs pointer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LPE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The exploit creates a new user account &lt;code&gt;needle:needle&lt;/code&gt; with UID 0 by abusing the &lt;code&gt;modprobe_path&lt;/code&gt; variable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy root privileges.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asciinema.org/a/mVTu420tWy8ocdFY70sWD9VLO&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://asciinema.org/a/mVTu420tWy8ocdFY70sWD9VLO.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;asciicast&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;David Bouman&#39;s &lt;code&gt;libnftnl&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pqlx/CVE-2022-1015&#34;&gt;implementation&lt;/a&gt; and detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.dbouman.nl/2022/04/02/How-The-Tables-Have-Turned-CVE-2022-1015-1016/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>maximegmd/CyberEngineTweaks</title>
    <updated>2023-04-14T01:30:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-14:/maximegmd/CyberEngineTweaks</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/maximegmd/CyberEngineTweaks" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cyberpunk 2077 tweaks, hacks and scripting framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Cyber Engine Tweaks&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/tiltedphoques&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Patreon-donate-purple.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Patreon&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://lbesson.mit-license.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-MIT-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;MIT license&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/Epkq79kd96&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discord/717692382849663036.svg?label=&amp;amp;logo=discord&amp;amp;logoColor=ffffff&amp;amp;color=7389D8&amp;amp;labelColor=6A7EC2&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin: bc1q0neujk5e8v8sc3934ajn8z8zav7hl6557fjj54&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Cash: qps5ze9p8fxmu4rszyxwy3g0ctlmrhvc3uqq0fzsnl&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Dogecoin: DMoReR33D87D6rYeUkyQb2BsEHJTqfBFva&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ethereum: 0x7Cd23BE1C507Da85ABF0B05c7A3C03e6d3d0233B&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cyber Engine Tweaks&lt;/strong&gt; is a framework giving modders a way to script mods using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lua.org/&#34;&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; with access to all the internal scripting features. It also comes with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ocornut/imgui/tree/v1.82&#34;&gt;Dear ImGui&lt;/a&gt; to provide GUI for different mods you are using, along with console and TweakDB editor for more advanced usage. It also adds some patches for quality of life, all of which can be enabled/disabled through the settings menu or config files (requires game restart to apply).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current version works with 1.61 game version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Current patches&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Patch&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;AMD SMT&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;For AMD CPUs that did not get a performance boost after CDPR&#39;s patch&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Remove pedestrians and traffic&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Removes most of the pedestrians and traffic&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disable Async Compute&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disables async compute, this can give a boost on older GPUs (Nvidia 10xx series for example)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disable Temporal Antialiasing&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disables antialiasing, not recommended but you do what you want!&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Skip start menu&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Skips the menu asking you to press space bar to continue (Breaching...)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Suppress Intro Movies&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disables logos played at the beginning&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disable Vignette&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disables vignetting along screen borders&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disable Boundary Teleport&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Allows players to access out-of-bounds locations&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disable Windows 7 VSync&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Disables VSync on Windows 7 to bypass the 60 FPS limit&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Current mod development options&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Draw ImGui Diagnostics Window&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Toggles drawing of internal ImGui diagnostics window to show what is going on behind the scenes (good for mod debugging)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Remove Dead Bindings&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Removes bindings for mods that were not loaded&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Enable ImGui Assertions&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Enables all ImGui assertions (use this option to check mods for errors before shipping!)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Debug Menu&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Enables the debug menus in game&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dump Game Options&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dumps all game options into main log file&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage and configuration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.redmodding.org/cyber-engine-tweaks/&#34;&gt;Read the wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/WolvenKit/cet-examples&#34;&gt;Official mod examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.redmodding.org/cyber-engine-tweaks/getting-started/installing/untitled&#34;&gt;Usage with Proton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you wish to contribute to the main repo, try to follow the coding style in the code, otherwise not much to say, don&#39;t use code that is not yours unless the license is compatible with MIT.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the wiki, please ask on discord for write permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>davidgiven/wordgrinder</title>
    <updated>2023-04-14T01:30:47Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-14:/davidgiven/wordgrinder</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/davidgiven/wordgrinder" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A word processor which gets the hell out of your way and lets you get some work done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                           WORDGRINDER V0.9&#xA;                           ================&#xA;&#xA;                       © 2007-2022 David Given&#xA;                             2022-11-07&#xA;&#xA;                            Unix version&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;INTRODUCTION&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder is a simple, Unicode-aware word processor that runs on the console. It&#39;s designed to get the hell out of your way and let you write; it does very little, but what it does it does well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It supports basic paragraph styles, basic character styles, basic screen markup, a menu interface that means you don&#39;t have to remember complex key sequences, HTML import and export, and some other useful features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder does not require a GUI. It can run in a terminal. (But there are GUI versions for Unixishes, Windows and OSX if you want them.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;INSTALLATION&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder needs the following packages installed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;ninja, the build tool. This is available from: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ninja-build.org/&#34;&gt;https://ninja-build.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;ncursesw, the wide-character version of curses. This is supplied with most systems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;an OpenGL/GLFW development kit (if you want the OpenGL frontend). This is supplied with most systems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;zlib. You will already have this, but just on the offchance, it&#39;s here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zlib.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.zlib.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Optionally: Lua, the programming language. WordGrinder has its own built- in copy, but if you want to use the system Lua, install it and edit the Makefile. Lua is available from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lua.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.lua.org/&lt;/a&gt; WordGrinder will work with Lua versions 5.1, 5.2, 5.3, 5.4 or LuaJIT.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;a terminal emulator that supports UTF-8. gnome-terminal, konsole, xterm and rxvt-unicode do. rxvt and the Linux console don&#39;t (unless you use jfbterm). You will also need a decent set of Unicode fonts or WordGrinder will look funny.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chances are you already have these in your distribution. Merely install these packages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have Debian/Ubuntu: ninja-build libncursesw5-dev liblua5.3-dev zlib1g-dev libglfw3-dev&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have Fedora: lua lua-devel lua-libs lua-filesystem zlib-devel libglfw-devel ncurses ncurses-devel ninja-build&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have OSX with Homebrew: ninja pkg-config glfw&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To detect a sensible configuration and build, simply do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;make&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install into your home directory, do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to install somewhere else, do:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PREFIX=/usr/local ./configure&#xA;make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Change PREFIX to whatever you like; naturally, if you&#39;re not installing in a global location, you don&#39;t need sudo.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(There are various other poorly-documented configuration options in the configure script.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is now ready to use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special note for compilation on Windows: do &#39;make&#39; from MSYS2 with the Mingw64 toolchain and nsis installed. use Cygwin. You&#39;ll end up with the installer package in bin/.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;USAGE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wordgrinder&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;...to get a blank document. You can load an existing document with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wordgrinder README.wg&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please read README.wg; it contains the manual. There is also a man page, which describes the command line interface.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you use WordGrinder, please join the mailing list. This will allow you to ask questions, hopefully receive answers, and get news about any new releases. You can subscribe or view the archives at the following page:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://lists.sourceforge.net/lists/listinfo/wordgrinder-users&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder contains a number of embedded libraries, described here. Not all of them may be used by any given binary depending on your configuration. Please look in the &lt;code&gt;licenses&lt;/code&gt; directory for the full license text.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder is © 2007-2020 David Given, and is available under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of Lua 5.1. This is also MIT licensed and is © 1994–2017 Lua.org, PUC-Rio. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://lua.org&#34;&gt;http://lua.org&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of the Lpeg parser library. This is also MIT licensed and is © 2007-2019 Lua.org, PUC-Rio. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://inf.puc-rio.br/~roberto/lpeg&#34;&gt;http://inf.puc-rio.br/~roberto/lpeg&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of LuaBitOp. This is also MIT licensed and is © 2008-2012 Mike Pall. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitop.luajit.org/&#34;&gt;http://bitop.luajit.org/&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of the MiniZip library. This is © 1998-2010 Gilles Vollant and Mathis Svenson, and is available under the BSD license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of the SCOWL wordlist for British and American-Canadian English. This is © Kevin Atkinson and J. Ross Beresford. Please see the licenses/COPYING.Scowl file for the full license text.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of the xpattern module. This is also MIT licensed and is © 2008-2009 David Manura. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://lua-users.org/wiki/ExPattern&#34;&gt;http://lua-users.org/wiki/ExPattern&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a (thoroughly hacked up) copy of the Lunamark Markdown parser. This is also MIT licensed and is © 2009-2016 John MacFarlane. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jgm/lunamark&#34;&gt;https://github.com/jgm/lunamark&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains a copy of the LargeLineHeight-NoLoopK version of the Fantasque Sans Mono font family. This is distributable under the terms of the Open Font License 1.1 © 2013-2017 Jany Belluz. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/belluzj/fantasque-sans&#34;&gt;https://github.com/belluzj/fantasque-sans&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains parts of the libstb utility library, written by Sean T Barrett et al. This is public domain where possible and MIT licensed otherwise. Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nothings/stb/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nothings/stb/blob/master/LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The distribution contains most of the clip clipboard library, written by David Capello. This is MIT licensed and is © 2015-2022 David Capello. Please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dacap/clip&#34;&gt;https://github.com/dacap/clip&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;REVISION HISTORY&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.9: 2021-XX-XX: threw away the X11 and Windows GDI frontends and replaced them with OpenGL --- there&#39;s now a GUI version for OSX! New shiny colour scheme and ruler layout kindly contributed by Pacrox. Also threw away and replaced the build.lua file with something even worse. Added the ability to quit WordGrinder by closing the window. Fixed a bug where the global settings would be reset during CLI use. WordGrinder files with CRLF line endings can now be read. Emacs orgmode export (contributed by VitorGoatman@github). ESCAPE can be used to cancel things. Both TAB and ^I can be used for autocompletion in file dialogues. Miscellaneous editor state machine bugfixes. Multiple scroll modes. Changed the cursor shape for visibility. Use the system clipboard where possible. Added mouse support.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.8: 2020-10-13: started out as a bugfix release but then I got carried away. New features: a paragraph style for numbered bulletpoints; more look-and-feel options; the caret now flashes; basic template support; word count display of selected text; custom autosave directory; autocompletion in file dialogues; Windows console version; recent documents list; Markdown import. Bugfixes: lots of import and export fixes (and tests so that they stay fixed); spellchecker fixes; selection position fixes; keyboard entry fixes on Windows; graphics fixes on Windows; filesystem fixes on Windows; assorted other minor tweaks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.7.2: 2018-11-29: bugfix release. Pasting immediately after loading a document no longer hard crashes. Don&#39;t buffer overrun if given invalid unicode. Global settings are now updated correctly (in several places). Fix a data loss situation when saving fails.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.7.1: 2017-11-02: correct and cleaner license reporting; rearrange the source so that we can avoid shipping upstream dependencies if we want. No actual code changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.7: 2017-10-30: new plain text diffable file format; Lua 5.3 support; better locale detection; dense paragraphs mode; lots of bugfixes. Official OSX support. New (better, hopefully) build system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.6: 2015-04-18: New X11 frontend (actual bold and italic on Linux machines!); shift+cursor keys starts a selection; more HTML emission fixes; non-document persistent settings; global key maps (currently via a configurationfile); search works properly across words with markup; italic display in a terminal (if you have a new enough version of ncurses); more traditional charstyle selection (you can press ^B at the beginning of words now!); more traditional selection model (shift+cursor keys works now!); fix crash on loading very large .wg files; smart quote support; more efficient files; undo and redo; spellchecker; colour configuration on X11 and Windows; MarkDown export.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.5.2.1: 2015-02-21: Minor bugfixes: build system fixes; updated minizip to a version which builds better on Ubuntu; OSX Homebrew build system; delete word; subsection counts now correct; HTML PRE emission issue corrected.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.5.1: 2013-12-08: Major overhaul: fixed hideous file corruption bug; much improved Windows text renderer; bold; page count; widescreen mode; UI style overhaul; many other minor bugfixes. Many thanks to Connor Karatzas for extensive Windows testing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.4.1: 2013-04-14: Minor bugfixes and build optimisation in aid of the Debian package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.4: 2013-03-24: Major overhaul: OpenDocument import/export, new much smaller file format, a proper Windows port, updated to Lua 5.2, switched away from Prime Mover to make (sob), much bug fixage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.3.3: 2009-12-13: Fixed a bug when searching for or replacing strings containing multiple whitespace characters (that was triggering the crash handler). Thanks to lostnbronx for the report. Added RAW and PRE paragraph styles. Cleaned up HTML import. Add customisability to HTML export. Relicensed to MIT.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.3.2: 2008-11-03: Fixed a very simple and very stupid typo that caused a crash if you tried to turn autosave on. Added a simple exception handler to try and prevent data loss on error in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.3.1: 2008-09-08: Minor bugfix revision to correct a few minor but really embarrassing crashes problems in 0.3: no crash on HTML import, no crash on File-&amp;gt;New. Also some minor cosmetic fixes I noticed while doing the work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.3: 2008-09-07: Lots more bug fixes. Added LaTeX export; troff export; next/previous word/character; table of contents; autosave; scrapbook; Windows console port. Fixed some issues with key binding. Lua bytecode is now embedded in the executable, making it self contained. --lua option. General overhaulage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.2: 2008-01-13: Lots of bug fixes. Added word count. Added about dialogue.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder 0.1: 2007-10-14: Initial release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;THE AUTHOR&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordGrinder was written by me, David Given. You may contact me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dg@cowlark.com&#34;&gt;dg@cowlark.com&lt;/a&gt;, or visit my website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cowlark.com&#34;&gt;http://www.cowlark.com&lt;/a&gt;. There may or may not be anything interesting there.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>