<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-20T01:31:06Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HeroWO-js/Workbench</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T01:31:06Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-20:/HeroWO-js/Workbench</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HeroWO-js/Workbench" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Workspace for running HeroWO game client and generating databanks and maps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HeroWO&#39;s Workbench&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;— It’s dangerous to go alone! Take this&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HeroWO is a JavaScript re-implementation of &lt;em&gt;Heroes of Might and Magic III&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository sets up a workspace for running HeroWO game client and generating databanks and maps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HeroWO-js&#34;&gt;https://github.com/HeroWO-js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://herowo.game&#34;&gt;https://herowo.game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get to start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off, install &lt;strong&gt;git&lt;/strong&gt;, PHP (7+) and any web server. On *nix, you&#39;ll have all the stuff easily available via apt/yum/pacman/whatever. On Windows, installing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/git-for-windows/git/releases/&#34;&gt;Git for Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tortoisegit.org/download/&#34;&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/a&gt; (optional) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/xampp/files/latest/download&#34;&gt;XAMPP&lt;/a&gt; will get you everything needed. XAMPP can be installed with all optional components unchecked.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Clone it deeply&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not use GitHub&#39;s code download function because the archive it generates lacks the required submodules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead, open Command Prompt, &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into your web server&#39;s document root (typically &lt;code&gt;/var/www&lt;/code&gt; on *nix, &lt;code&gt;C:\xampp\htdocs&lt;/code&gt; on Windows) and type this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recurse-submodules https://github.com/HeroWO-js/Workbench.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, if you have installed &lt;strong&gt;TortoiseGit&lt;/strong&gt;: open Explorer, right-click on the web server&#39;s document root or on any folder inside it, call &lt;code&gt;Git Clone...&lt;/code&gt;, paste &lt;code&gt;https://github.com/HeroWO-js/Workbench.git&lt;/code&gt; into &lt;code&gt;URL&lt;/code&gt;, tick &lt;code&gt;Recursive&lt;/code&gt;, leave other settings at their defaults and click OK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above does an anonymous checkout. If you have an account on GitHub, use this URL:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git@github.com:HeroWO-js/Workbench.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Check the structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Workbench&lt;/code&gt; folder will have a bunch of subfolders, most initially absent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You must see the &lt;code&gt;core&lt;/code&gt; subfolder (the game engine itself; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HeroWO-js/Core&#34;&gt;https://github.com/HeroWO-js/Core&lt;/a&gt;) and it must be filled with files - if not then you didn&#39;t initialize submodules as explained above. Game over, try again!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll also see &lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt; - the script populating various subfolders and making it easier to update the data later with less typing in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another one, &lt;code&gt;optimize-png.sh&lt;/code&gt;, reduces size of static images by converting them to WebP or by running &lt;code&gt;oxipng&lt;/code&gt;. You&#39;d typically execute it on your own game client hosting server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, you&#39;ll get:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;subfolders with game animations, images and audio - totalling about 1 GiB, but you&#39;ll need about 7 more GiB during initial convertion&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;temporary subfolders used during initialization - &lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt; will suggest removing them once done&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;databanks&lt;/code&gt; subfolder - game data in HeroWO format, extracted from HoMM 3 files and possibly modded&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;maps&lt;/code&gt; subfolder - maps in HeroWO format, usually converted from HoMM 3 maps (&lt;code&gt;.h3m&lt;/code&gt;) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;this will take 11+ GiB for all official maps but it&#39;ll come down by 90% if you enable file system compression (&lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt; will advise)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;several &lt;code&gt;*.ahk&lt;/code&gt; scripts - help extracting DEF frames (can be deleted)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By convention, folders with data coming from HoMM 3 are named after the data&#39;s original file extension in upper-case, optionally followed by &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; and the converted extension (e.g. &lt;code&gt;WAV-OGG&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Boot&#39;n&#39;strap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;re all set, type this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;php path/to/update.php&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On Windows, you may be able to just double-click &lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt; to run it. Or click the Shell button in XAMPP Control Panel and type the line above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow the script&#39;s interactive instructions to finish configuring your local environment (or run &lt;code&gt;update.php -h&lt;/code&gt; for options). It may take a while, be patient even if nothing seems to be happening on screen!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instructions for manual convertion are found in &lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt;&#39;s source code, &lt;code&gt;convertH3Data()&lt;/code&gt; function&#39;s comment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Fast track&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository to a directory, say &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download contents of the torrent file found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://herowo.io/dl&#34;&gt;herowo.io/dl&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; (so you get &lt;code&gt;X/BMP/OBJECTS.TXT&lt;/code&gt;, etc.) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The torrent with intermediate data is useful only if you&#39;re planning to tinker with modifications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;update.php&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Other considerations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Default Apache caching may get in the way of debugging. You can turn it off by adding the following lines to the configuration file (such as &lt;code&gt;/etc/apache2/apache2.conf&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;C:\xampp\apache\conf\httpd.conf&lt;/code&gt;) and restarting Apache:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Header unset Last-Modified&#xA;Header unset Etag&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>