<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tinycorelinux/tinyx</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-30:/tinycorelinux/tinyx</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tinycorelinux/tinyx" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Necromancy&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We resurrected Xvesa from the depths of git history, and intend to maintain it with Xfbdev.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This includes bugfixes, security fixes, and occasional new features if required.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The TinyX servers fill our needs while being a lot smaller than Xorg can be made.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why 1.2.0 and not 1.3.0?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you know, Xvesa was killed in 1.4.0, so the latest released version would be 1.3.0. However, they broke all input in 1.3.0 (keyboard and mouse), so the last working released version is 1.2.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There were also some changes later on that we disagree with (mandatory xinput &amp;amp; xkb).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Design choices&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We aim for the smallest fully featured X server binary. Currently there are the vesa and fbdev servers, but others may appear in the future (Xmodesetting?).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;no xkb; it&#39;s bloat when console keymaps suffice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;no xinput&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;no xinerama&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;no gl&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TCP listening disabled by default, shadow FB enabled by default ...&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the original codebase is MIT, any changes here are GPLv3. Supporting closed devices with this code is not a goal.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a similar tinyX fork from the Puppy folks: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/idunham/tinyxserver&#34;&gt;https://github.com/idunham/tinyxserver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In case you can&#39;t find the sources for libXfont ver 1 or other libs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.x.org/archive/individual/lib/&#34;&gt;https://www.x.org/archive/individual/lib/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>antirez/kilo</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-30:/antirez/kilo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/antirez/kilo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A text editor in less than 1000 LOC with syntax highlight and search.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Kilo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kilo is a small text editor in less than 1K lines of code (counted with cloc).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A screencast is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://asciinema.org/a/90r2i9bq8po03nazhqtsifksb&#34;&gt;https://asciinema.org/a/90r2i9bq8po03nazhqtsifksb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usage: kilo &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keys:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CTRL-S: Save&#xA;CTRL-Q: Quit&#xA;CTRL-F: Find string in file (ESC to exit search, arrows to navigate)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kilo does not depend on any library (not even curses). It uses fairly standard VT100 (and similar terminals) escape sequences. The project is in alpha stage and was written in just a few hours taking code from my other two projects, load81 and linenoise.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;People are encouraged to use it as a starting point to write other editors or command line interfaces that are more advanced than the usual REPL style CLI.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kilo was written by Salvatore Sanfilippo aka antirez and is released under the BSD 2 clause license.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>flowdriveai/flowpilot</title>
    <updated>2023-06-30T01:31:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-30:/flowdriveai/flowpilot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/flowdriveai/flowpilot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;flow-pilot is an openpilot based driver assistance system that runs on linux, windows and android powered machines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.ibb.co/LZtKvfB/Screenshot-from-2022-09-15-22-15-14.png&#34; alt=&#34;table&#34; width=&#34;1270&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;What is Flowpilot?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flowpilot is an open source driver assistance system built on top of openpilot, that can run on most windows/linux and android powered machines. It performs the functions of Adaptive Cruise Control (ACC), Automated Lane Centering (ALC), Forward Collision Warning (FCW), Lane Departure Warning (LDW) and Driver Monitoring (DM) for a growing variety of supported car makes, models, and model years maintened by the community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/L9O-WFmigSA&#34; title=&#34;Video By Ender&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/L9O-WFmigSA/maxresdefault.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/mt86H67DhE0&#34; title=&#34;Video By Miso&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/mt86H67DhE0/maxresdefault.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/06DLmtF6og4&#34; title=&#34;Video By Ender&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/06DLmtF6og4/maxresdefault.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/FBB2XRMej9M&#34; title=&#34;Video By Miso&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i3.ytimg.com/vi/FBB2XRMej9M/maxresdefault.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Running on a Car&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For running flowpilot on your car, you need:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A supported machine to run flowpilot i.e. A windows/linux PC or an android phone.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A white / grey panda with giraffe or a black/red panda with car harness.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;1x USB-A to USB-A cable for connecting panda to PC and aditionally, an OTG cable is required if connecting panda to phone.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/commaai/openpilot/raw/master/docs/CARS.md&#34;&gt;200+ supported cars&lt;/a&gt;. The community supports Honda, Toyota, Hyundai, Nissan, Kia, Chrysler, Lexus, Acura, Audi, VW, and more. If your car is not supported but has adaptive cruise control and lane-keeping assist, it&#39;s likely able to run flowpilot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a more detailed overview, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flowdriveai/flowpilot/wiki/Connecting-to-Car&#34;&gt;wiring and hardware wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/flowdriveai/flowpilot/wiki/Installation&#34;&gt;installation wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Running With a Virtual Car&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to develop on a virtual car / simulation before jumping onto testing on a real car. Flowpilot supports CARLA simulation. Optionally, you can use FlowStreamer to test flowpilot with any videogame. For more thorough testing, in addition to simulation, real panda hardware can be put in the loop for a more &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flowdrive_ai/status/1566680576962478086&#34;&gt;thorough testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Community&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/APJaQR9nhz&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://assets-global.website-files.com/6257adef93867e50d84d30e2/636e0b5061df29d55a92d945_full_logo_blurple_RGB.svg?sanitize=true&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flowpilot&#39;s core community lives on the official flowdrive &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/APJaQR9nhz&#34;&gt;discord server&lt;/a&gt;. Check the pinned messages or search history through messages to see if your issues or question has been discussed earlier. You may also join &lt;a href=&#34;https://linktr.ee/flowdrive&#34;&gt;more awesome&lt;/a&gt; openpilot discord communities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also push frequent updates on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/flowdrive_ai&#34;&gt;twitter handle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;User Data&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flowpilot will require your email address for setting up you flowdrive account. Flowpilot logs the road-facing cameras, CAN, GPS, IMU, magnetometer, thermal sensors, crashes, and operating system logs. The driver-facing camera is only logged if you explicitly opt-in in settings. The microphone is not recorded.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You understand that use of this software or its related services will generate certain types of user data, which may be logged and stored at the sole discretion of flowdrive. By accepting this agreement, you grant an irrevocable, perpetual, worldwide right to flowdrive for the use of this data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THIS IS ALPHA QUALITY SOFTWARE FOR RESEARCH PURPOSES ONLY. THIS IS NOT A PRODUCT. YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR COMPLYING WITH LOCAL LAWS AND REGULATIONS. NO WARRANTY EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>