<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-01T01:36:41Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of C in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>JoshParnell/libphx</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:36:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/JoshParnell/libphx</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/JoshParnell/libphx" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Phoenix Game Engine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;LibPHX&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LibPHX is a lightweight, (mostly) C-based game engine developed for the cancelled space simulation game Limit Theory. LibPHX focuses on implementing the core features necessary to build performant 3D games without including the kitchen sink.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rather than acting as a framework like most modern game engines, the LibPHX philosophy is to provide a game engine &lt;em&gt;as a library&lt;/em&gt; -- that is, control flow is in the hands of the user, not the engine. LibPHX is designed specifically to be controlled from Lua scripts using the LuaJIT runtime. The engine&#39;s C interface, combined with LuaJIT&#39;s FFI technology, allows for scripts to make zero-overhead calls into the engine, thus allowing &lt;em&gt;the majority&lt;/em&gt; of game logic and control to remain in script. Keeping control flow in the hands of Lua opens up a world of fast iteration and fully-moddable game logic, while achieving maximal performance by delegating heavy computation to engine-side functions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LibPHX is now abandoned and mostly undocumented, however you can see examples of its usage in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JoshParnell/ltheory&#34;&gt;https://github.com/JoshParnell/ltheory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mborgerson/xemu</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:36:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/mborgerson/xemu</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mborgerson/xemu" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Original Xbox Emulator for Windows, macOS, and Linux (Active Development)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://xemu.app&#34;&gt;https://xemu.app&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lua/lua</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:36:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/lua/lua</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lua/lua" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Lua development repository, as seen by the Lua team. Mirrored irregularly. Please DO NOT send pull requests. Report issues in the Lua mailing list https://www.lua.org/lua-l.html&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Lua&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository of Lua development code, as seen by the Lua team. It contains the full history of all commits but is mirrored irregularly. For complete information about Lua, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lua.org/&#34;&gt;Lua.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;strong&gt;do not&lt;/strong&gt; send pull requests. To report issues, post a message to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lua.org/lua-l.html&#34;&gt;Lua mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download official Lua releases from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lua.org/download.html&#34;&gt;Lua.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>