<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub XSLT Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-08T01:47:24Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of XSLT in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>usnistgov/metaschema-xslt</title>
    <updated>2023-08-08T01:47:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-08:/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;[WIP] The XSLT implementation of the metaschema modeling language&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Metaschema XSLT&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;project license&lt;/a&gt; in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is placed into the worldwide public domain.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Software description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metaschema-XSLT is an XSLT-based implementation of the NIST (ITL/CSD) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema&#34;&gt;Metaschema Information Modeling Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NIST Metaschema defines how to describe sets of data objects -- serialized information sets, considered abstractly -- &lt;em&gt;across&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;between&lt;/em&gt; implementations of processing systems that are coded to manipulate and process such objects. These descriptions are provided by means of a formal &lt;em&gt;language&lt;/em&gt; developed for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In support of metaschemas defined using this language, this software can be used to generate utilities and software artifacts including XML Schema (XSD) and JSON Schema, data conversion scripts, and model documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Such utilities can in turn provide the basis for ecosystems of tools supporting data models and data sets expressed in the supported formats. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make-your-own Schema Kit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; except your schema comes with many extras, including not only documentation, but also the ability to cast your data between formats and maintain formal format-agnosticism.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Statement of purpose&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NIST ITL/CSD Metaschema is a data modeling technology, which works by providing formal and validable descriptions of data models such that instances (data sets) conforming to these models can be cast and rewritten in various alternative syntaxes, i.e. optimized at the level of format, while permitting lossless conversion of defined-as-equal information sets across format boundaries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to neutralizing the &#34;XML vs JSON&#34; or more broadly &#34;Markup language vs object notation&#34; issue, this technology also offers other capabilities such as external specification and validation of application-oriented semantics (&#34;business rules&#34;) defined over models appropriate to specialized knowledge domains.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The current effort seeks to implement, demonstrate and enable the capabilities of a NIST Metaschema system, with respect to functionalities including schema generation, data conversion or pipelining, stylesheet generation or a host of other potential uses of Metaschema and metaschemas considered broadly. In addition, we aspire to do so sustainably, not in the sense that the software will meet all requirements for all time, but that it will be reliable, validable, traceable, extensible -- and replaceable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Considering data traceability and process transparency as primary goals will also serve secondary goals, such as the creation and demonstration of use cases (for this and compatible software) and the codification and maturation of relevant standards, including standards supported by Metaschema such as OSCAL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stress is therefore on:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Transparency, testability and maintainability of processing on an open-source stack&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Conformance in support of Metaschema-based data interchange / interop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generality of support of Metaschema features&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, we care about, but do not prioritize:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Performance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Portability beyond the XML/XSLT dependency stack (instead relying on other Metaschema initiatives)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Specific use cases&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Origins&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Formerly housed in the Metaschema repository, this code base traces the history of development of the Metaschema concept in the context of the OSCAL project. It was originally conceived as a demonstration and proof of concept, providing a bridge enabling JSON- and XML-based development in parallel over common problem sets and common data. Success in this effort led to a determination that multiple implementations of a platform-independent specification were needed, at which point this implementation was carved out into its own repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Project sunset&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NIST team has no long-term plan to maintain this project outside the context of the initiatives it supports, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/OSCAL&#34;&gt;OSCAL&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema&#34;&gt;Metaschema&lt;/a&gt;, while we reserve the right to change and adapt to community needs in alignment with NIST&#39;s mission. A project goal is to enable the stabilization and socialization of the Metaschema technology, as evidenced by the use and support of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; Metaschema implementations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best way to ensure long-term access to the code base is to clone or fork the git repository and archive a copy for study or use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; includes XSLT source code, with supporting infrastructure including ad-hoc testing&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;support&lt;/code&gt; includes dependent submodules with other static resources for configuration&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation and operation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To operate in trial, test or &#39;bare-bones&#39; mode, scripts are offered to perform operations with no installation except Maven (with JDK as required) and &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt; as a command line environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The utilities are however designed for integration in a range of environments, and core functionalities are implemented in XSLT 3, which is supported across platforms including Java, node JS and C.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The software is designed to be used in a range of ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Directly, in development of metaschemas and Metaschema-based software and tools&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Within Metaschema-based builds, including under CI/CD, to generate artifacts or productions from metaschema source under controlled conditions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;To run&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following generalized services are provided by the tools in this repository, separately or in combination&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;XSD and JSON schema generation - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/src/schema-gen&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;src/schema-gen&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Converter XSLTs for metaschema-supported data - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/src/converter-gen&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;src/converter-gen&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Metaschema documentation production - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/src/document&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;src/document&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripts and stylesheets are documented in place using readmes and in line. Most scripts depend on Apache Maven supporting a Java runtime. Since XSLTs can call, import, include or read XSLTs from elsewhere in the repo, and sometimes do, keep the modules together: each folder on its own is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; self-contained.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Accordingly, a good place to start for further research is the &lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; directory with &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/src/README.md&#34;&gt;its &lt;code&gt;readme.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For testing, all XSpec scenarios (&lt;code&gt;*.xspec&lt;/code&gt;) can be run in place to generate local test reports.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Users are also expected to call resources in this repository from their own scripts. Do this either by cloning, copying and modifying scripts here; by writing your own; or by adapting code into the XML/XSLT processing framework or stack of your choice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, at least two invocations will be offered for each process, an XProc-based invocation and a pure-XSLT-based invocation. Either may be useful in different scenarios.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A convention is used indicating that an XProc (&lt;code&gt;*.xpl&lt;/code&gt; file) or XSLT (&lt;code&gt;*.xsl&lt;/code&gt;) intended to be invoked directly (that is, not only to be used as a module or component) is given a name entirely or partly in &lt;code&gt;ALL-CAPITALS&lt;/code&gt;. For example, &lt;code&gt;src/schema-gen/METASCHEMA-ALL-SCHEMAS.xpl&lt;/code&gt; is such an XProc pipeline (a step definition intended to be used directly). The XSLTs that observe this convention are, additionally, higher-order transformations by virtue of using the &lt;code&gt;transform()&lt;/code&gt; function; for all other resources the convention &lt;code&gt;lower-case-hyphenated&lt;/code&gt; is followed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a freely-available XSLT 3.0 engine, the Saxon XSLT processor can be regarded as a &lt;em&gt;de facto&lt;/em&gt; dependency - while this XSLT-conformant code should in principle run in any processor implementing the language. Saxon-HE can be bundled using Maven or another Java packaging technology.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/support/pom.xml&#34;&gt;POM file&lt;/a&gt; for Java/Maven configuration indicates the current tested version of Saxon. At time of writing, Saxon versions 10 and 11 are known to work with this codebase. When reporting bugs please include the version of your processor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developers interested in demonstrating the viability of these processes in different processors and environments are eagerly invited to participate in development of this tool or related tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Git Client Setup&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See more on git setup on the page on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/develop/CONTRIBUTING&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone the project:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recurse-submodules https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or to clone with submodule initialization:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recurse-submodules https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Initializing Git submodules&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This GitHub repository makes use of Git submodules to mount other repositories as subdirectories. When cloning this repo for the first time, you need to initialize these.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule update --init&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or do this in one step using &lt;code&gt;clone --recurse-submodules&lt;/code&gt; as noted.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Updating submodules&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Submodule contents will be periodically updated. To ensure you have the latest commits for a configured submodule:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule update --init --recursive&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact information&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Principal Investigator: Wendell Piez, NIST (US National Institute of Standards and Technology) ITL/CSD (Information Technology Laboratory, Computer Security Division).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Email w e n d e l l (dot) p i e z (at) n i s t (dot) g o v.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As this initiative spins off from and supports the ITL/CSD &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema&#34;&gt;Metaschema&lt;/a&gt; Project, originally and currently being developed in support of OSCAL, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/OSCAL&#34;&gt;Open Security Controls Assessment Language&lt;/a&gt;, feedback on this project will be gratefully received in those forums.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For OSCAL-related discussions see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/OSCAL/contribute&#34;&gt;OSCAL Site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Cite this work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Piez, Wendell (2023), Metaschema-XSLT. US National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST). &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt&#34;&gt;https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related projects&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema&#34;&gt;Metaschema Repository&lt;/a&gt; and its &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.nist.gov/metaschema/&#34;&gt;Pages Site&lt;/a&gt; for a description and specification of the technology this software is designed to support. Those pages also contain links to other projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the Project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/usnistgov/metaschema-xslt/wiki&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; for documentation maintained on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Required outline&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This page includes all the following, as described by guidelines at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/opensource-repo/main/README.md&#34;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/usnistgov/opensource-repo/main/README.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Software or Data description &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Statements of purpose and maturity&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Description of the repository contents&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Technical installation instructions, including operating system or software dependencies&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contact information &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;PI name, NIST OU, Division, and Group names&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Contact email address at NIST&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Details of mailing lists, chatrooms, and discussion forums, where applicable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Related Material &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;URL for associated project on the NIST website or other Department of Commerce page, if available&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;References to user guides if stored outside of GitHub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Directions on appropriate citation with example text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;References to any included non-public domain software modules, and additional license language if needed, &lt;em&gt;e.g.&lt;/em&gt; BSD, GPL, or MIT&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>