<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub XSLT Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-22T01:52:26Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of XSLT in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PreTeXtBook/pretext</title>
    <updated>2023-06-22T01:52:26Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-22:/PreTeXtBook/pretext</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PreTeXtBook/pretext" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PreTeXt: an authoring and publishing system for scholarly documents&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PreTeXt&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An authoring and publishing system for authors of textbooks, research articles, and monographs, especially in STEM disciplines.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GPL License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quickstart instructions at project website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pretextbook.org&#34;&gt;pretextbook.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Help and development discussions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support forum/mailing-list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/pretext-support&#34;&gt;pretext-support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Announcements only, low-volume: &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/pretext-announce&#34;&gt;pretext-announce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submitting an issue is the last option for receiving help. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PreTeXtBook/pretext/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;PreTeXt is guided by the following principles:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt is a markup language that captures the structure of textbooks and research papers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt is human-readable and human-writable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt documents serve as a single source which can be easily converted to multiple other formats, current and future.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt respects the good design practices which have been developed over the past centuries.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt makes it easy for authors to implement features which are both common and reasonable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt supports online documents which make use of the full capabilities of the Web.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt output is styled by selecting from a list of available templates, relieving the author of the burden involved in micromanaging the output format.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt is free: the software is available at no cost, with an open license. The use of PreTeXt does not impose any constraints on documents prepared with the system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt is not a closed system: documents can be converted to LaTeX and then developed using standard LaTeX tools.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt recognizes that scholarly documents involve the interaction of authors, publishers, scholars, curators, instructors, students, and readers, with each group having its own needs and goals.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PreTeXt recognizes the inherent value in producing material that is accessible to everyone.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>