<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-20T01:35:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mrniko/netty-socketio</title>
    <updated>2023-04-20T01:35:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-20:/mrniko/netty-socketio</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mrniko/netty-socketio" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Socket.IO server implemented on Java. Realtime java framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Netty-socketio Overview&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is an open-source Java implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://socket.io/&#34;&gt;Socket.IO&lt;/a&gt; server. Based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://netty.io/&#34;&gt;Netty&lt;/a&gt; server framework.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Checkout &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrniko/netty-socketio-demo&#34;&gt;Demo project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the Apache License 2.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.x&lt;/strong&gt; version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/socketio/socket.io-client&#34;&gt;Socket.IO-client&lt;/a&gt; is supported&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports xhr-polling transport&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports websocket transport&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports namespaces and rooms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports ack (acknowledgment of received data)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports SSL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports client store (Memory, &lt;a href=&#34;https://redisson.org&#34;&gt;Redisson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hazelcast.com/&#34;&gt;Hazelcast&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports distributed broadcast across netty-socketio nodes (&lt;a href=&#34;https://redisson.org&#34;&gt;Redisson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hazelcast.com/&#34;&gt;Hazelcast&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports OSGi&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Supports Spring&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lock-free and thread-safe implementation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Declarative handler configuration via annotations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Performance&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Customer feedback in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt; CentOS, 1 CPU, 4GB RAM runned on VM: CPU 10%, Memory 15%&lt;br&gt; 6000 xhr-long polling sessions or 15000 websockets sessions&lt;br&gt; 4000 messages per second&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Customer feedback in &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt; &#34;To stress test the solution we run 30 000 simultaneous websocket clients and managed to peak at total of about 140 000 messages per second with less than 1 second average delay.&#34; (c) Viktor Endersz - Kambi Sports Solutions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Projects using netty-socketio&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AVOS Cloud: &lt;a href=&#34;https://avoscloud.com/&#34;&gt;avoscloud.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; Bingo Crack: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bingocrack.com/&#34;&gt;bingocrack.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; Kambi Sports Solutions: &lt;a href=&#34;http://kambi.com/&#34;&gt;kambi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; ARSnova: &lt;a href=&#34;https://arsnova.eu&#34;&gt;arsnova.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; Zipwhip: &lt;a href=&#34;https://zipwhip.com/&#34;&gt;zipwhip.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Recent Releases&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Please Note: trunk is current development branch.&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;17-Apr-2023 - version 1.7.25 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - io.netty.channel.ChannelPipelineException error&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;14-Apr-2023 - version 1.7.24 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - SocketIOClient.isWritable() method added (thanks @xuwenqing04)&lt;br&gt; Feature - Namespace.addListeners(Iterable&#xA; &lt;l&gt;&#xA;   listeners) method added (thanks @damonxue)&#xA; &lt;/l&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - disconnect event packet should be a subtype of MESSAGE (thanks @MasterShi)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - BaseStoreFactory throws NPE&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;02-Feb-2023 - version 1.7.23 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - Added support for bulk join and leave (thanks @ksahu750)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - auto disconnected (regression since 1.7.22)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;22-Sep-2022 - version 1.7.22 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - ping/pong support for socketio v4 protocol (thanks to @HashZhang)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;06-Aug-2022 - version 1.7.21 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - transport name should be checked in uppercase (regression since 1.7.20)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;26-Jul-2022 - version 1.7.20 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - needClientAuth setting added (thanks to @huws)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - ContinuationWebSocketFrame should be used if payload &amp;gt; maxFramePayloadLength (thanks to 俞伟搏)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - event listener src class and dest bean is no match (thanks to @cifaz)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - illegal transport parameter (thanks to @mirus36)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;29-Apr-2021 - version 1.7.19 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - writeBufferWaterMarkLow and writeBufferWaterMarkHigh settings added (thanks to @xuminwlt)&lt;br&gt; Feature - allowHeaders setting added (thanks to @HuangHuan)&lt;br&gt; Feature - getCurrentRoomSize() method added (thanks to @sunxiaoyu3)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - namespace bug (thanks to @@johntyty912)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - multiple nodes with redisson receive same message (thanks to 梁嘉祺)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - multiple nodes receive only one LEAVE msg on client disconnect (thanks to @GaryLeung922)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;17-Jan-2020 - version 1.7.18 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - support for event interceptors which catch all events (thanks to @yosiat)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - namespace event broadcasting (thanks to Volodymyr Masliy)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;11-Jan-2019 - version 1.7.17 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - randomSession setting added to Config object (thanks to @yuanxiangz)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - NPE in WebSocketTransport&lt;br&gt; Fixed - NPE &amp;amp; memory leak (thanks to zhaolianwang)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - namespace parsing (thanks to Redliver)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Redisson 3.9+ compatibility&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;06-Jul-2018 - version 1.7.16 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - non thread-safe ACK handling (thanks to @dawnbreaks)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - inactive long-polling channels cause memory leak (thanks to @dawnbreaks)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - websocket CloseFrame processing (thanks to @hangsu.cho)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - WebSocketTransport NPE&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;15-May-2018 - version 1.7.15 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - Session ID is not unique anymore&lt;br&gt; Fixed - fixed underlying connection not closing on ping timeout&lt;br&gt; Fixed - the &#34;fin_close&#34; problem&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;26-Feb-2018 - version 1.7.14 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - added local socket address for the connection (thanks to @SergeyGrigorev)&lt;br&gt; Feature - &lt;code&gt;addPingListener&lt;/code&gt; method added (thanks to @lovebing)&lt;br&gt; Feature - add ThreadFactory for HashedWheelTimer (thanks to @hand515)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - changed SO_LINGER to be handled as child channel (not server channel) option (thanks to @robymus)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - ByteBuf leak if binary attachments are used&lt;br&gt; Fixed - restore session from Cookie (thanks to @wuxudong)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - NumberFormatException when b64 is bool value (thanks to @vonway)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - data encoding for polling transport&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;20-Sep-2017 - version 1.7.13 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - Added option to change the SSL KeyFactoryAlgorithm using Configuration (thanks to @robymus)&lt;br&gt; Improvement - Binary ack handling improvements (thanks to Sergey Bushik)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Failed to mark a promise as success because it has succeeded already (thanks to @robymus)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;27-Aug-2016 - version 1.7.12 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - &lt;code&gt;SocketIOServer.removeAllListeners&lt;/code&gt; method added&lt;br&gt; Feature - &lt;code&gt;BroadcastOperations.sendEvent&lt;/code&gt; method with &lt;code&gt;excludedClient&lt;/code&gt; param added&lt;br&gt; Improvement - Redisson updated to 2.4.0&lt;br&gt; Fixed - memory leak in Namespace object (thanks to @CrazyIvan007)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;13-Jul-2016 - version 1.7.11 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - Throw error if transport not supported&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Client disconnecting when using Polling - IndexOutOfBoundsException&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;4-Mar-2016 - version 1.7.10 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - netty updated to 4.1.0.CR3 version&lt;br&gt; Fixed - binary packet parsing (thanks to Winston Li)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;6-Feb-2016 - version 1.7.9 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - Compression support&lt;br&gt; Fixed - DotNET client request handling&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Packet length format parsing&lt;br&gt; Fixed - skipping &#39;d=&#39; in packet&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Polling clients sporadically get prematurely disconnected (thanks to lpage30)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - connections stay open forever if server sent &lt;code&gt;close&lt;/code&gt; packet&lt;br&gt; Fixed - compatibility with Redisson latest version&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;30-Nov-2015 - version 1.7.8 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - &lt;code&gt;WebSocketServerHandshaker.allowExtensions&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; now&lt;br&gt; Improvement - SessionID cookie implementation (thanks to @ryandietrich)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - clientRooms leak (thanks to @andreaspalm)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - ExceptionListener not used for errors in JSON parsing&lt;br&gt; Fixed - &#34;silent channel&#34; attack&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;26-Mar-2015 - version 1.6.7 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - &lt;code&gt;useStrictOrdering&lt;/code&gt; param added for websocket packets strict ordering&lt;br&gt; Improvement - &lt;code&gt;FAIL_ON_EMPTY_BEANS = false&lt;/code&gt; option setted in json decoder&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;18-Feb-2015 - version 1.7.7 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - no need to add jackson lib if you use own JsonSupport impl&lt;br&gt; Fixed - SocketIO client 1.3.x support&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Charset encoding handling (thanks to alim-akbashev)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;17-Jan-2015 - version 1.7.6 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - &lt;code&gt;SocketIONamespace.getName()&lt;/code&gt; added&lt;br&gt; Fixed - WebSocket frames aggregation&lt;br&gt; Fixed - WebSocket buffer release&lt;br&gt; Fixed - &lt;code&gt;Unexpected end-of-input in VALUE_STRING&lt;/code&gt; error&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Access-Control-Allow-Credentials is TRUE for requests with origin header&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;05-Dec-2014 - version 1.7.5 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - &lt;code&gt;Configuration.sslProtocol&lt;/code&gt; param added&lt;br&gt; Fixed - BinaryEvent ack handling&lt;br&gt; Fixed - BinaryEvent non b64 encoding/decoding&lt;br&gt; Fixed - buffer leak during packet encoding&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;15-Nov-2014 - version 1.7.4 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - packet encoding&lt;br&gt; Fixed - BinaryEvent encoding/decoding&lt;br&gt; Fixed - unchallenged connections handling&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;29-Sep-2014 - version 1.6.6 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - &lt;code&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; setting added&lt;br&gt; Feature - &lt;code&gt;crossDomainPolicy&lt;/code&gt; setting added&lt;br&gt; Feature - &lt;code&gt;SocketIOServer.startAsync&lt;/code&gt; method added&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;24-Sep-2014 - version 1.7.3 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - Epoll support&lt;br&gt; Improvement - BinaryEvent support&lt;br&gt; Fixed - SocketIOClient disconnect handling&lt;br&gt; Fixed - broadcast callback&lt;br&gt; Fixed - NPE then no transport defined during auth&lt;br&gt; Fixed - ping timeout for polling transport&lt;br&gt; Fixed - buffer leak in PacketEncoder&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;22-Aug-2014 - version 1.7.2 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - wrong outgoing message encoding using websocket transport&lt;br&gt; Fixed - NPE in websocket transport&lt;br&gt; Fixed - multiple packet decoding in polling transport&lt;br&gt; Fixed - buffer leak&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;07-Jul-2014 - version 1.7.1 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - ability to set custom &lt;code&gt;Access-Control-Allow-Origin&lt;/code&gt; via Configuration.origin&lt;br&gt; Fixed - connection via CLI socket.io-client&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;28-Jun-2014 - version 1.7.0 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feature - Socket.IO 1.0 protocol support. Thanks to the new protocol decoding/encoding has speedup&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dropped&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;code&gt;SocketIOClient.sendMessage&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SocketIOClient.sendJsonObject&lt;/code&gt; methods and corresponding listeners&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dropped&lt;/strong&gt; - Flashsocket transport support&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dropped&lt;/strong&gt; - protocol version 0.7 ... 0.9.16&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;13-May-2014 - version 1.6.5 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - single packet encoding optimized, used mostly in WebSocket transport. Encoding time reduced up to 40% (thanks to Viktor Endersz)&lt;br&gt; Improvement - rooms handling optimized&lt;br&gt; Improvement - ExceptionListener.exceptionCaught method added&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Breaking api change&lt;/strong&gt; - Configuration.autoAck replaced with ackMode&lt;br&gt; Feature - trustStore setting added&lt;br&gt; Feature - maxFramePayloadLength setting added&lt;br&gt; Feature - getAllClients and getClient methods added to SocketIONamespace&lt;br&gt; Fixed - SocketIOServer.getAllClients returns wrong clients amount&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;25-Mar-2014 - version 1.6.4 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - message release problem&lt;br&gt; Fixed - problem with exception listener configuration redefinition&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Breaking api change&lt;/strong&gt; - DataListener.onData now throws Exception&lt;br&gt; Improvement - data parameter added to exception listener&lt;br&gt; Improvement - ability to setup socket configuration&lt;br&gt; Improvement - Configuration.autoAck parameter added&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;06-Mar-2014 - version 1.6.3 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - AckCallback handling during client disconnect&lt;br&gt; Fixed - unauthorized handshake HTTP code changed to 401&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Breaking api change&lt;/strong&gt; - Configuration.heartbeatThreadPoolSize setting removed&lt;br&gt; Feature - annotated Spring beans support via &lt;em&gt;SpringAnnotationScanner&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt; Feature - common exception listener&lt;br&gt; Improvement - &lt;em&gt;ScheduledExecutorService&lt;/em&gt; replaced with &lt;em&gt;HashedWheelTimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;08-Feb-2014 - version 1.6.2 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - wrong namespace client disconnect handling&lt;br&gt; Fixed - exception in onConnect/onDisconnect/isAuthorized methods leads to server hang&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Breaking api change&lt;/strong&gt; - SocketIOClient.sendEvent methods signature changed&lt;br&gt; Improvement - multi type events support via &lt;em&gt;MultiTypeEventListener&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;OnEvent&lt;/em&gt; annotation&lt;br&gt; Improvement - multi type events ack support via &lt;em&gt;MultiTypeAckCallback&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt; Improvement - SocketIOClient.getHandshakeData method added&lt;br&gt; Improvement - Jedis replaced with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrniko/redisson&#34;&gt;Redisson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;14-Jan-2014 - version 1.6.1 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - JDK 1.6+ compatibility&lt;br&gt; Feature - authorization support&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;19-Dec-2013 - version 1.6.0 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - XHR-pooling transport regression&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Websocket transport regression&lt;br&gt; Fixed - namespace NPE in PacketHandler&lt;br&gt; Fixed - executors shutdown during server stop&lt;br&gt; Feature - client store (Memory, &lt;a href=&#34;http://redis.io/&#34;&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hazelcast.com/&#34;&gt;Hazelcast&lt;/a&gt;) support&lt;br&gt; Feature - distributed broadcast across netty-socketio nodes (&lt;a href=&#34;http://redis.io/&#34;&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hazelcast.com/&#34;&gt;Hazelcast&lt;/a&gt;) support&lt;br&gt; Feature - OSGi support (thanks to rdevera)&lt;br&gt; Improvement - XHR-pooling optimization&lt;br&gt; Improvement - SocketIOClient.getAllRooms method added&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;07-Dec-2013 - version 1.5.4 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - flash policy &#34;request leak&#34; after page reload (thanks to ntrp)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - websocket swf loading (thanks to ntrp)&lt;br&gt; Fixed - wrong urls causes a potential DDoS&lt;br&gt; Fixed - Event.class package visibility changed to avoid direct usage&lt;br&gt; Improvement - Simplified Jackson modules registration&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;24-Oct-2013 - version 1.5.2 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - NPE during shutdown&lt;br&gt; Improvement - isEmpty method added to Namespace&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;13-Oct-2013 - version 1.5.1 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - wrong ack timeout callback invocation&lt;br&gt; Fixed - bigdecimal serialization for JSON&lt;br&gt; Fixed - infinity loop during packet handling exception&lt;br&gt; Fixed - &#39;client not found&#39; handling&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;27-Aug-2013 - version 1.5.0 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Improvement - encoding buffers allocation optimization.&lt;br&gt; Improvement - encoding buffers now pooled in memory to reduce GC pressure (netty 4.x feature).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;03-Aug-2013 - version 1.0.1 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed - error on unknown property during deserialization.&lt;br&gt; Fixed - memory leak in long polling transport.&lt;br&gt; Improvement - logging error info with inbound data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;07-Jun-2013 - version 1.0.0 released&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First stable release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Maven&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Include the following to your dependency list:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&#xA; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;com.corundumstudio.socketio&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&#xA; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;netty-socketio&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&#xA; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt;1.7.19&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Supported by&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;YourKit is kindly supporting this open source project with its full-featured Java Profiler. YourKit, LLC is the creator of innovative and intelligent tools for profiling Java and .NET applications. Take a look at YourKit&#39;s leading software products: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yourkit.com/java/profiler/index.jsp&#34;&gt;YourKit Java Profiler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yourkit.com/.net/profiler/index.jsp&#34;&gt;YourKit .NET Profiler&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>