<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-16T01:29:36Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Helium314/HeliBoard</title>
    <updated>2024-02-16T01:29:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-16:/Helium314/HeliBoard</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Helium314/HeliBoard" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Customizable and privacy-conscious open-source keyboard&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HeliBoard&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HeliBoard is a privacy-conscious and customizable open-source keyboard, based on AOSP / OpenBoard. Does not use internet permission, and thus is 100% offline.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#faq--common-issues&#34;&gt;FAQ / Common Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#hidden-functionality&#34;&gt;Hidden Functionality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#contributing-&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#reporting-issues&#34;&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#translation&#34;&gt;Translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#dictionary-creation&#34;&gt;Dictionary Creation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#code-contribution&#34;&gt;Code Contribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/#credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add dictionaries for suggestions and spell check &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;build your own, or get them &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries#dictionaries&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries#experimental-dictionaries&#34;&gt;experimental&lt;/a&gt; section (quality may vary)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;additional dictionaries for emojis or scientific symbols can be used to provide suggestions (&#34;emoji search&#34;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;note that for Korean layouts, suggestions only work using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openboard-team/openboard/commit/83fca9533c03b9fecc009fc632577226bbd6301f&#34;&gt;this dictionary&lt;/a&gt;, the tools in the dictionary repository are not able to create working dictionaries&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Customize keyboard themes (style, colors and background image) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;can follow the system&#39;s day/night setting on Android 10+ (and on some versions of Android 9)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;can follow dynamic colors for Android 12+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Customize keyboard &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/layouts.md&#34;&gt;layouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Multilingual typing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Glide typing (&lt;em&gt;only with closed source library&lt;/em&gt;) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;library not included in the app, as there is no compatible open source library available&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;can be extracted from GApps packages (&#34;&lt;em&gt;swypelibs&lt;/em&gt;&#34;), or downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/erkserkserks/openboard/tree/master/app/src/main/jniLibs&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;if you are concerned about security implications of loading user-provides libraries, please use the &lt;em&gt;nouserlib&lt;/em&gt; build variant, which removes this option. If HeliBoard is installed as system app, and &lt;em&gt;swypelibs&lt;/em&gt; are available for the system, they will be used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If the app is installed as a system app and &lt;em&gt;swypelibs&lt;/em&gt; are available, glide typing will be available independent of the version.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clipboard history&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;One-handed mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Split keyboard (if the screen is large enough)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Number pad&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Backup and restore your learned word / history data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ / Common Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add a dictionary&lt;/strong&gt;: First download the dictionary file, e.g. from &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries#dictionaries&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Then go to language settings, click on the language, then on &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; next to &lt;em&gt;dictionary&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;em&gt;add&lt;/em&gt; and select the file. Alternatively you can open a &lt;code&gt;.dict&lt;/code&gt; file in a file explorer with HeliBoard and then select the language. Note that the latter method does not work with all file explorers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emoji search&lt;/strong&gt;: You can get addon dictionaries for emoji suggestions in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries&#34;&gt;dictionaries repo&lt;/a&gt;. An actual search funtion does not exist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No suggestions for some language&lt;/strong&gt;: Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries&#34;&gt;dictionaries repo&lt;/a&gt; whether a dictionary is available. If there is one, download it and add it in the language settings for this language.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No suggestions in some app / text field&lt;/strong&gt;: This app respects the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/text/InputType#TYPE_TEXT_FLAG_NO_SUGGESTIONS&#34;&gt;no suggestions flag&lt;/a&gt; set by some input fields, i.e. the developer does not want you to see suggestions here. Best do in issue report for that app if you think this behavior is wrong. Alternatively you can enable the &lt;em&gt;always show suggestions&lt;/em&gt; setting that overrides the &lt;em&gt;no suggestions&lt;/em&gt; flag.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to enable glide typing&lt;/strong&gt;: There is no glide typing built into this app, but you can load compatible libraries: Go to advanced settings -&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;load gesture typing library&lt;/em&gt; and point to a file. You can extract the file from GApps packages (&#34;&lt;em&gt;swypelibs&lt;/em&gt;&#34;), or download one &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/erkserkserks/openboard/tree/master/app/src/main/jniLibs&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure to use the correct version (app will tell you in the dialog to load the library).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the &lt;em&gt;nouserlib&lt;/em&gt; version?&lt;/strong&gt;: The normal version (&lt;em&gt;release&lt;/em&gt;) allows the user to provide a library for glide typing. Running code that isn&#39;t supplied with the app is &lt;em&gt;dynamic code loading&lt;/em&gt;, which is a security risk. Android Studio warns about this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;   &lt;p&gt;Dynamically loading code from locations other than the application&#39;s library directory or the Android platform&#39;s built-in library directories is dangerous, as there is an increased risk that the code could have been tampered with. Applications should use loadLibrary when possible, which provides increased assurance that libraries are loaded from one of these safer locations. Application developers should use the features of their development environment to place application native libraries into the lib directory of their compiled APKs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;The app checks the SHA256 checksum of the library and warns the user if it doesn&#39;t match with known library versions. A mismatch indicates the library was modified, but may also occur if the user intentionally provides a different library than expected (e.g. a self-built variant).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;to be expanded&lt;/em&gt;...) &#xA;   &lt;!-- auto-correct? incognito always on? can&#39;t load library? --&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Hidden Functionality&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Features that may go unnoticed, and further potentially useful information&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-pressing the Clipboard Key (the optional one in the suggestion strip) pastes system clipboard contents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-pressing keys in the suggestion strip toolbar pins them to the suggestion strip.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-press the Comma-key to access Clipboard View, Emoji View, One-handed Mode, Settings, or Switch Language: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Emoji View and Language Switch will disappear if you have the corresponding key enabled;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For some layouts it&#39;s not the Comma-key, but the key at the same position (e.g. it&#39;s &lt;code&gt;q&lt;/code&gt; for Dvorak layout).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When incognito mode is enabled, no words will be learned, and no emojis will be added to recents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sliding key input: Swipe from shift to another key to type a single uppercase key &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This also works for the &lt;code&gt;?123&lt;/code&gt; key to type a single symbol from the symbols keyboard, and for related keys.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-press the &lt;code&gt;?123&lt;/code&gt; from main view to directly open numpad.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-press a suggestion in the suggestion strip to show more suggestions, and a delete button to remove this suggestion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swipe up from a suggestion to open more suggestions, and release on the suggestion to select it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Long-press an entry in the clipboard history to pin it (keep it in clipboard until you unpin).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swipe left in clipboard view to remove an entry (except when it&#39;s pinned)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can add dictionaries by opening the file &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This only works with &lt;em&gt;content-uris&lt;/em&gt; and not with &lt;em&gt;file-uris&lt;/em&gt;, meaning that it may not work with some file explorers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;When using debug mode / debug APK&lt;/em&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Long-press a suggestion in the suggestion strip twice to show the source dictionary.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When using debug APK, you can find Debug Settings within the Advanced Preferences, though the usefulness is limited except for dumping dictionaries into the log.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In the event of an application crash, you will be prompted whether you want the crash logs when you open the Settings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When using multilingual typing, space bar will show an confidence value used for determining the currenly used language.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Suggestions will have some tiny numbers on top showing some internal score and source dictionary (can be disabled)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For users doing manual backups with root access: Starting at Android 7, some files and the main shared preferences file are not in the default location, because the app is using &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Context#createDeviceProtectedStorageContext()&#34;&gt;device protected storage&lt;/a&gt;. This is necessary so the settings and layout files can be read before the device is unlocked, e.g. at boot. The files are usually located in &lt;code&gt;/data/user_de/0/&amp;lt;package_id&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt;, though the location may depend on the device and Android version.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contributing ❤&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whether you encountered a bug, or want to see a new feature in HeliBoard, you can contribute to the project by opening a new issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Your help is always welcome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before opening a new issue, be sure to check the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the issue already exist?&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure a similar issue has not been reported by browsing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/issues&#34;&gt;existing issues&lt;/a&gt;. Please search open and closed issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the issue still relevant?&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your issue is not already fixed in the latest version of HeliBoard.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you use the issue template?&lt;/strong&gt; It is important to make life of our kind contributors easier by avoiding issues that miss key information to their resolution. Note that issues that that ignore part of the issue template will likely get treated with very low priority, as often they are needlessly hard to read or understand (e.g. huge screenshots, or addressing multiple topics).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Translation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translations can be added using &lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.codeberg.org/projects/heliboard/&#34;&gt;Weblate&lt;/a&gt;. You will need an account to update translations and add languages. Add the language you want to translate to in Languages -&amp;gt; Manage translated languages in the top menu bar.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Dictionary Creation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There will not be any further dictionaries bundled in this app. However, you can add dictionaries to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries&#34;&gt;dictionaries repository&lt;/a&gt;. To create or update a dictionary for your language, you can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/remi0s/aosp-dictionary-tools&#34;&gt;this tool&lt;/a&gt;. You will need a wordlist, as described &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/Helium314/aosp-dictionaries/src/branch/main/wordlists/sample.combined&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and in the repository readme.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code Contribution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HeliBoard project is based on Gradle and Android Gradle Plugin. To get started, you can install &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio&#34;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt;, and import project &#39;from Version Control / Git / Github&#39; by providing this git repository &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Helium314/HeliBoard&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; (or git SSH &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/git@github.com:Helium314/openboard.git&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt;). Of course you can also use any other compatible IDE, or work with text editor and command line.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once everything is up correctly, you&#39;re ready to go!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Guidelines&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HeliBoard is a complex application, when contributing, you must take a step back and make sure your contribution:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is actually wanted&lt;/strong&gt;. Best check related open issues before you start working on a PR. Issues with &#34;PR&#34; and &#34;contributor needed&#34; labels are accepted, but still it would be good if you announced that you are working on it. If there is no issue related to your intended contribution, it&#39;s a good idea to open a new one to avoid disappointment of the contribution not being accepted. For small changes or fixing obvious bugs this step is not necessary.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is only about a single thing&lt;/strong&gt;. Mixing unrelated contributions into a single PR is hard to review and can get messy.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has a proper description&lt;/strong&gt;. What your contribution does is usually less obvious to reviewers than for yourself. A good description helps a lot for understanding what is going on, and for separating wanted from unintended changes in behavior.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uses already in-place mechanism and take advantage of them&lt;/strong&gt;. In other terms, does not reinvent the wheel or uses shortcuts that could alter the consistency of the existing code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has a low footprint&lt;/strong&gt;. Some parts of the code are executed very frequently, and the keyboard should stay responsive even on older devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does not bring any non-free code or proprietary binary blobs&lt;/strong&gt;. This also applies to code/binaries with unknown licenses. Make sure you do not introduce any closed-source library from Google. If your contribution contains code that is not your own, provide a link to the source.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complies with the user privacy principle HeliBoard follows&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to previous elements, HeliBoard must stick to &lt;a href=&#34;https://f-droid.org/docs/Inclusion_Policy/&#34;&gt;F-Droid inclusion guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Adding Layouts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/layouts.md#adding-new-layouts--languages&#34;&gt;layouts.md&lt;/a&gt; for how to add new layouts to the app.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Update Emojis&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See make-emoji-keys tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/tools/make-emoji-keys/README.md&#34;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HeliBoard (as a fork of OpenBoard) is licensed under GNU General Public License v3.0.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Permissions of this strong copyleft license are conditioned on making available complete source code of licensed works and modifications, which include larger works using a licensed work, under the same license. Copyright and license notices must be preserved. Contributors provide an express grant of patent rights.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See repo&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/LICENSE-GPL-3&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the app is based on Apache 2.0 licensed AOSP Keyboard, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/main/LICENSE-Apache-2.0&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0&lt;/a&gt; license file is provided too.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Credits&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Icon by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marcotls.eu&#34;&gt;Marco TLS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openboard-team/openboard&#34;&gt;OpenBoard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://android.googlesource.com/platform/packages/inputmethods/LatinIME/&#34;&gt;AOSP Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://review.lineageos.org/admin/repos/LineageOS/android_packages_inputmethods_LatinIME&#34;&gt;LineageOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rkkr/simple-keyboard&#34;&gt;Simple Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/indicproject/indic-keyboard&#34;&gt;Indic Keyboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/florisboard/florisboard/&#34;&gt;FlorisBoard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Helium314/HeliBoard/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>opensearch-project/security</title>
    <updated>2024-02-16T01:29:36Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-16:/opensearch-project/security</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/opensearch-project/security" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;🔐 Secure your cluster with TLS, numerous authentication backends, data masking, audit logging as well as role-based access control on indices, documents, and fields&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/workflows/CI/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;CI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22untriaged%22&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/opensearch-project/security/untriaged?labelColor=red&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22security%20vulnerability%22&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/opensearch-project/security/security%20vulnerability?labelColor=red&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/opensearch-project/security&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/pulls&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues-pr/opensearch-project/security&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.codecov.io/gh/opensearch-project/security&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/codecov/c/gh/opensearch-project/security&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22v2.4.0%22&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/opensearch-project/security/v2.4.0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22v3.0.0%22&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/opensearch-project/security/v3.0.0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.slack.com/archives/C051Y637FKK&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Slack-4A154B?&amp;amp;logo=slack&amp;amp;logoColor=white&#34; alt=&#34;Slack&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Announcement: The Slack workspace is live! Please join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.slack.com/archives/C051Y637FKK&#34;&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opensearch.org/assets/img/opensearch-logo-themed.svg?sanitize=true&#34; height=&#34;64px&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;OpenSearch Security Plugin&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch Security is a plugin for OpenSearch that offers encryption, authentication and authorization. When combined with OpenSearch Security-Advanced Modules, it supports authentication via Active Directory, LDAP, Kerberos, JSON web tokens, SAML, OpenID and more. It includes fine grained role-based access control to indices, documents and fields. It also provides multi-tenancy support in OpenSearch Dashboards.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#opensearch-security-plugin&#34;&gt;OpenSearch Security Plugin&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#encryption&#34;&gt;Encryption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#authentication&#34;&gt;Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#access-control&#34;&gt;Access control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#auditcompliance-logging&#34;&gt;Audit/Compliance logging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#opensearch-dashboards-multi-tenancy&#34;&gt;OpenSearch Dashboards multi-tenancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#test-and-build&#34;&gt;Test and Build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#config-hot-reloading&#34;&gt;Config hot reloading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#onboarding-new-apis&#34;&gt;Onboarding new APIs&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#system-index-protection&#34;&gt;System Index Protection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#getting-help&#34;&gt;Getting Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/#copyright&#34;&gt;Copyright&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Encryption&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Full data in transit encryption&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Node-to-node encryption&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Certificate revocation lists&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hot Certificate renewal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Authentication&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Internal user database&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;HTTP basic authentication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PKI authentication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Proxy authentication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User Impersonation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Active Directory / LDAP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Kerberos / SPNEGO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;JSON web token (JWT)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenID Connect (OIDC)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SAML&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Access control&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Role-based cluster level access control&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Role-based index level access control&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User-, role- and permission management&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Document-level security&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Field-level security&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;REST management API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Audit/Compliance logging&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Audit logging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compliance logging for GDPR, HIPAA, PCI, SOX and ISO compliance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;OpenSearch Dashboards multi-tenancy&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;True OpenSearch Dashboards multi-tenancy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenSearch Security Plugin comes bundled by default as part of the OpenSearch distribution. Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.org/docs/latest/opensearch/install/index/&#34;&gt;installation guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.org/docs/latest/security-plugin/index/&#34;&gt;technical documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detailed information on installing and configuring the OpenSearch Security Plugin.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/raw/main/DEVELOPER_GUIDE.md&#34;&gt;developer guide&lt;/a&gt; which walks through the installation of the plugin for an OpenSearch server that doesn&#39;t initially have it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Test and Build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run all tests:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;./gradlew clean test&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run tests against local cluster:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;./gradlew integTestRemote -Dtests.rest.cluster=localhost:9200 -Dtests.cluster=localhost:9200 -Dtests.clustername=docker-cluster -Dsecurity=true -Dhttps=true -Duser=admin -Dpassword=admin -Dcommon_utils.version=&#34;2.2.0.0&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: To run against a remote cluster replace cluster-name and &lt;code&gt;localhost:9200&lt;/code&gt; with the IPAddress:Port of that cluster.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Build artifacts (zip, deb, rpm):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;./gradlew clean assemble&#xA;artifact_zip=`ls $(pwd)/build/distributions/opensearch-security-*.zip | grep -v admin-standalone`&#xA;./gradlew buildDeb buildRpm -ParchivePath=$artifact_zip&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This produces:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;build/releases/opensearch-security-&amp;lt;VERSION&amp;gt;.zip&#xA;build/distributions/opensearch-security-&amp;lt;VERSION&amp;gt;.deb&#xA;build/distributions/opensearch-security-&amp;lt;VERSION&amp;gt;.rpm&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Config hot reloading&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Security Plugin configuration is stored in a dedicated index in OpenSearch itself. Changes to the configuration are pushed to this index via the command line tool. This triggers a reload of the configuration on all nodes automatically. This has several advantages over configuration via &lt;code&gt;opensearch.yml&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configuration is stored in a central place&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;No configuration files on the nodes necessary&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configuration changes do not require a restart&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configuration changes take effect immediately&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Onboarding new APIs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is common practice to create new transport actions to perform different tasks between nodes when developing new APIs. For any new or existing plugins that want to onboard &amp;amp; integrate these actions with security, they should follow the steps below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Name your action (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/anomaly-detection/raw/main/src/main/java/org/opensearch/ad/transport/SearchADTasksAction.java#L35&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;), and register it (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/anomaly-detection/raw/main/src/main/java/org/opensearch/ad/AnomalyDetectorPlugin.java#L935&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt;) in your plugin. Best practice is to follow existing naming conventions, which follow a hierarchical pattern to keep the action names organized between different plugins.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Register the action in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security&#34;&gt;OpenSearch Security plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Each new action is registered in the plugin as a new permission. Usually, plugins will define different roles for their plugin (e.g., read-only access, write access). Each role will contain a set of permissions. An example of adding a new permission to the &lt;code&gt;anomaly_read_access&lt;/code&gt; role for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/anomaly-detection&#34;&gt;Anomaly Detection plugin&lt;/a&gt; can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/pull/997/files&#34;&gt;this PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Register the action in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security-dashboards-plugin&#34;&gt;OpenSearch Dashboards Security plugin&lt;/a&gt;. This plugin maintains the full list of possible permissions, so users can see all of them when creating new roles or searching permissions via Dashboards. An example of adding different permissions can be found in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security-dashboards-plugin/pull/689/files&#34;&gt;this PR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/ARCHITECTURE.md#plugin-authorization-flows&#34;&gt;plugin-authorization-flows&lt;/a&gt; in the ARCHITECTURE.md.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;System Index Protection&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Security Plugin provides protection to system indices used by plugins. The system index names must be explicitly registered in &lt;code&gt;opensearch.yml&lt;/code&gt; under the &lt;code&gt;plugins.security.system_indices.indices&lt;/code&gt; setting. See below for an example setup of system index protection from the demo configuration:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugins.security.system_indices.enabled: true&#xA;plugins.security.system_indices.indices: [&#34;.plugins-ml-model&#34;, &#34;.plugins-ml-task&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-alerting-config&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-alerting-alert*&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-anomaly-results*&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-anomaly-detector*&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-anomaly-checkpoints&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-anomaly-detection-state&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-reports-*&#34;, &#34;.opensearch-notifications-*&#34;, &#34;.opensearch-notebooks&#34;, &#34;.opensearch-observability&#34;, &#34;.opendistro-asynchronous-search-response*&#34;, &#34;.replication-metadata-store&#34;]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The demo configuration can be modified in the following files to add a new system index to the demo configuration:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/raw/main/tools/install_demo_configuration.sh&#34;&gt;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/blob/main/tools/install_demo_configuration.sh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/raw/main/tools/install_demo_configuration.bat&#34;&gt;https://github.com/opensearch-project/security/blob/main/tools/install_demo_configuration.bat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/DEVELOPER_GUIDE.md&#34;&gt;developer guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;how to contribute to this project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find a bug, or have a feature request, please don&#39;t hesitate to open an issue in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.org/&#34;&gt;project website&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensearch.org/docs/latest&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. If you need help and are unsure where to open an issue, try &lt;a href=&#34;https://discuss.opendistrocommunity.dev/&#34;&gt;forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Amazon Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/code-of-conduct-faq&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt;, or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opensource-codeofconduct@amazon.com&#34;&gt;opensource-codeofconduct@amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you discover a potential security issue in this project we ask that you notify AWS/Amazon Security via our &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/security/vulnerability-reporting/&#34;&gt;vulnerability reporting page&lt;/a&gt;. Please do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; create a public GitHub issue.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This code is licensed under the Apache 2.0 License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright OpenSearch Contributors. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/opensearch-project/security/main/NOTICE.txt&#34;&gt;NOTICE&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>