<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-29T01:31:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CaffeineMC/sodium</title>
    <updated>2024-10-29T01:31:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-29:/CaffeineMC/sodium</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CaffeineMC/sodium" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Minecraft mod designed to improve frame rates and reduce micro-stutter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CaffeineMC/sodium/dev/common/src/main/resources/sodium-icon.png&#34; width=&#34;128&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Sodium&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sodium is a powerful rendering engine and optimization mod for the Minecraft client which improves frame rates and reduces micro-stutter, while fixing many graphical issues in Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;📥 Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version of Sodium can be downloaded from our official &lt;a href=&#34;https://modrinth.com/mod/sodium&#34;&gt;Modrinth&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/mc-mods/sodium&#34;&gt;CurseForge&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the release of Sodium 0.6.0, both the &lt;em&gt;Fabric&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;NeoForge&lt;/em&gt; mod loaders are supported. We generally recommend that new users prefer to use the &lt;em&gt;Fabric&lt;/em&gt; mod loader, since it is more lightweight and stable (for the time being.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information about downloading and installing the mod, please refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CaffeineMC/sodium/wiki/Installation&#34;&gt;Installation Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;🐛 Reporting Issues&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can report bugs and crashes by opening an issue on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CaffeineMC/sodium/issues&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;. Before opening a new issue, use the search tool to make sure that your issue has not already been reported and ensure that you have completely filled out the issue template. Issues that are duplicates or do not contain the necessary information to triage and debug may be closed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that while the issue tracker is open to feature requests, development is primarily focused on improving hardware compatibility, performance, and finishing any unimplemented features necessary for parity with the vanilla renderer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;💬 Join the Community&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have an &lt;a href=&#34;https://caffeinemc.net/discord&#34;&gt;official Discord community&lt;/a&gt; for all of our projects. By joining, you can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get installation help and technical support for all of our mods&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get the latest updates about development and community events&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Talk with and collaborate with the rest of our team&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;... and just hang out with the rest of our community.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;✅ Hardware Compatibility&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We only provide support for graphics cards which have up-to-date drivers for OpenGL 4.6. Most graphics cards which have been released since year 2010 are supported, such as the...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AMD Radeon HD 7000 Series (GCN 1) or newer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NVIDIA GeForce 400 Series (Fermi) or newer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Intel HD Graphics 500 Series (Skylake) or newer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In some cases, older graphics cards may also work (so long as they have up-to-date drivers which have support for OpenGL 3.3), but they are not officially supported, and may not be compatible with future versions of Sodium.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;OpenGL Compatibility Layers&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Devices which need to use OpenGL translation layers (such as GL4ES, ANGLE, etc) are not supported and will very likely not work with Sodium. These translation layers do not implement required functionality and they suffer from underlying driver bugs which cannot be worked around.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🛠️ Developer Guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Building from sources&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sodium uses a typical Gradle project structure and can be compiled by simply running the default &lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt; task. The build artifacts (typical mod binaries, and their sources) can be found in the &lt;code&gt;build/libs&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We recommend using a package manager (such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdkman.io/&#34;&gt;SDKMAN&lt;/a&gt;) to manage toolchain dependencies and keep them up to date. For many Linux distributions, these dependencies will be standard packages in your software repositories.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OpenJDK 21 &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;We recommend using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoptium.net/&#34;&gt;Eclipse Temurin&lt;/a&gt; distribution, as it&#39;s known to be high quality and to work without issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Gradle 8.6.x (optional) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gradle.org/current/userguide/gradle_wrapper.html#sec:using_wrapper&#34;&gt;Gradle wrapper&lt;/a&gt; is provided in this repository can be used instead of installing a suitable version of Gradle yourself. However, if you are building many projects, you may prefer to install it yourself through a suitable package manager as to save disk space and to avoid many different Gradle daemons sitting around in memory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Typically, newer versions of Gradle will work without issues, but the build script is only tested against the version specified by the wrapper script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📜 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Except where otherwise stated (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CaffeineMC/sodium/dev/thirdparty/NOTICE.txt&#34;&gt;third-party license notices&lt;/a&gt;), the content of this repository is provided under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CaffeineMC/sodium/dev/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;Polyform Shield 1.0.0&lt;/a&gt; license by &lt;a href=&#34;https://jellysquid.me&#34;&gt;JellySquid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>