<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-12-23T01:32:19Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>etianl/Trouser-Streak</title>
    <updated>2024-12-23T01:32:19Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-12-23:/etianl/Trouser-Streak</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/etianl/Trouser-Streak" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A compilation of modules optimized for maximum grief. Featuring powerful mods &amp; exploits for Chunk Tracing, Base Hunting, and Griefing servers! A few modules were not originally written by me, but have been modified. Check the Github for credits and updates!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/etianl/Trouser-Streak/total.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Github All Releases&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trouser-Streak&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Griefing Utilities of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@mountainsoflavainc.6913&#34;&gt;Mountains of Lava Inc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trouser-Streak&lt;/strong&gt; is a compilation of modules for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://meteorclient.com/&#34;&gt;Meteor Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated to the latest version and optimized for maximum grief!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discord server for updates and help: &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/Az3G3p4ZCj&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/Az3G3p4ZCj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/etianl/Trouser-Streak/main/src/main/resources/assets/icon/icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;Trouser-Streak Logo&#34; width=&#34;28%&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few of these modules were not made by me!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits to the people I skidded from:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In no particular order&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DAMcraft/MeteorServerSeeker&#34;&gt;DAMcraft (ServerSeeker)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/meteordevelopment/meteor-client&#34;&gt;Meteor Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TaxEvasiqn/allah-hack&#34;&gt;Allah-Hack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AntiCope/meteor-rejects&#34;&gt;Meteor-Rejects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evaan/FrostBurn&#34;&gt;Frostburn Client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Bennooo/banana-for-everyone&#34;&gt;Banana&lt;/a&gt; Credits for checkbox array from AutoBuild, and the idea for TrouserBuild&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/B2H990/NUMA-117-Crafting-Dupe/&#34;&gt;1.17 Crafting Dupe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Thorioum&#34;&gt;Book And Quill Dupe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Saturn5Vfive/InstantKillBow&#34;&gt;InstantKillBow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Coderx-Gamer/lectern-crash&#34;&gt;LecternCrash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/etianl/&#34;&gt;etianl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;This modpack would not have been possible without you &lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;Features:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ActivatedSpawnerDetector&lt;/strong&gt; Detects if a player was ever near a spawner block. The intended use for this module would be on anarchy servers where people try to hide their items within chests in dungeons and mineshafts. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airstrike+:&lt;/strong&gt; Rains down whatever entities you desire. It used to only rain fireballs, and I also changed the positioning of the spawning. (Credits to Allah-Hack for the original)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AnHero:&lt;/strong&gt; Become An Hero! (A quick way back to spawn.) (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoCommand:&lt;/strong&gt; Automates a list of commands you set in it&#39;s options at the push of a button! Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaaasdfghjkllll&#34;&gt;aaaasdfghjkllll&lt;/a&gt;. I only added a full auto option because who doesn&#39;t love full auto?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoDisplays:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically spams block displays around all player&#39;s heads to blind them or text displays around them for trolling and advertising. Requires operator access. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoDrop:&lt;/strong&gt; Drops the stack in your selected slot automatically, or you can choose a slot to dump. You can shift click your inventory items to dump your trash easily. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoLavaCaster&lt;/strong&gt; Simple timer based bot for lavacasting. Aim at the top of the block you want to cast on and activate the module. It places lava, then after an amount of time removes the lava, places the water after a specified delay, removes it after a specified delay, it will build the mountain upward, tower you up and repeat. Position yourself on a block above and diagonally, mostly perpendicular from the targeted block for best results. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;AutoLavaCaster Notes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If not choosing the amount of time lava flows for, there are lava timing estimation modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The UseLastMountain timing mode uses your last Mountain to predict the LavaTimer and calculates the flow rate if the top of the mountain is a 45 degree angle and the rest is going straight down to the ground.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Do not disable AutoMountain before done building the mountain you want to cast on, it can break the timing for the above option. Pause by pressing useKey if you intend to make more stairs on that mountain.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The FortyFiveDegreeStairs timing mode estimates based on 45degree stairs down to sealevel(Y63), or down to Y-60 if you are below Y64.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The ChooseBottomY timing mode estimates time based on 45degree stairs going down to the Y level you set in the timer options from your position.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If you insist upon &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; starting AutoMountain paused, you can get the correct timing for the UseLastLowestBlockfromAutoMountain in AutoLavaCaster by 1: ENABLE ResetLowestBlockOnDEACTIVATE in AutoLavaCaster and 2: DISABLE ResetLowestBlockOnACTIVATE in AutoMountain. This will return the lowest block placed with AutoMountain until AutoLavacast is used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;You can reset lowestblock after doing the above by enabling and disabling AutoLavaCaster or by pressing the button in AutoMountain options.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The AutoPosition option moves you to automatically to a position suitable for casting if you are not on a block. May break caster if you enable it while right at the edge of a block. (Not actually on a block)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The .castertimer Command tells you how long each cycle has been running for.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The .lavacalc command gives you an approximation of how long lava will take to flow from top to bottom across a 45 degree staircase at 20TPS (input numbers), or the last Mountain you made from your Y level.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Do not use Timer with this module.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Rotating your character will break AutoLavaCaster. Disable rotate options in Freecam, Killaura, and any others that will rotate you when casting.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Fish buckets, and other water buckets with entities do not work. Put the fishy somewhere safe before mountaining.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If Build up is enabled, and not holding a block, appropriate blocks are selected from your hotbar automatically from left to right.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Autoreplenish is recommended if building up, but disable search hotbar option.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Do not use Flammable blocks if building up, and firespread is on.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Reducing timing options while it&#39;s on can break it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoMountain:&lt;/strong&gt; AutoMountain builds stairs in the direction you aim. It builds upward if you are looking toward the horizon or higher, and builds downward if you are looking down. (Credits to etianl :D)(Frostburn donated the framework and idea for the code, credits to them for that. &amp;lt;3)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The MountainMakerBot option builds stairs from bottom to top, and when it goes u it starts lavacasting on your staircase. Just click and wait for a mountain. Not intended for use in a closed in space (cave).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;AutoMountain Controls:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;UseKey (Right Click) starts and pauses mountain building.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Left and RightKeys turn Mountain building.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;ForwardKey Turns mountain up, Back Key turns mountain down.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;JumpKey adjusts spacing of stairs according to the OnDemandSpacing value.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Start building, then hold SneakKey and also hold Left or RightKey as well to build stairs diagonally. Release left or right key first to continue building in the direction you were prior.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoScoreboard:&lt;/strong&gt; Automates the creation of a custom scoreboard. Useful for advertising on griefed servers. Requires OP status. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaaasdfghjkllll&#34;&gt;aaaasdfghjkllll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoStaircase:&lt;/strong&gt; Builds stairs upward in the direction you are facing by running forward and jumping. (Credits to etianl for bringing it to life! As well as Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/majorsopa&#34;&gt;majorsopa&lt;/a&gt; for writing the original. &amp;lt;3) I just had to fix up some stuff for this one but Frostburn Client had the base code there. I believe this is the first publicly available automatic staircase builder in a Meteor addon, correct me if I&#39;m wrong maybe I didn&#39;t have to learn some Java to do this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoTitles:&lt;/strong&gt; Displays text (such as advertisements) across the screen of all the individuals who are online on a server at the time. Requires OP status. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Ogmur&#34;&gt;ogmur&lt;/a&gt; for figuring out these commands, and to etianl for writing a module for it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoVclipCommand&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically selects the nearest two block gap going either up or down to vclip into. (Credits to etianl, and credits to the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kittenvr/AutoVclip&#34;&gt;AutoVclip&lt;/a&gt; for minecraft 1.19.2 which inspired me to make this one. :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BaseFinder:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically detects if a Base or Build could be in a chunk by checking every block and entity in each chunk to see if there are &#34;Un-natural&#34; things within them. (Credits to etianl :D, and to Meteor-Rejects for some code from newchunks.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;BaseFinder Notes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The Blocks Lists have been tuned to reduce any false positives while throwing the maximum amount of &#34;good&#34; results for builds. Adjust if you feel you need to, or add/remove things as needed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The Number of Blocks to Find options is the total amount any of the blocks from one of the lists to find before throwing a base coord.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Do not do the same block in more than one list, it will be a waste of CPU time. The torches and signs in by default are fine because they are actually two different blocks, &#34;WALL_TORCH&#34; and just &#34;TORCH&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &#34;Unnatural Spawner Finder&#34; option locates spawners and if they do not have one of the blocks that spawners have around them in nature (Mossy Cobblestone, Stone Brick Stairs, Cobweb, Nether Brick Fence, and Chain), then flag the spawner as unnatural.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;.base command returns the nearest base to you&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;.base add or rmv will add or remove the location you are in as a base coord, or you can input X,Y after add/rmv (ex: .base add 69 420)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;.base rmv last will remove the last single base coordinate found. (Good for removing false positives)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;There are buttons in the options menu to do the same things as the commands listed above.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Base location data will be stored in the &#34;BaseChunks&#34; folder, in your Minecraft folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BetterAutoSign:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically writes signs with the text you specify, and can also apply glow ink or dye. Includes a &#34;Sign Aura&#34; option which rewrites all the signs around to the text of your choosing. Credits to Meteor-Tweaks for BetterAutoSign, and to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stever9487&#34;&gt;stever9487&lt;/a&gt; for the Sign Aura based off of Meteor Rejects&#39; Chest Aura&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BetterScaffold:&lt;/strong&gt; Give you more options for scaffolding, bigger range and others. (Credits to Meteor-Tweaks)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BlockListMineCommand:&lt;/strong&gt; Adds a custom #mine command to your message history containing all the blocks in the custom blocklist that are near you. Press T then up arrow, then ENTER key to execute the command. BETTER CHAT module is recommended for infinitely long commands. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BoatKill:&lt;/strong&gt; Kills passengers in a boat using funny packets. Is patched in Minecraft 1.21.2. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/not-filepile&#34;&gt;filepile&lt;/a&gt; for writing this and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Nxyi&#34;&gt;Nxyi&lt;/a&gt; for making it only kill the passenger!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book And Quill Dupe:&lt;/strong&gt; Overflows data in a book&#39;s title to cause dupes and chunk bans. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Thorioum&#34;&gt;Thorioum&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boom+:&lt;/strong&gt; Throws entities or spawns them on the targeted block when you click (Credits to Allah-Hack for the original) I just added more fun things you might want to throw as well as included the option for height based on player Y level.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BungeeSpoofer:&lt;/strong&gt; Allows you to join servers with an exposed bungeecord backend. (Credits to DAMcraft of ServerSeeker!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CrashCommand:&lt;/strong&gt; Crashes other players out using a nasty particle effect. Requires OP status. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaaasdfghjkllll&#34;&gt;aaaasdfghjkllll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ExplosionAura:&lt;/strong&gt; Spawns creepers at your position as you move that explode instantly. Like a bigger, more laggy Nuker module for creative mode. The use of the module Velocity is recommended to avoid being thrown around. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FlightAntikick:&lt;/strong&gt; Moves you down on a tick-based timer. Added in to substitute the lack of a &#34;Normal&#34; mode antikick for velocity flight in MeteorClient (not a great antikick it&#39;s just something). Bind it to the same key as Flight. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ForceOPBook:&lt;/strong&gt; Create malicious books in creative mode that can execute commands when clicked. Requires creative mode for you to make them, and requires you to give it to an operator and have them click it. (This is an old method, but credits to etianl for writing this implementation.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ForceOPSign:&lt;/strong&gt; Create malicious signs in creative mode that can execute commands when clicked. Requires creative mode for you to make them, and requires you to give it to an operator and have them place and click it while they are also in creative mode. The signs placed appear blank and commands executed may not appear in the server chat response for commands. There is a preset option for destroying the server in one click. Credits to CrushedPixel for their first implementation of a ForceOP sign module &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KofDNaPZWfg&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KofDNaPZWfg&lt;/a&gt;, and to etianl for writing this implementation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GarbageCleanerCommand:&lt;/strong&gt; Accessable by typing &#34;.cleanram&#34;. It cleans the RAM of useless junk and may be very handy for improving performance after chunk tracing for a while and can be used to clear other lag. (credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Ogmur&#34;&gt;ogmur&lt;/a&gt; for writing this)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HandOfGod:&lt;/strong&gt; Runs the &#34;/fill&#34; command on the world around you or around everyone else in different ways as you move around, and as you click. Destroy and modify the world with ease! Operator status required. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hole/Tunnel/StairsESP:&lt;/strong&gt; Detects 1x1 holes going straight down, horizontal tunnels of any height, and staircase tunnels. It by default ignores passable blocks such as torches or water but there is an option to have it only detect Air for holes and tunnels. (Thank you to Meteor Client for some code from TunnelESP, and credits to etianl for this version of it)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory Dupe (1.17):&lt;/strong&gt; Duplicates things in your crafting slots when the module is enabled and the Dupe button is pressed in your inventory. Only works on Minecraft servers on the version 1.17, not any version before or after.(Credit to ItsVen and Da0neDatGotAway for original creation of the dupe, and to B2H990 for making the fabric mod. Credits to etianl for porting to Meteor.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InstaKill:&lt;/strong&gt; Shoots arrows and tridents with incredible power and velocity. Enabling multiple buttons causes the amount of packets to add up. (Credits to Saturn5Vfive)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InstaMineNuker:&lt;/strong&gt; Sends packets to instantly mine the blocks around you until they are gone. There is an option in it to make it only target instamineable blocks such as crops, grass, slimeblocks, and more.. (Credits to etianl and to Meteor Client, as well as Meteor Rejects for some borrowed code)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;InstaSafetyBox:&lt;/strong&gt; Places a box around you for safety using the hardest blocks available in your hotbar. Also with adjustable range for thic box. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LavaAura:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically places and picks up lava buckets at an entity&#39;s position on a tick delay, or sets the entity on fire using flint and steel or fire charges. Also has the option of placing lavabuckets or fire on every block face which may be useful in creative mode. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LecternCrash:&lt;/strong&gt; Crash 1.18.X vanilla servers and possibly below. (Credits to Coderx-Gamer)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MaceKill:&lt;/strong&gt; Exploits Mace mechanics to make the Mace super OP everytime you swing it instead of just when you drop from a height. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NbtEditor:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires Creative mode. Generates custom entities in the form of a custom spawn egg, generate items with custom enchantments (Only in Minecraft 1.20.4 and below), and potions with custom effects all based on the settings you configure. It can also copy the Nbt data from one item to another. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NewerNewChunks:&lt;/strong&gt; NewChunks module with new newchunk estimation exploits, and the ability to save chunk data for later! Comes with several new homebrewed newchunks methods made by yours truly. (Credits to Meteor Rejects, and BleachHack from where it was ported, and etianl for updating :D.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NewerNewChunks Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;NEAR 100% accurate chunk detection in all dimensions!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;NewerNewChunks stores your NewChunks data as text files seperately per server and per dimension in the TrouserStreak/NewChunks folder in your Minecraft folder. This enables you to chunk trace multiple different servers and dimensions without mixing NewChunks data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If the game crashes, chunk data is saved! No loss in tracing progress.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Save and Load ChunkData options are for the stored files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;There is also an option for deleting chunk data in that particular dimension on the server.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The .newchunkcount command can tell you how many chunks have been saved in data in the dimension you are in.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;You can even send chunk data to your friends! Just copy the TrouserStreak/NewChunks folder and send it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;l33t new 3xpl0its:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palette Exploit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;PaletteExploit&lt;/strong&gt; option enabled by default detects new chunks by scanning the order of chunk section palettes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;PaletteExploit&lt;/strong&gt; highlights chunks that are being updated from an old version of minecraft as their own color.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;PaletteExploit&lt;/strong&gt; does not work in Minecraft servers where their version is less than 1.18. For those servers, disable &lt;strong&gt;PaletteExploit&lt;/strong&gt; and enable Liquid flow and BlockExploit.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;PaletteExploit&lt;/strong&gt; does not work in flat worlds that are entirely void.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Chunks appear to be defined as new until the person who generated them has unrendered them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The chunks that stay loaded due to the spawn chunk region always show up as new for some reason.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;In the Overworld dimension there are very rare false positives.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detection for Old Generation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Pre 1.17 Overworld OldChunk Detector&lt;/strong&gt; detects chunks in the Overworld that do not contain new 1.17 blocks above Y level 0. This should be used when the .world command returns &#34;This chunk is pre 1.17 generation!&#34; when run at spawn.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Pre 1.16 Nether OldChunk Detector&lt;/strong&gt; detects if Nether chunks are missing blocks found within the 1.16 Nether update.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;Pre 1.13 End OldChunk Detector&lt;/strong&gt; marks chunks as generated in an old version if they have the biome of minecraft:the_end.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;With the &lt;strong&gt;Pre 1.13 End OldChunk Detector&lt;/strong&gt; chunks that are old in the End just around the central end island are always marked as old because that biome is minecraft:the_end.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Default Color Descriptions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Red:&lt;/strong&gt; New chunk, never loaded before.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Green:&lt;/strong&gt; Old chunk, only loaded in 1.18 or after.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Yellow-Green:&lt;/strong&gt; Old Generation chunk, only loaded in 1.17 or before for OVERWORLD, 1.13 or before in END, or 1.15 or before in NETHER (defined by static means, the state does not change).&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Orange-Yellow:&lt;/strong&gt; Old chunk (1.17 or before) being currently updated to 1.18 or after (defined by dynamic means, the state does change if someone visits and leaves).\&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Detection Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;LiquidExploit&lt;/strong&gt; option estimates possible newchunks based on liquid being just starting to flow for the first time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;BlockUpdateExploit&lt;/strong&gt; option estimates possible newchunks based on block update packets. SOME OF THESE CHUNKS MAY BE OLD. Advanced Mode is needed to filter any false positives out. See Special Options notes for usage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;BlockUpdateExploit&lt;/strong&gt; option can produce false positives if you are hanging around in the same location for a while. It&#39;s best to keep moving for it to work best. &lt;em&gt;Modes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&#34;BlockExploitMode&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; will render BlockExploit chunks as their own color instead of a newchunk (Normal mode rendering).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;When using BlockExploitMode mode if the BlockUpdateExploit chunks appear infrequently and are combined with Old Chunks, then the chunks you are in are OLD. If there is alot of BlockUpdateExploit chunks appearing and/or they are mixed with NewChunks then the chunks are NEW.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&#34;IgnoreBlockExploit&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; will render BlockExploit chunks as an oldchunk instead of a newchunk.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;hr&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OnlinePlayerActivityDetector:&lt;/strong&gt; Detects if an online player is nearby if there are blocks missing from a BlockState palette and your render distances are overlapping. It can detect players that are outside of render distance. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPplayerTPmodule:&lt;/strong&gt; Uses operator commands to teleport you to each player online one by one at the push of a button, or those players to you one by one. There is a button in the options for it to reset the current player to zero. Thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Ogmur&#34;&gt;ogmur&lt;/a&gt; for the module suggestion (Credits to etianl for writing :D). REQUIRES OP STATUS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OPServerKillModule:&lt;/strong&gt; Runs a set of operator commands to disable a server and cover up the tracks of the kill command. REQUIRES OP STATUS (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PotESP:&lt;/strong&gt; Detects Decorated Pots with un-natural contents, and also tells you what item it is and the location of the pot. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RedstoneNuker:&lt;/strong&gt; It&#39;s just the regular Nuker module from Meteor client, customized for only breaking things that generate redstone signals. Also with included AutoTool. To keep you safer when placing lots of TNT. (Credits to Meteor Client for Nuker code, and AutoTool code inthere.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ShulkerDupe:&lt;/strong&gt; Duplicates the contents of a shulker when pressing &#34;Dupe&#34; or &#34;Dupe All&#34; in the shulker menu. Only works on Vanilla, Forge, and Fabric servers 1.19 and below. Use multiconnect or viafabric (Credits to Allah-Hack, I just brought back the buttons, and make it dupe slot1 as well.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;StorageLooter:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically steals the best stuff from storage containers according to itemlists and a list of values that are set for amounts of those items to take, and also puts junk items in there too. It either automatically opens the containers within reach and steals the stuff automatically, or steals the stuff automatically when you manually open the container. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SuperInstaMine:&lt;/strong&gt; This SuperInstaMine originated from the Meteor Rejects Instamine. I added an option called &#34;Break Modes (Range)&#34; which allows you to break more than one block at a time with SuperInstaMine. This option works best against easy-breaking blocks. The option adjusts the positioning and range of the block breaking. (Credits to Meteor Rejects for the original code.) &lt;strong&gt;ORIGINAL INSTAMINE FROM REJECTS CAN SOMETIMES WORK BETTER THAN THIS ONE, download meteor rejects for that!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teleport:&lt;/strong&gt; Sets your position ontop of targeted block, within a possible reach of 64 blocks. Rarely can cause damage, be careful. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERIMENTAL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TPFly:&lt;/strong&gt; It is a purely setPos based flight. PointAndFly mode is based off the ClickTP and AirPlace code, credits to Meteor for that. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXPERIMENTAL, movement is a little weird lol.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TrailMaker:&lt;/strong&gt; Leaves blocks behind you in a trail. Has a place delay option to spread placement further apart. Select the blocks you want to use in the block list setting for it to work. (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TrouserBlockESP:&lt;/strong&gt; A block esp module that uses chunk sections for block scanning. (Credits to etianl. :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TrouserBuild:&lt;/strong&gt; It can build either horizontally or vertically according to a 5x5 grid centered on the block you are aiming at. Right click to build at the targeted location. (Credits to etianl, and to Banana for the checkboxes and idea. :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ViewNbtCommand:&lt;/strong&gt; Returns the nbt data for the item in your hand in the chat box. There is also a Save option for the command that saves the data to a text file in your .minecraft folder in the &#34;SavedNBT&#34; folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voider+:&lt;/strong&gt; Replaces the world from the top down. (Credits to Allah-Hack) I added a 3x3 voiding script, a TP foward option for deleting strips, as well as options to set max and minimum height for voiding, and instead of just air it can do whatever block you want now too.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WorldInfoCommand&lt;/strong&gt; Type .world in chat to tell you some info about the server like world border coordinates and other things, and sometimes the players that have played there (players does not work on all servers). (Credits to etianl :D)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;Known Bugs:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoLavaCaster Bugs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The UseLastLowestBlockfromAutoMountain timing mode may not time correctly if AutoMountain is turned off before completing the mountain you want to cast on. Pause by pressing useKey if you intend to make more stairs on that mountain.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;The timing will break if the server is under 15TPS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If you are too far out of reach of the targeted block it breaks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If view of the targeted block is obstructed it breaks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If using AutoPosition and only slightly standing on a block (as far off the edge as you can get holdingshift) it will break.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AutoMountain Bugs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Some blocks may cause Automountain to attempt to build while not actually placing anything (Torches, walls, and doors did this until I fixed). If a block does not work please make an issue so I can correct it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Bugs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;NewerNewChunks can rarely boot you from the server when going back and forth through a nether portal. For example, it sometimes may boot you if you just came out of a portal then you re-enter it immediately after exiting.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;.newchunkcount command shows exactly the chunks that are saved in chunk data, so when you are in normal mode or flowbelowY0 mode the returned values are not exactly in correlation to what is rendered on screen.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;NewerNewChunks has to be turned on atleast once prior to running .newchunkcount for the counter to work even if you already have data in that world.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Joining a server with HandOfGod or Voider already on causes the module to be turned off due to &#34;Not being OP&#34; even if you are an operator&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;h2&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If you are using Minecraft version &lt;strong&gt;1.21.3&lt;/strong&gt;, then use the latest &lt;strong&gt;MeteorClient Dev Build of v0.5.9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;If you are using Minecraft version &lt;strong&gt;1.21.1&lt;/strong&gt;, then use &lt;strong&gt;MeteorClient &#34;Full Release&#34; v0.5.8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Please try &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FlorianMichael/ViaFabricPlus&#34;&gt;ViaFabricPlus&lt;/a&gt;, which will let you connect to almost any version from a new version client.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t forget to try updating any other mods you are using if your game is crashing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;plz give me star on githoob kthx&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>