<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-16T01:31:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HbmMods/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T01:31:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-16:/HbmMods/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HbmMods/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A flaming wreck of a minecraft mod about nuclear technology that is somehow still in development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;HBM&#39;s Nuclear Tech Mod for Minecraft 1.7.10&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://modrinth.com/mod/ntm&#34;&gt;NTM on Modrinth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://minecraft.curseforge.com/projects/hbms-nuclear-tech-mod?gameCategorySlug=mc-mods&amp;amp;projectID=235439&#34;&gt;NTM on CurseForge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nucleartech.wiki/wiki/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Official NTM Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hbmmods.github.io/&#34;&gt;Bobcat&#39;s Blog (the blag)&lt;/a&gt;, you can find lengthy yapping, upcoming features and some secrets here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is for 1.7.10!&lt;/strong&gt; For 1.12, check out these projects:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NTM Reloaded: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheOriginalGolem/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/TheOriginalGolem/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NTM Extended Edition (Alcater): &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Alcatergit/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/Alcatergit/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NTM WarFactory: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MisterNorwood/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MisterNorwood/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 1.18, try Martin&#39;s remake: &lt;a href=&#34;https://codeberg.org/MartinTheDragon/Nuclear-Tech-Mod-Remake/releases&#34;&gt;https://codeberg.org/MartinTheDragon/Nuclear-Tech-Mod-Remake/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Downloading pre-compiled versions from GitHub&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simply navigate to &#34;Releases&#34; on the right side of the page, download links for the compiled JAR as well as the corresponding source code are under the &#34;Assets&#34; category below the changelog. Make sure to review all changelogs when updating!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building from source&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tired of waiting until the next version comes out? Here is a tutorial on how to compile the very newest version yourself: Please note that these installation instructions are assuming you&#39;re running Microsoft Windows operating system. Linux users should know what to do by looking at the same guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have JDK8 installed. If not, download it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://adoptium.net/?variant=openjdk8&amp;amp;jvmVariant=hotspot&#34;&gt;adoptium.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you don&#39;t have git installed, download&amp;amp;install it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open up &#34;Git Bash&#34;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Press Windows Button, type &#34;Git Bash&#34; and press ENTER&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter the directory where you would like the sources to be (advanced users can use any directory)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    cd $HOME/Downloads&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the source code:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    git clone https://github.com/HbmMods/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter the source code directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    cd Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build the mod&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    ./gradlew build&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Locate the mod file. &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open up your file explorer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Navigate to the location where you downloaded the sources. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If you exactly followed step 1, it should be &lt;code&gt;C:/Users/%USER%/Downloads&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enter the downloaded source tree.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Navigate to &lt;code&gt;build/libs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Grab the &#34;HBM-NTM-&#xA;    &lt;version&gt;&#xA;     .jar&#34; one. &#xA;     &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;      &lt;li&gt;This is your mod file. You can install it like any other mod by putting it into your mods directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/version&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to make some changes to the mod, follow this guide:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow steps 1-2 from &lt;em&gt;Building from source&lt;/em&gt; section&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a directory where the repository will reside, using a name that is not &#34;Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the forge src from &lt;a href=&#34;https://files.minecraftforge.net/net/minecraftforge/forge/index_1.7.10.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and extract it into the directory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the source code:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Using Git Bash, enter wherever your directory is located:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    cd $HOME/Downloads&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the source code:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    git clone https://github.com/HbmMods/Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Move or copy every file within the new folder into your directory, making sure to overwrite any files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Feel free to delete the remaining folder and rename your directory (such as &#34;Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT&#34;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter the source directory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    cd Hbm-s-Nuclear-Tech-GIT&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup forge decompilation workspace&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    ./gradlew setupDecompWorkspace&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Necessary for Eclipse users&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Generate eclipse files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    ./gradlew eclipse&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Switch to the &lt;strong&gt;eclipse&lt;/strong&gt; folder inside your directory as a workspace.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If necessary, make sure that Eclipse is using the JDK8. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On Linux, enter Windows&amp;gt;Preferences&amp;gt;Java&amp;gt;Installed JREs. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Click search to navigate to /usr/lib/jvm and open it. Select the Java 8 JDK (e.g., java-8-openjdk).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Afterwards, enter Execution Environment, select JavaSE-1.8, and select the jre listed as a &lt;strong&gt;[perfect match]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On Windows, you may need to set your JAVA_HOME. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Search for Environment Variables and click Edit the System Environment Variables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Click Environment Variables. Click new under System Variables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Enter &lt;strong&gt;JAVA_HOME&lt;/strong&gt; under Variable Name and enter the path to your JDK 8 under Variable Value (e.g., C:\Program-Files\Java\jdk1.8.0_102).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;In Eclipse, now enter Windows&amp;gt;Preferences&amp;gt;Java&amp;gt;Installed JREs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Add Standard VM&lt;/strong&gt;; in the JRE home, navigate to the directory where the JDK is installed, then click finish and select it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Code!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing animations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Weapon animations in NTM are stored in JSON files, which are used alongside OBJ models to produce high quality animations with reasonable filesizes. Import/Export Blender addons are available for versions 2.79, 3.2, and 4.0 in &lt;code&gt;tools&lt;/code&gt;, and they should function reasonably well in newer versions as well. See the comments in the header of the export scripts for usage instructions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Compatibility notice&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NTM has certain behaviors intended to fix vanilla code or to increase compatibility in certain cases where it otherwise would not be possible. These behaviors have the potential of not playing well with other mods, and while no such cases are currently known, here&#39;s a list of them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Thermos&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thermos servers (along with its forks such as Crucible) have a &#34;performance&#34; feature that causes all tile entity ticking to slow down if there&#39;s no player present in the same chunk. For obvious reasons, this will heavily impact machines and cause phantom issues that, not having knowledge of this &#34;performance&#34; feature, are near impossible to diagnose. By default, NTM will crash on servers running the Thermos base code and print a lengthy message informing server owners about this &#34;performance&#34; feature as well as how to fix the issues it causes. The error message is printed in plain English on the top of the crash log, failure to read (as well as understand) it will leave the server inoperable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Shaders&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shaders (loaded by either Optifine, Iris or otherwise) will in all likelihood break when a gun is held. This is because guns need to skip vanilla&#39;s first person item setup for the rendering, however shaders apparently use the setup step for setting certain GL states, and skipping that will break rendering. &lt;a href=&#34;https://modrinth.com/mod/shader-fixer&#34;&gt;Shader Fixer&lt;/a&gt; is a mod with various fixes, among which is explicit compatibility for NTM&#39;s guns.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Optifine&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most common &#34;performance&#34; mods on 1.7.10, Optifine, achieves an increase in performance by breaking small things in spots that are usually hard to notice, although this can cause severe issues with NTM. A short list of problems, along with some solutions, follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Get rid of Optifine and use one of the many &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/makamys/7cb74cd71d93a4332d2891db2624e17c&#34;&gt;other, less intrusive performance mods&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks with connected textures may become invisible. This can be fixed by toggling triangulation (I do not know what or where this setting is, I just have been told that it exists and that it can fix the problem) or multicore chunk rendering (same here).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Entity &#34;optimization&#34; has a tendency to break chunkloading, this is especially noticeable with missiles which rely heavily on chunkloading to work, causing them to freeze mid-air. It&#39;s unclear what setting might fix this, and analysis of Optifine&#39;s source code (or rather, lack thereof) has not proven useful either.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Angelica&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In older versions, Angelica caused issues regarding model rendering, often times making 3D models transparent. Ever since the switch to VBOs, models work fine. Another issue was blocks with connected textures not rendering at all, but this too was fixed, meaning as of time of writing there are no major incompatibilities known with Angelica. However there a few minor issues that persist, but those can be fixed:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Often times when making a new world, all items appear as white squares. Somehow, scrolling though the NEI pages fixes this permanently&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reeds will render weirdly, this is an incompatibility with the &#34;Compact Vertex Format&#34; feature. Disabling it will make reeds look normal. Alternatively, reed rendering can be disabled by using &lt;code&gt;/ntmclient set RENDER_REEDS false&lt;/code&gt;, which works around the issue by not rendering the underwater portion of reeds at all.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Skybox chainloader&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NTM adds a few small things to the skybox using a custom skybox renderer. Minecraft can only have a single skybox renderer loaded, so setting the skybox to the NTM custom one would break compatibility with other mods&#39; skyboxes. To mend this, NTM employs a &lt;strong&gt;chainloader&lt;/strong&gt;. This chainloader will detect if a different skybox is loaded, save a reference to that skybox and then use NTM&#39;s skybox, which when used will also make sure to run the previous modded skybox renderer. In the event that NTM&#39;s skybox were to cause trouble, it can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.31_enableSkyboxes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Custom world provider&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A world provider is a piece of code that minecraft can load to determine certain aspects of how the world should be handled, like light levels, sky color, day/night cycle, etc. In order for the Tom impact effects to work, NTM employs such a world provider, although this is known to cause issues with Hardcore Darkness. The world provider can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.32_enableImpactWorldProvider&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Stat re-registering&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An often overlooked aspect of Minecraft is its stats, the game keeps track of how many of an item were crafted, placed, broken, etc. By default, Minecraft can only handle vanilla items, modded items would not show up in the stats window. Forge does little to fix this, and since NTM has to keep track of certain things (such as the use of an acidizer for spawning Mask Man) it will run its own code which re-registers all stats for all modded items. In the event that re-registering causes issues, or another mod already does this better already, this behavior can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.33_enableStatReRegistering&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Keybind overlap&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An often annoying aspect of modded Minecraft is its keybinds. Even though multiple binds can be assigned the same key, all but one will show up as &#34;conflicting&#34; and only the non-conflicting one will work. Which one this is is usually arbitrary, and there is no reason to have such limitation. Often times keybinds are only applicable in certain scenarios, and a commonly found degree of overlap is within reason. Therefore, NTM will run its own key handling code which allows conflicting keybinds to work. If there should be any issues with this behavior, it can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.34_enableKeybindOverlap&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Render distance capping&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a common crash caused by Minecraft&#39;s render distance slider going out of bounds, this usually happens when uninstalling a mod that extends the render distance (like Optifine) or when downgrading the Minecraft version (newer versions have higher render distance caps). To prevent crashes, the mod will attempt to decrease the render distance if it&#39;s above 16 unless Optifine is installed. If this behavior is not desired (for example, because another mod that allows higher render distance is being used), it can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.25_enableRenderDistCheck&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Log spam caused by ComparableStack&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In some modpacks (exact mods needed to replicate this are unknown), it&#39;s possible that invalid registered items may cause problems for NEI handlers. To prevent crashes, the ComparableStack class used to represent stacks will default to a safe registered item, and print a log message. In certain situations, this may cause dozens of errors to be printed at once, potentially even lagging the game. If that happens, the log message (but not the error handling) can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.28_enableSilentCompStackErrors&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sound system limit&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, the sound system only allows a limited amount of sounds to run at once (28 regular sounds and 4 streaming sounds), this causes issues when there&#39;s many machines running at once, since their looped sounds will constantly interrupt each other, causing them to immediately restart, which in some isolated cases has proven to cause massive lagspikes. To prevent this, NTM will increase the sound limit to 1000 regular sounds and 50 streaming sounds, this can be disabled with the config option &lt;code&gt;1.39_enableSoundExtension&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is licensed under the GNU Lesser General Public License version 3. In short: This software is free, you may run the software freely, create modified versions, distribute this software and distribute modified versions, as long as the modified software too has a free software license (with an exception for linking to this software, as stated by the &#34;Lesser&#34; part of the LGPL, where this may not be required). You win this round, Stallman. The full license can be found in the &lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;LICENSE.LESSER&lt;/code&gt; files.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>