<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-23T01:35:41Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>InterviewReady/Concurrency-Tester</title>
    <updated>2024-04-23T01:35:41Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-23:/InterviewReady/Concurrency-Tester</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/InterviewReady/Concurrency-Tester" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A tester that checks for correctness of code in distributed systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Concurrent Cache Testing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project introduces a comprehensive testing framework designed to evaluate the performance of different Least Recently Used (LRU) cache implementations integrated with a simulated database environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The framework tests under various configurations and scenarios to benchmark the efficiency, reliability, and scalability of cache strategies within concurrent systems.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sample configuration of an LRU cache is available. It includes features such as request collapsing and various threading models to simulate different real-world usage scenarios.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How It Works&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The testing framework operates by executing the following steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generate Requests&lt;/strong&gt;: Different patterns of requests are generated to simulate varied user interaction patterns with the cache.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organize Requests&lt;/strong&gt;: Requests are organized according to specified strategies to test the cache&#39;s response to different access patterns.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simulate Cache Operation&lt;/strong&gt;: Each cache configuration is tested with the organized requests. The cache interacts with the simulated database, handling GET and SET operations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measure Performance&lt;/strong&gt;: After executing the tests, the system reports various metrics which detail the effectiveness and efficiency of the cache configuration under test.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What You Get Out of It&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Understand &lt;strong&gt;performance impacts&lt;/strong&gt; of different cache configurations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Diagnose potential scalability and &lt;strong&gt;reliability issues&lt;/strong&gt; in cache implementations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How to Run&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just run the main program in &lt;em&gt;CacheTester&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>