<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-13T01:35:38Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T01:35:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-13:/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;NOTICE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the public FTC SDK for the Freight Frenzy (2021-2022) competition season.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This GitHub repository contains the source code that is used to build an Android app to control a &lt;em&gt;FIRST&lt;/em&gt; Tech Challenge competition robot. To use this SDK, download/clone the entire project to your local computer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are new to robotics or new to the &lt;em&gt;FIRST&lt;/em&gt; Tech Challenge, then you should consider reviewing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/Blocks-Tutorial&#34;&gt;FTC Blocks Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to get familiar with how to use the control system:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/Blocks-Tutorial&#34;&gt;FTC Blocks Online Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even if you are an advanced Java programmer, it is helpful to start with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/Blocks-Tutorial&#34;&gt;FTC Blocks tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, and then migrate to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/OnBot-Java-Tutorial&#34;&gt;OnBot Java Tool&lt;/a&gt; or to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/Android-Studio-Tutorial&#34;&gt;Android Studio&lt;/a&gt; afterwards.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Downloading the Project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are an Android Studio programmer, there are several ways to download this repo. Note that if you use the Blocks or OnBot Java Tool to program your robot, then you do not need to download this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a git user, you can clone the most current version of the repository:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;git clone https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController.git&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Or, if you prefer, you can use the &#34;Download Zip&#34; button available through the main repository page. Downloading the project as a .ZIP file will keep the size of the download manageable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can also download the project folder (as a .zip or .tar.gz archive file) from the Downloads subsection of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; page for this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Releases page also contains prebuilt APKs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have downloaded and uncompressed (if needed) your folder, you can use Android Studio to import the folder (&#34;Import project (Eclipse ADT, Gradle, etc.)&#34;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;User Documentation and Tutorials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIRST&lt;/em&gt; maintains online documentation with information and tutorials on how to use the &lt;em&gt;FIRST&lt;/em&gt; Tech Challenge software and robot control system. You can access this documentation using the following link:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki&#34;&gt;FtcRobotController Online Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the online documentation is an &#34;evergreen&#34; document that is constantly being updated and edited. It contains the most current information about the &lt;em&gt;FIRST&lt;/em&gt; Tech Challenge software and control system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Javadoc Reference Material&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Javadoc reference documentation for the FTC SDK is now available online. Click on the following link to view the FTC SDK Javadoc documentation as a live website:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://javadoc.io/doc/org.firstinspires.ftc&#34;&gt;FTC Javadoc Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Online User Forum&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For technical questions regarding the Control System or the FTC SDK, please visit the FTC Technology forum:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ftcforum.firstinspires.org/forum/ftc-technology&#34;&gt;FTC Technology Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sample OpModes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project contains a large selection of Sample OpModes (robot code examples) which can be cut and pasted into your /teamcode folder to be used as-is, or modified to suit your team&#39;s needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samples Folder: &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/master/FtcRobotController/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/robotcontroller/external/samples&#34;&gt;/FtcRobotController/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/robotcontroller/external/samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The readme.md file located in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/master/TeamCode/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/teamcode&#34;&gt;/TeamCode/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/teamcode&lt;/a&gt; folder contains an explanation of the sample naming convention, and instructions on how to copy them to your own project space.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Release Information&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 7.2 (20220723-130006)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updates the build tooling. For Android Studio users, this change requires Android Studio Chipmunk 2021.2.1.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes support for devices that are not competition legal, including Modern Robotics Core Control Modules, the Matrix Controller, and HiTechnic/NXT controllers and sensors. Support remains for Modern Robotics I2C sensors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Increases the height of the 3-dots Landscape menu touch area on the Driver Station, making it much easier to select.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds &lt;code&gt;terminateOpModeNow()&lt;/code&gt; method to allow OpModes to cleanly self-exit immediately.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds &lt;code&gt;opModeInInit()&lt;/code&gt; method to &lt;code&gt;LinearOpMode&lt;/code&gt; to facilitate init-loops. Similar to &lt;code&gt;opModeIsActive()&lt;/code&gt; but for the init phase.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Warns user if they have a Logitech F310 gamepad connected that is set to DirectInput mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows SPARKmini motor controllers to react more quickly to speed changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hides the version number of incorrectly installed sister app (i.e. DS installed on RC device or vice-versa) on inspection screen.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for allowing the user to edit the comment for the runOpMode block.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds parameterDefaultValues field to @ExportToBlocks. This provides the ability for a java method with an @ExportToBlocks annotation to specify default values for method parameters when it is shown in the block editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make LinearOpMode blocks more readable. The opmode name is displayed on the runOpMode block, but not on the other LinearOpMode blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added support to TensorFlow Object Detection for using a different frame generator, instead of Vuforia. Using Vuforia to pass the camera frame to TFOD is still supported.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes usage of Renderscript.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes logspam on app startup of repeated stacktraces relating to &lt;code&gt;&#34;Failed resolution of: Landroid/net/wifi/p2p/WifiP2pManager$DeviceInfoListener&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows disabling bluetooth radio from inspection screen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves warning messages when I2C devices are not responding&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for controlling the RGB LED present on PS4/Etpark gamepads from OpModes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes legacy Pushbot references from OpMode samples. Renames &#34;Pushbot&#34; samples to &#34;Robot&#34;. Motor directions reversed to be compatible with &#34;direct Drive&#34; drive train.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/316&#34;&gt;issue #316&lt;/a&gt; (MatrixF.inverted() returned an incorrectly-sized matrix for 1x1 and 2x2 matrixes).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Self inspect now allows for Driver Station and Robot Controller compatibility between point releases.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where if the same &lt;code&gt;RumbleEffect&lt;/code&gt; object instance was queued for multiple gamepads, it could happen that both rumble commands would be sent to just one gamepad.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug in Driver Station where on the Driver Hub, if Advanced Gamepad Features was disabled and an officially supported gamepad was connected, then opening the Advanced Gamepad Features or Gamepad Type Overrides screens would cause the gamepad to be rebound by the custom USB driver even though advanced gamepad features was disabled.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Protects against (unlikely) null pointer exception in Vuforia Localizer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Harden OnBotJava and Blocks saves to protect against save issues when disconnecting from Program and Manage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where the RC app would hang if a REV Hub I2C write failed because the previous I2C operation was still in progress. This hang most commonly occurred during REV 2M Distance Sensor initialization&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes ConceptWebcam.java sample program. This sample is not compatible with OnBotJava.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where using html tags in an @ExportToBlocks comment field prevented the blocks editor from loading.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes blocks editor so it doesn&#39;t ask you to save when you haven&#39;t modified anything.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes uploading a very large blocks project to offline blocks editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug that caused blocks for DcMotorEx to be omitted from the blocks editor toolbox.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftcforum.firstinspires.org/forum/ftc-technology/blocks-programming/87035-blocks-programs-stripped-of-blocks&#34;&gt;Blocks Programs Stripped of Blocks (due to using TensorFlow Label block)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 7.1 (20211223-120805)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes crash when calling &lt;code&gt;isPwmEnabled()&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/233&#34;&gt;issue #223&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes lint error (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/4&#34;&gt;issue #4&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes Driver Station crash when attempting to use DualShock4 v1 gamepad with Advanced Gamepad Features enabled (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/173&#34;&gt;issue #173&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes possible (but unlikely) Driver Station crash when connecting gamepads of any type.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where Driver Station would use generic 20% deadzone for Xbox360 and Logitech F310 gamepads when Advanced Gamepad Features was disabled.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added SimpleOmniDrive sample OpMode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds UVC white balance control API.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/259&#34;&gt;issue #259&lt;/a&gt; Most blocks samples for TensorFlow can&#39;t be used for a different model. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The blocks previously labeled TensorFlowObjectDetectionFreightFrenzy (from the subcategory named &#34;Optimized for Freight Frenzy&#34;) and TensorFlowObjectDetectionCustomModel (from the subcategory named &#34;Custom Model&#34;) have been replaced with blocks labeled TensorFlowObjectDetection. Blocks in existing opmodes will be automatically updated to the new blocks when opened in the blocks editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/260&#34;&gt;issue #260&lt;/a&gt; Blocks can&#39;t call java method that has a VuforiaLocalizer parameter. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Blocks now has a block labeled VuforiaFreightFrenzy.getVuforiaLocalizer for this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added a page to manage the TensorFlow Lite models in /sdcard/FIRST/tflitemodels. To get to the TFLite Models page: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can click on the link at the bottom of the the Manage page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can click on the link at the upper-right the Blocks project page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes logspam when &lt;code&gt;isBusy()&lt;/code&gt; is called on a motor not in RTP mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hides the &#34;RC Password&#34; item on the inspection screen for phone-based Robot Controllers. (It is only applicable for Control Hubs).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds channel 165 to Wi-Fi Direct channel selection menu in the settings screen. (165 was previously available through the web UI, but not locally in the app).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 7.0 (20210915-141025)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements and New Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for external libraries to OnBotJava and Blocks. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Upload .jar and .aar files in OnBotJava. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Known limitation - RobotController device must be running Android 7.0 or greater.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Known limitation - .aar files with assets are not supported.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries can provide support for hardware devices by using the annotation in the com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries can include .so files for native code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries can be used from OnBotJava op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries that use the following annotations can be used from Blocks op modes. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.robotcore.external.ExportClassToBlocks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.robotcore.external.ExportToBlocks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries that use the following annotations can add new hardware devices: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.AnalogSensorType&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.DeviceProperties&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.DigitalIoDeviceType&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.I2cDeviceType&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.MotorType&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;com.qualcomm.robotcore.hardware.configuration.annotations.ServoType&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;External libraries that use the following annotations can add new functionality to the Robot Controller: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.ftccommon.external.OnCreate&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.ftccommon.external.OnCreateEventLoop&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.ftccommon.external.OnCreateMenu&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.ftccommon.external.OnDestroy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;org.firstinspires.ftc.ftccommon.external.WebHandlerRegistrar&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for REV Robotics Driver Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds fully custom userspace USB gamepad driver to Driver Station (see &#34;Advanced Gamepad Features&#34; menu in DS settings). &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Allows gamepads to work on devices without native Linux kernel support (e.g. some Romanian Motorola devices).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Allows the DS to read the unique serial number of each gamepad, enabling auto-recovery of dropped gamepads even if two gamepads of the same model drop. &lt;em&gt;(NOTE: unfortunately this does not apply to Etpark gamepads, because they do not have a unique serial)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Reading the unique serial number also provides the ability to configure the DS to assign gamepads to a certain position by default (so no need to do start+a/b at all).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The LED ring on the Xbox360 gamepad and the RGB LED bar on the PS4 gamepad is used to indicate the driver position the gamepad is bound to.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The rumble motors on the Xbox360, PS4, and Etpark gamepads can be controlled from OpModes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The 2-point touchpad on the PS4 gamepad can be read from OpModes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The &#34;back&#34; and &#34;guide&#34; buttons on the gamepad can now be safely bound to robot controls (Previously, on many devices, Android would intercept these buttons as home button presses and close the app).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Advanced Gamepad features are enabled by default, but may be disabled through the settings menu in order to revert to gamepad support provided natively by Android.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves accuracy of ping measurement. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where the ping time showed as being higher than reality when initially connecting to or restarting the robot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To see the full improvement, you must update both the Robot Controller and Driver Station apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updates samples located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/master/FtcRobotController/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/robotcontroller/external/samples&#34;&gt;/FtcRobotController/src/main/java/org/firstinspires/ftc/robotcontroller/external/samples&lt;/a&gt;. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added ConceptGamepadRumble and ConceptGamepadTouchpad samples to illustrate the use of these new gampad capabilities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Condensed existing Vuforia samples into just 2 samples (ConceptVuforiaFieldNavigation &amp;amp; ConceptVuforiaFieldNavigationWebcam) showing how to determine the robot&#39;s location on the field using Vuforia. These both use the current season&#39;s Target images.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added ConceptVuforiaDriveToTargetWebcam to illustrate an easy way to drive directly to any visible Vuforia target.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes many improvements to the warning system and individual warnings. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Warnings are now much more spaced out, so that they are easier to read.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New warnings were added for conditions that should be resolved before competing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The mismatched apps warning now uses the major and minor app versions, not the version code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The warnings are automatically re-enabled when a Robot Controller app from a new FTC season is installed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for I2C transactions on the Expansion Hub / Control Hub without specifying a register address. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;See section 3 of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ti.com/lit/an/slva704/slva704.pdf&#34;&gt;TI I2C spec&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Calling these new methods when using Modern Robotics hardware will result in an UnsupportedOperationException.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes VuforiaLocalizer &lt;code&gt;close()&lt;/code&gt; method to be public.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for TensorFlow v2 object detection models.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reduces ambiguity of the Self Inspect language and graphics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OnBotJava now warns about potentially unintended file overwrites.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves behavior of the Wi-Fi band and channel selector on the Manage webpage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes Robot Controller app crash on Android 9+ when a Driver Station connects.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where an Op Mode was responsible for calling shutdown on the TensorFlow TFObjectDetector. Now this is done automatically.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes Vuforia initialization blocks to allow user to chose AxesOrder. Updated relevant blocks sample opmodes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/114&#34;&gt;FtcRobotController issue #114&lt;/a&gt; LED blocks and Java class do not work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes match logging for Op Modes that contain special characters in their names.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes Driver Station OpMode controls becoming unresponsive if the Driver Station was set to the landscape layout and an OnBotJava build was triggered while an OpMode was running.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes the Driver Station app closing itself when it is switched away from, or the screen is turned off.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &#34;black swirl of doom&#34; (Infinite &#34;configuring Wi-Fi Direct&#34; message) on older devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updates the wiki comment on the OnBotJava intro page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 6.2 (20210218-074821)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Attempts to automatically fix the condition where a Control Hub&#39;s internal Expansion Hub is not working by re-flashing its firmware&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes various improvements to the Wi-Fi Direct pairing screen, especially in landscape mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes the Robot Controller service no longer be categorically restarted when the main activity is brought to foreground &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;(e.g. the service is no longer restarted simply by viewing the Self Inspect screen and pressing the back button)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It is still restarted if the Settings menu or Configure Robot menu is opened&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/71&#34;&gt;FtcRobotController issue #71&lt;/a&gt; Cannot open OpModes in v6.1 Blocks offline editor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/issues/79&#34;&gt;FtcRobotController issue #79&lt;/a&gt; 6.1 causes a soft reboot on the Motorola E5 Play&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where the Control Hub OS&#39;s watchdog would restart the Robot Controller app if the Control Hub was not able to communicate with its internal Expansion Hub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes certain I2C devices not showing up in the appropriate &lt;code&gt;HardwareMap&lt;/code&gt; fields (such as &lt;code&gt;hardwareMap.colorSensor&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where performing a Wi-Fi factory reset on the Control Hub would not set the Wi-Fi band to 2.4 GHz&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where OnBotJava might fail to create a new file if the option to &#34;Setup Code for Configured Hardware&#34; was selected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where performing certain operations after an Op Mode crashes would temporarily break Control/Expansion Hub communication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where a Control Hub with a configured USB-connected Expansion Hub would not work if the Expansion Hub was missing at startup&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes potential issues caused by having mismatched Control/Expansion Hub firmware versions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/673&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue 673&lt;/a&gt; Latest matchlog is being deleted instead of old ones by RobotLog&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes ConceptVuforiaUltimateGoalNavigationWebcam sample opmode by correctly orienting camera on robot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where logcat would be spammed with InterruptedExceptions when stop is requested from the Driver Station (this behavior was accidentally introduced in v5.3). This change has no impact on functionality.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where the blocks editor fails to load if the name of any TeleOp opmode contains an apostrophe.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 6.1 (20201209-113742)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes the scan button on the configuration screen update the list of Expansion Hubs connected via RS-485 &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/143&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #143&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves web interface compatibility with older browser and Android System WebView versions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue in UVC driver where some cameras (e.g. certain MS Lifecams) which reported frame intervals as rounded rather than truncated values (e.g. &lt;code&gt;666667*100ns&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;666666*100ns&lt;/code&gt; for 15FPS) would fail to start streaming.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support in UVC driver for virtual PTZ control&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support in UVC driver for gain (ISO) control&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support in UVC driver for enabling/disable AE priority. This setting provides a means to tell the camera firmware either &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A) It can undershoot the requested frame rate in order to provide a theoretically better image (i.e. with a longer exposure than the inter-frame period of the selected frame rate allows)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;B) It &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; meet the inter-frame deadline for the selected frame rate, even if the image may be underexposed as a result&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for the Control Hub OS 1.1.2 Robot Controller watchdog &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Robot Controller app will be restarted if it stops responding for more than 10 seconds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for using the Driver Station app on Android 10+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduces an automatic TeleOp preselection feature &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For details and usage guide, please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/FtcRobotController/wiki/Automatically-Loading-a-Driver-Controlled-Op-Mode&#34;&gt;this wiki entry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shows icon next to OpMode name in the OpMode list dropdown on the Driver Station to indicate the source of the OpMode (i.e. the programming tool used to create it)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where the Driver Station app would exit after displaying the Configuring Wi-Fi Direct screen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes Blocks and OnBotJava prompts when accessed via the REV Hardware Client&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 6.0 (20200921-085816)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Important Notes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 6.0 is the version for the Ultimate Goal season.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Requires Android Studio 4.0.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android Studio users need to be connected to the Internet the first time they build the app (in order to download needed packages for the build).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 5.5 was a moderately large off-season, August 2020, drop. It&#39;s worth reviewing those release notes below also.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 5.5 and greater will not work on older Android 4.x and 5.x phones. Users must upgrade to an approved Android 6.x device or newer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The default PIDF values for REV motors have been reverted to the default PID values that were used in the 2018-2019 season &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This change was made because the 2018-2019 values turned out to work better for many mechanisms&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This brings the behavior of the REV motors in line with the behavior of all other motors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you prefer the 2019-2020 season&#39;s behavior for REV motors, here are the PIDF values that were in place, so that you can manually set them in your OpModes: &lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;HD Hex motors (all gearboxes):&lt;/strong&gt; Velocity PIDF values: &lt;code&gt;P = 1.17&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;I = 0.117&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;F = 11.7&lt;/code&gt; Position PIDF values: &lt;code&gt;P = 5.0&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Core Hex motor:&lt;/strong&gt; Velocity PIDF values: &lt;code&gt;P = 4.96&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;I = 0.496&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;F = 49.6&lt;/code&gt; Position PIDF values: &lt;code&gt;P = 5.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;New features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes TensorFlow inference model and sample op modes to detect Ultimate Goal Starter Stacks (four rings vs single ring stack).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes Vuforia Ultimate Goal vision targets and sample op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduces a digital zoom feature for TensorFlow object detection (to detect objects more accurately at greater distances).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds configuration entry for the REV UltraPlanetary HD Hex motor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds setGain() and getGain() methods to the NormalizedColorSensor interface &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;By setting the gain of a color sensor, you can adjust for different lighting conditions. For example, if you detect lower color values than expected, you can increase the gain.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The gain value is only applied to the argb() and getNormalizedColors() methods, not to the raw color methods. The getNormalizedColors() method is recommended for ease-of-use and clarity, since argb() has to be converted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Updates SensorColor Java sample to demonstrate gain usage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Merges SensorREVColorDistance Java sample into SensorColor Java sample, which showcases best practices for all color sensors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves retrieving values from the REV Color Sensor V3 &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Updates the normalization calculation of the RGB channels&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Improves the calculation of the alpha channel (can be used as an overall brightness indicator)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes the default sensor resolution, which caused issues with bright environments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Adds support for changing the resolution and measuring rate of the Broadcom sensor chip&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Removes IR readings and calculations not meant for the Broadcom sensor chip&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves reliability of BNO055IMU IMU initialization to prevent random initialization failures (which manifested as &lt;code&gt;Problem with &#39;imu&#39;&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.5 (20200824-090813)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 5.5 requires Android Studio 4.0 or later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;New features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for calling custom Java classes from Blocks OpModes (fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/161&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #161&lt;/a&gt;). &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Classes must be in the org.firstinspires.ftc.teamcode package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To have easy access to the opMode, hardwareMap, telemetry, gamepad1, and gamepad2, classes can extends org.firstinspires.ftc.robotcore.external.BlocksOpModeCompanion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Methods must be public static and have no more than 21 parameters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Methods must be annotated with org.firstinspires.ftc.robotcore.external.ExportToBlocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Parameters declared as OpMode, LinearOpMode, Telemetry, and HardwareMap are supported and the argument is provided automatically, regardless of the order of the parameters. On the block, the sockets for those parameters are automatically filled in.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Parameters declared as char or java.lang.Character will accept any block that returns text and will only use the first character in the text.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Parameters declared as boolean or java.lang.Boolean will accept any block that returns boolean.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Parameters declared as byte, java.lang.Byte, short, java.lang.Short, int, java.lang.Integer, long, or java.lang.Long, will accept any block that returns a number and will round that value to the nearest whole number.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Parameters declared as float, java.lang.Float, double, java.lang.Double will accept any block that returns a number.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds telemetry API method for setting display format &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Classic&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Monospace&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;HTML (certain tags only)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds blocks support for switching cameras.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds Blocks support for TensorFlow Object Detection with a custom model.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for uploading a custom TensorFlow Object Detection model in the Manage page, which is especially useful for Blocks and OnBotJava users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shows new Control Hub blink codes when the Wi-Fi band is switched using the Control Hub&#39;s button (only possible on Control Hub OS 1.1.2)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds new warnings which can be disabled in the Advanced RC Settings &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Mismatched app versions warning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Unnecessary 2.4 GHz Wi-Fi usage warning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV Hub is running outdated firmware (older than version 1.8.2)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for Sony PS4 gamepad, and reworks how gamepads work on the Driver Station &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Removes preference which sets gamepad type based on driver position. Replaced with menu which allows specifying type for gamepads with unknown VID and PID&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Attempts to auto-detect gamepad type based on USB VID and PID&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If gamepad VID and PID is not known, use type specified by user for that VID and PID&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If gamepad VID and PID is not known AND the user has not specified a type for that VID and PID, an educated guess is made about how to map the gamepad&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Driver Station will now attempt to automatically recover from a gamepad disconnecting, and re-assign it to the position it was assigned to when it dropped &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If only one gamepad is assigned and it drops: it can be recovered&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If two gamepads are assigned, and have &lt;strong&gt;different&lt;/strong&gt; VID/PID signatures, and only one drops: it will be recovered&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If two gamepads are assigned, and have &lt;strong&gt;different&lt;/strong&gt; VID/PID signatures, and BOTH drop: both will be recovered&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If two gamepads are assigned, and have &lt;strong&gt;the same&lt;/strong&gt; VID/PID signatures, and only one drops: it will be recovered&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If two gamepads are assigned, and have &lt;strong&gt;the same&lt;/strong&gt; VID/PID signatures, and BOTH drop: &lt;strong&gt;neither&lt;/strong&gt; will be recovered, because of the ambiguity of the gamepads when they re-appear on the USB bus.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There is currently one known edge case: if there are &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; gamepads with &lt;strong&gt;the same&lt;/strong&gt; VID/PID signature plugged in, &lt;strong&gt;but only one is assigned&lt;/strong&gt;, and they BOTH drop, it&#39;s a 50-50 chance of which one will be chosen for automatic recovery to the assigned position: it is determined by whichever one is re-enumerated first by the USB bus controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds landscape user interface to Driver Station &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New feature: practice timer with audio cues&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New feature (Control Hub only): wireless network connection strength indicator (0-5 bars)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New feature (Control Hub only): tapping on the ping/channel display will switch to an alternate display showing radio RX dBm and link speed (tap again to switch back)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The layout will NOT autorotate. You can switch the layout from the Driver Station&#39;s settings menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes support for Android versions 4.4 through 5.1 (KitKat and Lollipop). The minSdkVersion is now 23.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes the deprecated &lt;code&gt;LinearOpMode&lt;/code&gt; methods &lt;code&gt;waitOneFullHardwareCycle()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;waitForNextHardwareCycle()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Handles RS485 address of Control Hub automatically &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Control Hub is automatically given a reserved address&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Existing configuration files will continue to work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;All addresses in the range of 1-10 are still available for Expansion Hubs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Control Hub light will now normally be solid green, without blinking to indicate the address&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Control Hub will not be shown on the Expansion Hub Address Change settings page&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves REV Hub firmware updater &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The user can now choose between all available firmware update files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Version 1.8.2 of the REV Hub firmware is bundled into the Robot Controller app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Text was added to clarify that Expansion Hubs can only be updated via USB.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Firmware update speed was reduced to improve reliability&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Allows REV Hub firmware to be updated directly from the Manage webpage&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves log viewer on Robot Controller &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Horizontal scrolling support (no longer word wrapped)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supports pinch-to-zoom&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Uses a monospaced font&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Error messages are highlighted&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New color scheme&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Attempts to force-stop a runaway/stuck OpMode without restarting the entire app &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Not all types of runaway conditions are stoppable, but if the user code attempts to talk to hardware during the runaway, the system should be able to capture it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes various tweaks to the Self Inspect screen &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Renames &#34;OS version&#34; entry to &#34;Android version&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Renames &#34;Wi-Fi Direct Name&#34; to &#34;Wi-Fi Name&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Adds Control Hub OS version, when viewing the report of a Control Hub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hides the airplane mode entry, when viewing the report of a Control Hub&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Removes check for ZTE Speed Channel Changer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shows firmware version for &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; Expansion and Control Hubs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reworks network settings portion of Manage page &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;All network settings are now applied with a single click&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Wi-Fi Direct channel of phone-based Robot Controllers can now be changed from the Manage page&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Wi-Fi channels are filtered by band (2.4 vs 5 GHz) and whether they overlap with other channels&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The current Wi-Fi channel is pre-selected on phone-based Robot Controllers, and Control Hubs running OS 1.1.2 or later.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On Control Hubs running OS 1.1.2 or later, you can choose to have the system automatically select a channel on the 5 GHz band&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves OnBotJava &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;New light and dark themes replace the old themes (chaos, github, chrome,...) &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;the new default theme is &lt;code&gt;light&lt;/code&gt; and will be used when you first update to this version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;OnBotJava now has a tabbed editor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Read-only offline mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves function of &#34;exit&#34; menu item on Robot Controller and Driver Station &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Now guaranteed to be fully stopped and unloaded from memory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Shows a warning message if a LinearOpMode exists prematurely due to failure to monitor for the start condition&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves error message shown when the Driver Station and Robot Controller are incompatible with each other&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Driver Station OpMode Control Panel now disabled while a Restart Robot is in progress&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Disables advanced settings related to Wi-Fi Direct when the Robot Controller is a Control Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Tint phone battery icons on Driver Station when low/critical.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Uses names &#34;Control Hub Portal&#34; and &#34;Control Hub&#34; (when appropriate) in new configuration files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve I2C read performance &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Very large improvement on Control Hub; up to ~2x faster with small (e.g. 6 byte) reads&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Not as apparent on Expansion Hubs connected to a phone&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update/refresh build infrastructure &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Update to &#39;androidx&#39; support library from &#39;com.android.support:appcompat&#39;, which is end-of-life&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Update targetSdkVersion and compileSdkVersion to 28&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Update Android Studio&#39;s Android plugin to latest&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fix reported build timestamp in &#39;About&#39; screen&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add sample illustrating manual webcam use: ConceptWebcam&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bug fixes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/248&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #248&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/232&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #232&lt;/a&gt; and modifies bulk caching semantics to allow for cache-preserving MANUAL/AUTO transitions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves performance when REV 2M distance sensor is unplugged&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves readability of Toast messages on certain devices&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows a Driver Station to connect to a Robot Controller after another has disconnected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves generation of fake serial numbers for UVC cameras which do not provide a real serial number &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Previously some devices would assign such cameras a serial of &lt;code&gt;0:0&lt;/code&gt; and fail to open and start streaming&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/638&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #638&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes a slew of bugs with the Vuforia camera monitor including: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where preview could be displayed with a wonky aspect ratio&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where preview could be cut off in landscape&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where preview got totally messed up when rotating phone&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug where crosshair could drift off target when using webcams&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue in UVC driver on some devices (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/681&#34;&gt;ftc_app 681&lt;/a&gt;) if streaming was started/stopped multiple times in a row &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Issue manifested as kernel panic on devices which do not have &lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/patchwork/patch/352400/&#34;&gt;this kernel patch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On affected devices which &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; have the patch, the issue was manifest as simply a failure to start streaming.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Tech Team believes that the root cause of the issue is a bug in the Linux kernel XHCI driver. A workaround was implemented in the SDK UVC driver.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug in UVC driver where often half the frames from the camera would be dropped (e.g. only 15FPS delivered during a streaming session configured for 30FPS).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where TensorFlow Object Detection would show results whose confidence was lower than the minimum confidence parameter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes a potential exploitation issue of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cvedetails.com/cve/CVE-2019-11358/&#34;&gt;CVE-2019-11358&lt;/a&gt; in OnBotJava&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes changing the address of an Expansion Hub with additional Expansion Hubs connected to it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Preserves the Control Hub&#39;s network connection when &#34;Restart Robot&#34; is selected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where device scans would fail while the Robot was restarting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix RenderScript usage &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Use androidx.renderscript variant: increased compatibility&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Use RenderScript in Java mode, not native: simplifies build&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes webcam-frame-to-bitmap conversion problem: alpha channel wasn&#39;t being initialized, only R, G, &amp;amp; B&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes possible arithmetic overflow in Deadline&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes deadlock in Vuforia webcam support which could cause 5-second delays when stopping OpMode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.4 (20200108-101156)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/88&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #88&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds an inspection item that notes when a robot controller (Control Hub) is using the factory default password.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/61&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #61&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/142&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #142&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/417&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #417&lt;/a&gt; by adding more current and voltage monitoring capabilities for REV Hubs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://ftcforum.firstinspires.org/forum/ftc-technology/76217-onbotjava-crashes-robot-controller&#34;&gt;a crash sometimes caused by OnBotJava activity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves OnBotJava autosave functionality &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/738&#34;&gt;ftc_app #738&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes system responsiveness issue when an Expansion Hub is disconnected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where IMU initialization could prevent Op Modes from stopping&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where AndroidTextToSpeech.speak() would fail if it was called too early&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds telemetry.speak() methods and blocks, which cause the Driver Station (if also updated) to speak text&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds and improves Expansion Hub-related warnings &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Improves Expansion Hub low battery warning &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Displays the warning immediately after the hub reports it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Specifies whether the condition is current or occurred temporarily during an OpMode run&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Displays which hubs reported low battery&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Displays warning when hub loses and regains power during an OpMode run &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Fixes the hub&#39;s LED pattern after this condition&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Displays warning when Expansion Hub is not responding to commands &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Specifies whether the condition is current or occurred temporarily during an OpMode run&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Clarifies warning when Expansion Hub is not present at startup &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Specifies that this condition requires a Robot Restart before the hub can be used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;The hub light will now accurately reflect this state&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Improves logging and reduces log spam during these conditions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Syncs the Control Hub time and timezone to a connected web browser programming the robot, if a Driver Station is not available.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds bulk read functionality for REV Hubs &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A bulk caching mode must be set at the Hub level with &lt;code&gt;LynxModule#setBulkCachingMode()&lt;/code&gt;. This applies to all relevant SDK hardware classes that reference that Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The following following Hub bulk caching modes are available: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;BulkCachingMode.OFF&lt;/code&gt; (default): All hardware calls operate as usual. Bulk data can read through &lt;code&gt;LynxModule#getBulkData()&lt;/code&gt; and processed manually.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;BulkCachingMode.AUTO&lt;/code&gt;: Applicable hardware calls are served from a bulk read cache that is cleared/refreshed automatically to ensure identical commands don&#39;t hit the same cache. The cache can also be cleared manually with &lt;code&gt;LynxModule#clearBulkCache()&lt;/code&gt;, although this is not recommended.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;(advanced users) &lt;code&gt;BulkCachingMode.MANUAL&lt;/code&gt;: Same as &lt;code&gt;BulkCachingMode.AUTO&lt;/code&gt; except the cache is never cleared automatically. To avoid getting stale data, the cache must be manually cleared at the beginning of each loop body or as the user deems appropriate.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes PIDF Annotation values added in Rev 5.3 (to AndyMark, goBILDA and TETRIX motor configurations). &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The new motor types will still be available but their Default control behavior will revert back to Rev 5.2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds new &lt;code&gt;ConceptMotorBulkRead&lt;/code&gt; sample Opmode to demonstrate and compare Motor Bulk-Read modes for reducing I/O latencies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.3 (20191004-112306)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes external USB/UVC webcam support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Makes various bugfixes and improvements to Blocks page, including but not limited to: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Many visual tweaks&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Browser zoom and window resize behave better&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Resizing the Java preview pane works better and more consistently across browsers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Java preview pane consistently gets scrollbars when needed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Java preview pane is hidden by default on phones&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Internet Explorer 11 should work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Large dropdown lists display properly on lower res screens&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Disabled buttons are now visually identifiable as disabled&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A warning is shown if a user selects a TFOD sample, but their device is not compatible&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Warning messages in a Blocks op mode are now visible by default.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds goBILDA 5201 and 5202 motors to Robot Configurator&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds PIDF Annotation values to AndyMark, goBILDA and TETRIX motor configurations. This has the effect of causing the RUN_USING_ENCODERS and RUN_TO_POSITION modes to use PIDF vs PID closed loop control on these motors. This should provide more responsive, yet stable, speed control. PIDF adds Feedforward control to the basic PID control loop. Feedforward is useful when controlling a motor&#39;s speed because it &#34;anticipates&#34; how much the control voltage must change to achieve a new speed set-point, rather than requiring the integrated error to change sufficiently. The PIDF values were chosen to provide responsive, yet stable, speed control on a lightly loaded motor. The more heavily a motor is loaded (drag or friction), the more noticable the PIDF improvement will be.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes startup crash on Android 10&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/712&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #712&lt;/a&gt; (thanks to FROGbots-4634)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/542&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #542&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows &#34;A&#34; and lowercase letters when naming device through RC and DS apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.2 (20190905-083277)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes extra-wide margins on settings activities, and placement of the new configuration button&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds Skystone Vuforia image target data. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes sample Skystone Vuforia Navigation op modes (Java).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes sample Skystone Vuforia Navigation op modes (Blocks).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds TensorFlow inference model (.tflite) for Skystone game elements. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes sample Skystone TensorFlow op modes (Java).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes sample Skystone TensorFlow op modes (Blocks).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes older (season-specific) sample op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes 64-bit support (to comply with &lt;a href=&#34;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2019/01/get-your-apps-ready-for-64-bit.html&#34;&gt;Google Play requirements&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Protects against Stuck OpModes when a Restart Robot is requested. (Thanks to FROGbots-4634) (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/709&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #709&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks related changes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug with blocks generated code when hardware device name is a java or javascript reserved word.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shows generated java code for blocks, even when hardware items are missing from the active configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Displays warning icon when outdated Vuforia and TensorFlow blocks are used (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/27&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #27&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.1 (20190820-222104)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Defines default PIDF parameters for the following motors: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV Core Hex Motor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV 20:1 HD Hex Motor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV 40:1 HD Hex Motor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds back button when running on a device without a system back button (such as a Control Hub)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allows a REV Control Hub to update the firmware on a REV Expansion Hub via USB&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FIRST-Tech-Challenge/SkyStone/issues/9&#34;&gt;SkyStone issue #9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/715&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #715&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prevents extra DS User clicks by filtering based on current state.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prevents incorrect DS UI state changes when receiving new OpMode list from RC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds support for REV Color Sensor V3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds a manual-refresh DS Camera Stream for remotely viewing RC camera frames. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To show the stream on the DS, initialize &lt;strong&gt;but do not run&lt;/strong&gt; a stream-enabled opmode, select the Camera Stream option in the DS menu, and tap the image to refresh. This feature is automatically enabled when using Vuforia or TFODno additional RC configuration is required for typical use cases. To hide the stream, select the same menu item again.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Note that gamepads are disabled and the selected opmode cannot be started while the stream is open as a safety precaution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To use custom streams, consult the API docs for &lt;code&gt;CameraStreamServer#setSource&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;CameraStreamSource&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds many Star Wars sounds to RobotController resources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added Skystone Sounds Chooser Sample Program.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Switches out startup, connect chimes, and error/warning sounds for Star Wars sounds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updates OnBot Java to use a WebSocket for communication with the robot &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The OnBot Java page no longer has to do a full refresh when a user switches from editing one file to another&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Known issues:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Camera Stream &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Vuforia camera stream inherits the issues present in the phone preview (namely &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ftctechnh/ftc_app/issues/574&#34;&gt;ftc_app issue #574&lt;/a&gt;). This problem does not affect the TFOD camera stream even though it receives frames from Vuforia.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The orientation of the stream frames may not always match the phone preview. For now, these frames may be rotated manually via a custom &lt;code&gt;CameraStreamSource&lt;/code&gt; if desired.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OnBotJava &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Browser back button may not always work correctly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It&#39;s possible for a build to be queued, but not started. The OnBot Java build console will display a warning if this occurs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A user might not realize they are editing a different file if the user inadvertently switches from one file to another since this switch is now seamless. The name of the currently open file is displayed in the browser tab.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 5.0 (built on 19.06.14)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for the REV Robotics Control Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds a Java preview pane to the Blocks editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds a new offline export feature to the Blocks editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Display Wi-Fi channel in Network circle on Driver Station.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Adds calibration for Logitech C270&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updates build tooling and target SDK.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Compliance with Google&#39;s permissions infrastructure (Required after build tooling update).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keep Alives to mitigate the Motorola Wi-Fi scanning problem. Telemetry substitute no longer necessary.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improves Vuforia error reporting.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes ftctechnh/ftc_app issues 621, 713.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Miscellaneous bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 4.3 (built on 18.10.31)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes missing TensorFlow-related libraries and files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 4.2 (built on 18.10.30)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes fix to avoid deadlock situation with WatchdogMonitor which could result in USB communication errors. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Comm error appeared to require that user disconnect USB cable and restart the Robot Controller app to recover.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;robotControllerLog.txt would have error messages that included the words &#34;E RobotCore: lynx xmit lock: #### abandoning lock:&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes fix to correctly list the parent module address for a REV Robotics Expansion Hub in a configuration (.xml) file. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Bug in versions 4.0 and 4.1 would incorrect list the address module for a parent REV Robotics device as &#34;1&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If the parent module had a higher address value than the daisy-chained module, then this bug would prevent the Robot Controller from communicating with the downstream Expansion Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added requirement for ACCESS_COARSE_LOCATION to allow a Driver Station running Android Oreo to scan for Wi-Fi Direct devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added google() repo to build.gradle because aapt2 must be downloaded from the google() repository beginning with version 3.2 of the Android Gradle Plugin. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Important Note: Android Studio users will need to be connected to the Internet the first time build the ftc_app project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Internet connectivity is required for the first build so the appropriate files can be downloaded from the Google repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Users should not need to be connected to the Internet for subsequent builds.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This should also fix buid issue where Android Studio would complain that it &#34;Could not find com.android.tools.lint:lint-gradle:26.1.4&#34; (or similar).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added support for REV Spark Mini motor controller as part of the configuration menu for a servo/PWM port on the REV Expansion Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Provide examples for playing audio files in an Op Mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Block Development Tool Changes &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes a fix for a problem with the Velocity blocks that were reported in the FTC Technology forum (Blocks Programming subforum).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Change the &#34;Save completed successfully.&#34; message to a white color so it will contrast with a green background.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed the &#34;Download image&#34; feature so it will work if there are text blocks in the op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduce support for Google&#39;s TensorFlow Lite technology for object detetion for 2018-2019 game. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;TensorFlow lite can recognize Gold Mineral and Silver Mineral from 2018-2019 game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Example Java and Block op modes are included to show how to determine the relative position of the gold block (left, center, right).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 4.1 (released on 18.09.24)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to prevent crash when deprecated configuration annotations are used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Change to allow FTC Robot Controller APK to be auto-updated using FIRST Global Control Hub update scripts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removed samples for non supported / non legal hardware.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvements to Telemetry.addData block with &#34;text&#34; socket.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated Blocks sample op mode list to include Rover Ruckus Vuforia example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update SDK library version number.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 4.0 (released on 18.09.12)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Initial support for UVC compatible cameras&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If UVC camera has a unique serial number, RC will detect and enumerate by serial number.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If UVC camera lacks a unique serial number, RC will only support one camera of that type connected.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Calibration settings for a few cameras are included (see TeamCode/src/main/res/xml/teamwebcamcalibrations.xml for details).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;User can upload calibration files from Program and Manage web interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UVC cameras seem to draw a fair amount of electrical current from the USB bus. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;This does not appear to present any problems for the REV Robotics Control Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This does seem to create stability problems when using some cameras with an Android phone-based Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FTC Tech Team is investigating options to mitigate this issue with the phone-based Robot Controllers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Updated sample Vuforia Navigation and VuMark Op Modes to demonstrate how to use an internal phone-based camera and an external UVC webcam.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support for improved motor control.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV Robotics Expansion Hub firmware 1.8 and greater will support a feed forward mechanism for closed loop motor control.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FTC SDK has been modified to support PIDF coefficients (proportional, integral, derivative, and feed forward).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FTC Blocks development tool modified to include PIDF programming blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Deprecated older PID-related methods and variables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;REV&#39;s 1.8.x PIDF-related changes provide a more linear and accurate way to control a motor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wireless&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added 5GHz support for wireless channel changing for those devices that support it. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Tested with Moto G5 and E4 phones.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Also tested with other (currently non-approved) phones such as Samsung Galaxy S8.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Improved Expansion Hub firmware update support in Robot Controller app&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Changes to make the system more robust during the firmware update process (when performed through Robot Controller app).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;User no longer has to disconnect a downstream daisy-chained Expansion Hub when updating an Expansion Hub&#39;s firmware. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;If user is updating an Expansion Hub&#39;s firmware through a USB connection, he/she does not have to disconnect RS485 connection to other Expansion Hubs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The user still must use a USB connection to update an Expansion Hub&#39;s firmware.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The user cannot update the Expansion Hub firmware for a downstream device that is daisy chained through an RS485 connection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If an Expansion Hub accidentally gets &#34;bricked&#34; the Robot Controller app is now more likely to recognize the Hub when it scans the USB bus. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Robot Controller app should be able to detect an Expansion Hub, even if it accidentally was bricked in a previous update attempt.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Robot Controller app should be able to install the firmware onto the Hub, even if if accidentally was bricked in a previous update attempt.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Resiliency&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FTC software can detect and enable an FTDI reset feature that is available with REV Robotics v1.8 Expansion Hub firmware and greater. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;When enabled, the Expansion Hub can detect if it hasn&#39;t communicated with the Robot Controller over the FTDI (USB) connection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If the Hub hasn&#39;t heard from the Robot Controller in a while, it will reset the FTDI connection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This action helps system recover from some ESD-induced disruptions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Various fixes to improve reliability of FTC software.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Blocks&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed errors with string and list indices in blocks export to java.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for USB connected UVC webcams.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Refactored optimized Blocks Vuforia code to support Rover Ruckus image targets.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added programming blocks to support PIDF (proportional, integral, derivative and feed forward) motor control.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added formatting options (under Telemetry and Miscellaneous categories) so user can set how many decimal places to display a numerical value.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support to play audio files (which are uploaded through Blocks web interface) on Driver Station in addition to the Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug with Download Image of Blocks feature.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for REV Robotics Blinkin LED Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for REV Robotics 2m Distance Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for a REV Touch Sensor (no longer have to configure as a generic digital device).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks for DcMotorEx methods. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;These are enhanced methods that you can use when supported by the motor controller hardware.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The REV Robotics Expansion Hub supports these enhanced methods.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enhanced methods include methods to get/set motor velocity (in encoder pulses per second), get/set PIDF coefficients, etc..&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Modest Improvements in Logging&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Decrease frequency of battery checker voltage statements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Removed non-FTC related log statements (wherever possible).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduced a &#34;Match Logging&#34; feature. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Under &#34;Settings&#34; a user can enable/disable this feature (it&#39;s disabled by default).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If enabled, user provides a &#34;Match Number&#34; through the Driver Station user interface (top of the screen). &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;The Match Number is used to create a log file specifically with log statements from that particular Op Mode run.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Match log files are stored in /sdcard/FIRST/matlogs on the Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Once an op mode run is complete, the Match Number is cleared.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;This is a convenient way to create a separate match log with statements only related to a specific op mode run.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;New Devices&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for REV Robotics Blinkin LED Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for REV Robotics 2m Distance Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added configuration option for REV 20:1 HD Hex Motor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for a REV Touch Sensor (no longer have to configure as a generic digital device).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed some errors in the definitions for acceleration and velocity in our javadoc documentation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added ability to play audio files on Driver Station&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When user is configuring an Expansion Hub, the LED on the Expansion Hub will change blink pattern (purple-cyan) to indicate which Hub is currently being configured.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Renamed I2cSensorType to I2cDeviceType.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added an external sample Op Mode that demonstrates localization using 2018-2019 (Rover Ruckus presented by QualComm) Vuforia targets.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added an external sample Op Mode that demonstrates how to use the REV Robotics 2m Laser Distance Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added an external sample Op Mode that demonstrates how to use the REV Robotics Blinkin LED Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Re-categorized external Java sample Op Modes to &#34;TeleOp&#34; instead of &#34;Autonomous&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Known issues:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Initial support for UVC compatible cameras&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UVC cameras seem to draw significant amount of current from the USB bus. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;This does not appear to present any problems for the REV Robotics Control Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This does seem to create stability problems when using some cameras with an Android phone-based Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FTC Tech Team is investigating options to mitigate this issue with the phone-based Robot Controllers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There might be a possible deadlock which causes the RC to become unresponsive when using a UVC webcam with a Nougat Android Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wireless&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When user selects a wireless channel, this channel does not necessarily persist if the phone is power cycled. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Tech Team is hoping to eventually address this issue in a future release.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Issue has been present since apps were introduced (i.e., it is not new with the v4.0 release).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Wireless channel is not currently displayed for Wi-Fi Direct connections.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The blink indication feature that shows which Expansion Hub is currently being configured does not work for a newly created configuration file. &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;User has to first save a newly created configuration file and then close and re-edit the file in order for blink indicator to work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.6 (built on 17.12.18)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks Changes &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Uses updated Google Blockly software to allow users to edit their op modes on Apple iOS devices (including iPad and iPhone).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Improvement in Blocks tool to handle corrupt op mode files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Autonomous op modes should no longer get switched back to tele-op after re-opening them to be edited.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The system can now detect type mismatches during runtime and alert the user with a message on the Driver Station.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated javadoc documentation for setPower() method to reflect correct range of values (-1 to +1).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modified VuforiaLocalizerImpl to allow for user rendering of frames &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added a user-overrideable onRenderFrame() method which gets called by the class&#39;s renderFrame() method.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.5 (built on 17.10.30)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes with version 3.5 include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduced a fix to prevent random op mode stops, which can occur after the Robot Controller app has been paused and then resumed (for example, when a user temporarily turns off the display of the Robot Controller phone, and then turns the screen back on).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Introduced a fix to prevent random op mode stops, which were previously caused by random peer disconnect events on the Driver Station.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where log files would be closed on pause of the RC or DS, but not re-opened upon resume.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue with battery handler (voltage) start/stop race.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes issue where Android Studio generated op modes would disappear from available list in certain situations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes problem where OnBot Java would not build on REV Robotics Control Hub.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes problem where OnBot Java would not build if the date and time on the Robot Controller device was &#34;rewound&#34; (set to an earlier date/time).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved error message on OnBot Java that occurs when renaming a file fails.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removed unneeded resources from android.jar binaries used by OnBot Java to reduce final size of Robot Controller app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added MR_ANALOG_TOUCH_SENSOR block to Blocks Programming Tool.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.4 (built on 17.09.06)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes with version 3.4 include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added telemetry.update() statement for BlankLinearOpMode template.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Renamed sample Block op modes to be more consistent with Java samples.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added some additional sample Block op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reworded OnBot Java readme slightly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.3 (built on 17.09.04)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version of the software includes improves for the FTC Blocks Programming Tool and the OnBot Java Programming Tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes with verion 3.3 include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android Studio ftc_app project has been updated to use Gradle Plugin 2.3.3.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android Studio ftc_app project is already using gradle 3.5 distribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Robot Controller log has been renamed to /sdcard/RobotControllerLog.txt (note that this change was actually introduced w/ v3.2).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvements in I2C reliability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optimized I2C read for REV Expansion Hub, with v1.7 firmware or greater.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated all external/samples (available through OnBot and in Android project folder).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vuforia &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for VuMarks that will be used for the 2017-2018 season game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Update to latest Google Blockly release.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Sample op modes can be selected as a template when creating new op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where the blocks would disappear temporarily when mouse button is held down.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks for Range.clip and Range.scale.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;User can now disable/enable Block op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fix to prevent occasional Blocks deadlock.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OnBot Java &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Significant improvements with autocomplete function for OnBot Java editor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Sample op modes can be selected as a template when creating new op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes and changes to complete hardware setup feature.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Updated (and more useful) onBot welcome message.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Known issues:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android Studio &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;After updating to the new v3.3 Android Studio project folder, if you get error messages indicating &#34;InvalidVirtualFileAccessException&#34; then you might need to do a File-&amp;gt;Invalidate Caches / Restart to clear the error.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OnBot Java &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Sometimes when you push the build button to build all op modes, the RC returns an error message that the build failed. If you press the build button a second time, the build typically suceeds.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.2 (built on 17.08.02)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version of the software introduces the &#34;OnBot Java&#34; Development Tool. Similar to the FTC Blocks Development Tool, the FTC OnBot Java Development Tool allows a user to create, edit and build op modes dynamically using only a Javascript-enabled web browser.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OnBot Java Development Tool is an integrated development environment (IDE) that is served up by the Robot Controller. Op modes are created and edited using a Javascript-enabled browser (Google Chromse is recommended). Op modes are saved on the Robot Controller Android device directly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The OnBot Java Development Tool provides a Java programming environment that does NOT need Android Studio.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes with version 3.2 include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enhanced web-based development tools&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction of OnBot Java Development Tool.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Web-based programming and management features are &#34;always on&#34; (user no longer needs to put Robot Controller into programming mode).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Web-based management interface (where user can change Robot Controller name and also easily download Robot Controller log file).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;OnBot Java, Blocks and Management features available from web based interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Blocks Programming Development Tool:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Changed &#34;LynxI2cColorRangeSensor&#34; block to &#34;REV Color/range sensor&#34; block.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed tooltip for ColorSensor.isLightOn block. Added blocks for ColorSensor.getNormalizedColors and LynxI2cColorRangeSensor.getNormalizedColors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Added example op modes for digital touch sensor and REV Robotics Color Distance sensor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;User selectable color themes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Includes many minor enhancements and fixes (too numerous to list).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Known issues:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auto complete function is incomplete and does not support the following (for now): &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Access via &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; keyword&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Access via &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; keyword&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Members of the super cloass, not overridden by the class&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Any methods provided in the current class&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Inner classes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can&#39;t handle casted objects&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Any objects coming from an parenthetically enclosed expression&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.10 (built on 17.05.09)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This version of the software provides support for the REV Robotics Expansion Hub. This version also includes improvements in the USB communication layer in an effort to enhance system resiliency. If you were using a 2.x version of the software previously, updating to version 3.1 requires that you also update your Driver Station software in addition to updating the Robot Controller software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also note that in version 3.10 software, the setMaxSpeed and getMaxSpeed methods are no longer available (not deprecated, they have been removed from the SDK). Also note that the the new 3.x software incorporates motor profiles that a user can select as he/she configures the robot.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks changes &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added VuforiaTrackableDefaultListener.getPose and Vuforia.trackPose blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added optimized blocks support for Vuforia extended tracking.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added atan2 block to the math category.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added useCompetitionFieldTargetLocations parameter to Vuforia.initialize block. If set to false, the target locations are placed at (0,0,0) with target orientation as specified in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gearsincorg/FTCVuforiaDemo/raw/master/Robot_Navigation.java&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gearsincorg/FTCVuforiaDemo/blob/master/Robot_Navigation.java&lt;/a&gt; tutorial op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Incorporates additional improvements to USB comm layer to improve system resiliency (to recover from a greater number of communication disruptions).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional Notes Regarding Version 3.00 (built on 17.04.13)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the release changes listed below (see section labeled &#34;Version 3.00 (built on 17.04.013)&#34;), version 3.00 has the following important changes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 3.00 software uses a new version of the FTC Robocol (robot protocol). If you upgrade to v3.0 on the Robot Controller and/or Android Studio side, you must also upgrade the Driver Station software to match the new Robocol.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 3.00 software removes the setMaxSpeed and getMaxSpeed methods from the DcMotor class. If you have an op mode that formerly used these methods, you will need to remove the references/calls to these methods. Instead, v3.0 provides the max speed information through the use of motor profiles that are selected by the user during robot configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Version 3.00 software currently does not have a mechanism to disable extra i2c sensors. We hope to re-introduce this function with a release in the near future.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 3.00 (built on 17.04.13)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** Use this version of the software at YOUR OWN RISK!!! ***&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is being released as an &#34;alpha&#34; version. Use this version at your own risk!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This pre-release software contains SIGNIFICANT changes, including changes to the Wi-Fi Direct pairing mechanism, rewrites of the I2C sensor classes, changes to the USB/FTDI layer, and the introduction of support for the REV Robotics Expansion Hub and the REV Robotics color-range-light sensor. These changes were implemented to improve the reliability and resiliency of the FTC control system.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note, however, that version 3.00 is considered &#34;alpha&#34; code. This code is being released so that the FIRST community will have an opportunity to test the new REV Expansion Hub electronics module when it becomes available in May. The developers do not recommend using this code for critical applications (i.e., competition use).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;*** Use this version of the software at YOUR OWN RISK!!! ***&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Major rework of sensor-related infrastructure. Includes rewriting sensor classes to implement synchronous I2C communication.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to reset Autonomous timer back to 30 seconds.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Implementation of specific motor profiles for approved 12V motors (includes Tetrix, AndyMark, Matrix and REV models).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modest improvements to enhance Wi-Fi P2P pairing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes telemetry log addition race.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Publishes all the sources (not just a select few).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Includes Block programming improvements &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Addition of optimized Vuforia blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Auto scrollbar to projects and sounds pages.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed blocks paste bug.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Blocks execute after while-opModeIsActive loop (to allow for cleanup before exiting op mode).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added gyro integratedZValue block.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixes bug with projects page for Firefox browser.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added IsSpeaking block to AndroidTextToSpeech.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Implements support for the REV Robotics Expansion Hub &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Implements support for integral REV IMU (physically installed on I2C bus 0, uses same Bosch BNO055 9 axis absolute orientation sensor as Adafruit 9DOF abs orientation sensor). - Implements support for REV color/range/light sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Provides support to update Expansion Hub firmware through FTC SDK.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detects REV firmware version and records in log file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Includes support for REV Control Hub (note that the REV Control Hub is not yet approved for FTC use).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Implements FTC Blocks programming support for REV Expansion Hub and sensor hardware.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detects and alerts when I2C device disconnect.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.62 (built on 17.01.07)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added null pointer check before calling modeToByte() in finishModeSwitchIfNecessary method for ModernRoboticsUsbDcMotorController class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes to enhance Modern Robotics USB protocol robustness.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.61 (released on 16.12.19)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks Programming mode changes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fix to correct issue when an exception was thrown because an OpticalDistanceSensor object appears twice in the hardware map (the second time as a LightSensor).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.6 (released on 16.12.16)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixes for Gyro class: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Improve (decrease) sensor refresh latency.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;fix isCalibrating issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks Programming mode changes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Blocks now ignores a device in the configuration xml if the name is empty. Other devices work in configuration work fine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.5 (internal release on released on 16.12.13)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks Programming mode changes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks support for AdafruitBNO055IMU.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added Download Op Mode button to FtcBocks.html.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for copying blocks in one OpMode and pasting them in an other OpMode. The clipboard content is stored on the phone, so the programming mode server must be running.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Modified Utilities section of the toolbox.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Programming Mode, display information about the active connections.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed paste location when workspace has been scrolled.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks support for the android Accelerometer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue where Blocks Upload Op Mode truncated name at first dot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks support for Android SoundPool.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Acceleration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for AdafruitBNO055IMU.Parameters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for AnalogInput.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for AngularVelocity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Color.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for ColorSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for CompassSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for CRServo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for DigitalChannel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for ElapsedTime.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Gamepad.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for GyroSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for IrSeekerSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for LED.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for LightSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for LinearOpMode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for MagneticFlux.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for MatrixF.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for MrI2cCompassSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for MrI2cRangeSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for OpticalDistanceSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Orientation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Position.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Quaternion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Servo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for ServoController.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Telemetry.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Temperature.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for TouchSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for UltrasonicSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for VectorF.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for Velocity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for VoltageSensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for VuforiaLocalizer.Parameters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for VuforiaTrackable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for VuforiaTrackables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for enums in AdafruitBNO055IMU.Parameters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type safety to blocks for AndroidAccelerometer, AndroidGyroscope, AndroidOrientation, and AndroidTextToSpeech.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.4 (released on 16.11.13)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to avoid crashing for nonexistent resources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blocks Programming mode changes: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support OpenGLMatrix, MatrixF, and VectorF.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support AngleUnit, AxesOrder, AxesReference, CameraDirection, CameraMonitorFeedback, DistanceUnit, and TempUnit.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support Acceleration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support LinearOpMode.getRuntime.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support MagneticFlux and Position.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed typos.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Made blocks for ElapsedTime more consistent with other objects.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support Quaternion, Velocity, Orientation, AngularVelocity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added blocks to support VuforiaTrackables, VuforiaTrackable, VuforiaLocalizer, VuforiaTrackableDefaultListener.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed a few blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added type checking to new blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Updated to latest blockly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added default variable blocks to navigation and matrix blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed toolbox entry for openGLMatrix_rotation_withAxesArgs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When user downloads Blocks-generated op mode, only the .blk file is downloaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When user uploads Blocks-generated op mode (.blk file), Javascript code is auto generated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added DbgLog support.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added logging when a blocks file is read/written.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug to properly render blocks even if missing devices from configuration file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for additional characters (not just alphanumeric) for the block file names (for download and upload).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for OpMode flavor (Autonomous or TeleOp) and group.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes to Samples to prevent tutorial issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Incorporated suggested changes from public pull 216 (Replace .. paths).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Remove Servo Glitches when robot stopped.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;if user hits Cancels when editing a configuration file, clears the unsaved changes and reverts to original unmodified configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added log info to help diagnose why the Robot Controller app was terminated (for example, by watch dog function).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added ability to transfer log from the controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed inconsistency for AngularVelocity&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Limit unbounded growth of data for telemetry. If user does not call telemetry.update() for LinearOpMode in a timely manner, data added for telemetry might get lost if size limit is exceeded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.35 (released on 16.10.06)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blockly programming mode - Removed unnecesary idle() call from blocks for new project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.30 (released on 16.10.05)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blockly programming mode: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Mechanism added to save Blockly op modes from Programming Mode Server onto local device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To avoid clutter, blocks are displayed in categorized folders&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for DigitalChannel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for ModernRoboticsI2cCompassSensor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for ModernRoboticsI2cRangeSensor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for VoltageSensor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for AnalogInput&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Added support for AnalogOutput&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fix for CompassSensor setMode block&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vuforia &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fix deadlock / make camera data available while Vuforia is running.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Update to Vuforia 6.0.117 (recommended by Vuforia and Google to close security loophole).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix for autonomous 30 second timer bug (where timer was in effect, even though it appeared to have timed out).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;opModeIsActive changes to allow cleanup after op mode is stopped (with enforced 2 second safety timeout).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to avoid reading i2c twice.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated sample Op Modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved logging and fixed intermittent freezing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added digital I/O sample.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cleaned up device names in sample op modes to be consistent with Pushbot guide.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to allow use of IrSeekerSensorV3.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.20 (released on 16.09.08)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for Modern Robotics Compass Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for Modern Robotics Range Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Revise device names for Pushbot templates to match the names used in Pushbot guide.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug so that IrSeekerSensorV3 device is accessible as IrSeekerSensor in hardwareMap.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modified computer vision code to require an individual Vuforia license (per legal requirement from PTC).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minor fixes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blockly enhancements: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for Voltage Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for Analog Input.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for Analog Output.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for Light Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for Servo Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.10 (released on 16.09.03)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for Adafruit IMU.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvements to ModernRoboticsI2cGyro class &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Block on reset of z axis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;isCalibrating() returns true while gyro is calibration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated sample gyro program.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Blockly enhancements &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for android.graphics.Color.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;added support for ElapsedTime.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;improved look and legibility of blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for compass sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for ultrasonic sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for IrSeeker.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for LED.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for color sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;support for CRServo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;prompt user to configure robot before using programming mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Provides ability to disable audio cues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;various bug fixes and improvements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Version 2.00 (released on 16.08.19)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This is the new release for the upcoming 2016-2017 FIRST Tech Challenge Season.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Channel change is enabled in the FTC Robot Controller app for Moto G 2nd and 3rd Gen phones.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users can now use annotations to register/disable their Op Modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes in the Android SDK, JDK and build tool requirements (minsdk=19, java 1.7, build tools 23.0.3).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Standardized units in analog input.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cleaned up code for existing analog sensor classes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;setChannelMode and getChannelMode were REMOVED from the DcMotorController class. This is important - we no longer set the motor modes through the motor controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;setMode and getMode were added to the DcMotor class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ContinuousRotationServo class has been added to the FTC SDK.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Range.clip() method has been overloaded so it can support this operation for int, short and byte integers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Some changes have been made (new methods added) on how a user can access items from the hardware map.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users can now set the zero power behavior for a DC motor so that the motor will brake or float when power is zero.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prototype Blockly Programming Mode has been added to FTC Robot Controller. Users can place the Robot Controller into this mode, and then use a device (such as a laptop) that has a Javascript enabled browser to write Blockly-based Op Modes directly onto the Robot Controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users can now configure the robot remotely through the FTC Driver Station app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android Studio project supports Android Studio 2.1.x and compile SDK Version 23 (Marshmallow).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vuforia Computer Vision SDK integrated into FTC SDK. Users can use sample vision targets to get localization information on a standard FTC field.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Project structure has been reorganized so that there is now a TeamCode package that users can use to place their local/custom Op Modes into this package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Inspection function has been integrated into the FTC Robot Controller and Driver Station Apps (Thanks Team HazMat 9277 &amp;amp; 10650!).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Audio cues have been incorporated into FTC SDK.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swap mechanism added to FTC Robot Controller configuration activity. For example, if you have two motor controllers on a robot, and you misidentified them in your configuration file, you can use the Swap button to swap the devices within the configuration file (so you do not have to manually re-enter in the configuration info for the two devices).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix mechanism added to all user to replace an electronic module easily. For example, suppose a servo controller dies on your robot. You replace the broken module with a new module, which has a different serial number from the original servo controller. You can use the Fix button to automatically reconfigure your configuration file to use the serial number of the new module.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improvements made to fix resiliency and responsiveness of the system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For LinearOpMode the user now must for a telemetry.update() to update the telemetry data on the driver station. This update() mechanism ensures that the driver station gets the updated data properly and at the same time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Auto Configure function of the Robot Controller is now template based. If there is a commonly used robot configuration, a template can be created so that the Auto Configure mechanism can be used to quickly configure a robot of this type.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The logic to detect a runaway op mode (both in the LinearOpMode and OpMode types) and to abort the run, then auto recover has been improved/implemented.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix has been incorporated so that Logitech F310 gamepad mappings will be correct for Marshmallow users.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 16.07.08&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For the ftc_app project, the gradle files have been modified to support Android Studio 2.1.x.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 16.03.30&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For the MIT App Inventor, the design blocks have new icons that better represent the function of each design component.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Some changes were made to the shutdown logic to ensure the robust shutdown of some of our USB services.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A change was made to LinearOpMode so as to allow a given instance to be executed more than once, which is required for the App Inventor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Javadoc improved/updated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 16.03.09&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes made to make the FTC SDK synchronous (significant change!) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;waitOneFullHardwareCycle() and waitForNextHardwareCycle() are no longer needed and have been deprecated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;runOpMode() (for a LinearOpMode) is now decoupled from the system&#39;s hardware read/write thread.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;loop() (for an OpMode) is now decoupled from the system&#39;s hardware read/write thread.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Methods are synchronous.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For example, if you call setMode(DcMotorController.RunMode.RESET_ENCODERS) for a motor, the encoder is guaranteed to be reset when the method call is complete.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For legacy module (NXT compatible), user no longer has to toggle between read and write modes when reading from or writing to a legacy device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes made to enhance reliability/robustness during ESD event.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes made to make code thread safe.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Debug keystore added so that user-generated robot controller APKs will all use the same signed key (to avoid conflicts if a team has multiple developer laptops for example).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Firmware version information for Modern Robotics modules are now logged.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes made to improve USB comm reliability and robustness.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added support for voltage indicator for legacy (NXT-compatible) motor controllers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Changes made to provide auto stop capabilities for op modes. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A LinearOpMode class will stop when the statements in runOpMode() are complete. User does not have to push the stop button on the driver station.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If an op mode is stopped by the driver station, but there is a run away/uninterruptible thread persisting, the app will log an error message then force itself to crash to stop the runaway thread.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Driver Station UI modified to display lowest measured voltage below current voltage (12V battery).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Driver Station UI modified to have color background for current voltage (green=good, yellow=caution, red=danger, extremely low voltage).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;javadoc improved (edits and additional classes).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added app build time to About activity for driver station and robot controller apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Display local IP addresses on Driver Station About activity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added I2cDeviceSynchImpl.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added I2cDeviceSync interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added seconds() and milliseconds() to ElapsedTime for clarity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added getCallbackCount() to I2cDevice.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added missing clearI2cPortActionFlag.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added code to create log messages while waiting for LinearOpMode shutdown.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix so Wi-Fi Direct Config activity will no longer launch multiple times.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added the ability to specify an alternate i2c address in software for the Modern Robotics gyro.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 16.02.09&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved battery checker feature so that voltage values get refreshed regularly (every 250 msec) on Driver Station (DS) user interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved software so that Robot Controller (RC) is much more resilient and self-healing to USB disconnects: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If user attempts to start/restart RC with one or more module missing, it will display a warning but still start up.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When running an op mode, if one or more modules gets disconnected, the RC &amp;amp; DS will display warnings,and robot will keep on working in spite of the missing module(s).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If a disconnected module gets physically reconnected the RC will auto detect the module and the user will regain control of the recently connected module.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Warning messages are more helpful (identifies the type of module thats missing plus its USB serial number).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Code changes to fix the null gamepad reference when users try to reference the gamepads in the init() portion of their op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NXT light sensor output is now properly scaled. Note that teams might have to readjust their light threshold values in their op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;On DS user interface, gamepad icon for a driver will disappear if the matching gamepad is disconnected or if that gamepad gets designated as a different driver.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Robot Protocol (ROBOCOL) version number info is displayed in About screen on RC and DS apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Incorporated a display filter on pairing screen to filter out devices that dont use the &#xA;  &lt;team number&gt;&#xA;   - format. This filter can be turned off to show all Wi-Fi Direct devices.&#xA;  &lt;/team&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated text in License file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed formatting error in OpticalDistanceSensor.toString().&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue on with a blank () device name that would disrupt Wi-Fi Direct Pairing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Made a change so that the Wi-Fi info and battery info can be displayed more quickly on the DS upon connecting to RC.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved javadoc generation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modified code to make it easier to support language localization in the future.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 16.01.04&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated compileSdkVersion for apps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prevent Wi-Fi from entering power saving mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;removed unused import from driver station&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Corrrected &#34;Dead zone&#34; joystick code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LED.getDeviceName and .getConnectionInfo() return null&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;apps check for ROBOCOL_VERSION mismatch&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix for Telemetry also has off-by-one errors in its data string sizing / short size limitations error&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;User telemetry output is sorted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;added formatting variants to DbgLog and RobotLog APIs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;code modified to allow for a long list of op mode names.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;changes to improve thread safety of RobocolDatagramSocket&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix for &#34;missing hardware leaves robot controller disconnected from driver station&#34; error&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fix for &#34;fast tapping of Init/Start causes problems&#34; (toast is now only instantiated on UI thread).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;added some log statements for thread life cycle.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;moved gamepad reset logic inside of initActiveOpMode() for robustness&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;changes made to mitigate risk of race conditions on public methods.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;changes to try and flag when Wi-Fi Direct name contains non-printable characters.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fix to correct race condition between .run() and .close() in ReadWriteRunnableStandard.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;updated FTDI driver&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;made ReadWriteRunnableStanard interface public.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fixed off-by-one errors in Command constructor&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;moved specific hardware implmentations into their own package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;moved specific gamepad implemnatations to the hardware library.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;changed LICENSE file to new BSD version.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fixed race condition when shutting down Modern Robotics USB devices.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;methods in the ColorSensor classes have been synchronized.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;corrected isBusy() status to reflect end of motion.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;corrected &#34;back&#34; button keycode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the notSupported() method of the GyroSensor class was changed to protected (it should not be public).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 15.11.04.001&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added Support for Modern Robotics Gyro.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The GyroSensor class now supports the MR Gyro Sensor.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users can access heading data (about Z axis)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Users can also access raw gyro data (X, Y, &amp;amp; Z axes).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Example MRGyroTest.java op mode included.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improved error messages&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More descriptive error messages for exceptions in user code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated DcMotor API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable read mode on new address in setI2cAddress&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix so that driver station app resets the gamepads when switching op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;USB-related code changes to make USB comm more responsive and to display more explicit error messages.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix so that USB will recover properly if the USB bus returns garbage data.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix USB initializtion race condition.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Better error reporting during FTDI open.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More explicit messages during USB failures.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed bug so that USB device is closed if event loop teardown method was not called.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed timer UI issue&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed duplicate name UI bug (Legacy Module configuration).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed race condition in EventLoopManager.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fix to keep references stable when updating gamepad.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For legacy Matrix motor/servo controllers removed necessity of appending &#34;Motor&#34; and &#34;Servo&#34; to controller names.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated HT color sensor driver to use constants from ModernRoboticsUsbLegacyModule class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated MR color sensor driver to use constants from ModernRoboticsUsbDeviceInterfaceModule class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Correctly handle I2C Address change in all color sensors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated/cleaned up op modes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated comments in LinearI2cAddressChange.java example op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Replaced the calls to &#34;setChannelMode&#34; with &#34;setMode&#34; (to match the new of the DcMotor method).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removed K9AutoTime.java op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added MRGyroTest.java op mode (demonstrates how to use MR Gyro Sensor).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added MRRGBExample.java op mode (demonstrates how to use MR Color Sensor).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added HTRGBExample.java op mode (demonstrates how to use HT legacy color sensor).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added MatrixControllerDemo.java (demonstrates how to use legacy Matrix controller).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated javadoc documentation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Updated release .apk files for Robot Controller and Driver Station apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 15.10.06.002&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added support for Legacy Matrix 9.6V motor/servo controller.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cleaned up build.gradle file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Minor UI and bug fixes for driver station and robot controller apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Throws error if Ultrasonic sensor (NXT) is not configured for legacy module port 4 or 5.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release 15.08.03.001&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New user interfaces for FTC Driver Station and FTC Robot Controller apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An init() method is added to the OpMode class. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For this release, init() is triggered right before the start() method.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Eventually, the init() method will be triggered when the user presses an &#34;INIT&#34; button on driver station.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The init() and loop() methods are now required (i.e., need to be overridden in the user&#39;s op mode).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The start() and stop() methods are optional.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A new LinearOpMode class is introduced. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Teams can use the LinearOpMode mode to create a linear (not event driven) program model.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Teams can use blocking statements like Thread.sleep() within a linear op mode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The API for the Legacy Module and Core Device Interface Module have been updated. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for encoders with the Legacy Module is now working.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The hardware loop has been updated for better performance.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>arduino/Arduino</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T01:35:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-13:/arduino/Arduino</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/arduino/Arduino" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Arduino IDE 1.x&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://content.arduino.cc/brand/arduino-color.svg?sanitize=true&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arduino is an open-source physical computing platform based on a simple I/O board and a development environment that implements the Processing/Wiring language. Arduino can be used to develop stand-alone interactive objects or can be connected to software on your computer (e.g. Flash, Processing and MaxMSP). The boards can be assembled by hand or purchased preassembled; the open-source IDE can be downloaded for free at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arduino.cc/en/Main/Software&#34;&gt;https://arduino.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/arduino/Arduino&#34; alt=&#34;Github&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;More info at&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;Our website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;The forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arduino&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;And like us at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/official.arduino&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bug reports and technical discussions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To report a &lt;em&gt;bug&lt;/em&gt; in the software or to request &lt;em&gt;a simple enhancement&lt;/em&gt; go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/issues&#34;&gt;Github Issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;More complex requests and technical discussion should go on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/a/arduino.cc/forum/#!forum/developers&#34;&gt;Arduino Developers mailing list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in modifying or extending the Arduino software, we strongly suggest discussing your ideas on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/a/arduino.cc/forum/#!forum/developers&#34;&gt;Developers mailing list&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; starting to work on them. That way you can coordinate with the Arduino Team and others, giving your work a higher chance of being integrated into the official release&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you think you found a vulnerability or other security-related bug in this project, please read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/security/policy&#34;&gt;security policy&lt;/a&gt; and report the bug to our Security Team  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;e-mail contact: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@arduino.cc&#34;&gt;security@arduino.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Detailed instructions for installation in popular operating systems can be found at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arduino.cc/en/Guide/Linux&#34;&gt;Linux&lt;/a&gt; (see also the &lt;a href=&#34;https://playground.arduino.cc/Learning/Linux&#34;&gt;Arduino playground&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arduino.cc/en/Guide/macOS&#34;&gt;macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arduino.cc/en/Guide/Windows&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contents of this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains just the code for the Arduino IDE itself. Originally, it also contained the AVR and SAM Arduino core and libraries (i.e. the code that is compiled as part of a sketch and runs on the actual Arduino device), but those have been moved into their own repositories. They are still automatically downloaded as part of the build process and included in built releases, though.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The repositories for these extra parts can be found here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Non-core specific Libraries are listed under: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino-libraries/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/arduino-libraries/&lt;/a&gt; (and also a few other places, see &lt;code&gt;build/build.xml&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The AVR core can be found at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/ArduinoCore-avr&#34;&gt;https://github.com/arduino/ArduinoCore-avr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Other cores are not included by default but installed through the board manager. Their repositories can also be found under &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/arduino/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building and testing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instructions for building the IDE and running unit tests can be found on the wiki:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/wiki/Building-Arduino&#34;&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/wiki/Building-Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/wiki/Testing-Arduino&#34;&gt;https://github.com/arduino/Arduino/wiki/Testing-Arduino&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arduino is an open source project, supported by many.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Arduino team is composed of Massimo Banzi, David Cuartielles, Tom Igoe and David A. Mellis.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arduino uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://gcc.gnu.org/wiki/avr-gcc&#34;&gt;GNU avr-gcc toolchain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://launchpad.net/gcc-arm-embedded&#34;&gt;GCC ARM Embedded toolchain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nongnu.org/avr-libc/&#34;&gt;avr-libc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nongnu.org/avrdude/&#34;&gt;avrdude&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shumatech.com/web/products/bossa&#34;&gt;bossac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://openocd.org/&#34;&gt;openOCD&lt;/a&gt; and code from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.processing.org&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiring.org.co&#34;&gt;Wiring&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Icon and about image designed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.todo.to.it/&#34;&gt;ToDo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions</title>
    <updated>2022-09-13T01:35:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-13:/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Your Cheat Sheet For Android Interview - Android Interview Questions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;AndroidInterviewQuestions&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/assets/banner-android-interview-questions.jpg&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Android Interview Questions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/open-source-projects&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/mindorks-opensource-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;MindOrks&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/join-community&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/join-community-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;MindOrks Community&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/android/store&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Mindorks%20Android%20Store-Android%20Interview%20Questions-blue.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;MindOrks Android Store&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Android Interview Questions - Your Cheat Sheet For Android Interview&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prepared and maintained by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/amitshekhariitbhu&#34;&gt;Amit Shekhar&lt;/a&gt; who is having experience of taking interviews of many Android developers and cracking interviews of top companies.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/android-app-development-online-course&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Android Roadmap&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/assets/roadmap.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;A complete guide for learning Android Development - &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/android-app-development-online-course&#34;&gt;Check here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#core-android&#34;&gt;Core Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#android-libraries&#34;&gt;Android Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#android-architecture&#34;&gt;Android Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#android-design-problem&#34;&gt;Android Design Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#android-unit-testing&#34;&gt;Android Unit Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#android-tools-and-technologies&#34;&gt;Android Tools And Technologies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#java-and-kotlin&#34;&gt;Java and Kotlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#data-structures-and-algorithms&#34;&gt;Data Structures And Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/#other-topics&#34;&gt;Other Topics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Core Android&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Base&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell all the Android application components.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/fundamentals.html#Components&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the project structure of an Android Application?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/projects&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Context&lt;/code&gt;? How is it used?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-context-in-android-application-330913e32514&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;AndroidManifest.xml&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/manifest/manifest-intro&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Application&lt;/code&gt; class?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The Application class in Android is the base class within an Android app that contains all other components such as activities and services. The Application class, or any subclass of the Application class, is instantiated before any other class when the process for your application/package is created.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Activity and Fragment&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt; and its lifecycle?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RiFui-i-s-o&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between onCreate() and onStart()&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RiFui-i-s-o&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When only onDestroy is called for an activity without onPause() and onStop()?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QSxcLnZ1-RU&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do we need to call setContentView() in onCreate() of Activity class?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zeYK8JdMOi8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is onSavedInstanceState() and onRestoreInstanceState() in activity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;onSavedInstanceState() - This method is used to store data before pausing the activity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;onRestoreInstanceState() - This method is used to recover the saved state of an activity when the activity is recreated after destruction. So, the onRestoreInstanceState() receive the bundle that contains the instance state information.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Fragment&lt;/code&gt; and its lifecycle.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-fragments-and-its-lifecycle&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are &#34;launch modes&#34;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-activity-launchmode-explained-cbc6cf996802&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between a &lt;code&gt;Fragment&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt;? Explain the relationship between the two.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10478233/why-fragments-and-when-to-use-fragments-instead-of-activities&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When should you use a Fragment rather than an Activity?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When you have some UI components to be used across various activities&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When multiple view can be displayed side by side just like viewPager&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between FragmentPagerAdapter vs FragmentStatePagerAdapter?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FragmentPagerAdapter: Each fragment visited by the user will be stored in the memory but the view will be destroyed. When the page is revisited, then the view will be created not the instance of the fragment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;FragmentStatePagerAdapter: Here, the fragment instance will be destroyed when it is not visible to the user, except the saved state of the fragment.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between adding/replacing fragment in backstack?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/24466302/basic-difference-between-add-and-replace-method-of-fragment/24466345&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it recommended to use only the default constructor to create a &lt;code&gt;Fragment&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9EdvcycKP9A&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you communicate between two Fragments?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-communicate-between-fragments&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is retained &lt;code&gt;Fragment&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;By default, Fragments are destroyed and recreated along with their parent Activitys when a configuration change occurs. Calling setRetainInstance(true) allows us to bypass this destroy-and-recreate cycle, signaling the system to retain the current instance of the fragment when the activity is recreated.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the purpose of &lt;code&gt;addToBackStack()&lt;/code&gt; while commiting fragment transaction?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;By calling addToBackStack(), the replace transaction is saved to the back stack so the user can reverse the transaction and bring back the previous fragment by pressing the Back button. For more &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/22984950/what-is-the-meaning-of-addtobackstack-with-null-parameter&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Views and ViewGroups&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;View&lt;/code&gt; in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-user-interface-view-components&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between &lt;code&gt;View.GONE&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;View.INVISIBLE&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/11556607/android-difference-between-invisible-and-gone&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you a create custom view? How?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/create-your-own-custom-view&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are ViewGroups and how they are different from the Views?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;View: View objects are the basic building blocks of User Interface(UI) elements in Android. View is a simple rectangle box which responds to the users actions. Examples are EditText, Button, CheckBox etc. View refers to the android.view.View class, which is the base class of all UI classes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;ViewGroup: ViewGroup is the invisible container. It holds View and ViewGroup. For example, LinearLayout is the ViewGroup that contains Button(View), and other Layouts also. ViewGroup is the base class for Layouts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Canvas?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-canvas-api-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;SurfaceView&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/view/SurfaceView&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relative Layout vs Linear Layout.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-layout-relative-linear-frame&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell about Constraint Layout&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-constraint-layout-in-android-531e68019cd&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you know what is the view tree? How can you optimize its depth?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/view/ViewTreeObserver&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the Touch Control and Events work in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/touch-control-and-events-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tKeYr7iV5xE&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Displaying Lists of Content&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between &lt;code&gt;ListView&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;RecyclerView&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/26728651/recyclerview-vs-listview&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does RecyclerView work internally?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-does-recyclerview-work-internally&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=60IYWdnHsZI&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the ViewHolder pattern? Why should we use it?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/21501316/what-is-the-benefit-of-viewholder-pattern-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RecyclerView Optimization - Scrolling Performance Improvement&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/recyclerview-optimization&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;SnapHelper&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-snaphelper-in-recyclerview-fc616b6833e8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Dialogs and Toasts&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Dialog&lt;/code&gt; in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/dialogs&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Toast&lt;/code&gt; in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/ui/notifiers/toasts&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the difference between &lt;code&gt;Dialog&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Dialog Fragment&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7977392/android-dialogfragment-vs-dialog&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Intents and Broadcasting&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Intent&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-intents-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an Implicit &lt;code&gt;Intent&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-intents-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an Explicit &lt;code&gt;Intent&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-intents-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;BroadcastReceiver&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/broadcasts&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;LocalBroadcastManager&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-localbroadcastmanager-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the function of an &lt;code&gt;IntentFilter&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/IntentFilter&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a Sticky &lt;code&gt;Intent&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Sticky Intents allows communication between a function and a service. sendStickyBroadcast() performs a sendBroadcast(Intent) known as sticky, i.e. the Intent you are sending stays around after the broadcast is complete, so that others can quickly retrieve that data through the return value of registerReceiver(BroadcastReceiver, IntentFilter). For example, if you take an intent for ACTION_BATTERY_CHANGED to get battery change events: When you call registerReceiver() for that action  even with a null BroadcastReceiver  you get the Intent that was last Broadcast for that action. Hence, you can use this to find the state of the battery without necessarily registering for all future state changes in the battery.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe how broadcasts and intents work to be able to pass messages around your app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7276537/using-a-broadcast-intent-broadcast-receiver-to-send-messages-from-a-service-to-a&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;PendingIntent&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you want someone to perform any Intent operation at future point of time on behalf of you, then we will use Pending Intent.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the different types of Broadcasts?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/broadcasts&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Services&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;Service&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/services&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Service&lt;/code&gt; vs &lt;code&gt;IntentService&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/service-vs-intentservice-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;JobScheduler&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/android/app/job/JobScheduler&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Inter-process Communication&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can two distinct Android apps interact?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/basics/intents&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it possible to run an Android app in multiple processes? How?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/6567768/how-can-an-android-application-have-more-than-one-process&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is AIDL? Enumerate the steps in creating a bounded service through AIDL.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/aidl&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What can you use for background processing in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/background&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;ContentProvider&lt;/code&gt; and what is it typically used for?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-provider-basics&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-providers&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Long-running Operations&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to run parallel tasks in Java or Android, and get callback when all complete?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v0ZSnISeyKE&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should you avoid to run non-ui code on the main thread?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/multiple-threads/communicate-ui&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is ANR? How can the ANR be prevented?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/vitals/anr.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an &lt;code&gt;AsyncTask&lt;/code&gt;(Deprecated in API level 30) ?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZZ-6nGbfVdA&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the problems in AsyncTask?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZZ-6nGbfVdA&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When would you use java thread instead of an AsyncTask?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/18480206/asynctask-vs-thread-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;Loader&lt;/code&gt;? (Deprecated)&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/loaders&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the relationship between the life cycle of an &lt;code&gt;AsyncTask&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt;? What problems can this result in? How can these problems be avoided?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;An AsyncTask is not tied to the life cycle of the Activity that contains it. So, for example, if you start an AsyncTask inside an Activity and the user rotates the device, the Activity will be destroyed (and a new Activity instance will be created) but the AsyncTask will not die but instead goes on living until it completes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then, when the AsyncTask does complete, rather than updating the UI of the new Activity, it updates the former instance of the Activity (i.e., the one in which it was created but that is not displayed anymore!). This can lead to an Exception (of the type java.lang.IllegalArgumentException: View not attached to window manager if you use, for instance, findViewById to retrieve a view inside the Activity).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Theres also the potential for this to result in a memory leak since the AsyncTask maintains a reference to the Activity, which prevents the Activity from being garbage collected as long as the AsyncTask remains alive.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;For these reasons, using AsyncTasks for long-running background tasks is generally a bad idea . Rather, for long-running background tasks, a different mechanism (such as a service) should be employed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: AsyncTasks by default run on a single thread using a serial executor, meaning it has only 1 thread and each task runs one after the other.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain &lt;code&gt;Looper&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Handler&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;HandlerThread&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-core-looper-handler-and-handlerthread-bd54d69fe91a&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rfLMwbOKLRk&amp;amp;list=PL6nth5sRD25hVezlyqlBO9dafKMc5fAU2&#34;&gt;from video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the threading work in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zfDYK-xB1Uo&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Memory Leak and Garbage Collection&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zCSSFRRIreo&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Working With Multimedia Content&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you handle bitmaps in Android as it takes too much memory?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/graphics/load-bitmap&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/graphics/manage-memory&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between a regular &lt;code&gt;Bitmap&lt;/code&gt; and a nine-patch image?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In general, a Nine-patch image allows resizing that can be used as background or other image size requirements for the target device. The Nine-patch refers to the way you can resize the image: 4 corners that are unscaled, 4 edges that are scaled in 1 axis, and the middle one that can be scaled into both axes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell about the &lt;code&gt;Bitmap&lt;/code&gt; pool.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-use-bitmap-pool-in-android-56c71a55533c&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to play sounds in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-mediaplayer-to-play-an-audio-file-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How image compression is preformed?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-image-compression-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Data Saving&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to persist data in an Android app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-shared-preferences-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is ORM? How does it work?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9OHzXUo3Ymk&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you preserve &lt;code&gt;Activity&lt;/code&gt; state during a screen rotation?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/3915952/how-to-save-state-during-orientation-change-in-android-if-the-state-is-made-of-m&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are different ways to store data in your Android app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-storage-system-to-store-data-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Scoped Storage in Android.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-the-scoped-storage-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to encrypt data in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-encrypt-data-safely-on-device-and-use-the-androidkeystore&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is commit() and apply() in SharedPreferences?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;commit() returns a boolean value of success or failure immediately by writing data synchronously.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;apply() is asynchronous and it won&#39;t return any boolean response. If you have an apply() outstanding and you are performing commit(), then the commit() will be blocked until the apply() is not completed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Look and Feel&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;Spannable&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/androiddevelopers/underspanding-spans-1b91008b97e4&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;SpannableString&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A SpannableString has immutable text, but its span information is mutable. Use a SpannableString when your text doesn&#39;t need to be changed but the styling does. Spans are ranges over the text that include styling information like color, heighliting, italics, links, etc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the best practices for using text in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/best-practices-for-using-text-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement Dark mode in any application?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/implementing-dark-mode-theme-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to generate dynamic colors based in image?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/color-palette-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain about Density Independence Pixel&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-density-independent-pixel-sp-dp-dip-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Memory Optimizations&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the &lt;code&gt;onTrimMemory()&lt;/code&gt; method?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/memory&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the OutOfMemory happens?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/practical-guide-to-solve-out-of-memory-error-in-android-application&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you find memory leaks in Android applications?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/practical-guide-to-solve-out-of-memory-error-in-android-application&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/blog/detecting-and-fixing-memory-leaks-in-android&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Battery Life Optimizations&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to reduce battery usage in an android application?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/battery-optimization-for-android-apps-f4ef6170ff70&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Doze? What about App Standby?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/monitoring-device-state/doze-standby&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;overdraw&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/rendering/overdraw.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Supporting Different Screen Sizes&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you support different types of resolutions?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/multiscreen/screensizes&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Permissions&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the different protection levels in permission?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-the-different-protection-levels-in-android-permission&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Native Programming&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the NDK and why is it useful?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iljxHVt7Arc&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/getting-started-with-android-ndk-android-tutorial&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iljxHVt7Arc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is renderscript?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/comparing-android-ndk-and-renderscript-1a718c01f6fe&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Android System Internal&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the Dalvik Virtual Machine?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-the-differences-between-dalvik-and-art&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference JVM, DVM and ART?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://android.jlelse.eu/closer-look-at-android-runtime-dvm-vs-art-1dc5240c3924&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the differences between Dalvik and ART?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-the-differences-between-dalvik-and-art&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DEX?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/dalvik/system/DexFile&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you manually call the Garbage collector?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/15632734/can-we-call-the-garbage-collector-explicitly&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Android Jetpack&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Android Jetpack and why to use this?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-is-android-jetpack-and-why-should-we-use-it&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Android Architecture Components?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-are-android-architecture-components&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is LiveData in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-livedata-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How LiveData is different from ObservableField?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/livedata-vs-observable-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between setValue and postValue in LiveData?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/livedata-setvalue-vs-postvalue-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to share ViewModel between Fragments in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/shared-viewmodel-in-android-shared-between-fragments&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Work Manager in Android.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/integrating-work-manager-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use-cases of WorkManager in Android.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4LTpYXFMnJw&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How ViewModel work internally?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-viewmodels-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Others&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Bundle class is used for data passing and why cannot we use simple Map data structure?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/guide/components/activities/parcelables-and-bundles&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you troubleshoot a crashing application?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/performance/vitals/crash&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Android notification system?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-increase-push-notification-delivery-rate-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between Serializable and Parcelable? Which is the best approach in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://android.jlelse.eu/parcelable-vs-serializable-6a2556d51538&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is AAPT?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/command-line/aapt2&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the best way to update the screen periodically?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/5452394/best-way-to-perform-an-action-periodically-while-an-app-is-running-handler&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FlatBuffers vs JSON.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/why-consider-flatbuffer-over-json-2e4aa8d4ed07&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;HashMap&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ArrayMap&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;SparseArray&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-app-optimization-using-arraymap-and-sparsearray-f2b4e2e3dc47&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Annotations?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/creating-custom-annotations-in-android-a855c5b43ed9&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/improve-your-android-coding-through-annotations-26b3273c137a&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEb9if2HHSw&#34;&gt;and from video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to create custom Annotation?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/creating-custom-annotations-in-android-a855c5b43ed9&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LEb9if2HHSw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to handle multi-touch in android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/gestures/multi&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement XML namespaces?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/reference/javax/xml/namespace/NamespaceContext&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the support library? Why was it introduced?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/support-library&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Android Data Binding?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/data-binding/index.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to check if Software keyboard is visible or not?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-check-the-visibility-of-software-keyboard-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to take screenshot in Android programmatically?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-programmatically-take-a-screenshot-on-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Android Libraries&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain OkHttp Interceptor&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/okhttp-interceptor-making-the-most-of-it&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OkHttp - HTTP Caching - How caching work in Android&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D6dQn6pUQD0&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell me something about RxJava.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/a-complete-guide-to-learn-rxjava-b55c0cea3631&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will you handle error in RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/error-handling-in-rxjava&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FlatMap Vs Map Operator&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/mindorks/rxjava-operator-map-vs-flatmap-427c09678784&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to use &lt;code&gt;Create&lt;/code&gt; operator and when to use &lt;code&gt;fromCallable&lt;/code&gt; operator of RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-rxjava-create-and-fromcallable-operator&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to use &lt;code&gt;defer&lt;/code&gt; operator of RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-rxjava-defer-operator&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are Timer, Delay, and Interval operators used in RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-rxjava-timer-delay-and-interval-operators&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to make two network calls in parallel using RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-rxjava-zip-operator-with-example&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell the difference between Concat and Merge.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/rxjava-operator-concat-vs-merge&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Subject in RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-rxjava-subject-publish-replay-behavior-and-async-subject-224d663d452f&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the types of Observables in RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-types-of-observables-in-rxjava-6c3a2d0819c8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement EventBus with RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/implementing-eventbus-with-rxjava-rxbus-e6c940a94bd8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement search feature using RxJava in your application?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/implement-search-using-rxjava-operators-c8882b64fe1d&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How The Android Image Loading Library Glide and Fresco Works?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-the-android-image-loading-library-glide-and-fresco-works-962bc9d1cc40&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between Schedulers.io() and Schedulers.computation() in RxJava.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do we use the Dependency Injection Framework like Dagger in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/why-do-we-use-the-dependency-injection-framework-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the Dagger work?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-annotation-processing-tutorial-part-1-a-practical-approach&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MindorksOpenSource/android-interview-questions/master/(https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Grzqz-B3NWU)&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Component in Dagger?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Grzqz-B3NWU&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Module in Dagger?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Grzqz-B3NWU&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the custom scope work in Dagger?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to call dispose and clear on CompositeDisposable in RxJava?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47057885/when-to-call-dispose-and-clear-on-compositedisposable&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Multipart Request in Networking?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p7SiNT0q1I8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Flow in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-is-flow-in-kotlin-and-how-to-use-it-in-android-project&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Android Architecture&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe the architecture of your last app.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe MVP.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/course/android-mvp-introduction&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe MVVM.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mvvm-architecture-android-tutorial-for-beginners-step-by-step-guide&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HJMZNF-tG-4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MVC vs MVP vs MVVM architecture.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mvc-mvp-mvvm-architecture-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is presenter?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/course/android-mvp-introduction&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is model?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/course/android-mvp-introduction&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe MVC.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mvc-mvp-mvvm-architecture-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe MVI&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MindorksOpenSource/MVI-Architecture-Android-Beginners&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe the repository pattern&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-mvp-architecture-extension-with-interactors-and-repositories-bd4b51972339&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is controller?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mvc-mvp-mvvm-architecture-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell something about clean code&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/every-programmer-should-read-this-book-6755dedec78d&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Android Design Problem&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Uber App.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MindorksOpenSource/ridesharing-uber-lyft-app&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Facebook App.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Facebook Near-By Friends App.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design WhatsApp.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design SnapChat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design problems based on location based app.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to build offline-first app? Explain the architecture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design LRU Cache.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design File Downloader&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MindorksOpenSource/PRDownloader&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design an Image Loading Library&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@maheswaranapk/android-create-your-own-image-loading-library-in-kotlin-diy-bc7be9f286c5&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP Request vs HTTP Long-Polling vs WebSockets&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k56H0DHqu5Y&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Android Unit Testing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Espresso?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/testing/ui-testing/espresso-testing.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Robolectric?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://robolectric.org/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the disadvantages of using Robolectric?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/18271474/robolectric-vs-android-test-framework&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is UI-Automator?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/testing/ui-testing/uiautomator-testing.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain unit test.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/testing/unit-testing/local-unit-tests&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain instrumented test.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/training/testing/unit-testing/instrumented-unit-tests&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you done unit testing or automatic testing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Mockito is used?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://site.mockito.org/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe JUnit test.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JUnit&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe code coverage.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/generate-global-code-coverage-report-in-android-development-using-jacoco-plugin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Android Tools And Technologies&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is ADB?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/command-line/adb&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is DDMS and what can you do with it?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/studio/profile/monitor&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the StrictMode?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/use-strictmode-to-find-things-you-did-by-accident-in-android-development-4cf0e7c8d997&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Lint? What is it used for?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-is-lint-what-is-it-used-for&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D4h8Dbrjt4M&amp;amp;list=PL6nth5sRD25itbyNVUULAebzL-VLrLfkK&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Development Useful Tools.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-development-useful-tools-fd73283e82e3&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Firebase.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://firebase.google.com/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to measure method execution time in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/measure-method-execution-time-in-android-debug-build&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you access your database of SQLite Database for debugging?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-access-sqlite-database-in-android-for-debugging&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are things that we need to take care while using Proguard?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/things-to-care-while-using-proguard-in-android-application&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Multidex in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-multidex-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use Android Studio Memory Profiler?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FxDa2td6Ej8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use Firebase realtime database in your app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/firebase-realtime-database-android-tutorial&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Gradle?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/gradle-for-android-developers-getting-the-most-of-it&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APK Size Reduction.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-reduce-apk-size-in-android-2f3713d2d662&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-r8-to-reduce-apk-size-in-android&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can you speed up the Gradle build?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/speed-up-gradle-build-for-android-to-save-your-time&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About gradle build system.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/gradle-for-android-developers-getting-the-most-of-it&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About multiple apk for android application.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/blog/how-to-create-multiple-apk-files-for-android-application&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is proguard used for?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/applying-proguard-in-an-android-application&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is obfuscation? What is it used for? What about minification?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yduedsaxfDw&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to change some parameters in an app without app update?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/getting-started-with-firebase-remote-config-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Java and Kotlin&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;OOP&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain OOP Concepts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Object-Oriented Programming is a methodology of designing a program using classes, objects, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inheritance_(object-oriented_programming)&#34;&gt;inheritance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polymorphism_(computer_science)&#34;&gt;polymorphism&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstraction_(software_engineering)&#34;&gt;abstraction&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Encapsulation_(computer_programming)&#34;&gt;encapsulation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between a constructor and a method?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The name of the constructor is same as that of the class name, whereas the name of the method can be anything.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is no return type of a constructor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you make an object of a class, then the constructor of that class will be called automatically. But for methods, we need to call it explicitely.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Constructors can&#39;t be inherited but you can call the constructor of the parent class by calling &lt;code&gt;super()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Constructor and a method they both run a block of code but the difference is in calling them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We can call method directly using their name.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Constructor Syntax -&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public class SomeClassName{&#xA;    SomeClassName(parameter_list){ &#xA;        ...&#xA;    } &#xA;    ...&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: In the above syntax, the name of the constructor is the same as that of class and it has no return type.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Method Syntax&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public class SomeClassName{&#xA;    public void someMethodName(parameter_list){&#xA;        ...&#xA;    }&#xA;    // call method&#xA;    someMethodName(parameter_list)&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differences between abstract classes and interfaces?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An abstract class, is a class that contains both concrete and abstract methods (methods without implementations). An abstract method must be implemented by the abstract class sub-classes. Abstract classes cannot be instantiated and need to be extended to be used.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An interface is like a blueprint/contract of a class (or it may be thought of as a class with methods, but without their implementation). It contains empty methods that represent, what all of its subclasses should have in common. The subclasses provide the implementation for each of these methods. Interfaces are implemented.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between iterator and enumeration in java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Enumeration we don&#39;t have remove() method and we can only read and traverse through a collection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Iterators can be applied to any collection. In Iterator, we can read and remove items from a collection.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you agree we use composition over inheritance?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journaldev.com/12086/composition-vs-inheritance&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between method overloading and overriding.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Overloading and Overriding&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/codeshef/android-interview-questions/raw/master/assets/overloading-vs-overriding.png&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Overloading happens at compile-time while Overriding happens at runtime: The binding of overloaded method call to its definition happens at compile-time however binding of overridden method call to its definition happens at runtime. More info on static vs. dynamic binding: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/19017258/static-vs-dynamic-binding-in-java&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Static methods can be overloaded which means a class can have more than one static method of same name. Static methods cannot be overridden, even if you declare a same static method in child class it has nothing to do with the same method of parent class as overridden static methods are chosen by the reference class and not by the class of the object.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So, for example:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public class Animal {&#xA;    public static void testClassMethod() {&#xA;        System.out.println(&#34;The static method in Animal&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    public void testInstanceMethod() {&#xA;        System.out.println(&#34;The instance method in Animal&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&#xA;public class Cat extends Animal {&#xA;    public static void testClassMethod() {&#xA;        System.out.println(&#34;The static method in Cat&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    public void testInstanceMethod() {&#xA;        System.out.println(&#34;The instance method in Cat&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    public static void main(String[] args) {&#xA;        Cat myCat = new Cat();&#xA;        myCat.testClassMethod();&#xA;        Animal myAnimal = myCat;&#xA;        myAnimal.testClassMethod();&#xA;        myAnimal.testInstanceMethod();&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Will output:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;The static method in Cat    // testClassMethod() is called from &#34;Cat&#34; reference&#xA;&#xA;The static method in Animal // testClassMethod() is called from &#34;Animal&#34; reference,&#xA;                            // ignoring actual object inside it (Cat)&#xA;&#xA;The instance method in Cat  // testInstanceMethod() is called from &#34;Animal&#34; reference,&#xA;                            // but from &#34;Cat&#34; object underneath&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most basic difference is that overloading is being done in the same class while for overriding base and child classes are required. Overriding is all about giving a specific implementation to the inherited method of parent class.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Static binding is being used for overloaded methods and dynamic binding is being used for overridden/overriding methods. Performance: Overloading gives better performance compared to overriding. The reason is that the binding of overridden methods is being done at runtime.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Private and final methods can be overloaded but they cannot be overridden. It means a class can have more than one private/final methods of same name but a child class cannot override the private/final methods of their base class.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Return type of method does not matter in case of method overloading, it can be same or different. However in case of method overriding the overriding method can have more specific return type (meaning if, for example, base method returns an instance of Number class, all overriding methods can return any class that is extended from Number, but not a class that is higher in the hierarchy, like, for example, Object is in this particular case).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Argument list should be different while doing method overloading. Argument list should be same in method Overriding. It is also a good practice to annotate overridden methods with &lt;code&gt;@Override&lt;/code&gt; to make the compiler be able to notify you if child is, indeed, overriding parent&#39;s class method during compile-time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the access modifiers you know? What does each one do?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There are four access modifiers in Java language (from strictest to the most lenient): &#xA;    &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;private&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;variables&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;methods&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;constructors&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;inner classes&lt;/em&gt; are only visible to its&#39; containing class and its&#39; methods. This modifier is most commonly used, for example, to allow variable access only through getters and setters or to hide underlying implementation of classes that should not be used by user and therefore maintain encapsulation. Singleton constructor is also marked &lt;code&gt;private&lt;/code&gt; to avoid unwanted instantiation from outside.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Default&lt;/code&gt; (no keyword is used) this modifier can be applied to &lt;em&gt;classes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;variables&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;constructors&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;methods&lt;/em&gt; and allows access from classes and methods inside the same package.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;protected&lt;/code&gt; can be used on &lt;em&gt;variables&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;methods&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;constructors&lt;/em&gt; therefore allowing access only to subclasses and classes that are inside the same package as protected members&#39; class.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; modifier is widely-used on &lt;em&gt;classes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;variables&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;constructors&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;methods&lt;/em&gt; to grant access from any class and method anywhere. It should not be used everywhere as it implies that data marked with &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; is not sensitive and can not be used to harm the program.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can an Interface implement another Interface?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Yes, an interface can implement another interface (and more than one), but it needs to use &lt;code&gt;extends&lt;/code&gt;, rather than &lt;code&gt;implements&lt;/code&gt; keyword. And while you can not remove methods from parent interface, you can add new ones freely to your sub-interface.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Polymorphism? What about Inheritance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Polymorphism in Java has two types: Compile time polymorphism (static binding) and Runtime polymorphism (dynamic binding). Method overloading is an example of static polymorphism, while method overriding is an example of dynamic polymorphism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An important example of polymorphism is how a parent class refers to a child class object. In fact, any object that satisfies more than one IS-A relationship is polymorphic in nature.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For instance, lets consider a class &lt;code&gt;Animal&lt;/code&gt; and let &lt;code&gt;Cat&lt;/code&gt; be a subclass of &lt;code&gt;Animal&lt;/code&gt;. So, any cat IS animal. Here, Cat satisfies the IS-A relationship for its own type as well as its super class Animal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Inheritance can be defined as the process where one class acquires the properties (methods and fields) of another. With the use of inheritance the information is made manageable in a hierarchical order.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The class which inherits the properties of other is known as subclass (derived class, child class) and the class whose properties are inherited is known as superclass (base class, parent class).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Inheritance uses the keyword &lt;code&gt;extends&lt;/code&gt; to inherit the properties of a class. Following is the syntax of extends keyword.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;class Super {&#xA;   .....&#xA;   .....&#xA;}&#xA;class Sub extends Super {&#xA;   .....&#xA;   .....&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple inheritance in Classes and Interfaces in java&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://codeinventions.blogspot.in/2014/07/can-interface-extend-multiple.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the design patterns?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mastering-design-patterns-in-android-with-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Creational patterns &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Builder &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Builder_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Factory &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Factory_method_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Singleton &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singleton_pattern&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Monostate &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.c2.com/?MonostatePattern&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Fluent Interface Pattern &lt;a href=&#34;https://martinfowler.com/bliki/FluentInterface.html&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Structural patterns &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Adapter &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adapter_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Decorator &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decorator_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Facade &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facade_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Behavioural patterns &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Chain of responsibility &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chain-of-responsibility_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Iterator &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iterator_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Strategy &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Strategy_pattern?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Collections and Generics&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrays Vs ArrayLists&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/32020000/what-is-the-difference-between-an-array-arraylist-and-a-list/32020072&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SMtSW3Zke_k&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HashSet Vs TreeSet&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/25602382/java-hashset-vs-treeset-when-should-i-use-over-other&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HashMap Vs Set&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2773824/difference-between-hashset-and-hashmap&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack Vs Queue&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/stack-and-queue&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Generics in Java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Generics were included in Java language to provide stronger type checks, by allowing the programmer to define, which classes can be used with other classes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;     &lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, generics enable types (classes and interfaces) to be parameters when defining classes, interfaces and methods. Much like the more familiar formal parameters used in method declarations, type parameters provide a way for you to re-use the same code with different inputs. The difference is that the inputs to formal parameters are values, while the inputs to type parameters are types. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/generics/why.html&#34;&gt;Official Java Documentation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;This means that, for example, you can define:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;List&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt; list = new ArrayList&amp;lt;&amp;gt;();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And let the compiler take care of noticing, if you put some object, of type other than &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; into this list and warn you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It should be noted that standard class hierarchy &lt;em&gt;does not&lt;/em&gt; apply to generic types. It means that &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;List&amp;lt;Integer&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is not inherited from &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Number&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; - it is actually inherited directly from &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Object&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. You can still put some constraints on what classes can be passed as a parameter into a generic by using &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/extra/generics/wildcards.html&#34;&gt;wildcards&lt;/a&gt; like &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;? extends MyCustomClass&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;? super Number&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;While generics are very useful, late inclusion into Java language has put some restraints on their implementation - backward compatibility required them to remain just &#34;syntactic sugar&#34; - they are erased (&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/generics/erasure.html&#34;&gt;type erasure&lt;/a&gt;) during compile-time and replaced with &lt;code&gt;object&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Java PriorityQueue?&lt;/strong&gt; - In Priority Queue, each element is having some priority and all the elements are present in a queue. The operations are performed based on the priority.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Objects and Primitives&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; class implemented? Why was it made immutable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is no primitive variant of &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; class in Java language - all strings are just wrappers around underlying array of characters, which is declared &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt;. This means that, once a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; object is instantiated, it cannot be changed through normal tools of the language (Reflection still can mess things up horribly, because in Java no object is truly immutable). This is why &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; variables in classes are the first candidates to be used, when you want to override &lt;code&gt;hashCode()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;equals()&lt;/code&gt; of your class - you can be sure, that all their required contracts will be satisfied.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;     &lt;p&gt;Note: The String class is immutable, so that once it is created a String object cannot be changed. The String class has a number of methods, some of which will be discussed below, that appear to modify strings. Since strings are immutable, what these methods really do is create and return a new string that contains the result of the operation. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/data/strings.html&#34;&gt;Official Java Documentation&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;This class is also unique in a sense, that, when you create an instance like this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;String helloWorld = &#34;Hello, World!&#34;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#34;Hello, World!&#34;&lt;/code&gt; is called a &lt;em&gt;literal&lt;/em&gt; and compiler creates a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; object with its&#39; value. So&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;String capital = &#34;Hello, World!&#34;.toUpperCase();&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;is a valid statement, that, firstly, will create an object with literal value &#34;Hello, World!&#34; and then will create and return another object with value &#34;HELLO, WORLD!&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; was made immutable to prevent malicious manipulation of data, when, for example, user login or other sensitive data is being send to a server.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does it means to say that a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; is immutable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;It means that once created, &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt; object&#39;s &lt;code&gt;char[]&lt;/code&gt; (its&#39; containing value) is declared &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; and, therefore, it can not be changed during runtime.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;String.intern()&lt;/code&gt;? When and why should it be used?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;String.intern()&lt;/code&gt; is used to mange memory in Java code. It is used when we have duplicates value in different strings. When you call the &lt;code&gt;String.intern()&lt;/code&gt;, then if in the String pool that string is present then the &lt;code&gt;equals()&lt;/code&gt; method will return true and it will return that string only.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you list 8 primitive types in java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;byte&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;short&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;long&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;float&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;double&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;boolean&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between an Integer and int?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; is a primitive data type (with &lt;code&gt;boolean&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;byte&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;char&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;short&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;long&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;float&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;double&lt;/code&gt;), while &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; (with &lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Byte&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Character&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Short&lt;/code&gt;,&lt;code&gt;Long&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Float&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Double&lt;/code&gt;) is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/data/numberclasses.html&#34;&gt;wrapper&lt;/a&gt; class that encapsulates primitive data type, while providing useful methods to perform different tasks with it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Autoboxing and Unboxing?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Autoboxing and Unboxing is the process of automatic wrapping (putting in a box) and unwrapping (getting the value out) of primitive data types, that have &#34;wrapper&#34; classes. So &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; can (almost always) be used interchangeably in Java language, meaning a method &lt;code&gt;void giveMeInt(int i) { ... }&lt;/code&gt; can take &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; as well as &lt;code&gt;Integer&lt;/code&gt; as a parameter.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typecast in Java&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Java, you can use casts to polymorph one class into another, compatible one. For example: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;    long i = 10l;&#xA;    int j = (int) i;&#xA;    long k = j;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; Here we see, that, while narrowing (&lt;code&gt;long i&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;int j&lt;/code&gt;) requires an explicit cast to make sure the programmer realizes, that there may be some data or precision loss, widening (&lt;code&gt;int j&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;long k&lt;/code&gt;) does not require an explicit cast, because there can be no data loss (&lt;code&gt;long&lt;/code&gt; can take larger numbers than &lt;code&gt;int&lt;/code&gt; allows).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do objects get passed by reference or value in Java? Elaborate on that.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In Java all primitives and objects are passed by value, meaning that their copy will be manipulated in the receiving method. But there is a caveat - when you pass an object reference into a method, a &lt;em&gt;copy of this reference&lt;/em&gt; is made, so it still points to the same object. This means, that any changes that you make to the insides of this object are retained, when the method exits. &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public class Pointer {&#xA;&#xA;    int innerField;&#xA;&#xA;    public Pointer(int a) {&#xA;        this.innerField = a;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public class ValueAndReference {&#xA;&#xA;    public static void main(String[] args) {&#xA;&#xA;        Pointer a = new Pointer(0);&#xA;        int b = 1;&#xA;&#xA;        print(&#34;Before:&#34;);&#xA;        print(&#34;b = &#34; + b);&#xA;        print(&#34;a.innerField = &#34; + a.innerField);&#xA;        exampleMethod(a, b);&#xA;        print(&#34;After:&#34;);&#xA;        print(&#34;b = &#34; + b);&#xA;        print(&#34;a.innerField = &#34; + a.innerField);&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    static void exampleMethod(Pointer a, int b) {&#xA;        a.innerField = 2;&#xA;        b = 10;&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    static void print(String text) {&#xA;        System.out.println(text);&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; Will output: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;    Before:&#xA;&#xA;    b = 1&#xA;&#xA;    a.innerField = 0&#xA;&#xA;    After:&#xA;&#xA;    b = 1        // a new local int variable was created and operated on, so &#34;b&#34; didn&#39;t change&#xA;&#xA;    a.innerField = 2 // Pointer a got its&#39; innerField variable changed&#xA;                     //  from 0 to 2, because method was operating on&#xA;                     //  the same reference to an instance&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between instantiation and initialization of an object?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/javaOO/objectcreation.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What the difference between local, instance and class variables?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Local variables exist only in methods that created them, they are stored separately in their respected Thread Stack (for more information, see question about Java Memory Model) and cannot have their reference passed outside of the method scope. That also means that they cannot be assigned any access modifier or made &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; - because they only exist during enclosing method&#39;s execution and those modifiers just do not make sense, since no other outside method can get them anyway.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Instance variables are the ones, that are declared in classes and their value can be different from one instance of the class to another, but they always require that class&#39; instance to exist.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Class variables are those, that are marked with &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; keyword in their class&#39; body. They can only have one value across all instances of that class (changing it in one place will change it in their class and, therefore, in all instances) and can even be retrieved without that class&#39; instance (if their access modifier allows it).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Java Memory Model and Garbage Collector&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is garbage collector? How does it work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;All objects are allocated on the heap area managed by the JVM. As long as an object is being referenced, the JVM considers it alive. Once an object is no longer referenced and therefore is not reachable by the application code, the garbage collector removes it and reclaims the unused memory.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Java Memory Model? What contracts does it guarantee? How are its&#39; Heap and Stack organized?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://tutorials.jenkov.com/java-concurrency/java-memory-model.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is memory leak and how does Java handle it?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.redhat.com/blog/2014/08/14/find-fix-memory-leaks-java-application/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are strong, soft, weak and phantom references in Java?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://dzone.com/articles/weak-soft-and-phantom-references-in-java-and-why-they-matter&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Concurrency&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does the keyword &lt;code&gt;synchronized&lt;/code&gt; mean?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/a/1085745/2621950&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a &lt;code&gt;ThreadPoolExecutor&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/threadpoolexecutor-in-android-8e9d22330ee3&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;volatile&lt;/code&gt; modifier?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://tutorials.jenkov.com/java-concurrency/volatile.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The classes in the atomic package expose a common set of methods: &lt;code&gt;get&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;set,&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lazyset&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;compareAndSet&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;weakCompareAndSet&lt;/code&gt;. Please describe them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Exceptions&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the &lt;code&gt;try{}&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;catch{}&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt; works?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z_5e8MjRWnc&amp;amp;list=PL6nth5sRD25g_M_OgsMQgYIrESzzkGLME&amp;amp;index=13&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between a &lt;code&gt;Checked Exception&lt;/code&gt; and an &lt;code&gt;Un-Checked Exception&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.in/java-questions-answers/difference-between-checked-and-unchecked-exceptions-in-java/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Others&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is serialization? How do you implement it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Serialization is the process of converting an object into a stream of bytes in order to store an object into memory, so that it can be recreated at a later time, while still keeping the object&#39;s original state and data. In Android you may use either the Serializable, Externalizable (implements Serializable) or Parcelable interfaces.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;While Serializable is the easiest to implement, Externalizable may be used if you need to insert custom logic into the process of serialization (although it is almost never used nowadays as it is considered a relic from early versions of Java). But it is highly recommended to use Parcelable in Android instead, as Parcelable was created exclusively for Android and it performs about 10x faster than Serializable, because Serializable uses reflection, which is a slow process and tends to create a lot of temporary objects and it may cause garbage collection to occur more often.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To use Serializable all you have to do is implement the interface:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;/**&#xA;*  Implementing the Serializable interface is all that is required&#xA;*/&#xA;public class User implements Serializable {&#xA;&#xA;    private String name;&#xA;    private String email;&#xA;&#xA;        public User() {&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public String getName() {&#xA;            return name;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public void setName(final String name) {&#xA;            this.name = name;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public String getEmail() {&#xA;            return email;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public void setEmail(final String email) {&#xA;            this.email = email;&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Parcelable requires a bit more work:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;    public class User implements Parcelable {&#xA;&#xA;        private String name;&#xA;        private String email;&#xA;&#xA;        /**&#xA;         * Interface that must be implemented and provided as a public CREATOR field&#xA;         * that generates instances of your Parcelable class from a Parcel.&#xA;         */&#xA;        public static final Creator&amp;lt;User&amp;gt; CREATOR = new Creator&amp;lt;User&amp;gt;() {&#xA;&#xA;            /**&#xA;             * Creates a new USer object from the Parcel. This is the reason why&#xA;             * the constructor that takes a Parcel is needed.&#xA;             */&#xA;            @Override&#xA;            public User createFromParcel(Parcel in) {&#xA;                return new User(in);&#xA;            }&#xA;&#xA;            /**&#xA;             * Create a new array of the Parcelable class.&#xA;             * @return an array of the Parcelable class,&#xA;             * with every entry initialized to null.&#xA;             */&#xA;            @Override&#xA;            public User[] newArray(int size) {&#xA;                return new User[size];&#xA;            }&#xA;        };&#xA;&#xA;        public User() {&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        /**&#xA;         * Parcel overloaded constructor required for&#xA;         * Parcelable implementation used in the CREATOR&#xA;         */&#xA;        private User(Parcel in) {&#xA;            name = in.readString();&#xA;            email = in.readString();&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public String getName() {&#xA;            return name;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public void setName(final String name) {&#xA;            this.name = name;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public String getEmail() {&#xA;            return email;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        public void setEmail(final String email) {&#xA;            this.email = email;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        @Override&#xA;        public int describeContents() {&#xA;            return 0;&#xA;        }&#xA;&#xA;        /**&#xA;         * This is where the parcel is performed.&#xA;         */&#xA;        @Override&#xA;        public void writeToParcel(final Parcel parcel, final int i) {&#xA;            parcel.writeString(name);&#xA;            parcel.writeString(email);&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: For a full explanation of the &lt;b&gt;describeContents()&lt;/b&gt; method see &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/4076946/parcelable-where-when-is-describecontents-used/4914799#4914799&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;. In Android Studio, you can have all of the parcelable code auto generated for you, but like with everything else, it is always a good thing to try and understand everything that is happening.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;transient&lt;/code&gt; modifier?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.javatpoint.com/transient-keyword&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are anonymous classes?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.oracle.com/javase/tutorial/java/javaOO/anonymousclasses.html&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between using &lt;code&gt;==&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;.equals&lt;/code&gt; on an object?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aVjnX1MIHB8&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the &lt;code&gt;hashCode()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;equals()&lt;/code&gt; used for?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/equals-hashcode-methods-java/&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why would you not call abstract method in constructor?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/15327417/is-it-ok-to-call-abstract-method-from-constructor-in-java&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When would you make an object value &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are these &lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;finalize&lt;/code&gt; keywords?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; is a keyword in the java language. It is used to apply restrictions on class, method and variable. Final class can&#39;t be inherited, final method can&#39;t be overridden and final variable value can&#39;t be changed. &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;class FinalExample {&#xA;    public static void main(String[] args) {&#xA;        final int x=100;&#xA;        x=200;//Compile Time Error because x is final&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;finally&lt;/code&gt; is a code block and is used to place important code, it will be executed whether exception is handled or not. &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;class FinallyExample {&#xA;    public static void main(String[] args) {&#xA;        try {&#xA;            int x=300;&#xA;        }catch(Exception e) {&#xA;            System.out.println(e.getMessage());            }&#xA;        finally {&#xA;            System.out.println(&#34;finally block is executed&#34;);&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Finalize&lt;/code&gt; is a method used to perform clean up processing just before object is garbage collected. &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;class FinalizeExample {&#xA;    public void finalize() {&#xA;        System.out.println(&#34;finalize called&#34;);&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    public static void main(String[] args) {&#xA;        FinalizeExample f1=new FinalizeExample();&#xA;        FinalizeExample f2=new FinalizeExample();&#xA;        f1=null;&#xA;        f2=null;&#xA;        System.gc();&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between &#34;throw&#34; and &#34;throws&#34; keyword in Java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;throws&lt;/code&gt; is just used to indicated which exception is to be thrown. But the &lt;code&gt;throw&lt;/code&gt; keyword is used to throw some exception from any static block or any method.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does the &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; word mean in Java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;In case of &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; variable it means that this variable (its&#39; value or the object it references) spans across all instances of enclosing class (changing it in one instance affects all others), while in case of &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; methods it means that these methods can be invoked without an instance of their enclosing class. It is useful, for example, when you create util classes that need not be instantiated every time you want to use them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can a &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; method be overridden in Java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;While child class can override a static method with another static method with the same signature (return type can be down-casted), it is not truly overridden - it becomes &#34;hidden&#34;, but both methods can still be accessed under right circumstances (see question about overloading/overriding above).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When is a &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; block run?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Code inside static block is executed only once: the first time you make an object of that class or the first time you access a static member of that class (even if you never make an object of that class).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is reflection?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can inspect classes, interfaces, fields, and method at runtime with the help of reflection and the best part is that you need not know the names of these classes, methods, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Dependency Injection?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Grzqz-B3NWU&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How is a &lt;code&gt;StringBuilder&lt;/code&gt; implemented to avoid the immutable string allocation problem?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/54023816/how-is-a-stringbuilder-implemented-to-avoid-the-immutable-string-allocation-prob&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between &lt;code&gt;StringBuffer&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;StringBuilder&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journaldev.com/538/string-vs-stringbuffer-vs-stringbuilder&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between fail-fast and fail-safe iterators in Java?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fail-safe iterator will not throw any exception even if the collection is modified while iteration over it. But in Fail-safe iterator, it throws a ConcurrentModificationException when you try to modify the collection while using it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Java NIO?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Non-blocking_I/O_(Java)&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor and Synchronization&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oLTw1aJpSho&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell some advantages of Kotlin.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kRhivT-jKzY&amp;amp;t=16s&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between &lt;code&gt;val&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;var&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/44200075/val-and-var-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between &lt;code&gt;const&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;val&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-is-the-difference-between-const-and-val&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to ensure &lt;code&gt;null&lt;/code&gt; safety in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/safecalls-vs-nullchecks-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to use &lt;code&gt;lateint&lt;/code&gt; keyword used in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-lateinit-vs-lazy&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to check if a &lt;code&gt;lateinit&lt;/code&gt; variable has been initialized?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-check-if-a-lateinit-variable-has-been-initialized&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to do lazy initialization of variables in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-lateinit-vs-lazy&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yEX9_PeNRy4&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are &lt;code&gt;companion objects&lt;/code&gt; in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/companion-object-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the visibility modifiers in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-visibility-modifiers-private-protected-internal-public&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the equivalent of Java static methods in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/what-is-the-equivalent-of-java-static-methods-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is a data class in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-data-class&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to create a Singleton class in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-create-a-singleton-class-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the difference between &lt;code&gt;open&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;public&lt;/code&gt; in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-open-keyword-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain the use-case of &lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;run&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;also&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;apply&lt;/code&gt; in Kotlin.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-scoped-functions-in-kotlin-let-run-with-also-apply&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AiFBEH54Xpw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difference between List and Array types in Kotlin&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/difference-between-list-and-array-types-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are &lt;code&gt;Labels&lt;/code&gt; in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-returns-jumps-labels&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an &lt;code&gt;Init&lt;/code&gt; block in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-init-block-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain &lt;code&gt;pair&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;triple&lt;/code&gt; in Kotlin.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/pair-and-triple-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to choose between &lt;code&gt;apply&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;with&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-apply-vs-with&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to choose between &lt;code&gt;switch&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;when&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/replace-switch-with-when-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Coroutines in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mastering-kotlin-coroutines-in-android-step-by-step-guide&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Coroutine Scope?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mastering-kotlin-coroutines-in-android-step-by-step-guide&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Coroutine Context?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mastering-kotlin-coroutines-in-android-step-by-step-guide&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launch vs Async in Kotlin Coroutines&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nC30UiDv8Xc&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is inline function in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-inline-noinline-and-crossinline-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to use Kotlin sealed classes?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/learn-kotlin-sealed-classes&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain function literals with receiver in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/function-literals-with-receiver-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell about Kotlin DSL.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/mastering-kotlin-dsl-in-android-step-by-step-guide&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are higher-order functions in Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-higher-order-functions-and-lambdas-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are Lambdas in Kotlin&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-higher-order-functions-and-lambdas-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell about the Collections in Kotlin&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XeRt2ZZ-jkA&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Data Structures And Algorithms&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;The level of questions asked on the topic of Data Structures And Algorithms totally depends on the company for which you are applying.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Whiteboard Interview Series - Data Structures and Algorithms on Youtube - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLqOiaH9id5qt_lZl2bFi8q9RQoV1JJUpf&#34;&gt;Check here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Tech Interview Preparation Kit - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview&#34;&gt;Check here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Android Developer should know these Data Structures for Next Interview - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-developer-should-know-these-data-structures-for-next-interview&#34;&gt;Check here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complexity Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/complexity-analysis&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Input, Output, Correctness, Efficiency of Algorithms?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Input Size and Running Time of Algorithms?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain the Worst, Best, and Average case analysis of Algorithms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Big-O Notation with respect to Time and Space Complexity?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iteration and Two Pointer Approach&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/iteration-and-two-pointer-approach&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Initialization, Maintenance, and Termination used in iteration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain the use-case of Two Pointer approach&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recursion and Divide &amp;amp; Conquer Approach&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/recursion-and-divide-and-conquer-approach&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Recursion with the help of an example and also draw the recursion call stack for the same.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How will you analyse the recursive solution of some problem?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Is there any difference between Recursion and Iteration?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain the Divide and Conquer technique with the help of a real-world example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arrays and Linked List&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/array-and-linked-list&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What do you mean by Linear Data Structures?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain the basic operations that can be performed on Arrays? Also, tell about Amortized analysis of array.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Linked List? Explain with an example by performing some operations on Linked List.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are the types of Linked List?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can you tell the difference between an Array and a Linked List?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stack and Queue&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/stack-and-queue&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Stack? Explain various operations that can be performed on a Stack.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can you implement Stack using an Array or using a Linked List? How?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Queue? Explain various operations that can be performed on a Queue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can you implement Queue using an Array or using a Linked List? How?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Is there any difference between a Stack and a Queue?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sorting Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sorting_algorithm?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Using the most efficient sorting algorithm (and correct data structures that implement it) is vital for any program, because data manipulation can be one of the most significant bottlenecks in case of performance and the main purpose of spending time, determining the best algorithm for the job, is to drastically improve said performance. The efficiency of an algorithm is measured in its&#39; &#34;Big O&#34; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/487258/what-is-a-plain-english-explanation-of-big-o-notation&#34;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;) score. Really good algorithms perform important actions in O(n log n) or even O(log n) time and some of them can even perform certain actions in O(1) time (HashTable insertion, for example). But there is always a trade-off - if some algorithm is really good at adding a new element to a data structure, it is, most certainly, much worse at data access than some other algorithm. If you are proficient with math, you may notice that &#34;Big O&#34; notation has many similarities with &#34;limits&#34;, and you would be right - it measures best, worst and average performances of an algorithm in question, by looking at its&#39; function limit. It should be noted that, when we are speaking about O(1) - constant time - we are not saying that this algorithm performs an action in one operation, rather that it can perform this action with the same number of operations (roughly), regrardless of the amount of elements it has to take into account. Thankfully, a lot of &#34;Big O&#34; scores have been already calculated, so you don&#39;t have to guess, which algorithm or data structure will perform better in your project. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bigocheatsheet.com/&#34;&gt;&#34;Big O&#34; cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Bubble sort &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bubble_sort?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Bubble sort is one of the simplest sorting algorithms. It just compares neighbouring elements and if the one that precedes the other is smaller - it changes their places. So over one iteration over the data list, it is guaranteed that &lt;strong&gt;at least&lt;/strong&gt; one element will be in its&#39; correct place (the biggest/smallest one - depending on the direction of sorting). This is not a very efficient algorithm, as highly unordered arrays will require a lot of reordering (upto O(n^2)), but one of the advantages of this algorithm is its&#39; space complexity - only two elements are compared at once and there is no need to allocate more memory, than those two will occupy. &#xA;      &lt;table&gt; &#xA;       &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th colspan=&#34;3&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Time Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Space Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;       &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Selection sort &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Selection_sort&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Firstly, selection sort assumes that the first element of the array to be sorted is the smallest, but to confirm this, it iterates over all other elements to check, and if it finds one, it gets defined as the smallest one. When the data ends, the element, that is currently found to be the smallest, is put in the beginning of the array. This sorting algorithm is quite straightforward, but still not that efficient on larger data sets, because to assign just one element to its&#39; place, it needs to go over all data. &#xA;      &lt;table&gt; &#xA;       &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th colspan=&#34;3&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Time Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Space Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;       &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Insertion sort &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insertion_sort?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Insertion sort is another example of an algorithm, that is not that difficult to implement, but is also not that efficient. To do its&#39; job, it &#34;grows&#34; sorted portion of data, by &#34;inserting&#34; new encountered elements into already (innerly) sorted part of the array, which consists of previously encountered elements. This means that in best case (data is already sorted) it can confirm that its&#39; job is done in (n) operations, while, if all encountered elements are not in their required order as many as O(n^2) operations may be needed. &#xA;      &lt;table&gt; &#xA;       &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th colspan=&#34;3&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Time Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Space Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(1)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;       &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Merge sort &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Merge_sort?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;This is a &#34;divide and conquer&#34; algorithm, meaning it recursively &#34;divides&#34; given array in to smaller parts (up to 1 element) and then sorts those parts, combining them with each other. This approach allows merge sort to achieve very high speed, while doubling required space, of course, but today memory space is more available than it was a couple of years ago, so this trade-off is considered acceptable. &#xA;      &lt;table&gt; &#xA;       &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th colspan=&#34;3&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Time Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Space Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n log(n))&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n log(n))&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n log(n))&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;       &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Quicksort &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quicksort?oldformat=true&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Quicksort is considered, well, quite quick. When implemented correctly, it can be a significant number of times faster than its&#39; main competitors. This algorithm is also of &#34;divide and conquer&#34; family and its&#39; first step is to choose a &#34;pivot&#34; element (choosing it randomly, statistically, minimizes the chance to get the worst performance), then by comparing elements to this pivot, moving it closer and closer to its&#39; final place. During this process, the elements that are bigger are moved to the right side of it and smaller elements to the left. After this is done, quicksort repeats this process for subarrays on each side of placed pivot (does first step recursively), until the array is sorted. &#xA;      &lt;table&gt; &#xA;       &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th colspan=&#34;3&#34; align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Time Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Space Complexity&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Average&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;         &lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Worst&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;        &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n log(n))&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;(n log(n))&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n^2)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;         &lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;O(n)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;       &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There are, of course, more sorting algorithms and their modifications. We strongly recommend all readers to familiarize themselves with a couple more, because knowing algorithms is very important quality of a candidate, applying for a job and it shows understanding of what is happening &#34;under the hood&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary Tree&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/binary-tree&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are non-linear data structures? Give example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Tree Data Structure? Explain the properties of tree with an example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How is Binary Tree different from a normal Tree?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is inorder, pre-order, post-order, and level-order traversal of a tree? Explain with an example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can you find the inorder, pre-order, and post-order of a tree using Stack? How?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain how searching, insertion, and deletion operations are performed on a Tree?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary Search Tree&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/binary-search-tree&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Binary Search Tree? Explain its properties also.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain how searching, insertion, and deletion operations are performed on a Binary Search Tree?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How is Binary Search Tree different from Binary Tree?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heap and Priority Queue&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/heap-and-priority-queue&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Heap data structure and when it is used?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain the operations that can be performed on a Heap.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is the difference between a min-heap and a max-heap? How to implement these two?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What do you mean by Priority Queue? How to implement Priority Queue?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are the real-life applications of Priority Queue?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hash Table&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/hash-table&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What do you mean by Direct Address Table?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can you perform search, insert, and delete in O(1)? How?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Hash Table and its properties.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How to remove collision in Hash Table by Chaining and Open Addressing?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are the real-life applications of Hash Table?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Programming&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/dynamic-programming&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Dynamic Programming and how to find if a problem can be solved using DP or not?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are two approaches of solving a Dynamic Programming problem?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Optimization and Combinatorial problems?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greedy Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/greedy-algorithms&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What do you mean by Greedy algorithms? How to find if a problem can be solved by Greedy approach or not?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Is there any difference between Dynamic Programming and Greedy Algorithms?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backtracking&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/backtracking&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Backtracking?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How to find if a problem can be solved with Backtracking or not?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Exhaustive Searching?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graph&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/tech-interview/ds-algo-concepts/graph&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is Graph and how to represent a Graph?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Depth First Search and Breadth First Search.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;How to represent a Graph?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What are the real-life applications of Graph?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What do you mean by Topological Sorting?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Explain Dijkstra algorithm with an example.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;What is a Minimum Spanning Tree?&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other Topics&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe how REST APIs work. What is REST?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1wSEI6_SzMU&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HgXAoBomGcA&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe SQLite.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-sqlite-database-in-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9OHzXUo3Ymk&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe database.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://afteracademy.com/blog/what-is-a-database-and-dbms&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you control the application version update to specific number of users?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can we identify users who have uninstalled our application?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Development Best Practices.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-development-best-practices-83c94b027fd3&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Android Code Style And Guidelines.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-code-style-and-guidelines-d5f80453d5c7&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you tried Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/why-you-must-try-kotlin-for-android-development-e14d00c8084b&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the metrics that you should measure continuously while android application development?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-app-performance-metrics-a1176334186e&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Chrome Custom Tabs? How to display web content in your app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-browser-lets-launch-chrome-custom-tabs-with-kotlin&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to avoid API keys from check-in into VCS?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-local-properties-file-to-avoid-api-keys-check-in-into-version-control-system&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the Kotlin Multiplatform work?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-does-the-kotlin-multiplatform-work&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use Memory Heap Dumps data?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-use-memory-heap-dumps-data&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to implement Dark Theme in your app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/build-material-and-dark-themes-apps-using-style-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have you tried Jetpack compose?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-jetpack-compose-to-build-ui-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to secure the API keys used in an app?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/securing-api-keys-using-android-ndk&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to convert check Java equivalent code of Kotlin?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-convert-a-kotlin-source-file-to-a-java-source-file&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell something about memory usage in Android.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/understanding-memory-usage-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Benchmarking?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/improving-android-app-performance-with-benchmarking&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you create transparent activity in Android?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-create-a-transparent-activity-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to use Android Sensors?&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/using-android-sensors-android-tutorial&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explain Annotation processing.&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/android-annotation-processing-tutorial-part-1-a-practical-approach&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to increase the Notification delivery rate?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-increase-push-notification-delivery-rate-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does the notification system work?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-increase-push-notification-delivery-rate-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to show local Notification at an exact time?&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mindorks.com/how-to-increase-push-notification-delivery-rate-in-android&#34;&gt;Learn from here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Found this project useful &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support by clicking the &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; button on the upper right of this page. &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mindorks.com/open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Check out MindOrks awesome open source projects here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   Copyright (C) 2020 MINDORKS NEXTGEN PRIVATE LIMITED&#xA;&#xA;   Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &#34;License&#34;);&#xA;   you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.&#xA;   You may obtain a copy of the License at&#xA;&#xA;       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&#xA;&#xA;   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software&#xA;   distributed under the License is distributed on an &#34;AS IS&#34; BASIS,&#xA;   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.&#xA;   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and&#xA;   limitations under the License.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing to Android Interview Questions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just make pull request. You are in!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>