<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-22T01:40:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>datavane/datasophon</title>
    <updated>2023-06-22T01:40:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-22:/datavane/datasophon</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/datavane/datasophon" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is committed to rapidly implementing the deployment, management, monitoring and automatic operation and maintenance of the big data cloud native platform, helping you quickly build a stable, efficient, elastic and scalable big data cloud native platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gaodayu168/datasophon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datavane/datasophon/dev/website/static/img/logo.png&#34; width=&#34;20%&#34; height=&#34;20%&#34; alt=&#34;DataSophon Logo&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA; &lt;h1&gt;DataSophon&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Makes it easy to manage and monitor clusters&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/release/gaodayu168/datasophon.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/gaodayu168/datasophon&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/gaodayu168/datasophon&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%202-4EB1BA.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://datasophon.github.io/datasophon-website/&#34;&gt;Office Website&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/datasophon/datasophon/raw/dev/README_CN.md&#34;&gt;Chinese&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;If you like,star fork it and join us&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Vision&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aiming at quickly deploying,managing,monitoring and automating the operation and maintenance of Big Data service components and nodes,helping you quickly build stable, efficient Big Data cluster services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;What is DataSophon?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Three-Body Problem&lt;/em&gt;, a Hugo Award-winning work of the world&#39;s highest science fiction literature, is known for its stunning &#34;hard science fiction&#34; style, and its author Liu Cixin is credited with &#34;single-handedly raising Chinese science fiction to a world-class level&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a very important role in the Triad, the Sophon is a two-dimensional unfolding of the nine-dimensional proton, which is transformed into a supercomputer through circuit etching and then transferred back to the microscopic eleventh dimension to monitor every human movement and use quantum entanglement to achieve instantaneous communication to report to the Triad civilization four light years away. To put it bluntly, the Sophon is a AI real-time remote monitoring and management platform deployed by the Triad civilization on Earth.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DataSophon is a similar management platform. Unlike the Sophon, which aims to limit human&#39;s basic science and hinder human&#39;s technology development, DataSophon is dedicated to automatical monitoring, operation and management of Big Data infrastructure components and nodes, helping you to quickly build a stable, efficient Big Data cluster service.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Easy to deploy, can quickly complete the deployment of about 300 nodes of big data clusters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nationalization compatible, compatible with arm servers and common localized operating systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive and rich monitoring indicators, showing that the users care about most, based on production practice.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Flexible and convenient alarm service, which can realize user-defined alarm groups and alarm indicators&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Strong scalability, users can integrate or upgrade any components through configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datavane/datasophon/dev/website/static/img/dashboard.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Product Architecture&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datavane/datasophon/dev/website/static/img/product-en.png&#34; alt=&#34;product-en&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Architecture&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/datavane/datasophon/dev/website/static/img/archive.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For questions, bugs and supports please open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gaodayu168/datasophon/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;, we&#39;ll reply you in time.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>IridiumIdentity/iridium</title>
    <updated>2023-06-22T01:40:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-22:/IridiumIdentity/iridium</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/IridiumIdentity/iridium" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A low-code, customer identity and access management (CIAM) system for social provider integration&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Iridium&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IridiumIdentity/iridium/main/assets/color/iridium-3C-large.png&#34; alt=&#34;iridium&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is iridium?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iridium is an OAuth2.x-compliant customer identity and access management (CIAM) system. It allows developers to integrate 3rd party social login providers into their own systems in a low-code manner.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is a social login provider?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a 3rd party authorization services like Github, Google, Twitter, Microsoft etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IridiumIdentity/iridium/main/assets/system-overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;system-overview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why is this important&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iridium helps developers improve the customer experience by providing a seamless and customizable log in experience with a low-code approach. With Iridium, you can reduce development time and streamline product development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcoming Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are just getting started!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We are welcoming, inclusive, and friendly&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Iridium is 100% free and open source. We encourage and support an active, healthy community that accepts contributions from the public – including you!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Our end goal isn&#39;t to hang on to Iridium. Once we get the project and community built up enough, we&#39;d like to donate the the project to a larger managing organization. Help us get there.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We need your help, this project is early in terms of open source releases, we need as many eyes on it as we can.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/IridiumIdentity/iridium/discussions&#34;&gt;Participate in discussions on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why build Iridium?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve used other closed-source providers and found that the biggest issue when things go wrong is the options for support are minimal, communities don&#39;t exist, and because of this people are often left making best guesses on how to implement authentication or authorization into their system. Iridium is here to give you a path forward in managing your customers seamless log in experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How can I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many places to start. You can start with documentation, fixing bugs related to issues, helping with building examples, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to you telling us how we can make the project better.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/IridiumIdentity/iridium/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>