<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Java Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-09T01:36:14Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Java in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>lcomplete/huntly</title>
    <updated>2023-03-09T01:36:14Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-09:/lcomplete/huntly</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lcomplete/huntly" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Huntly, information management tool, rss reader, automatic saving browsed contents include tweets, github stars management tool. 信息管理工具、RSS 阅读器、GitHub stars 管理、推文管理、自动记录浏览过的文章。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Huntly&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/lcomplete/huntly/main/README.zh-CN.md&#34;&gt;中文&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Huntly is a self-hosted information management tool, in simple terms, contains the following features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RSS subscription and reading.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically saves the pages that have been viewed， then you can saves them as read later, favorites or archives.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There is a special treatment for Twitter sites that automatically saves the requested tweet timeline, recording whether it has been viewed or not, and in huntly you can even revisit these tweets in a more convenient way.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You can search by title, content, type, favorite method, and other dimensions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect to other services, currently GitHub is supported, so it&#39;s also a Github stars management tool.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the future, it may support connections to services like Pocket, Hypothesis, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Demo: &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntly.rom666.com:8000/&#34;&gt;http://huntly.rom666.com:8000/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Username: demo&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Password: huntlydemo&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Java 11&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Running the server side&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use docker or java to run the server.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Run with docker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;docker run -d --name huntly -p &amp;lt;host port&amp;gt;:80 -v &amp;lt;host directory&amp;gt;:/data lcomplete/huntly:&amp;lt;tag&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;host port&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;host directory&amp;gt; Replace with the ones you want to use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;tag&amp;gt; Replace with the version number, which is currently &lt;code&gt;0.1.0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Run with the Java command&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the jar package from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lcomplete/huntly/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;, in which the react client is also packaged.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After downloading, cd to the current directory from the command line and run it with the following Java command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;java -Xms128m -Xmx1024m -jar huntly-server-0.1.0-SNAPSHOT.jar&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default it runs on port 8080, you can open the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8080/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8080/&lt;/a&gt; port for access, or if you need to use another port, such as port 80, you can run the following command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;java -Xms128m -Xmx1024m -jar huntly-server-0.1.0-SNAPSHOT.jar --server.port=80&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that the Jar package name needs to be modified appropriately according to the downloaded package name.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install the browser extension&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: The plugin is still under development and is not yet available on the Google Play Store.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the browser-extension.zip from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lcomplete/huntly/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; and unpack it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manage the extension in your browser, enable developer mode, and load the unpacked extension.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Browser extension settings&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Click the huntly extension icon, choose to set huntly&#39;s server address, for example, when using the demo server, then set it to &lt;a href=&#34;http://huntly.rom666.com:8000/&#34;&gt;http://huntly.rom666.com:8000/&lt;/a&gt;, for the remote address, in formal use, it is highly recommended to use the https protocol, after all, the browsing history is quite private. If the server is running locally, then set it to the local address.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Login and enjoy it&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you open huntly website for the first time, you will be prompted to register an administrator user, currently only single user is supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After registration, you will be automatically logged into the system, and the huntly extension will only send browsing history to the server if you are logged in.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>