<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TypeScript Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-06T02:03:42Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TypeScript in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>langgenius/dify</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T02:03:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-06:/langgenius/dify</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/langgenius/dify" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One API for plugins and datasets, one interface for prompt engineering and visual operation, all for creating powerful AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/images/describe-en.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README.md&#34;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README_CN.md&#34;&gt;简体中文&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README_JA.md&#34;&gt;日本語&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/README_ES.md&#34;&gt;Español&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dify.ai&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai/getting-started/install-self-hosted&#34;&gt;Deployment Docs&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai/getting-started/faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dify_ai&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dify&lt;/strong&gt; is an easy-to-use LLMOps platform designed to empower more people to create sustainable, AI-native applications. With visual orchestration for various application types, Dify offers out-of-the-box, ready-to-use applications that can also serve as Backend-as-a-Service APIs. Unify your development process with one API for plugins and datasets integration, and streamline your operations using a single interface for prompt engineering, visual analytics, and continuous improvement.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Applications created with Dify include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out-of-the-box web sites supporting form mode and chat conversation mode A single API encompassing plugin capabilities, context enhancement, and more, saving you backend coding effort Visual data analysis, log review, and annotation for applications&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Highlighted Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. LLMs support:&lt;/strong&gt; Choose capabilities based on different models when building your Dify AI apps. Dify is compatible with Langchain, meaning it will support various LLMs. Currently supported:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;OpenAI: GPT-4, GPT-3.5-turbo, GPT-3.5-turbo-16k, text-davinci-003&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Azure OpenAI Service&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Anthropic: Claude2, Claude-instant&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Hugging Face Hub (coming soon)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We provide the following free resources for registered Dify cloud users (sign up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://dify.ai&#34;&gt;dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;1000 free Claude model queries to build Claude-powered apps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;200 free OpenAI queries to build OpenAI-based apps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Visual orchestration:&lt;/strong&gt; Build an AI app in minutes by writing and debugging prompts visually.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Text embedding:&lt;/strong&gt; Fully automated text preprocessing embeds your data as context without complex concepts. Supports PDF, TXT, and syncing data from Notion, webpages, APIs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. API-based:&lt;/strong&gt; Backend-as-a-service. Access web apps directly or integrate via APIs without complex backend setup.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Plugins:&lt;/strong&gt; Dify &#34;Smart Chat&#34; now supports first-party plugins like web browsing, Google search, Wikipedia to enable online lookup, analyzing web content, and explaining the AI&#39;s reasoning process conversationally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Team workspaces:&lt;/strong&gt; Team members can join workspaces to collaboratively edit, manage, and use team AI apps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Data labeling and improvement:&lt;/strong&gt; Visually inspect AI app logs and improve data via labeling. Observe the AI&#39;s reasoning process to continuously enhance performance. (Coming soon)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use cases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai/use-cases/create-an-ai-chatbot-with-business-data-in-minutes&#34;&gt;Create an AI ChatBot with Business Data in Minutes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai/use-cases/build-an-notion-ai-assistant&#34;&gt;How to Build an Notion AI Assistant Based on Your Own Notes?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.dify.ai/use-cases/create-a-midjoureny-prompt-bot-with-dify&#34;&gt;Create a Midjoureny Prompt Bot Without Code in Just a Few Minutes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use Cloud Services&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://dify.ai&#34;&gt;Dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install the Community Edition&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before installing Dify, make sure your machine meets the following minimum system requirements:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CPU &amp;gt;= 1 Core&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RAM &amp;gt;= 4GB&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to start the Dify server is to run our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/docker/docker-compose.yaml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file. Before running the installation command, make sure that &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/compose/install/&#34;&gt;Docker Compose&lt;/a&gt; are installed on your machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;cd docker&#xA;docker compose up -d&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After running, you can access the Dify dashboard in your browser at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/install&#34;&gt;http://localhost/install&lt;/a&gt; and start the initialization installation process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Helm Chart&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A big thanks to @BorisPolonsky for providing us with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/&#34;&gt;Helm Chart&lt;/a&gt; version, which allows Dify to be deployed on Kubernetes. You can go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BorisPolonsky/dify-helm&#34;&gt;https://github.com/BorisPolonsky/dify-helm&lt;/a&gt; for deployment information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Configuration&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to customize the configuration, please refer to the comments in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/docker/docker-compose.yaml&#34;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/a&gt; file and manually set the environment configuration. After making the changes, please run &#39;docker-compose up -d&#39; again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Features under development:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Datasets&lt;/strong&gt;, supporting more datasets, e.g. syncing content from Notion or webpages We will support more datasets, including text, webpages, and even Notion content. Users can build AI applications based on their own data sources.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugins&lt;/strong&gt;, introducing ChatGPT Plugin-standard plugins for applications, or using Dify-produced plugins We will release plugins complying with ChatGPT standard, or Dify&#39;s own plugins to enable more capabilities in applications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open-source models&lt;/strong&gt;, e.g. adopting Llama as a model provider or for further fine-tuning We will work with excellent open-source models like Llama, by providing them as model options in our platform, or using them for further fine-tuning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What can I do with Dify?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: Dify is a simple yet powerful LLM development and operations tool. You can use it to build commercial-grade applications, personal assistants. If you want to develop your own applications, LangDifyGenius can save you backend work in integrating with OpenAI and offer visual operations capabilities, allowing you to continuously improve and train your GPT model.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: How do I use Dify to &#34;train&#34; my own model?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: A valuable application consists of Prompt Engineering, context enhancement, and Fine-tuning. We&#39;ve created a hybrid programming approach combining Prompts with programming languages (similar to a template engine), making it easy to accomplish long-text embedding or capturing subtitles from a user-input Youtube video - all of which will be submitted as context for LLMs to process. We place great emphasis on application operability, with data generated by users during App usage available for analysis, annotation, and continuous training. Without the right tools, these steps can be time-consuming.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What do I need to prepare if I want to create my own application?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: We assume you already have an OpenAI API Key; if not, please register for one. If you already have some content that can serve as training context, that&#39;s great!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: What interface languages are available?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A: English and Chinese are currently supported, and you can contribute language packs to us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Star History&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://star-history.com/#langgenius/dify&amp;amp;Date&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.star-history.com/svg?repos=langgenius/dify&amp;amp;type=Date&#34; alt=&#34;Star History Chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome you to contribute to Dify to help make Dify better. We welcome contributions in various ways, submitting code, issues, new ideas, or sharing the interesting and useful AI applications you have created based on Dify. At the same time, we also welcome you to share Dify at different events, conferences, and social media.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Submit a Pull Request&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To ensure proper review, all code contributions, including from contributors with direct commit access, must be submitted as PR requests and approved by core developers before merging branches. We welcome PRs from everyone! If you&#39;re willing to help out, you can learn more about how to contribute code to the project in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribution Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Submit issues or ideas&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can submit your issues or ideas by adding issues to the Dify repository. If you encounter issues, please describe the steps you took to encounter the issue as much as possible so we can better discover it. If you have any new ideas for our product, we also welcome your feedback. Please share your insights as much as possible so we can get more feedback and further discussion in the community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Share your applications&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We encourage all community members to share their AI applications built on Dify, which can be applied to different scenarios or different users. This will provide powerful inspiration for people who want to create AI capabilities! You can share your experience by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/langgenius/dify-user-case/issues&#34;&gt;submitting an issue in the Dify-user-case repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Share Dify with others&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We encourage community contributors to actively demonstrate different aspects of using Dify. You can talk or share any feature of using Dify at meetups and conferences, blogs or social media. We believe your unique sharing will be of great help to others! Mention @Dify.AI on Twitter and/or communicate on &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; so we can give pointers and tips and help you spread the word by promoting your content on the different Dify communication channels.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Help others&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also help people in need of help on Discord, GitHub issues or other social platforms, guide others to solve problems encountered during use and share usage experiences. This is also a great contribution! If you want to become a maintainer of the Dify community, please contact the official team via &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; or email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@dify.ai&#34;&gt;support@dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, suggestions, or partnership inquiries, feel free to contact us through the following channels:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit an Issue or PR on our GitHub Repo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Join the discussion in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/FngNHpbcY7&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; Community&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@dify.ai&#34;&gt;hello@dify.ai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re eager to assist you and together create more fun and useful AI applications!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To protect your privacy, please avoid posting security issues on GitHub. Instead, send your questions to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@dify.ai&#34;&gt;security@dify.ai&lt;/a&gt; and we will provide you with a more detailed answer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Citation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software uses the following open-source software:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chase, H. (2022). LangChain [Computer software]. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hwchase17/langchain&#34;&gt;https://github.com/hwchase17/langchain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, please refer to the official website or license text of the respective software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is available under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/langgenius/dify/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Dify Open Source License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>sei-protocol/sei-chain</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T02:03:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-06:/sei-protocol/sei-chain</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/sei-protocol/sei-chain" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sei&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sei-protocol/sei-chain/main/assets/SeiLogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Banner!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sei is a general purpose, open-source L1 blockchain offering the best infrastructure for the exchange of digital assets. The chain emphasizes reliability, security and high throughput above all else, enabling an entirely new echelon of ultra-high performance DeFi products built on top. Sei&#39;s on-chain CLOB and matching engine provides deep liquidity and price-time-priority matching for traders and apps. Apps built on Sei benefit from built-in orderbook infrastructure, deep liquidity, and a fully decentralized matching service. Users benefit from this exchange model with the ability to select price, size, and direction of their trades coupled with MEV protection.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Sei&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sei&lt;/strong&gt; is a blockchain built using Cosmos SDK and Tendermint. It is built using the Cosmos SDK and Tendermint core, and features a built-in central limit orderbook (CLOB) module. Decentralized applications building on Sei can build on top of the CLOB, and other Cosmos-based blockchains can leverage Sei&#39;s CLOB as a shared liquidity hub and create markets for any asset.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Designed with developers and users in mind, Sei serves as the infrastructure and shared liquidity hub for the next generation of DeFi. Apps can easily plug-and-play to trade on Sei orderbook infrastructure and access pooled liquidity from other apps. To prioritize developer experience, Sei Network has integrated the wasmd module to support CosmWasm smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the most up to date documentation please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sei.io/&#34;&gt;https://www.sei.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Central Limit Orderbook&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most financial applications in traditional finance make use of CLOBs to create markets. This works well if you have cheap transaction fees and large amounts of liquidity. In decentralized finance however, the automated market-maker (AMM) model is more popular because it doesn&#39;t require constantly updating orders and works with lower amounts of liquidity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sei offers cheap transaction fees and works with market makers to have large amounts of liquidity. As a result, it can offer the orderbook based trading experience in a decentralized, permissionless manner. This unlocks many use cases that previously didn&#39;t work with the AMM model.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Sei Ecosystem&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sei Network is an L1 blockchain with a built-in on-chain orderbook that allows smart contracts easy access to shared liquidity. Sei architecture enables composable apps that maintain modularity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sei Network serves as the matching core of the ecosystem, offering superior reliability and ultra-high transaction speed to ecosystem partners, each with their own functionality and user experience. Anyone can create a DeFi application that leverages Sei&#39;s liquidity and the entire ecosystem benefits.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developers, traders, and users can all connect to Sei as ecosystem partners benefiting from shared liquidity and decentralized financial primitives.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Testnet&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to validate on the Sei Testnet&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This is the Sei Testnet-1 (sei-testnet-1)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Genesis &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sei-protocol/testnet/raw/main/sei-testnet-1/genesis.json&#34;&gt;Published&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Peers &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sei-protocol/testnet/raw/main/sei-testnet-1/addrbook.json&#34;&gt;Published&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Hardware Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;64 GB RAM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;1 TB NVME SSD&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;16 Cores (modern CPU&#39;s)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Operating System&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Linux (x86_64) or Linux (amd64) Recommended Arch Linux&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: go1.18+ required.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux: &lt;code&gt;pacman -S go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu: &lt;code&gt;sudo snap install go --classic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Prerequisite: git.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux: &lt;code&gt;pacman -S git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Optional requirement: GNU make.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Arch Linux: &lt;code&gt;pacman -S make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ubuntu: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install make&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Seid Installation Steps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone git repository&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/sei-protocol/sei-chain&#xA;cd sei-chain&#xA;git checkout $VERSION&#xA;make install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generate keys&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;seid keys add [key_name]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;seid keys add [key_name] --recover&lt;/code&gt; to regenerate keys with your mnemonic&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;seid keys add [key_name] --ledger&lt;/code&gt; to generate keys with ledger device&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Validator setup instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install seid binary&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Initialize node: &lt;code&gt;seid init &amp;lt;moniker&amp;gt; --chain-id sei-testnet-1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Download the Genesis file: &lt;code&gt;wget https://github.com/sei-protocol/testnet/raw/main/sei-testnet-1/genesis.json -P $HOME/.sei/config/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Edit the minimum-gas-prices in ${HOME}/.sei/config/app.toml: &lt;code&gt;sed -i &#39;s/minimum-gas-prices = &#34;&#34;/minimum-gas-prices = &#34;0.01usei&#34;/g&#39; $HOME/.sei/config/app.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Start seid by creating a systemd service to run the node in the background &lt;code&gt;nano /etc/systemd/system/seid.service&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Copy and paste the following text into your service file. Be sure to edit as you see fit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;[Unit]&#xA;Description=Sei-Network Node&#xA;After=network.target&#xA;&#xA;[Service]&#xA;Type=simple&#xA;User=root&#xA;WorkingDirectory=/root/&#xA;ExecStart=/root/go/bin/seid start&#xA;Restart=on-failure&#xA;StartLimitInterval=0&#xA;RestartSec=3&#xA;LimitNOFILE=65535&#xA;LimitMEMLOCK=209715200&#xA;&#xA;[Install]&#xA;WantedBy=multi-user.target&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Start the node&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start seid on Linux&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reload the service files: &lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl daemon-reload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create the symlinlk: &lt;code&gt;sudo systemctl enable seid.service&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start the node sudo: &lt;code&gt;systemctl start seid &amp;amp;&amp;amp; journalctl -u seid -f&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start a chain on 4 node docker cluster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start local 4 node cluster: &lt;code&gt;make docker-cluster-start&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SSH into a docker container: &lt;code&gt;docker exec -it [container_name] /bin/bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stop local 4 node cluster: &lt;code&gt;make docker-cluster-stop&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Create Validator Transaction&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;seid tx staking create-validator \&#xA;--from {{KEY_NAME}} \&#xA;--chain-id  \&#xA;--moniker=&#34;&amp;lt;VALIDATOR_NAME&amp;gt;&#34; \&#xA;--commission-max-change-rate=0.01 \&#xA;--commission-max-rate=1.0 \&#xA;--commission-rate=0.05 \&#xA;--details=&#34;&amp;lt;description&amp;gt;&#34; \&#xA;--security-contact=&#34;&amp;lt;contact_information&amp;gt;&#34; \&#xA;--website=&#34;&amp;lt;your_website&amp;gt;&#34; \&#xA;--pubkey $(seid tendermint show-validator) \&#xA;--min-self-delegation=&#34;1&#34; \&#xA;--amount &amp;lt;token delegation&amp;gt;usei \&#xA;--node localhost:26657&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Build with Us!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in building with Sei Network: Email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:team@seinetwork.io&#34;&gt;team@seinetwork.io&lt;/a&gt; DM us on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SeiNetwork&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/SeiNetwork&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>openstatusHQ/openstatus</title>
    <updated>2023-08-06T02:03:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-06:/openstatusHQ/openstatus</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/openstatusHQ/openstatus" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The open-source status page&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34; style=&#34;margin-top: 120px&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;The Open-source Status Page and Alerting System &lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; The Atlassian&#39;s Statuspage Open Source Alternative. &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstatus.dev&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more »&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstatus.dev/discord&#34;&gt;Discord&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstatus.dev&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstatushq/openstatus/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&#34;https://openstatus.productlane.com/roadmap&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About OpenStatus&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenStatus is open-source status page and alerting system. We are building it publicly for everyone to see our progress. We believe great softwares are built this way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can choose to host it yourself or use our hosted version at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstatus.dev&#34;&gt;openstatus.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact us&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more about this project or have any questions, book a call with us or send us an email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hello@openstatus.dev&#34;&gt;hello@openstatus.dev&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cal.com/thibault-openstatus/30min&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Book us with Cal.com&#34; src=&#34;https://cal.com/book-with-cal-dark.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Built with&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nextjs.org/&#34;&gt;Next.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tailwindcss.com/&#34;&gt;Tailwind CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ui.shadcn.com/&#34;&gt;shadcn/ui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tinybird.co/?ref=openstatus.dev&#34;&gt;tinybird&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://turso.tech/&#34;&gt;turso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orm.drizzle.team/&#34;&gt;drizzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clerk.com/&#34;&gt;clerk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resend.com/&#34;&gt;Resend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org/en/&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; &amp;gt;= 18.0.0&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pnpm.io/&#34;&gt;pnpm&lt;/a&gt; &amp;gt;= 8.6.2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clone the repository&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/openstatushq/openstatus.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install dependencies&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;pnpm install&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Set up your .env file&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;from &lt;code&gt;apps/web&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;packages/db&lt;/code&gt; you will find .env.example create your own.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow the steps to run your sqlite database locally inside of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstatusHQ/openstatus/raw/main/packages/db/README.md&#34;&gt;README.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Start the development server&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt; pnpm dev&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Open &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:3000&#34;&gt;http://localhost:3000&lt;/a&gt; with your browser to see the result.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&#34;https://clerk.com&#34;&gt;clerk&lt;/a&gt;, you will need to create a webhook endpoint. To access the link via ngrok (free), after login, append &lt;code&gt;/api/webhook/clerk&lt;/code&gt; to the link you get after entering:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ngrok http 3000&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s our &lt;a href=&#34;https://openstatus.productlane.com/roadmap&#34;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt; feel free to contribute to it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to help us building the best status page and alerting system, you can check our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstatusHQ/openstatus/raw/main/CONTRIBUTING.MD&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Top Contributors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstatushq/openstatus/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://contrib.rocks/image?repo=openstatushq/openstatus&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Made with &lt;a href=&#34;https://contrib.rocks&#34;&gt;Contrib.rocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>