<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-17T02:26:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:26:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Anomaly G.A.M.M.A. modpack definition files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Stalker GAMMA&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Anomaly G.A.M.M.A. modpack definition files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get the client to use this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.A.M.M.A. stands for Grok&#39;s Automated Modular Modpack for Anomaly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get the latest Stalker GAMMA client and install intructions, head to the associated discord server:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/KT2bEHZQbh&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/KT2bEHZQbh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.A.M.M.A. aims at providing a balanced survival, scavenging, cooking, crafting and repairing focused experience with a long progression and smooth gameplay.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For people accustomed to Skyrim modding, G.A.M.M.A. is basically Wabbajack remade from scratch in PowerShell + a modlist of 200+ addons and its own developed modular add-ons for STALKER Anomaly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This modpack is 100% copyright free since it doesn&#39;t redistribute any copyrighted content developed by other modders. Indeed, G.A.M.M.A. downloads every add-on directly from moddb or github, and installs them automatically and in the correct order in a Mod Organizer 2 (MO2) instance. You will thus directly support modders by installing G.A.M.M.A.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.A.M.M.A. is easy to use, since by simply executing 3 scripts and following basic instructions, you&#39;ll find on your desktop the G.A.M.M.A. icon which will launch a MO2 instance directly linked to your STALKER Anomaly folder. From there, you will find every add-on installed and be able to deactivate the ones you don&#39;t like, or add new add-ons. This is especially easy since all add-ons used in G.A.M.M.A. are separated by their type, i.e. Audio, Gameplay, Gunplay, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This modpack also features its own new modular set of add-ons including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A new UI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A rebalanced survival experience focused on crafting, repairing and cooking.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A new economy where traders will only sell you supplies, and where good ammunition will only be available to trustful stalkers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New starting loadouts focused on providing pistols, SMGs or WW2 guns to have a smoother start with calibers for which you can buy ammo. It also gives you the basic tools to wander the Zone, which is nice for Ironman runs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced close quarter combat to make knives more useful and to free even more inventory slots, yup you can equip 2 pistols and 2 main weapons and still profit from your best knife with a reworked quick melee motion and system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced actor damage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced sleep.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced Skill System from Haruka.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Overhauled radiations effects and dynamic radiation areas.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Many fixes for some major addons including the Boomsticks and Sharpsticks gunpack.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And more!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>gphanikumar/Demo</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:26:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/gphanikumar/Demo</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/gphanikumar/Demo" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a demo repository for illustrating github to the students of MM2090.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Demo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a demo repository for illustrating github to the students of MM2090.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>riscv/riscv-isa-manual</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:26:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/riscv/riscv-isa-manual</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;RISC-V Instruction Set Manual&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;RISC-V Instruction Set Manual &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.travis-ci.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://app.travis-ci.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the LaTeX source for the draft RISC-V Instruction Set Manual. The preface of each document indicates the version of each standard that has been formally ratified by RISC-V International.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License. See the LICENSE file for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Manual is split up into the following volumes:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Volume I: User-Level ISA&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Volume II: Privileged Architecture&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official versions&lt;/strong&gt; of the specifications are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://riscv.org/specifications/&#34;&gt;https://riscv.org/specifications/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compiled versions of the most recent drafts&lt;/strong&gt; of the specifications are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/releases/latest&#34;&gt;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/releases/latest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Older official versions&lt;/strong&gt; of the specifications are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/releases/tag/archive&#34;&gt;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/releases/tag/archive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The canonical list of &lt;strong&gt;open-source RISC-V implementations&#39; marchid CSR values&lt;/strong&gt; is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/raw/master/marchid.md&#34;&gt;https://github.com/riscv/riscv-isa-manual/blob/master/marchid.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>