<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-15T02:07:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>jakegut/resume</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T02:07:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-15:/jakegut/resume</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jakegut/resume" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LaTeX template for my personal resume&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;resume&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX template for my personal resume&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Based off of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sb2nov/resume/&#34;&gt;sb2nov/resume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use it on overleaf: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.overleaf.com/latex/templates/jakes-resume/syzfjbzwjncs&#34;&gt;Jake&#39;s Resume&lt;/a&gt; (Not updated)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jakegut/resume/master/resume.png&#34; alt=&#34;Resume Preview&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>riscvarchive/riscv-dejagnu</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T02:07:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-15:/riscvarchive/riscv-dejagnu</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/riscvarchive/riscv-dejagnu" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;DejaGnu RISC-V port&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to DejaGnu!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DejaGnu is a framework for testing other programs. Its purpose is to provide a single front-end for all tests. Beyond this, DejaGnu offers several advantages for testing:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* The flexibility and consistency of the DejaGnu framework make it&#xA;  easy to write tests for any program.&#xA;&#xA;* DejaGnu provides a layer of abstraction which makes all tests&#xA;  portable to any host or target where a program must be tested.&#xA;  For instance, a test for GDB can run (from any UNIX based host)&#xA;  on any target architecture supported by DejaGnu.  DejaGnu has&#xA;  run tests on several single board computers, whose operating&#xA;  software ranges from a boot monitor to a fully-fledged,&#xA;  UNIX-like realtime OS.&#xA;&#xA;* DejaGnu is written in Expect, which in turn uses Tcl (Tool&#xA;  command language).  The framework comprises two parts: the&#xA;  testing framework and the testsuites themselves.  Tests are&#xA;  usually written in Tcl and distributed with the programs, not&#xA;  with DejaGnu.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For detailed instructions on installing DejaGnu, see the INSTALL file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting bugs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you think you have found a bug in DejaGnu, then please send a bug report. Guidelines for reporting bugs can be found at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.gnu.org/software/dejagnu/#bug&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The DejaGnu documentation is written in Docbook/XML. The Makefile does not render the documentation into other formats by default, as this requires a range of Docbook packages to be installed. The intention is that this will be done by the maintainers when a release is made. HTML, RTF, PostScript and PDF versions of the current user manual are kept on the web at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;http://www.gnu.org/software/dejagnu/#documentation&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Info documentation is installed on a system as part of the installation process. You can read this by typing &#34;info dejagnu&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>