<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-09-01T01:45:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots/Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots</title>
    <updated>2024-09-01T01:45:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-09-01:/Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots/Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots/Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Autonomous Robots&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Introduction-to-Autonomous-Robots&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An open textbook focusing on computational principles of autonomous robots. The source-code is released under Creative Commons 4.0 (CC-BY-NC-ND), whereas the print version is copyrighted by MIT Press. You are therefore permitted to use images and content from the book for non-commercial purposes (including teaching) with proper attribution, but you cannot post compiled versions of the book online.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to compile a PDF of this book yourself, you either need a working implementation of Latex on your computer or use the online Latex editor overleaf.com. Here, you can either upload a zip file of the source code (&#34;download ZIP&#34; option underneath the green &#34;Code&#34; button on this page), or fork the project into your Github account and import it directly into Overleaf from there.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This book can be cited as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Nikolaus Correll, Bradley Hayes, Christoffer Heckman and Alessandro Roncone. Introduction to Autonomous Robots: Mechanisms, Sensors, Actuators, and Algorithms, MIT Press, 2022 (forthcoming).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@book{correll2022introduction,&#xA;  title={ Introduction to Autonomous Robots: Mechanisms, Sensors, Actuators, and Algorithms},&#xA;  author={Correll, Nikolaus and Hayes, Bradley, and Heckman, Christoffer, and Roncone, Alessandro},&#xA;  year={2022},&#xA;  edition={1st},&#xA;  publisher={MIT Press, Cambridge, MA}&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mooculus/calculus</title>
    <updated>2024-09-01T01:45:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-09-01:/mooculus/calculus</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mooculus/calculus" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Compiling the textbooks using Xake (and LaTeX)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compiling these documents is a bit tricky.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First install SAGE: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sagemath.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.sagemath.org/&lt;/a&gt; This should install SageTeX.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now if you are planning to use Xake to compile this repository, you first need to compile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;frontCover.tex spine.tex backCover.tex&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;for every subdirectory of coverArt, for example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pdflatex coverArt/calculus1Cover/frontCover.tex&#xA;pdflatex coverArt/calculus1Cover/spine.tex&#xA;pdflatex coverArt/calculus1Cover/backCover.tex&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After this, you should be able to compile the .tex files and PDFlatex.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike License. To view a copy of this license, visit&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;or send a letter to Creative Commons, 543 Howard Street, 5th Floor, San Francisco, California, 94105, USA. If you distribute this work or a derivative, include the history of the document.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The source code is available at&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mooculus/calculus&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mooculus/calculus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This text contains source material from several other open-source texts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Single and Multivariable Calculus: Early Transcendentals. Guichard. Copyright 2015 Guichard, Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike License 3.0.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://communitycalculus.org/&#34;&gt;http://communitycalculus.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;APEX Calculus. Hartman, Heinold, Siemers, Chalishajar, Bowen (Ed.). Copyright 2014 Hartman, Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apexcalculus.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.apexcalculus.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Elementary Calculus: An Infinitesimal Approach. Keisler. Copyright 2015 Keisler, Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike License 3.0.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.math.wisc.edu/~keisler/calc.html&#34;&gt;http://www.math.wisc.edu/~keisler/calc.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will be glad to receive corrections and suggestions for improvement at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ximera@math.osu.edu&#34;&gt;ximera@math.osu.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>