<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-18T02:03:42Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>gphanikumar/june2023</title>
    <updated>2023-06-18T02:03:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-18:/gphanikumar/june2023</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/gphanikumar/june2023" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository is to evaluate the third assignment of the course ID2090 offered during March-June-2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;june2023&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is to evaluate the third assignment of the course ID2090 offered during March-June-2023.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each student shall do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;fork this repository in their account&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;create a branch&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;update the folder named after their roll number to include a tex file and any other files for the content task as described below&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;push the folder to the github server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;create a pull request to have your updates reflected in the june2023 repo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The content task is as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The folder shall contain a Makefile so that upon running the make command, a pdf file will be created from the tex file compilation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The folder shall contain a tex file and any other files (such as image files, bib files etc.,) as needed to let the latex or pdflatex compilation run without errors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The final output pdf will show the name of the student, roll number, github username clearly at the top of the page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The content shall not have overlap with any other student of the course or previous students of this course.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The content shall include the following things from a topic of your interest preferably from the subjects of your parent Department: an equation, a plot that describes the equation, a brief description of the equation and the symbols contained in it, a set of references that give more informatiom about the equation and finally, a paragraph on how you went about choosing the equation.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alert me over email if your pull request is not accepted for any reason. Your email shall include your github username for ready lookup.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>