<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-28T02:01:18Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>COD1995/A-Comprehensive-Note-on-Machine-Learning</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T02:01:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/COD1995/A-Comprehensive-Note-on-Machine-Learning</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/COD1995/A-Comprehensive-Note-on-Machine-Learning" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;These notes are for personal and educational use only. Any redistribution or sharing without my explicit consent is prohibited. They serve as a private learning and reference resource.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;A Comprehensive Note on Machine Learning&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document serves as an educational resource primarily designed for the courses I teach, including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSE 474/574 Introduction to Machine Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSE 455/555 Pattern Recognition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSE 676 Deep Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it functions as a personal reference in the field of machine learning.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Purpose and Use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This compilation aims to provide an extensive overview and guide for students and practitioners of machine learning, incorporating a blend of &lt;strong&gt;direct&lt;/strong&gt; references and &lt;strong&gt;adaptations&lt;/strong&gt; from established texts and sources. It is intended for:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educational Aid&lt;/strong&gt;: As a supplementary resource for teaching and learning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference Material&lt;/strong&gt;: For personal and academic use.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document is &lt;strong&gt;not authorized&lt;/strong&gt; for commercial use, redistribution, or sale without explicit consent. To read the pdf version of the document: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/COD1995/A-Comprehensive-Note-on-Machine-Learning/raw/main/machine_learning.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community Contributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From my side there will be constant updates but in order to motivate my students to read I have a &lt;strong&gt;3 bonus points&lt;/strong&gt; if they make significant and meaningful contribution to each chapters of the note. I welcome contributions and feedback from the community! If you have suggestions, corrections, or additional material you think would enhance this resource, please feel free to contribute. Here&#39;s how you can do that:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fork the Repository&lt;/strong&gt;: Create your own fork of the project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make Changes&lt;/strong&gt;: Add your contributions or modifications.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submit a Pull Request&lt;/strong&gt;: Open a pull request to the original repository with a clear list of what you&#39;ve done.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review &amp;amp; Merge&lt;/strong&gt;: I will review your changes and merge them into the main document as appropriate.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Details on how to create a pull request: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/pull-requests/collaborating-with-pull-requests/proposing-changes-to-your-work-with-pull-requests/creating-a-pull-request&#34;&gt;Creating a pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When contributing, please adhere to the following guidelines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure that any added content is accurate and relevant to machine learning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Respect intellectual property and cite sources appropriately.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Maintain a respectful and constructive tone in discussions and pull requests.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation of LaTeX&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX is a high-quality typesetting system; it includes features designed for the production of technical and scientific documentation. My preferred setup for writing LaTeX documents is Visual Studio Code (VSCode) with the LaTeX Workshop extension, offering a user-friendly and efficient LaTeX writing experience. Below is a guide to help you set up this environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. Install LaTeX Distribution&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To begin with, you need a LaTeX distribution installed on your computer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt;: Use MiKTeX or TeX Live. MiKTeX is more user-friendly for beginners, while TeX Live is more comprehensive. Download from &lt;a href=&#34;https://miktex.org/&#34;&gt;MiKTeX&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tug.org/texlive/&#34;&gt;TeX Live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS&lt;/strong&gt;: Install MacTeX, which is a macOS version of TeX Live with additional tools. Download from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tug.org/mactex/&#34;&gt;MacTeX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;: Most Linux distributions include TeX Live in their package repositories. Install it using your package manager (for example, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install texlive-full&lt;/code&gt; in Ubuntu).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;2. Install Visual Studio Code (VSCode)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;VSCode is a free, open-source editor with a wide array of features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download and install VSCode from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;3. Install LaTeX Workshop Extension in VSCode&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LaTeX Workshop enhances VSCode with LaTeX typesetting capabilities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open VSCode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Navigate to Extensions (&lt;code&gt;Ctrl+Shift+X&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;Cmd+Shift+X&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Search for &#34;LaTeX Workshop&#34; and install the extension.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;4. Configure LaTeX Workshop&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Customize LaTeX Workshop settings for your needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;File &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Settings&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;Code &amp;gt; Preferences &amp;gt; Settings&lt;/code&gt; on macOS).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Search for &#34;LaTeX Workshop&#34; settings.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure according to your preferences, like setting up a default compiler or enabling auto-build on save.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;5. Start Writing LaTeX&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now, you are ready to write LaTeX documents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new file with a &lt;code&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; extension in VSCode.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Write your LaTeX content.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the build feature in LaTeX Workshop to compile your document into a PDF.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;6. Additional Tools and Tips&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: VSCode&#39;s integrated support for Git is beneficial for version controlling your LaTeX documents.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live Preview&lt;/strong&gt;: LaTeX Workshop supports live preview of your document.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Snippets&lt;/strong&gt;: Create custom snippets for frequently used LaTeX commands to improve efficiency.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This setup with VSCode and LaTeX Workshop provides a powerful, modern environment for writing and managing LaTeX documents, blending LaTeX&#39;s typesetting capabilities with the features of a contemporary code editor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Primary Sources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The majority of the material referenced in this document comes from the following key sources:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Zhang, Aston, et al. &#34;Dive into Deep Learning.&#34; Cambridge University Press, 2023.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bishop, C. M., &amp;amp; Nasrabadi, N. M. &#34;Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning&#34; (Vol. 4, No. 4, p. 738). New York: Springer, 2006.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hart, P. E., Stork, D. G., &amp;amp; Duda, R. O. &#34;Pattern Classification.&#34; Hoboken: Wiley, 2000.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Burkov, A. &#34;The Hundred-Page Machine Learning Book&#34; (Vol. 1, p. 32). Quebec City, QC, Canada: Andriy Burkov, 2019.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Burkov, A. &#34;Machine Learning Engineering&#34; (Vol. 1). Montreal, QC, Canada: True Positive Incorporated, 2020.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional References&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All other referenced materials and sources are cited in the bibliography section of this document.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact Information&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For inquiries, permissions, or further information, please reach out to me at ( &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jueguo@buffalo.edu&#34;&gt;jueguo@buffalo.edu&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document is provided &#34;as is,&#34; and the author makes no representations or warranties, express or implied, regarding its completeness, accuracy, or reliability.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>statds/ids-s24</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T02:01:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/statds/ids-s24</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/statds/ids-s24" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Introduction to Data Science, STAT 3255/5255, Spring 2024, University of Connecticut&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc02</title>
    <updated>2024-01-28T02:01:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-28:/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc02</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CS-MATH-113-Spring-2024/wc02" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Weekly Challenge 02te: Thinking Logically&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;CS/MATH 113 Discrete Mathematics, Spring 2024&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each Weekly Challenge (WC) invites you to critically engage with the topics covered up to that week. They may take on a variety of formats and be available and attempted through diverse platforms as the semester progresses. They may be attempted individually or in teams as indicated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first few Weekly Challenges, including this one, get you used to logical thinking, without necessarily relying on formal course work. This mode of thinking is required and developed in this course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Purpose&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This WC familiarizes you with both the process that future WCs will follow and the kind of thinking that will be required for them.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Background and Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To attempt and submit the task you will need&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;familiarity with high school mathematics&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;a problem solving and logical approach.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the willingness to work through the LaTeX source&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;comfort with GitHub and LaTeX&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Grading is as per the rubric shared on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Task&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The task for this WC is explained in the accompanying prompt which is to be compiled in LaTeX. You will enter your solution in the indicated space in the same file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Deadline and discussion&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The deadline is mentioned on Canvas.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For discussion on the WC, please use the related Canvas discussion thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;viel Spass!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>