<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub TeX Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-04T01:48:07Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of TeX in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>berndpfrommer/tagslam_web</title>
    <updated>2022-12-04T01:48:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-04:/berndpfrommer/tagslam_web</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/berndpfrommer/tagslam_web" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;web pages for the tagslam project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Web page for tagslam&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to build the web site:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First test it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The point your browser to &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tagslam_web/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:1313/tagslam_web/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If that works:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo -d docs&#xA;git commit -a&#xA;git push origin master&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It can take a good while until the changes will be reflected on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://berndpfrommer.github.io/tagslam_web&#34;&gt;project page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This documentation and any future contributions to it are licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/berndpfrommer/tagslam_web/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Apache License 2.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>borisveytsman/acmart</title>
    <updated>2022-12-04T01:48:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-04:/borisveytsman/acmart</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/borisveytsman/acmart" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;ACM consolidated LaTeX styles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;This package provides a class for typesetting publications of the Association for Computing Machinery.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your TeX distribution probably includes the latest released version of this package. If you decide to install it yourself, please see the Installation section of the User&#39;s Guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note that the version on Github is a development (or experimental) version: please download it for testing new features. The production version is the one on CTAN and ACM sites.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Changes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.88 New ISSNs Documentation updates New journal: PACMNET&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.87 CC license is allowed for non-acm documents and ACM Engage documents only New format acmcp for the cover page New journals: JATS, ACMJCSS, TORS Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.86. Empty country in affiliation now produces an error Bug fixes New samples for acmengage&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.85. Bug fixes Added support for Creative Commons licenses (requires doclicense images) New journals New format acmengage for ACM Engage CSEdu course materials&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.84 Support for BibLaTeX rewritten (thanks to Roberto Di Cosmo and Kartik Singhal) Corrected German translation (thanks to Dirk Beyer) New journals&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.83 Support for multilanguage papers ISSN changes for some journals&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.82 Bug fixes. New command \anon for anonymization of short strings. Documentation update.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.81 Bug fixes New bib field distinctURL to print URL even if doi is present. Reworded samples&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.80 New journals: DLT, FAC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.79 Fixed pages with index (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/borisveytsman/acmart/issues/440&#34;&gt;https://github.com/borisveytsman/acmart/issues/440&lt;/a&gt;) Updated information for TAP, TCPS, TEAC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.78 Documentation update. Magic texcount comments for samples. Title page now is split if there are too many authors Bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.77 Changed the way to typeset multiple affiliations (Christoph Sommer)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.76 Added many journal abbreviations to the bst. New experimental option: pbalance ORCID linking code&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.75 Omitted \country now produces error. Added \AtBeginMaketitle&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.74 Bug fixes. A regression introduced in the font changes is reverted.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.73 Bug fixes The elements institution, city and country are now obligatory for affiliations. The absence of them produces a warning&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.72 Bug fixes. Better handling of metadata.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.71 Bug fixes Formats sigchi and sigchi-a are retired Bibliography formatting changes for @inproceedings entries having both series and volume LuaLaTeX now uses the same OTF fonts as XeLaTeX&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.70 Title change for ACM/IMS Transactions on Data Science Bug fixes for bibliography&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.69 Bug fixes Compatibility with LaTeX 2020-02-02 release&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.68 Bug fixes BST now recognizes words `Paper&#39; or &#39;Article&#39; in eid or articleno&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.67 Urgent bug fixes: BibTeX style bug fixed (Michael D. Adams) Sigplan special section bugfix&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.66 Bug fixes BibTeX change: location is now a synonym for city (Feras Saad) ACM reference format is now mandatory for papers over one page. CCS concepts and keywords are now mandatory for papers over two pages. Authors&#39; addresses are mandatory for journal articles.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.65 Bug fixes New journal: DGOV DTRAP and HEALTH are now using acmlarge format&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.64 Produce error if abstract is entered after maketitle (previously abstract was silently dropped) Bug fixes for line numbering&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.63a Moved TQUANT to TQC&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.63 New journals: TQUANT, FACMP&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.62 Documentation update New journal: TELO Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.61 Bug fixes New bibtex types for artifacts&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.60 New option: urlbreakonhyphens (thanks to Peter Kemp) Smaller header size for acmsmall&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.59 Now a journal format can be used for conference proceedings All samples are now generated from the same .dtx file Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.58 Suppressed spurious warnings. New journal: HEALTH. TDSCI is renamed to TDS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.57 Change of \baselinestretch now produces an error Booktabs is now always loaded Added option `balance&#39; to balance last page in two-column mode E-mail is no longer split in addresses New samples (Stephen Spencer)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.56 Bug fixes Added \flushbottom to two column formats (Philip Quinn) The final punctuation for the list of concepts is now a period instead of a semicolon (Philip Quinn) New command \Description to describe images for visually impaired users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.55 Bug fixes Font changes for SIGCHI table captions&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.54 New option: &#39;nonacm&#39; (Gabriel Scherer) Deleted indent for subsubsection (suggested by Ross Moore) Suppressed some obscurious warning in BibTeX processing Suppressed hyperrerf warnings (Paolo G. Giarrusso) New code for sections to help with accessibility patches (Ross Moore) Submission id, if present, is printed in anon mode Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.53 New journals: PACMCGIT, TIOT, TDSCI&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.52 Another rewording of licenses&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.51 Journal footers now use abbreviated journal titles. Corrected the bug with acmPrice. Do not show price when copyright is set to iw3c2w3 and iw3c2w3g. The package now is compatible with polyglossia (Joachim Breitner). Slightly reworded copyright statements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.50 Changes in iw3c2w3 and iw3c2w3g&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.49 New jorunal: DTRAP&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.48 Bug fixes Review mode now switches on folios Code prettying (Michael D. Adams) Bibliography changes: @MISC entries no longer have a separate date Sigch-a sample bibliography renamed Bib code cleanup (Zack Weinberg) Acmart and version info are added to pdfcreator tag \citeyear no longer produces parenthetical year Added initial support for Biblatex (Daniel Thomas) Added support for IW3C2 conferences&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.47 New journal: THRI&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.46 Bug fixes for bibliography: label width is now calculated correctly. All PACM now use screen option. This requires etoolbox. Added subtitle to ACM reference format. Now acmart is compatible with fontspec. \thanks is now obsolete. The addresses are automatically added to the journal version; this can be overriden with \authorsaddresses command. Deleted the rule at the end of frontmatter for all formats. Deleted new line before doi in the reference format. Reintegrated theorem code into acmart.dtx (Matthew Fluet)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.45 Workaround for a Libertine bug. Thanks to LianTze Lim from Overleaf&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.44 Bug fixes. Empty DOI and ISBN suppress printing DOI or ISBN lines Separated theorem code into acmthm.sty, loaded by default. Article number can be set for proceedings. New commands: \acmBooktile, \editor. Reference citation format updated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.43 Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.42 Deleted ACM badges Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.41 Rearranged bib files Added new badges&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.40 Bibliography changes Added processing of one-compoment ccsdesc nodes Bug fixes. Made the height a multiple of \baselineskip + \topskip Added cleveref We no longer print street address in SIGs&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.39 Added \authornotemark commmand&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.38 Increase default font size for SIGPLAN&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.37 Reduce list indentation (Matthew Fluet)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.36 Bug fixes Moved PACMPL to acmlarge format New journal: PACMHCI Added the possibility to adjust number of author boxes per row in conference formats&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.35 Author-year bib style now uses square brackets. Changed defaults for TOG sample Price is suppressed for usgov and rightsretained modes. Bugs fixed&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.34 Deleted DOI from doi numbers Changed bibstrip formatting The command \terms is now obsolete The rulers in review mode now have continuous numbering&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.33 New option &lt;code&gt;timestamp&#39; (Michael D. Adams) New option &lt;/code&gt;authordraft&#39; Documentation updates Bug fixes We now use Type 1 versions of Libertine fonts even with XeTeX. New hook acmart-preload-hook.tex (wizards only!) Added new options `obeypunctuation&#39; for \affiliation command Added SubmissionID Added right line count ruler for two-column formats Added workaround for Adobe Acrobat bugs in selection Added eid field to the bibliography&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.32 New DOI formatting. Format siggraph is now obsolete, and sigconf is used instead. New proceedings title: POMACS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.31 Changed default year and month to the current ones (thanks to Matteo Riondato) Table of contents now works Marginalia now work in all formats New command \additionalaffiliation Documentation changes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.30 Bibtex style now recognizes https:// in doi. Added \frenchspacing. \department now has an optional hierarchy level. Switched to T1 encoding Updated IMWUT and PACMPL&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.29 Documentation changes. Head height increased from 12pt to 13pt. Removed spurious indent at start of abstract. Improved kerning in CCS description list.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.28 Bug fixes: natbib=false now behaves correctly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.27 Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.26 Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.25 Updated PACMPL journal option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.24 Added IMWUT journal option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.23 Added PACM PL journal option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.22 Bibliography changes for Aptara backend; should be invisible for the users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.21 Bibliography changes: added arXiv, some cleanup&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.20 Bug fixes, documentation updates&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.19 Include &#39;Abstract&#39;, &#39;Acknowledgements&#39;, and &#39;References&#39; in PDF bookmarks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.18 Natbib is now the default for all versions. A unified bib file is used for all styles. Better treatment of multiple affiliations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.17 Formatting changes for margins and lists. Bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.16 Formatting changes for headers and footers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.15 New structured affiliation command. New commands for acknowledgements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.14 Warn about undefined citation styles; move definitions of acmauthoryear and acmnumeric citation styles before use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.13 Formatting changes: headers, folios etc. Bibliography changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.12 Bug fixes and documentation updates. Footnotes rearranged. Option natbib is now mostly superfluous: the class makes a guess based on the format chosen.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.11 Customization of ACM theorem styles and proof environment (Matthew Fluet).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.10 Bug fixes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.09 SIGPLAN: revert caption rules (Matthew Fluet)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Version 1.08 SIGPLAN reformatting (Matthew Fluet); bug fixes&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>