<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-06-22T01:36:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>hmcts/bulk-scan-ccd-definitions</title>
    <updated>2023-06-22T01:36:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-06-22:/hmcts/bulk-scan-ccd-definitions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hmcts/bulk-scan-ccd-definitions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Bulk Scan CCD Definitions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. Modify the JSON data&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Move into the directory of case type the one you need.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;|- definitions&#xA;    |-bulkscan&#xA;    |-cmc&#xA;    |-divorce&#xA;    |-finrem&#xA;    |-probate&#xA;    |-sscs&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything in this README file now assumes that you are in your chosen case type directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The JSON files are in the directory data/sheets. There is a JSON file for each CCD definition spreadsheet tab.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Generate the spreadsheet from the current JSON files&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;../../bin/json2xlsx.sh {ENV}&#xA;&#xA;ENV= can be aat, demo or prod&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will create a file called {ENV}-{CASE TYPE}-created-ccd.xlsx in the /data directory. It requires environment info as an argument. It will replace placeholder URLs with environment specific URLs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Make changes to the spreadsheet&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make changes to the definition as you would normally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Convert the spreadsheet back to JSON&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;../../bin/xlsx2json.sh&#xA;&#xA;Creates json files under /data/sheets&#xA;The source excel file which is going to be parsed to JSON should be under case type folder (same level with ./data folder) and it can be named anything ending *.xlsx but there should be only 1 xlsx file.&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Testing and uploading Exception Record CCD definitions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Test the converted spreadsheet in local docker (bulk-scan-shared-infrastructure).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the change cannot be tested in local docker, use the demo environment. Make sure to inform the bulkscan developers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Attach the CCD screenshot to the JIRA ticket before creating the PR.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Merge the ccd-definitions PR to demo branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upload the service Exception Record CCD definition in confluence (service-demo folder).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If there are code changes involved, deploy the code changes in demo environment and request QA to test the changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Raise a PR for ccd-definitions changes to merge in the master branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Update bulkscan CCD definition in bulk-scan-shared-infrastructure repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upload the CCD definition in AAT and PROD (raise a JIRA ticket for CCD team to upload the CCD defintiion in PROD).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Upload the CCD definition spreadsheets in confluence (service-AAT and service-PROD folders).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Raise PR/s for code changes to merge the changes in the master branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>