<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-17T01:33:18Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>LinkedInLearning/level-up-java-3213389</title>
    <updated>2022-11-17T01:33:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-17:/LinkedInLearning/level-up-java-3213389</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LinkedInLearning/level-up-java-3213389" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the LInkedIn Learning repo for Level Up: Java.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Level Up: Java&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Level Up: Java. The full course is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/level-up-java&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.lynda.com/course/3213389/3213389-1667864430381-16x9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Level Up: Java &#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you get better at writing code in Java? Practice, practice, practice. Test your skill set as a Java developer by working through these hands-on practical challenges. In this course, instructor Kathryn Hodge presents a variety of concise coding challenges, each running about five minutes or less, that give you an opportunity to try out your Java skills, whether you’re a beginner, intermediate, or advanced user. Each lesson has been designed independently, so you can skip around and watch them in any order that works for you. One challenge at a time, Kathryn provides an overview of solutions and automated testing files. By the end of this course, you’ll have developed a brand-new set of skills in Java, along with some tricks of the trade that software developers in the industry use every day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This course is integrated with GitHub Codespaces, an instant cloud developer environment that offers all the functionality of your favorite IDE without the need for any local machine setup. With GitHub Codespaces, you can get hands-on practice from any machine, at any time—all while using a tool that you’ll likely encounter in the workplace.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Each installment of the &lt;em&gt;Level Up&lt;/em&gt; series offers at least 15 bite-sized opportunities to practice programming at various levels of difficulty, so you can challenge yourself and reinforce what you’ve learned. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/level-up-java/using-github-codespaces-with-this-course&#34;&gt;Using GitHub Codespaces with this course&lt;/a&gt; video to learn how to get a codespace up and running.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instructor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kathryn Hodge&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out my other courses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/instructors/kathryn-hodge?u=104&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>asquarezone/DockerZone</title>
    <updated>2022-11-17T01:33:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-17:/asquarezone/DockerZone</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/asquarezone/DockerZone" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Project contains the samples for Docker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Code-Institute-Org/postgres-migration-tool</title>
    <updated>2022-11-17T01:33:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-17:/Code-Institute-Org/postgres-migration-tool</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Code-Institute-Org/postgres-migration-tool" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codeinstitute.s3.amazonaws.com/fullstack/ci_logo_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;CI logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Reel2Reel&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is it?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a tool for Code Institute students and alumni. It allows you to dump a database from Heroku and upload it to Render/ElephantSQL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I use it?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need to have created a new database on ElephantSQL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open this repo in Gitpod&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;reel2reel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In a different browser tab, go to your app in Heroku and select the &lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt; tab&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;em&gt;Reveal Config Vars&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy the value in the &lt;code&gt;DATABASE_URL&lt;/code&gt; Config Var. It will start with &lt;code&gt;postgres://&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Return to Gitpod and paste in the URL you just copied&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In a different browser tab, get your ElephantSQL database URL. Again, it will start with &lt;code&gt;postgres://&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Return to Gitpod and paste in the URL where prompted&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The data will now be downloaded from Heroku and uploaded to your ElephantSQL database&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Problems&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the URLs are copied correctly. Reel2Reel will throw an error if the URL doesn&#39;t start with &lt;code&gt;postgres://&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure that you run the process as soon as you copy the Heroku &lt;code&gt;DATABASE_URL&lt;/code&gt;. Heroku periodically rotates the credentials, which means an old &lt;code&gt;DATABASE_URL&lt;/code&gt; may not work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I use this with VSCode?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, but we&#39;d really prefer you to use it with Gitpod. This repo has the latest versions of the Postgres tools installed to ensure compatibility with Heroku and Render/ElephantSQL. We like VSCode too, but just this once, please use Gitpod.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m a power user. Is there an easier way to use this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. You can supply the URLs as arguments like so:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;reel2reel &amp;lt;Heroku URL&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Render URL&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does it actually do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connects to Heroku and dumps the database to a local &lt;code&gt;dump.sql&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Modifies the &lt;code&gt;dump.sql&lt;/code&gt; file so that it contains the database name and username for the new database&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Runs the modified &lt;code&gt;dump.sql&lt;/code&gt; file against the specified Render/ElephantSQL database&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to examine the code and see if you understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reel2Reel??&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because we like to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vuo8kD5zF5I&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;move it, move it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>