<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-07T01:26:30Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>caglejohn/vacationplannerpro</title>
    <updated>2024-02-07T01:26:30Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-07:/caglejohn/vacationplannerpro</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/caglejohn/vacationplannerpro" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SE_VacationPlannerRepo: School project repository for the Vacation Planner Pro web application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Vacation Planner Pro&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vacation Planner Pro is a web-based application designed for large organizations, aiming to simplify the complexities of vacation planning and tracking. This solution offers a standardized platform for employees and managers to create, monitor, and manage vacation times effectively. It provides a detailed organizational view of vacation accruals, usages, and schedules, ensuring a smooth and efficient vacation planning process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vacation Profiles:&lt;/strong&gt; Enables the creation and management of individual vacation profiles for employees, factoring in total vacation based on years of service and personal choice holidays.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vacation Planning:&lt;/strong&gt; Allows employees to submit their vacation plans for the year, distinguishing between full or half days for standard vacations and personal choice holidays.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accrual Tracking:&lt;/strong&gt; Implements a comprehensive system to track accrued, taken, and remaining vacation days for each employee, ensuring accurate vacation management.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quarterly Summaries:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides automated alerts and summaries for both employees and managers regarding vacation times accrued but not taken, promoting proactive vacation usage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Departmental Views:&lt;/strong&gt; Facilitates the visualization of department-wide vacation schedules to aid in planning and coordination among team members.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-of-Year Reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; Features the ability to carry over and report on vacations not taken at the end of the year, aiding in future vacation planning.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Technical Stack&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizes Java-based services, hosted on IBM&#39;s Open Liberty application server, ensuring high performance and reliability.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; Employs flexible frontend development practices using preferred JavaScript libraries, allowing for a dynamic user experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security:&lt;/strong&gt; Secured with JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) for robust authentication and authorization measures.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microservices Architecture:&lt;/strong&gt; Designed for scalability and resilience, adhering to best practices in microservices architecture.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employees:&lt;/strong&gt; Can log in to the planner, view and update their vacation plans, and observe other department members&#39; vacation schedules.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managers:&lt;/strong&gt; Possess all the capabilities of employees, in addition to accessing departmental summaries and alerts on vacations accrued but not taken.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Connecting to this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fork this repository &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;button on the top right of this repo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new project in an IDE of your choice. (I use IntelliJ) &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Intellij link: &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;jetbrains.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository using Git &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Install Git at &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;git-scm.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;run command &#34;git clone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xxMYFORKEDADDRESSxx&#34;&gt;https://github.com/xxMYFORKEDADDRESSxx&lt;/a&gt;&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Running the Application&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Navigate to the directory with the pom.xml file &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;run command &#34;cd vacation-planner-pro&#34; on windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Build using Maven &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Install Maven at &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;https://maven.apache.org/download.cgi&lt;/a&gt; (Binary zip archive for windows)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Create a system path variable for Maven pointed at its &#34;bin&#34; folder&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;run command &#34;mvn liberty:run&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To be discussed!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!--This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the [LICENSE.md](LICENSE.md) file for details.--&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A special thank you to the SUNY Ulster Faculty and IBM Team for the opprotunity to work on this project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A heartfelt thanks to all contributors who have helped shape Vacation Planner Pro, good luck to us all!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>VivSoftOrg/k8s-sherlock</title>
    <updated>2024-02-07T01:26:30Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-07:/VivSoftOrg/k8s-sherlock</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/VivSoftOrg/k8s-sherlock" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;K8s-Sherlock is your open-source investigative tool for diving deep into Kubernetes cluster mysteries. Designed to simplify and expedite debugging processes, it&#39;s the essential utility for demystifying complex container orchestration issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;K8s-Sherlock 🕵️‍♂️&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;K8s-Sherlock is an open-source Kubernetes pod designed for debugging and diagnostics. As a swiss-army knife for your Kubernetes cluster, it comes pre-loaded with a host of tools to help you diagnose issues with network, containers, and more. Developed to expedite the troubleshooting process, K8s-Sherlock is your go-to pod for resolving complex orchestration issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Networking Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: Comes with &lt;code&gt;iproute2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;iputils-ping&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;traceroute&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;netcat&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;dnsutils&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;telnet&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP Tools&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wget&lt;/code&gt; pre-installed for HTTP requests.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: AWS CLI is installed for interacting with AWS services.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Docker CLI&lt;/strong&gt;: Perform Docker operations without leaving the pod.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A Kubernetes cluster up and running&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;kubectl installed and configured&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Deploy K8s-Sherlock Pod&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;bash&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f pod/sherlock.yaml --namespace=&amp;lt;namespace_name&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Associate Service Account to Pod to AWS IAM role&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;bash&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;kubectl annotate service shelock-sa eks.amazonaws.com/role-arn=&amp;lt;YOUR_IAM_ROLE_ARN&amp;gt; --namespace=&amp;lt;namespace_name&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the K8s-Sherlock pod is up and running, you can &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; into it to use the tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;bash&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;kubectl exec -it &amp;lt;pod-name&amp;gt; -- /bin/bash&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We love contributions! Please read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VivSoftOrg/k8s-sherlock/main/CONTRIBUTING.MD&#34;&gt;Contributing Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to get involved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VivSoftOrg/k8s-sherlock/main/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>