<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-03-23T01:33:10Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>LinkedInLearning/level-up-rust-3041143</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T01:33:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-23:/LinkedInLearning/level-up-rust-3041143</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LinkedInLearning/level-up-rust-3041143" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a LinkedIn Learning repo for Level Up: Rust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Level Up: Rust&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Level Up: Rust. The full course is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/level-up-rust?dApp=59033956&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/C560DAQEOULbtwwYf8Q/learning-public-crop_288_512/0/1677009134347?e=2147483647&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=upv4qh8qFO7ZR9gBPQGQQW8wg9gyTjKoaDC4gD0OwxU&#34; alt=&#34;Level Up: Rust&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’ll take time—and a whole lot of practice—to improve your Rust coding skills. It’s important to push yourself with new challenges, which is exactly what this course is for. Join author and instructor Tim McNamara as he takes you through a series of coding challenges, testing your ability to perform certain functions so you can reach the next level with Rust. Acquire new Rust skills with exercises that start off simple and become progressively more difficult. Learn how to write better, faster, and more reliable code when you need it. Find out why Rust is taking over the industry, offering an efficient and secure alternative to many other programming languages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This course is integrated with GitHub Codespaces, an instant cloud developer environment that offers all the functionality of your favorite IDE without the need for any local machine setup. With GitHub Codespaces, you can get hands-on practice from any machine, at any time—all while using a tool that you’ll likely encounter in the workplace.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each installment of the Level Up series offers at least 15 bite-sized opportunities to practice programming at various levels of difficulty, so you can challenge yourself and reinforce what you’ve learned. Check out the “Using GitHub Codespaces with this course” video to learn how to get a codespace up and running.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has branches for each of the videos in the course. You can use the branch pop up menu in github to switch to a specific branch and take a look at the course at that stage, or you can add &lt;code&gt;/tree/BRANCH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; to the URL to go to the branch you want to access.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Branches&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The branches are structured to correspond to the videos in the course. The naming convention is &lt;code&gt;CHAPTER#_MOVIE#&lt;/code&gt;. As an example, the branch named &lt;code&gt;02_03&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to the second chapter and the third video in that chapter. Some branches will have a beginning and an end state. These are marked with the letters &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;beginning&#34; and &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;end&#34;. The &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the beginning of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the end of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch holds the final state of the code when in the course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When switching from one exercise files branch to the next after making changes to the files, you may get a message like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;error: Your local changes to the following files would be overwritten by checkout:        [files]&#xA;Please commit your changes or stash them before you switch branches.&#xA;Aborting&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Add changes to git using this command: git add .&#xA;Commit changes using this command: git commit -m &#34;some message&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To use these exercise files, you must have the following installed: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;[list of requirements for course]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository into your local machine using the terminal (Mac), CMD (Windows), or a GUI tool like SourceTree.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;[Course-specific instructions]&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instructor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tim McNamara&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Author, Software Architect&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out my other courses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/instructors/tim-mcnamara&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>bagrinsergiu/brizy-protobuf-idl</title>
    <updated>2023-03-23T01:33:10Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-03-23:/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protobuf-idl</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protobuf-idl" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Brizy API Messages&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this lib we will have message classes that will be used by messenger component(or other messaging components from other languages)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All messages are declared as protobuf (v3) files in ./src. For more information about protobuf read &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/proto3&#34;&gt;https://developers.google.com/protocol-buffers/docs/proto3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to declare a class&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a custom-message.proto&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Declare a new value in DescriminatorType enum in: ./src/message.proto&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to release and generate the code&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Go to github repository and create a release: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protobuf-idl/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protobuf-idl/releases&lt;/a&gt; This will trigger an github action that will generate the code and commit it in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you created a new message you must go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php&lt;/a&gt; and add the new message in the ProtobufHydrator &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php/raw/master/src/Hydrator/ProtobufHydrator.php&#34;&gt;https://github.com/bagrinsergiu/brizy-protogen-php/blob/master/src/Hydrator/ProtobufHydrator.php&lt;/a&gt; PS: This is small problem that we need to automate.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;WARNING: All classes must have &lt;code&gt;Message.DescriminatorType descriminator = 1;&lt;/code&gt; as first field.&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ex:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-protobuf&#34;&gt;message RemoveEntityTranslationMessage {&#xA;  Message.DescriminatorType descriminator = 1;&#xA;  int32 project_id = 2;&#xA;  string entity_iri = 3;&#xA;  string project_iri = 4;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>