<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-29T01:26:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>NCBI-Codeathons/mlxai-2024-team-smith</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T01:26:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-29:/NCBI-Codeathons/mlxai-2024-team-smith</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/NCBI-Codeathons/mlxai-2024-team-smith" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;A Gentle Introduction to ML/AI as Applied to Antibody Engineering&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Smith Roster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Role&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Participant&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Affiliation&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Team Lead&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Todd Smith, PhD&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Digital World Biology, LLC&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Tech Lead&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Herminio Vazquez&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Copado Inc.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Writer&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Stephen Panossian&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Unaffiliated&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Flex&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Zainab Adenaike&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;NIH/NLM/NCBI&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Flex&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Jake Lance&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;student, University of Toronto&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Flex&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Mohsen Sharifi Renani&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Spotify AB&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Project Goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on applying machine learning and artificial intelligence (ML/AI) methods to immunoprofiling. The team will develop a Jupyter notebook and underlying software to first undertake comparative analyses of the iReceptor dataset, and then incorporate the AbLang2 antibody-specific language model to characterize data within the Structural Antibody Database. Also, the team will develop a dictionary/glossary defining essential computer and biology terms related to the computations processed within the Jupyter notebook.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following diagrams represent the high-level methods employed in Data Science and Bioinformatics&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Data Method&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;    flowchart LR&#xA;    &#xA;    A[Collect] --&amp;gt; B[Profile]&#xA;    B --&amp;gt;C{complete?}&#xA;    C--&amp;gt;|Yes|D[Exploration]&#xA;    C--&amp;gt;|No|A&#xA;    D --&amp;gt; E[Charts]&#xA;    D --&amp;gt; F[Impute]&#xA;    E --&amp;gt; G[Aggregate]&#xA;    F --&amp;gt; G&#xA;    G --&amp;gt; H[Model]&#xA;    H --&amp;gt; I[Feature Engineering]&#xA;    I --&amp;gt; J[Train/Test]&#xA;    I --&amp;gt; K[Tune]&#xA;    K --&amp;gt; J&#xA;    J --&amp;gt; L[Predict]&#xA;    L --&amp;gt; M[Operationalize]&#xA;    M --&amp;gt; N[Monitor]&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Approach&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The team will use software tools including Amazon Web Service (AWS) cloud computing accounts, Docker containers, Jupyter notebooks, and datasets from both iReceptor and SAbDab (The Structural Antibody Database) from the Oxford Protein Information Group (OPIG). The team will also identify relevant NCBI SRA (Sequence Read Archive) datasets. The general workflow is: 1) create an AWS instance, 2) upload a Docker container, 3) step through the enclosed Jupyter notebook, and 4) analyze the antibody results. Prior work illustrates this approach:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example: Covid not Covid&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/covid-not-covid&#34;&gt;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/covid-not-covid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;notebook: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/covid-not-covid/raw/main/ab_predict_neutralising.ipynb&#34;&gt;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/covid-not-covid/blob/main/ab_predict_neutralising.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;datafile: covabdab_all.csv&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example: ImmuneProfiling&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/immune-profiling&#34;&gt;https://github.com/AntibodyEngineers/immune-profiling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;data: (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gateway.ireceptor.org/sequences?query_id=85212&#34;&gt;https://gateway.ireceptor.org/sequences?query_id=85212&lt;/a&gt;), needs to be uploaded to our Amazon instance&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2024 ML/AI Codeathon Log&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Issues&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;26-Feb-2024&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Several issues utilizing Docker&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;27-Feb-2024&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Team accessed AWS account and Jupyter notebook; runtime challenges&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;28-Feb-2024&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;None reported&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;29-Feb-2024&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;01-Mar-2024&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future Work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Project materials will create a resource with instruction and hands-on examples that can demystify ML/AI for many scientists and students who need greater awareness of the data, steps, and practicalities. The focus on antibodies supports work in basic research and biotechnology. Digital World Biology&#39;s Antibody Engineering Hackathons are creating materials for course-base undergraduate research in community colleges (&lt;a href=&#34;https://antibody-engineers.org/&#34;&gt;https://antibody-engineers.org/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The resulting work will be used in Digital World Biology&#39;s National Science Foundation funded summer hackathon (August 2024) on antibody engineering. In the project we will consider ML applications for predicting antibody antigen recognition, genetic contributions to antibody expression, and de novo antibody design. Work will identify one or two examples that include specific datasets, workflows, an appropriate ML method, and tests. The examples will then be used to create instructions and explanations that can be used in classroom settings, starting points for undergraduate research, and scientists wishing they had ways to better understand ML.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;NCBI Codeathon Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software was created as part of an NCBI codeathon, a hackathon-style event focused on rapid innovation. While we encourage you to explore and adapt this code, please be aware that NCBI does not provide ongoing support for it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For general questions about NCBI software and tools, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/home/about/contact/&#34;&gt;NCBI Contact Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>auth0-training/labs-node-working-with-actions</title>
    <updated>2024-02-29T01:26:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-29:/auth0-training/labs-node-working-with-actions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/auth0-training/labs-node-working-with-actions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://training.auth0.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/73120/125103885-a2bb5d80-e091-11eb-8084-383003f1e484.png&#34; alt=&#34;Auth0 Training&#34; title=&#34;Auth0 Training&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Lab Node Working with Actions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this hands-on lab learners will put Actions into practice. Specifically, they&#39;ll create an explicit Allow User List, create an Allow User List for Admin Applications, and enable Admin Only Access for Admin Applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Note: This lab template is an experimental release, and is built on a best-efforts basis by some Auth0 developers in their available innovation time. It is open-source licensed and free to use, and is not covered by any Auth0 Terms of Service or Agreements. If you have issues with this template you can engage with the project&#39;s developer community through the repository GitHub Issues list, or contribute fixes and enhancements of your own via a Pull Request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A GitHub account: Our labs use GitHub Codespaces, so you&#39;ll need a GitHub account to access them. Create a free account &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/get-started/signing-up-for-github/signing-up-for-a-new-github-account&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An Auth0 account: You&#39;ll also need an Auth0 account. If you do not already have one, you can create a free one &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/signup&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Accessing and Working with Auth0 Labs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fork this lab repo to your GitHub account:&lt;/strong&gt; Click the &#34;Fork&#34; button located in the top right corner of the GitHub page. On the resulting page, under &#34;Owner,&#34; select the dropdown menu and choose yourself as the owner for the forked repository. Then click the “Create fork” button. After a moment or two, you&#39;ll land on your fork of the repository. This fork now belongs to you, and you can revisit it later at any time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open the lab repo in a Codespace:&lt;/strong&gt; From the “Code” dropdown menu, toggle to the Codespaces tab. Click the plus sign to create and open the lab in a Codespace. A new tab will open, and Codespaces will begin configuring the lab environment. Wait for the environment to finish building.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Begin working with the lab:&lt;/strong&gt; Once the environment is ready you&#39;ll see a Codetour popup with instructions for connecting the lab to your Auth0 account. This can take some time, as the environment is installing several plugins to facilitate the lab. Once it is complete, you can open the Codetour to view all steps using the panel in the lower right. Follow the lab instructions (clicking to configure, selecting next, inserting code, etc.) in order to complete the lab.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you&#39;d like to save your work to your forked lab repo:&lt;/strong&gt; You can commit and push your changes to your fork (See: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/codespaces/developing-in-codespaces/using-source-control-in-your-codespace&#34;&gt;Using Source Control in Your Codespace&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IMPORTANT: Close the Codespace when you&#39;re finished with the lab:&lt;/strong&gt; Codespaces come with a set amount of free usage. To avoid using all of your free use allocation, be sure to return to the forked repo, select the &#34;Code&#34; dropdown, select the dots next to your open Codespace, and select &#34;Delete.&#34; This will not delete your forked repository. You can keep that forever, and open a new Codespace whenever you like.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is Auth0?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Auth0 helps you to:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add authentication with &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/docs/identityproviders&#34;&gt;multiple authentication sources&lt;/a&gt;, either social like &lt;strong&gt;Google, Facebook, Microsoft Account, LinkedIn, GitHub, Twitter, Box, Salesforce, among others&lt;/strong&gt;, or enterprise identity systems like &lt;strong&gt;Windows Azure AD, Google Apps, Active Directory, ADFS or any SAML Identity Provider&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add authentication through more traditional &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/docs/connections/database/custom-db&#34;&gt;username/password databases&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add support for &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/docs/link-accounts&#34;&gt;linking different user accounts&lt;/a&gt; with the same user.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for generating signed &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/docs/jwt&#34;&gt;JSON Web Tokens&lt;/a&gt; to call your APIs and &lt;strong&gt;flow the user identity&lt;/strong&gt; securely.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Analytics of how, when, and where users are logging in.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pull data from other sources and add it to the user profile, through &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/docs/rules/current&#34;&gt;JavaScript rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Issue Reporting&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have found a bug or if you have a feature request, please report them at this repository issues section. Please do not report security vulnerabilities on the public GitHub issue tracker. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/whitehat&#34;&gt;Responsible Disclosure Program&lt;/a&gt; details the procedure for disclosing security issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Author&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com&#34;&gt;Auth0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT license. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/auth0-training/labs-node-working-with-actions/main/LICENSE.txt&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for more info.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>