<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-15T01:28:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp</title>
    <updated>2023-11-15T01:28:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-15:/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Gravitational Wave Data Exploration: A Practical Training in Programming and Analysis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;引力波数据探索：编程与分析实战训练营&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Gravitational Wave Data Exploration: A Practical Training in Programming and Analysis&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Under construction...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the GitHub repository for the Gravitational Wave Data Exploration Bootcamp Series! This course is meticulously designed to provide a solid foundation in programming, operational knowledge, and data-driven modeling skills centered around gravitational wave data analysis and research.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/logo-taiji.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width:20%;height:auto;&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Training Objectives&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Equip participants with robust programming and operational skills, and foundational training in data-driven modeling, focusing on gravitational wave data analysis and related research areas.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: The course is conducted entirely in Mandarin Chinese to cater to a wide range of Chinese-speaking students and researchers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Discuss the common research methodologies combining gravitational wave data processing with AI technologies, with hands-on examples and projects for practical understanding and mastery.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Analyze cutting-edge deep learning models and apply them to real-world gravitational wave data analysis problems through specific case studies.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Target Audience&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Undergraduate and graduate students interested in data analysis and algorithm development, especially those focusing on gravitational wave data processing and related research.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The course also welcomes undergraduates with a basic programming background, looking to enhance their data analysis skills or with an interest in gravitational wave data processing.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Future professionals aspiring to work in space-based gravitational wave detection projects and related research fields.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Design Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Drawing from past teaching experiences and identified knowledge gaps in student research projects, the course introduces relevant concepts and common methods to ensure comprehensive understanding and application in research.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The course is scheduled weekly or bi-weekly, each session lasting about 3 hours, combining online and offline methods (腾讯会议) to ensure interactivity and practicality.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The curriculum is expected to be offered once per semester or annually, with continual updates and enrichment based on student feedback and research demands.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Course Outline / Schedule&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part Zero&lt;/strong&gt;: Motivational Introduction: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/2023/intro/readme.md&#34;&gt;2023/11/08&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part One&lt;/strong&gt;: Programming Development Environment and Workflow: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/2023/workflow/readme.md&#34;&gt;2023/11/12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Linux Commands and Shell Scripting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Git Version Control (GitHub / GitLab)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;SSH Remote Server Access (Shell / VSCode)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Containerization with Docker&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Setting up Python / Jupyter Development Environment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Compiling LALsuite / LISAcode Source Code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part Two&lt;/strong&gt;: Python-Based Data Analysis Fundamentals&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Python Programming&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Algorithms with Numpy / Pandas / Scipy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Exploratory Data Analysis of GW Event Catalog / Glitch Data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Matched Filtering for GW150914 Data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Data Visualization in Python: Theory and Practice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Reproducing Figures from GWTC Papers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part Three&lt;/strong&gt;: Basics of Machine Learning&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Overview of Artificial Intelligence&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Definitions, Objectives, and Types of Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Machine Learning Project Development and Preparation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Clustering Analysis of LIGO&#39;s Glitch Data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part Four&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduction to Deep Learning&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Overview of Deep Learning Technologies&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fundamentals of Artificial Neural Networks (ANN)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Hands-On: Identifying Gravitational Waves from Binary Black Hole Systems using CNN&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Frontiers of Gravitational Wave Data Analysis and AI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To participate in this course:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clone the repository: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Under construction)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Staff&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This class is co-taught by &lt;a href=&#34;https://iphysresearch.github.io/blog/&#34;&gt;He Wang&lt;/a&gt; and several esteemed colleagues, including guest lecturers and industry experts, whose names will be announced as they join.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any inquiries regarding the course, please email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:taiji@ucas.ac.cn&#34;&gt;📧 taiji@ucas.ac.cn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We look forward to your participation and contribution to this exciting field of study!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome contributions to enhance course materials. Please fork the repository, make your changes, and submit a pull request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Collaborating Institutions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://english.ucas.ac.cn/&#34;&gt;University of Chinese Academy of Sciences&lt;/a&gt; (UCAS)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/logo-ucas.png&#34; style=&#34;width:30%;height:auto;&#34;&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ictp-ap.org/&#34;&gt;International Centre for Theoretical Physics Asia-Pacific&lt;/a&gt; (ICTP-AP)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/logo-ictp-ap.png&#34; style=&#34;width:30%;height:auto;&#34;&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ictp-ap.org/page/taiji-laboratory&#34;&gt;Taiji Laboratory for Gravitational Wave Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/logo-taiji-lab.png&#34; style=&#34;width:20%;height:auto;&#34;&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/iphysresearch/GWData-Bootcamp/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Contributions from the Gravitational Wave Open Science Center (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gwosc.org/&#34;&gt;gwosc.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Educational resources and datasets from renowned institutions and projects in the field.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LinkedInLearning/advanced-python-working-with-databases-4365479</title>
    <updated>2023-11-15T01:28:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-15:/LinkedInLearning/advanced-python-working-with-databases-4365479</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LinkedInLearning/advanced-python-working-with-databases-4365479" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Advanced Python: Working with Databases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Advanced Python: Working with Databases&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the repository for the LinkedIn Learning course Advanced Python: Working with Databases. The full course is available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/advanced-python-working-with-databases-22307421?dApp=59033956&amp;amp;leis=LAA&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D560DAQGxhz_OMvM_mQ/learning-public-crop_675_1200/0/1683668063867?e=2147483647&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=frT7osblpohhLDjZqRYyklw6-Fay7Mgtr5hsv0QvLuc&#34; alt=&#34;Advanced Python: Working with Databases&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To create functional and useful Python applications, you need a database. Databases allow you to store data from user sessions, track inventory, make recommendations, and more. However, Python is compatible with many options: SQLite, MySQL, and PostgreSQL, among others. Selecting the right database is a skill that advanced developers are expected to master. This course provides an excellent primer, comparing the different types of databases that can be connected through the Python Database API. Instructor Kathryn Hodge teaches the differences between SQLite, MySQL, and PostgreSQL and shows how to use the ORM tool SQLAlchemy to query a database. The final chapters put your knowledge to practical use in two hands-on projects: developing a full-stack application with Python, PostgreSQL, and Flask and creating a data analysis app with pandas and Jupyter Notebook. By the end, you should feel comfortable creating and using databases and be able to decide which Python database is right for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository has branches for each of the videos in the course. You can use the branch pop up menu in github to switch to a specific branch and take a look at the course at that stage, or you can add &lt;code&gt;/tree/BRANCH_NAME&lt;/code&gt; to the URL to go to the branch you want to access.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Branches&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The branches are structured to correspond to the videos in the course. The naming convention is &lt;code&gt;CHAPTER#_MOVIE#&lt;/code&gt;. As an example, the branch named &lt;code&gt;02_03&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to the second chapter and the third video in that chapter. Some branches will have a beginning and an end state. These are marked with the letters &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;beginning&#34; and &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; for &#34;end&#34;. The &lt;code&gt;b&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the beginning of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; branch contains the code as it is at the end of the movie. The &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch holds the final state of the code when in the course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When switching from one exercise files branch to the next after making changes to the files, you may get a message like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;error: Your local changes to the following files would be overwritten by checkout:        [files]&#xA;Please commit your changes or stash them before you switch branches.&#xA;Aborting&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To resolve this issue:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Add changes to git using this command: git add .&#xA;Commit changes using this command: git commit -m &#34;some message&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instructor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kathryn Hodge&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out my other courses on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/learning/instructors/kathryn-hodge&#34;&gt;LinkedIn Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>