<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-07T01:27:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>containers/ai-lab-recipes</title>
    <updated>2024-05-07T01:27:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-07:/containers/ai-lab-recipes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Examples for building and running LLM services and applications locally with Podman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AI Lab Recipes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains recipes for building and running containerized AI and LLM Applications with Podman.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These containerized AI recipes can be used to help developers quickly prototype new AI and LLM based applications locally, without the need for relying on any other externally hosted services. Since they are already containerized, it also helps developers move quickly from prototype to production.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Model servers&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;What&#39;s a model server?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A model server is a program that serves machine-learning models, such as LLMs, and makes their functions available via an API. This makes it easy for developers to incorporate AI into their applications. This repository provides descriptions and code for building several of these model servers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the sample applications rely on the &lt;code&gt;llamacpp_python&lt;/code&gt; model server by default. This server can be used for various generative AI applications with various models. However, each sample application can be paired with a variety of model servers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build and run the llamacpp_python model server by following the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/model_servers/llamacpp_python/README.md&#34;&gt;llamacpp_python model server README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current Recipes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recipes consist of at least two components: A model server and an AI application. The model server manages the model, and the AI application provides the specific logic needed to perform some specific task such as chat, summarization, object detection, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are several sample applications in this repository that can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes&#34;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;They fall under the categories:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes/audio&#34;&gt;audio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes/computer_vision&#34;&gt;computer-vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes/multimodal&#34;&gt;multimodal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes/natural_language_processing&#34;&gt;natural language processing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to build and run each application by visiting their README&#39;s. For example, learn how to run the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/recipes/natural_language_processing/chatbot&#34;&gt;chatbot recipe here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current AI Lab Recipe images built from this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Images for many sample applications and models are available in &lt;code&gt;quay.io&lt;/code&gt;. All currently built images are tracked in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/ailab-images.md&#34;&gt;ailab-images.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/containers/ai-lab-recipes/main/training/README.md&#34;&gt;Training&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux Operating System Bootable containers enabled for AI Training&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>