<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-04T01:33:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Code-Institute-Org/ci-full-template</title>
    <updated>2023-05-04T01:33:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-04:/Code-Institute-Org/ci-full-template</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Code-Institute-Org/ci-full-template" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://codeinstitute.s3.amazonaws.com/fullstack/ci_logo_small.png&#34; alt=&#34;CI logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome,&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the Code Institute student template for Codeanywhere. We have preinstalled all of the tools you need to get started. It&#39;s perfectly ok to use this template as the basis for your project submissions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can safely delete this README.md file, or change it for your own project. Please do read it at least once, though! It contains some important information about Codeanywhere and the extensions we use. Some of this information has been updated since the video content was created. The last update to this file was: &lt;strong&gt;March 3rd, 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Codeanywhere Reminders&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run a frontend (HTML, CSS, Javascript only) application in Codeanywhere, in the terminal, type:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python3 -m http.server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A button should appear to click: &lt;em&gt;Open Preview&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Open Browser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run a frontend (HTML, CSS, Javascript only) application in Codeanywhere with no-cache, you can use this alias for &lt;code&gt;python3 -m http.server&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;http_server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run a backend Python file, type &lt;code&gt;python3 app.py&lt;/code&gt;, if your Python file is named &lt;code&gt;app.py&lt;/code&gt; of course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A button should appear to click: &lt;em&gt;Open Preview&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Open Browser&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Codeanywhere you have superuser security privileges by default. Therefore you do not need to use the &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; (superuser do) command in the bash terminal in any of the lessons.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To log into the Heroku toolbelt CLI:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Log in to your Heroku account and go to &lt;em&gt;Account Settings&lt;/em&gt; in the menu under your avatar.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to the &lt;em&gt;API Key&lt;/em&gt; and click &lt;em&gt;Reveal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy the key&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In Codeanywhere, from the terminal, run &lt;code&gt;heroku_config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Paste in your API key when asked&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can now use the &lt;code&gt;heroku&lt;/code&gt; CLI program - try running &lt;code&gt;heroku apps&lt;/code&gt; to confirm it works. This API key is unique and private to you so do not share it. If you accidentally make it public then you can create a new one with &lt;em&gt;Regenerate API Key&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Happy coding!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>