<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Dockerfile Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-13T01:35:29Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Dockerfile in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>jduncan-rva/container-fundamentals</title>
    <updated>2023-07-13T01:35:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-13:/jduncan-rva/container-fundamentals</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jduncan-rva/container-fundamentals" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code associated with Corise.com Conainer Fundamentals Course&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository and any associated artifacts are designed to be used with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://corise.com/course/docker-and-container-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Container Fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; online course.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;edge_server&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A simple static website used to manage folks in the field and provide positive reinforcement. It&#39;s also used to help discuss how container images are constructed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EspressoCake/BOF_Development_Docker</title>
    <updated>2023-07-13T01:35:29Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-13:/EspressoCake/BOF_Development_Docker</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/EspressoCake/BOF_Development_Docker" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A VSCode devcontainer for development of COFF files with batteries included.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;BOF_Development_Docker&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository serves as a fully functional, &lt;strong&gt;lightweight&lt;/strong&gt; template for developing and compiling &lt;code&gt;BOF&lt;/code&gt; or otherwise &lt;code&gt;Windows&lt;/code&gt;-centric applications via &lt;code&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/code&gt; has supported idempotent, purpose-built containers for development for a few years.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is meant to illustrate on how powerful this is, namely:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Remote installation of extension configurations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reliable &lt;code&gt;Intellisense&lt;/code&gt; for development using path inspection&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Quick, reliable, readily deployable images for rapid development&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lack of configuration drift between traditional virtual machine IDEs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Opening this folder within &lt;code&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/code&gt;, you will be prompted to reopen within a container.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging this (and assuming you have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/containers/overview&#34;&gt;Docker VSCode extension&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Docker&lt;/code&gt; already installed) will reload the current window to be &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; of the container it has built for you. That&#39;s it. Happy hacking.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Elections and Benefits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m currently using &lt;code&gt;musl&lt;/code&gt; as the set of header files/libraries/compiler options. This plays a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; nicer with the numerous hacks of function pointers leveraged within many popular projects, to include reflective loaders of choice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re running on a slim &lt;code&gt;Alpine&lt;/code&gt; image due to its size and first-class support of &lt;code&gt;musl&lt;/code&gt; natively. This is just one less headache, and we can leave the &#34;kitchen sink&#34; bloat of other images.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The configuration of the extensions is already done for you, so &lt;code&gt;Intellisense&lt;/code&gt; among other things (such as peeking definitions) is a single right-click away.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>