<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-29T01:53:01Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>radius-project/radius</title>
    <updated>2023-10-29T01:53:01Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-29:/radius-project/radius</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/radius-project/radius" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Radius is a cloud-native, portable application platform that makes app development easier for teams building cloud-native apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Radius&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radius is a cloud-native application platform that enables developers and the platform engineers that support them to collaborate on delivering and managing cloud-native applications that follow organizational best practices for cost, operations and security, by default. Radius is an open-source project that supports deploying applications across private cloud, Microsoft Azure, and Amazon Web Services, with more cloud providers to come.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The evolution of cloud computing has increased the speed of innovation for many companies, whether they are building 2 and 3-tier applications, or complex microservice-based applications. Cloud native technologies like Kubernetes have made it easier to build applications that can run anywhere. At the same time, many applications have become more complex, and managing them in the cloud increasingly difficult, as companies build cloud-native applications composed of interconnected services and deploy them to multiple public clouds and their private infrastructure. While Kubernetes is a key enabler, we see many organizations building abstractions over Kubernetes, usually focused on compute, to work around its limitations: Kubernetes has no formal definition of an application, it mingles infrastructure and application concepts and it is overwhelmingly complex. Developers also inevitably realize their applications require much more than Kubernetes, including support for dependencies like application programming interface (API) front ends, key/value stores, caches, and observability systems. Amidst these challenges for developers, their corporate IT counterparts also must enforce an ever-growing matrix of corporate standards, compliance, and security requirements, while enabling rapid application innovation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radius was designed to address these distinct but related challenges that arise across development and operations as companies continue their journey to cloud. Radius meets application teams where they are by supporting proven technologies like Kubernetes, existing infrastructure tools including Terraform and Bicep and by integrating with existing CI/CD systems like GitHub Actions. Radius supports multi-tier web-plus-data to complex microservice applications like eShop, a popular cloud reference application from Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Key features of the Radius platform include:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Collaboration&lt;/em&gt;: Radius Applications and Environments allow developers to work with Operations on application definition and delivery.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infrastructure Recipes&lt;/em&gt;: Swappable infrastructure that complies with organization best practicies and IT policy be default.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Application Graph&lt;/em&gt;: Understand how services and infrastructure in an application are interconnected.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cloud Neutral&lt;/em&gt;: Deploy across development, on-premises and cloud environments with a consistent experience.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incremental Adoption&lt;/em&gt;: Integrate Radius into existing workflows and existing catalogs of Infrastructure-as-Code templates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Release status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an early release of Radius which enables the community to learn about and experiment with the platform. Please let us know what you think and open Issues when you find bugs or want to request a new feature. Radius is not yet ready for production workloads.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.radapp.io/getting-started/&#34;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt; to install and try out Radius&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.radapp.io/tutorials&#34;&gt;Tutorials&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.radapp.io/guides&#34;&gt;User Guides&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about Radius and start radifying your apps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;❓ &lt;strong&gt;Have a question?&lt;/strong&gt; - Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/SRG3ePMKNy&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; to post your question and we&#39;ll get back to you ASAP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;⚠️ &lt;strong&gt;Found an issue?&lt;/strong&gt; - Refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/radius-project/radius/main/docs/contributing/contributing-issues&#34;&gt;Issues guide&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on filing a bug report&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;strong&gt;Have a proposal?&lt;/strong&gt; - Refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/radius-project/radius/main/docs/contributing/contributing-issues&#34;&gt;Issues guide&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on filing a feature request&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome your contributions and suggestions! One of the easiest ways to contribute is to participate in Issue discussions, chat on &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/SRG3ePMKNy&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; or the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/radius-project/radius/main/#community-calls&#34;&gt;community calls&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on the community engagement, developer and contributing guidelines and more, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/community&#34;&gt;Radius community repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contact us&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/SRG3ePMKNy&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; to contact us and we&#39;ll get back to you ASAP.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Community calls&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every month we host a community call to showcase new features, review upcoming milestones, and engage in a Q&amp;amp;A. All are welcome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;📞 Visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/community/#community-meetings&#34;&gt;community meetings&lt;/a&gt; page for upcoming dates and the meeting link.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing to Radius&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/radius-project/radius/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to contribute to Radius. To author Radius Recipes visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.radapp.io/guides/recipes/howto-author-recipes/&#34;&gt;Author Custom Radius Recipes&lt;/a&gt;. To contribute to Radius documentation visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.radapp.io/contributing/docs/&#34;&gt;Radius documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repositories&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/radius&#34;&gt;Radius&lt;/a&gt; is the main Radius repository. It contains all of Radius code and documentation. In addition, we have the below repositories.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Repo&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/docs&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repository contains the Radius documentation source for Radius.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/samples&#34;&gt;Samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repository contains the source code for quickstarts, reference apps, and tutorials for Radius.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/recipes&#34;&gt;Recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repo contains commonly used Recipe templates for Radius Environments.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/website&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repository contains the source code for the Radius website.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/bicep&#34;&gt;Bicep&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repository contains source code for Bicep, which is a DSL for deploying cloud resources types.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/bicep-types-aws&#34;&gt;AWS Bicep Types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This repository contains the tooling for Bicep support for AWS resource types.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to our guide on &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/radius-project/radius/main/SECURITY.md&#34;&gt;Reporting security vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radius-project/community/raw/main/CODE-OF-CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Radius Community Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>syncthing/syncthing</title>
    <updated>2023-10-29T01:53:01Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-29:/syncthing/syncthing</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open Source Continuous File Synchronization&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/syncthing/syncthing/main/assets/logo-text-128.png&#34; alt=&#34;Syncthing&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/MPL/2.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-MPLv2-blue.svg?style=flat-square&#34; alt=&#34;MPLv2 License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/88&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/88/badge&#34; alt=&#34;CII Best Practices&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/syncthing/syncthing&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/syncthing/syncthing&#34; alt=&#34;Go Report Card&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syncthing is a &lt;strong&gt;continuous file synchronization program&lt;/strong&gt;. It synchronizes files between two or more computers. We strive to fulfill the goals below. The goals are listed in order of importance, the most important ones first. This is the summary version of the goal list - for more commentary, see the full &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/raw/main/GOALS.md&#34;&gt;Goals document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Syncthing should be:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safe From Data Loss&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Protecting the user&#39;s data is paramount. We take every reasonable precaution to avoid corrupting the user&#39;s files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Against Attackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Again, protecting the user&#39;s data is paramount. Regardless of our other goals, we must never allow the user&#39;s data to be susceptible to eavesdropping or modification by unauthorized parties.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy to Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syncthing should be approachable, understandable, and inclusive.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;User interaction should be required only when absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universally Available&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syncthing should run on every common computer. We are mindful that the latest technology is not always available to every individual.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Individuals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Syncthing is primarily about empowering the individual user with safe, secure, and easy to use file synchronization.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything Else&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are many things we care about that don&#39;t make it on to the list. It is fine to optimize for these values, as long as they are not in conflict with the stated goals above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.syncthing.net/intro/getting-started.html&#34;&gt;getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few examples for keeping Syncthing running in the background on your system in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/raw/main/etc&#34;&gt;the etc directory&lt;/a&gt;. There are also several &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.syncthing.net/users/contrib.html#gui-wrappers&#34;&gt;GUI implementations&lt;/a&gt; for Windows, Mac, and Linux.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Docker&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To run Syncthing in Docker, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/raw/main/README-Docker.md&#34;&gt;the Docker README&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Vote on features/bugs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like to encourage you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bountysource.com/teams/syncthing/issues&#34;&gt;vote&lt;/a&gt; on issues that matter to you. This helps the team understand what are the biggest pain points for our users, and could potentially influence what is being worked on next.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting in Touch&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first and best point of contact is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Forum&lt;/a&gt;. If you&#39;ve found something that is clearly a bug, feel free to report it in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you believe that you’ve found a Syncthing-related security vulnerability, please report it by emailing &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@syncthing.net&#34;&gt;security@syncthing.net&lt;/a&gt;. Do not report it in the Forum or issue tracker.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building Syncthing from source is easy. After extracting the source bundle from a release or checking out git, you just need to run &lt;code&gt;go run build.go&lt;/code&gt; and the binaries are created in &lt;code&gt;./bin&lt;/code&gt;. There&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.syncthing.net/dev/building.html&#34;&gt;a guide&lt;/a&gt; with more details on the build process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Signed Releases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of v0.10.15 and onwards, release binaries are GPG signed with the key D26E6ED000654A3E, available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/security.html&#34;&gt;https://syncthing.net/security.html&lt;/a&gt; and most key servers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is also a built-in automatic upgrade mechanism (disabled in some distribution channels) which uses a compiled in ECDSA signature. macOS binaries are also properly code signed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the Syncthing &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;documentation site&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/docs&#34;&gt;[source]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All code is licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/syncthing/syncthing/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;MPLv2 License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>apache/incubator-answer</title>
    <updated>2023-10-29T01:53:01Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-29:/apache/incubator-answer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/apache/incubator-answer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Q&amp;A platform software for teams at any scales. Whether it&#39;s a community forum, help center, or knowledge management platform, you can always count on Answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://answer.dev&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;logo&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/incubator-answer/main/docs/img/logo.svg?sanitize=true&#34; height=&#34;99px&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Answer - Build Q&amp;amp;A platform&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Q&amp;amp;A platform software for teams at any scales. Whether it’s a community forum, help center, or knowledge management platform, you can always count on Answer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the project, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://answer.dev&#34;&gt;answer.dev&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/answerdev/answer/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/answerdev/answer&#34; alt=&#34;LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-go-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://reactjs.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/language-react-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Language&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/answerdev/answer&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/answerdev/answer&#34; alt=&#34;Go Report Card&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/Jm7Y4cbUej&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/discord-chat-5865f2?logo=discord&amp;amp;logoColor=f5f5f5&#34; alt=&#34;Discord&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apache/incubator-answer/main/docs/img/screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Running with docker&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;docker run -d -p 9080:80 -v answer-data:/data --name answer answerdev/answer:latest&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://answer.dev/docs/installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Answer provides a plugin system for developers to create custom plugins and expand Answer’s features. You can find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://answer.dev/docs/development/extending/&#34;&gt;plugin documentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We value your feedback and suggestions to improve our documentation. If you have any comments or questions, please feel free to contact us. We’re excited to see what you can create using our plugin system!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/answerdev/plugins&#34;&gt;plugins here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are always welcome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://answer.dev/docs/development/contributing/&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; for ways to get started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/answerdev/answer/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;Apache License 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>