<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-18T01:46:16Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish</title>
    <updated>2022-09-18T01:46:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-18:/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;evilginx2 + gophish&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;evilgophish&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Combination of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kgretzky/evilginx2&#34;&gt;evilginx2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gophish/gophish&#34;&gt;GoPhish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I would like to say that I am in no way bashing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kgretzky&#34;&gt;Kuba Gretzky&lt;/a&gt; and his work. I thank him personally for releasing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kgretzky/evilginx2&#34;&gt;evilginx2&lt;/a&gt; to the public. In fact, without his work this work would not exist. I must also thank &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordan-wright&#34;&gt;Jordan Wright&lt;/a&gt; for developing/maintaining the incredible &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gophish/gophish&#34;&gt;GoPhish&lt;/a&gt; toolkit. The last thank you I must make is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_wizard32?lang=en&#34;&gt;Fotios Liatsis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://outpost24.com/&#34;&gt;Outpost24&lt;/a&gt; for sharing their solution to combine these two frameworks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have a fundamental understanding of how to use &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shall not be responsible or liable for any misuse or illegitimate use of this software. This software is only to be used in authorized penetration testing or red team engagements where the operator(s) has(ve) been given explicit written permission to carry out social engineering.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a penetration tester or red teamer, you may have heard of &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; as a proxy man-in-the-middle framework capable of bypassing &lt;code&gt;two-factor/multi-factor authentication&lt;/code&gt;. This is enticing to us to say the least, but when trying to use it for social engineering engagements, there are some issues off the bat. I will highlight the two main problems that have been addressed with this project, although some other bugs have been fixed in this version which I will highlight later.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Lack of tracking - &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; does not provide unique tracking statistics per victim (e.g. opened email, clicked link, etc.), this is problematic for clients who want/need/pay for these statistics when signing up for a social engineering engagement.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Session overwriting with NAT and proxying - &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; bases a lot of logic off of remote IP address and will whitelist an IP for 10 minutes after the victim triggers a lure path. &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; will then skip creating a new session for the IP address if it triggers the lure path again (if still in the 10 minute window). This presents issues for us if our victims are behind a firewall all sharing the same public IP address, as the same session within &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; will continue to overwrite with multiple victim&#39;s data, leading to missed and lost data. This also presents an issue for our proxy setup, since &lt;code&gt;localhost&lt;/code&gt; is the only IP address requesting &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is based on this &lt;a href=&#34;https://outpost24.com/blog/Better-proxy-than-story&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and I encourage you to read it before getting started. In this setup, &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; is used to send emails, track opened emails, and provide a dashboard for &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; campaign statistics, but it is not used for any landing pages. To provide tracking between the two, the function resposible for providing campaign results inside &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; has been modified to instead get clicked link event details and submitted data event details from logs related to &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt;. Your phishing links sent from &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; will point to an &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; lure path and &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; will be used for landing pages. This provides the ability to still bypass &lt;code&gt;2FA/MFA&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt;, without losing those precious stats. The operator will also be informed of a submitted data event in realtime. This should ensure the operator won&#39;t run out of time to use captured cookies, or at least be informed as soon as possible. The operator will still need to bounce over to the &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; terminal to fetch the full &lt;code&gt;JSON&lt;/code&gt; string of captured tokens/cookies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Infrastructure Layout&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; will listen locally on port &lt;code&gt;8443&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; will listen locally on port &lt;code&gt;8080&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; will listen on port &lt;code&gt;443&lt;/code&gt; externally and proxy to either local &lt;code&gt;GoPhish/evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; depending on the subdomain name requested. &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; access log file is created for both &lt;code&gt;GoPhish/evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; servers &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Requests will be filtered at &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; layer based on redirect rules and IP blacklist configuration &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;404&lt;/code&gt; functionality for unauthorized requests is still baked into &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; if a request hits the &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Redirect functionality for unauthorized requests is still baked into &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; if a request hits the &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; server&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;setup.sh&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://outpost24.com/blog/Better-proxy-than-story&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and understand how the setup works, &lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt; has been provided to automate the needed configurations for you. Once this script is run and you&#39;ve fed it the right values, you should be ready to get started. Below is the setup help (note that certificate setup is based on &lt;code&gt;letsencrypt&lt;/code&gt; filenames):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Usage:&#xA;./setup &amp;lt;root domain&amp;gt; &amp;lt;evilginx2 subdomain(s)&amp;gt; &amp;lt;evilginx2 root domain bool&amp;gt; &amp;lt;gophish subdomain(s)&amp;gt; &amp;lt;gophish root domain bool&amp;gt; &amp;lt;redirect url&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Teams messages bool&amp;gt; &#xA; - root domain                     - the root domain to be used for the campaign&#xA; - evilginx2 subdomains            - a space separated list of evilginx2 subdomains, can be one if only one&#xA; - evilginx2 root domain bool      - true or false to proxy root domain to evilginx2&#xA; - gophish subdomains              - a space separated list of gophish subdomains, can be one if only one&#xA; - gophish root domain bool        - true or false to proxy root domain to gophish&#xA; - redirect url                    - URL to redirect unauthorized Apache requests&#xA; - Teams messages bool             - true or false to setup Microsoft Teams messages&#xA;Example:&#xA;  ./setup.sh example.com login false &#34;download www&#34; false https://redirect.com/ true&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Redirect rules have been included to keep unwanted visitors from visiting the phishing server as well as an IP blacklist. The blacklist contains IP addresses/blocks owned by ProofPoint, Microsoft, TrendMicro, etc. Redirect rules will redirect known &lt;em&gt;&#34;bad&#34;&lt;/em&gt; remote hostnames as well as User-Agent strings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Email Campaign Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once &lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt; is run, the next steps are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure the &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; log file for &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; exists before starting &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; (starting &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; will automatically do this)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; and configure email template (see note below about email opened tracking), email sending profile, fake landing page, and groups&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; and configure phishlet and lure&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; server is started&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Launch campaign from &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; and make the landing URL your lure path for &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; phishlet&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROFIT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SMS Campaign Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An entire reworking of &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; was performed in order to provide &lt;code&gt;SMS&lt;/code&gt; campaign support with &lt;code&gt;Twilio&lt;/code&gt;. Your new &lt;code&gt;evilgophish&lt;/code&gt; dashboard will look like below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/new-dashboard.png&#34; alt=&#34;new-dashboard&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have run &lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt;, the next steps are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure the &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; log file for &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; exists before starting &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; (starting &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; will automatically do this)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure &lt;code&gt;SMS&lt;/code&gt; message template. You will use &lt;code&gt;Text&lt;/code&gt; only when creating a &lt;code&gt;SMS&lt;/code&gt; message template, and you should not include a tracking link as it will appear in the &lt;code&gt;SMS&lt;/code&gt; message. Leave &lt;code&gt;Envelope Sender&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Subject&lt;/code&gt; blank like below:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/sms-message-template.png&#34; alt=&#34;sms-message-template&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configure &lt;code&gt;SMS Sending Profile&lt;/code&gt;. Enter your &lt;code&gt;Twilio&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;Account SID&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Auth Token&lt;/code&gt;, and delay in between messages into the &lt;code&gt;SMS Sending Profile&lt;/code&gt; page:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/sms-sending-profile.png&#34; alt=&#34;sms-sending-profile&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Import groups. The &lt;code&gt;CSV&lt;/code&gt; template values have been kept the same for compatibility, so keep the &lt;code&gt;CSV&lt;/code&gt; column names the same and place your target phone numbers into the &lt;code&gt;Email&lt;/code&gt; column. Note that &lt;code&gt;Twilio&lt;/code&gt; accepts the following phone number formats, so they must be in one of these three:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/twilio-number-formats.png&#34; alt=&#34;twilio-number-formats&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a fake landing page in &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; and configure phishlet and lure&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ensure &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; server is started&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Launch campaign from &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; and make the landing URL your lure path for &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; phishlet&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROFIT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Teams Setup&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This feature will send campaign events as messages to a &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/code&gt; channel. This setup is optional and you do not have to receive campaign events via &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/code&gt;. If you &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; like to, this setup will guide you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a new channel for the campaign&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Within the web version of &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/code&gt; (I experienced a bug with the Desktop version), select the three dots next to the channel and click on &lt;code&gt;Connectors&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/teams-connectors.png&#34; alt=&#34;teams-connectors&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Within this menu, search for &lt;code&gt;Incoming Webhook&lt;/code&gt;, you should see the following:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/teams-webhook.png&#34; alt=&#34;teams-webhook&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Give the webhook a name, copy the &lt;code&gt;URL&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;DON&#39;T LOSE IT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When running &lt;code&gt;setup.sh&lt;/code&gt;, set &lt;code&gt;Teams messages bool&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; and paste the webhook URL into the script when prompted&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Setup complete! You will now receive &lt;code&gt;Microsoft Teams&lt;/code&gt; messages to a channel notifying you of events for your campaigns, you will see the messages start to come through like below:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/fin3ss3g0d/evilgophish/main/images/teams-demo.png&#34; alt=&#34;teams-demo.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Ensuring Email Opened Tracking&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;CANNOT&lt;/strong&gt; use the default &lt;code&gt;Add Tracking Image&lt;/code&gt; button when creating your email template. You &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; include your own image tag that points at the &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; server with the tracking URL scheme. This is also explained/shown in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://outpost24.com/blog/Better-proxy-than-story&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. For example, if your &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; subdomain is &lt;code&gt;download.example.org&lt;/code&gt;, and your &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; lure path is &lt;code&gt;https://login.example.org/login&lt;/code&gt;, you would include the following tag in your email &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; which will provide email opened tracking in &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&#34;https://download.example.org/login/track?client_id={{.RId}}&#34;/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; make sure &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; is logging to the file defined in &lt;code&gt;gophish/config.json&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; server, the default path is &lt;code&gt;/var/log/apache2/access_evilginx2.log&lt;/code&gt; unless you change it. For example, if &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt; is logging to &lt;code&gt;/var/log/apache2/access_evilginx2.log.1&lt;/code&gt; and you have &lt;code&gt;/var/log/apache2/access_evilginx2.log&lt;/code&gt; defined in &lt;code&gt;gophish/config.json&lt;/code&gt;, you will lose tracking statistics.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Phishlets Surprise&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Included in the &lt;code&gt;evilginx2/phishlets&lt;/code&gt; folder are three custom phishlets not included in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kgretzky/evilginx2&#34;&gt;evilginx2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;O3652&lt;/code&gt; - modified/updated version of the original &lt;code&gt;o365&lt;/code&gt; (stolen from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.optiv.com/insights/source-zero/blog/spear-phishing-modern-platforms&#34;&gt;Optiv blog&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;google&lt;/code&gt; - updated from previous examples online&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;knowbe4&lt;/code&gt; - custom (don&#39;t have access to an account for testing auth URL, works for single-factor campaigns, have not fully tested MFA)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;A Word About Phishlets&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I feel like the world has been lacking some good phishlet examples lately. It would be great if this repository could be a central repository for the latest phishlets. Send me your phishlets at &lt;code&gt;fin3ss3g0d@pm.me&lt;/code&gt; for a chance to end up in &lt;code&gt;evilginx2/phishlets&lt;/code&gt;. If you provide quality work, I will create a &lt;code&gt;Phishlets Hall of Fame&lt;/code&gt; and you will be added to it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changes To evilginx2&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All IP whitelisting functionality removed, new proxy session is established for every new visitor that triggers a lure path regardless of remote IP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom credential logging on submitted passwords to &lt;code&gt;~/.evilginx/creds.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Fixed issue with phishlets not extracting credentials from &lt;code&gt;JSON&lt;/code&gt; requests&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Further &lt;em&gt;&#34;bad&#34;&lt;/em&gt; headers have been removed from responses&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added logic to check if &lt;code&gt;mime&lt;/code&gt; type was failed to be retrieved from responses&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; headers relating to &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; have been removed throughout the code (to remove IOCs)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changes to GoPhish&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom logic inserted into &lt;code&gt;GetCampaignResults&lt;/code&gt; function that handles &lt;code&gt;evilginx2&lt;/code&gt; tracking from Apache2 access log&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom logging of events to &lt;code&gt;JSON&lt;/code&gt; format in &lt;code&gt;HandleEvent&lt;/code&gt; functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additional config parameter added for Apache2 log path&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt; headers relating to &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt; have been removed throughout the code (to remove IOCs)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Default server name has been changed to &lt;code&gt;IGNORE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom 404 page functionality, place a &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; file named &lt;code&gt;404.html&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;templates&lt;/code&gt; folder (example has been provided)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;rid=&lt;/code&gt; is now &lt;code&gt;client_id=&lt;/code&gt; in phishing URLs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Transparency endpoint and messages completely removed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;SMS&lt;/code&gt; Campaign Support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;code&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/code&gt; file for changes made since the initial release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All events will only be submitted once into &lt;code&gt;GoPhish&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Issues and Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am taking the same stance as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kgretzky&#34;&gt;Kuba Gretzky&lt;/a&gt; and will not help creating phishlets. There are plenty of examples of working phishlets and for you to create your own, if you open an issue for a phishlet it will be closed. I will also not consider issues with your &lt;code&gt;Apache2&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;DNS&lt;/code&gt;, or certificate setup as legitimate issues and they will be closed. Please read the included &lt;a href=&#34;https://outpost24.com/blog/Better-proxy-than-story&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for how to get setup properly. However, if you encounter a legitimate failure/error with the program, I will take the issue seriously.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future Goals&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additions to IP blacklist and redirect rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add more phishlets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would like to see this project improve and grow over time. If you have improvement ideas, new redirect rules, new IP addresses/blocks to blacklist, phishlets, or suggestions, please email me at: &lt;code&gt;fin3ss3g0d@pm.me&lt;/code&gt; or open a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kubernetes/kubernetes</title>
    <updated>2022-09-18T01:46:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-18:/kubernetes/kubernetes</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Production-Grade Container Scheduling and Management&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Kubernetes (K8s)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/k8s.io/kubernetes&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/badge/k8s.io/kubernetes.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GoPkg Widget&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/569&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bestpractices.coreinfrastructure.org/projects/569/badge&#34; alt=&#34;CII Best Practices&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/raw/master/logo/logo.png&#34; width=&#34;100&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes, also known as K8s, is an open source system for managing &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/overview/what-is-kubernetes/&#34;&gt;containerized applications&lt;/a&gt; across multiple hosts. It provides basic mechanisms for deployment, maintenance, and scaling of applications.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes builds upon a decade and a half of experience at Google running production workloads at scale using a system called &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.google.com/pubs/pub43438.html&#34;&gt;Borg&lt;/a&gt;, combined with best-of-breed ideas and practices from the community.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes is hosted by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cncf.io/about&#34;&gt;CNCF&lt;/a&gt;). If your company wants to help shape the evolution of technologies that are container-packaged, dynamically scheduled, and microservices-oriented, consider joining the CNCF. For details about who&#39;s involved and how Kubernetes plays a role, read the CNCF &lt;a href=&#34;https://cncf.io/news/announcement/2015/07/new-cloud-native-computing-foundation-drive-alignment-among-container&#34;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;To start using K8s&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See our documentation on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io&#34;&gt;kubernetes.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Try our &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tutorials/kubernetes-basics&#34;&gt;interactive tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take a free course on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udacity.com/course/scalable-microservices-with-kubernetes--ud615&#34;&gt;Scalable Microservices with Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use Kubernetes code as a library in other applications, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.k8s.io/kubernetes/staging/README.md&#34;&gt;list of published components&lt;/a&gt;. Use of the &lt;code&gt;k8s.io/kubernetes&lt;/code&gt; module or &lt;code&gt;k8s.io/kubernetes/...&lt;/code&gt; packages as libraries is not supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;To start developing K8s&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.k8s.io/community&#34;&gt;community repository&lt;/a&gt; hosts all information about building Kubernetes from source, how to contribute code and documentation, who to contact about what, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to build Kubernetes right away there are two options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;You have a working &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/install&#34;&gt;Go environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir -p $GOPATH/src/k8s.io&#xA;cd $GOPATH/src/k8s.io&#xA;git clone https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes&#xA;cd kubernetes&#xA;make&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;You have a working &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine&#34;&gt;Docker environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes&#xA;cd kubernetes&#xA;make quick-release&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the full story, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.k8s.io/community/contributors/devel#readme&#34;&gt;developer&#39;s documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need support, start with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/tasks/debug/&#34;&gt;troubleshooting guide&lt;/a&gt;, and work your way through the process that we&#39;ve outlined.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, if you have questions, reach out to us &lt;a href=&#34;https://git.k8s.io/community/communication&#34;&gt;one way or another&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community Meetings&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kubernetes.dev/resources/calendar/&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt; has the list of all the meetings in Kubernetes community in a single location.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Adopters&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/case-studies/&#34;&gt;User Case Studies&lt;/a&gt; website has real-world use cases of organizations across industries that are deploying/migrating to Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Governance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes project is governed by a framework of principles, values, policies and processes to help our community and constituents towards our shared goals.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/community/raw/master/governance.md&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Community&lt;/a&gt; is the launching point for learning about how we organize ourselves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/steering&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Steering community repo&lt;/a&gt; is used by the Kubernetes Steering Committee, which oversees governance of the Kubernetes project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/enhancements&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Enhancements repo&lt;/a&gt; provides information about Kubernetes releases, as well as feature tracking and backlogs.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>portainer/portainer</title>
    <updated>2022-09-18T01:46:16Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-18:/portainer/portainer</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/portainer/portainer" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Making Docker and Kubernetes management easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img title=&#34;portainer&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/portainer/portainer/raw/develop/app/assets/images/portainer-github-banner.png?raw=true&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portainer Community Edition&lt;/strong&gt; is a lightweight service delivery platform for containerized applications that can be used to manage Docker, Swarm, Kubernetes and ACI environments. It is designed to be as simple to deploy as it is to use. The application allows you to manage all your orchestrator resources (containers, images, volumes, networks and more) through a ‘smart’ GUI and/or an extensive API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer consists of a single container that can run on any cluster. It can be deployed as a Linux container or a Windows native container.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portainer Business Edition&lt;/strong&gt; builds on the open-source base and includes a range of advanced features and functions (like RBAC and Support) that are specific to the needs of business users.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://portainer.io/products&#34;&gt;Compare Portainer CE and Compare Portainer BE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://portainer.io/pricing/take5&#34;&gt;Take5 – get 5 free nodes of Portainer Business for as long as you want them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://install.portainer.io&#34;&gt;Portainer BE install guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Latest Version&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer CE is updated regularly. We aim to do an update release every couple of months.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/portainer/portainer/releases/latest&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/portainer/portainer?color=%2344cc11&amp;amp;label=Latest%20release&amp;amp;style=for-the-badge&#34; alt=&#34;latest version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.portainer.io/v/ce-2.9/start/install&#34;&gt;Deploy Portainer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.portainer.io&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.portainer.io/contributing/instructions/&#34;&gt;Contribute to the project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features &amp;amp; Functions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;View &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/products&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; table to see all of the Portainer CE functionality and compare to Portainer Business.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/solutions/docker&#34;&gt;Portainer CE for Docker / Docker Swarm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/solutions/kubernetes-ui&#34;&gt;Portainer CE for Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/solutions/serverless-containers&#34;&gt;Portainer CE for Azure ACI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer CE is an open source project and is supported by the community. You can buy a supported version of Portainer at portainer.io&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn more about Portainer&#39;s community support channels &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/community_help&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Issues: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues&#34;&gt;https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Slack (chat): &lt;a href=&#34;https://portainer.io/slack&#34;&gt;https://portainer.io/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can join the Portainer Community by visiting community.portainer.io. This will give you advance notice of events, content and other related Portainer content.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting bugs and contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Want to report a bug or request a feature? Please open &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/portainer/portainer/issues/new&#34;&gt;an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Want to help us build &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;portainer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;? Follow our &lt;a href=&#34;https://documentation.portainer.io/contributing/instructions/&#34;&gt;contribution guidelines&lt;/a&gt; to build it locally and make a pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Here at Portainer, we believe in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Responsible_disclosure&#34;&gt;responsible disclosure&lt;/a&gt; of security issues. If you have found a security issue, please report it to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:security@portainer.io&#34;&gt;security@portainer.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Work for us&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are a developer, and our code in this repo makes sense to you, we would love to hear from you. We are always on the hunt for awesome devs, either freelance or employed. Drop us a line to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@portainer.io&#34;&gt;info@portainer.io&lt;/a&gt; with your details and/or visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://portainer.io/careers&#34;&gt;careers page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Privacy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To make sure we focus our development effort in the right places we need to know which features get used most often. To give us this information we use &lt;a href=&#34;https://matomo.org/&#34;&gt;Matomo Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, which is hosted in Germany and is fully GDPR compliant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Portainer first starts, you are given the option to DISABLE analytics. If you &lt;strong&gt;don&#39;t&lt;/strong&gt; choose to disable it, we collect anonymous usage as per &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.portainer.io/documentation/in-app-analytics-and-privacy-policy/&#34;&gt;our privacy policy&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt;, there is no personally identifiable information sent or stored at any time and we only use the data to help us improve Portainer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer supports &#34;Current - 2 docker versions only. Prior versions may operate, however these are not supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer is licensed under the zlib license. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/portainer/portainer/develop/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for reference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Portainer also contains code from open source projects. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/portainer/portainer/develop/ATTRIBUTIONS.md&#34;&gt;ATTRIBUTIONS.md&lt;/a&gt; for a list.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>