<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Go Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-23T01:36:52Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of Go in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>QuilibriumNetwork/ceremonyclient</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T01:36:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-23:/QuilibriumNetwork/ceremonyclient</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/QuilibriumNetwork/ceremonyclient" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mirror of Quilibrium git repo: ceremonyclient&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Quilibrium - Dawn&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quilibrium is a decentralized alternative to platform as a service providers. This release, mirrored to GitHub, is the Dawn release, which contains the initial application, the MPC Powers-of-Tau Ceremony. Documentation for the underlying technology can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quilibrium.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.quilibrium.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All commands are to be run in the &lt;code&gt;node/&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have a voucher from the offline ceremony, first run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GOEXPERIMENT=arenas go run ./... -import-priv-key `cat /path/to/voucher.hex`&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do not, or have already run the above, run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GOEXPERIMENT=arenas go run ./...&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Peer ID&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to find the peer id of a running node, execute the following command from the &lt;code&gt;node/&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GOEXPERIMENT=arenas go run ./... -peer-id&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The peer id will be printed to stdout.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;EXPERIMENTAL – gRPC/REST Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to enable gRPC/REST, add the following entries to your config.yml:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;listenGrpcMultiaddr: &amp;lt;multiaddr&amp;gt; &#xA;listenRESTMultiaddr: &amp;lt;multiaddr&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please note: this interface, while read-only, is unauthenticated and not rate- limited. It is recommended that you only enable if you are properly controlling access via firewall or only query via localhost.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Token Balance&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to query the token balance of a running node, execute the following command from the &lt;code&gt;node/&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;GOEXPERIMENT=arenas go run ./... -balance&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The confirmed token balance will be printed to stdout in QUILs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that this feature requires that &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/QuilibriumNetwork/ceremonyclient/main/#experimental--grpcrest-support&#34;&gt;gRPC support&lt;/a&gt; is enabled.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Stats Collection&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to opt-in to stats collection about the health of the network, edit your &lt;code&gt;config.yml&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;node/.config&lt;/code&gt; directory to have a new section under &lt;code&gt;engine&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;earlier parts of config&amp;gt;&#xA;engine:&#xA;  statsMultiaddr: &#34;/dns/stats.quilibrium.com/tcp/443&#34;&#xA;  &amp;lt;rest of config continues below&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ceremony application provides a secure reference string (SRS) from which KZG proofs can be constructed for the network. This yields applicability for a number of proof systems, in particular for the release after Dawn, the ability to provide proofs of execution, and proofs of data availability for the network.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Rewards&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For participating in a round of the ceremony, nodes will be allocated:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;reward = 161 * log_2(participant_count) QUIL&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Basic Flow&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rounds of the ceremony follow the following order:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;OPEN: Nodes can join in for the round, deferring preference to nodes that could not join in on the prior round&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;IN PROGRESS: The MPC ceremony round is in progress, nodes are engaging in a logarithmic collection of Multiplication-to-Add Oblivious Transfer circuits, each sub round producing a new collection of values, until the sub rounds have completed, producing a collection of public G1 and G2 BLS48-581 points for each peer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;FINALIZING: The collection of points are broadcasted, and added together, producing a singular ceremony transcript contribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;VALIDATING: The updated ceremony transcript is validated against the predecessor, and is confirmed to be the new state, issuing rewards to the participant set. The next round can begin.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community Section&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This section contains community-built clients, applications, guides, etc &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;b&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/b&gt;: Because some of these may contain external links, do note that these are unofficial – every dependency added imparts risk, so if another project&#39;s github account were compromised, for example, it could lead people down a dangerous or costly path. Proceed with caution as always and refer to reliable members of the community for verification of links before clicking or connecting your wallets&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;1. The Q Guide - Beginners’ Guide&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A detailed beginners&#39; guide for how to setup a Quilibrium Node (on VPS, Ubuntu 22.04) - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/demipoet/demipoet.github.io&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Pull Requests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are welcome – a new network is rife with opportunities. We are in the process of updating our JIRA board so that it can be made public. The repository has basic coding guidelines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;80 character line limit, with the exception where gofmt or the syntax is impossible to achieve otherwise&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Error wrapping matching function names&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Interface composition and dependency injection with Wire&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Minimum System Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the Dawn phase, a server must have a minimum of 16GB of RAM, preferably 32 GB, 250GB of storage, preferably via SSD, and 50MBps symmetric bandwidth. For Intel/AMD, the baseline processor is a Skylake processor @ 3.4GHz with 12 dedicated cores. For ARM, the M1 line of Apple is a good reference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Dusk, these minimum requirements will reduce significantly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License + Interpretation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Significant portions of Quilibrium&#39;s codebase depends on GPL-licensed code, mandating a minimum license of GPL, however Quilibrium is licensed as AGPL to accomodate the scenario in which a cloud provider may wish to coopt the network software. The AGPL allows such providers to do so, provided they are willing to contribute back the management code that interacts with the protocol and node software. To provide clarity, our interpretation is with respect to node provisioning and management tooling for deploying alternative networks, and not applications which are deployed to the network, mainnet status monitors, or container deployments of mainnet nodes from the public codebase.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>aws/aws-sdk-go-v2</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T01:36:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-23:/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AWS SDK for the Go programming language.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AWS SDK for Go v2&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/actions/workflows/go.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/actions/workflows/go.yml/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;Go Build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/actions/workflows/codegen.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/actions/workflows/codegen.yml/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;Codegen Build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/aws-sdk-go-v2/docs/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/SDK-Documentation-blue&#34; alt=&#34;SDK Documentation&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/aws-sdk-go-v2/docs/migrating/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Migration-Guide-blue&#34; alt=&#34;Migration Guide&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/mod/github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/api-reference-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;API Reference&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/raw/main/LICENSE.txt&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/license-Apache%20V2-blue.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Apache V2 License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;aws-sdk-go-v2&lt;/code&gt; is the v2 AWS SDK for the Go programming language.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The v2 SDK requires a minimum version of &lt;code&gt;Go 1.20&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/raw/main/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; for information about the latest bug fixes, updates, and features added to the SDK.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jump To:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/main/#getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/main/#getting-help&#34;&gt;Getting Help&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/main/#feedback-and-contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/main/#resources&#34;&gt;More Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Maintenance and support for SDK major versions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information about maintenance and support for SDK major versions and their underlying dependencies, see the following in the AWS SDKs and Tools Shared Configuration and Credentials Reference Guide:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/credref/latest/refdocs/maint-policy.html&#34;&gt;AWS SDKs and Tools Maintenance Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/credref/latest/refdocs/version-support-matrix.html&#34;&gt;AWS SDKs and Tools Version Support Matrix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Go version support policy&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The v2 SDK follows the upstream &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/doc/devel/release#policy&#34;&gt;release policy&lt;/a&gt; with an additional six months of support for the most recently deprecated language version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS reserves the right to drop support for unsupported Go versions earlier to address critical security issues.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started working with the SDK setup your project for Go modules, and retrieve the SDK dependencies with &lt;code&gt;go get&lt;/code&gt;. This example shows how you can use the v2 SDK to make an API request using the SDK&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/&#34;&gt;Amazon DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt; client.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h6&gt;Initialize Project&lt;/h6&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ mkdir ~/helloaws&#xA;$ cd ~/helloaws&#xA;$ go mod init helloaws&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h6&gt;Add SDK Dependencies&lt;/h6&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ go get github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/aws&#xA;$ go get github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/config&#xA;$ go get github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/service/dynamodb&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h6&gt;Write Code&lt;/h6&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In your preferred editor add the following content to &lt;code&gt;main.go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34;&gt;package main&#xA;&#xA;import (&#xA;    &#34;context&#34;&#xA;    &#34;fmt&#34;&#xA;    &#34;log&#34;&#xA;&#xA;    &#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/aws&#34;&#xA;    &#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/config&#34;&#xA;    &#34;github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/service/dynamodb&#34;&#xA;)&#xA;&#xA;func main() {&#xA;    // Using the SDK&#39;s default configuration, loading additional config&#xA;    // and credentials values from the environment variables, shared&#xA;    // credentials, and shared configuration files&#xA;    cfg, err := config.LoadDefaultConfig(context.TODO(), config.WithRegion(&#34;us-west-2&#34;))&#xA;    if err != nil {&#xA;        log.Fatalf(&#34;unable to load SDK config, %v&#34;, err)&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    // Using the Config value, create the DynamoDB client&#xA;    svc := dynamodb.NewFromConfig(cfg)&#xA;&#xA;    // Build the request with its input parameters&#xA;    resp, err := svc.ListTables(context.TODO(), &amp;amp;dynamodb.ListTablesInput{&#xA;        Limit: aws.Int32(5),&#xA;    })&#xA;    if err != nil {&#xA;        log.Fatalf(&#34;failed to list tables, %v&#34;, err)&#xA;    }&#xA;&#xA;    fmt.Println(&#34;Tables:&#34;)&#xA;    for _, tableName := range resp.TableNames {&#xA;        fmt.Println(tableName)&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h6&gt;Compile and Execute&lt;/h6&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;$ go run .&#xA;Tables:&#xA;tableOne&#xA;tableTwo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please use these community resources for getting help. We use the GitHub issues for tracking bugs and feature requests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask us a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/discussions/new?category=q-a&#34;&gt;question&lt;/a&gt; or open a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/discussions/new?category=general&#34;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you think you may have found a bug, please open an &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a support ticket with &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.aws.amazon.com/awssupport/latest/user/getting-started.html&#34;&gt;AWS Support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This SDK implements AWS service APIs. For general issues regarding the AWS services and their limitations, you may also take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;Amazon Web Services Discussion Forums&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Opening Issues&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you encounter a bug with the AWS SDK for Go we would like to hear about it. Search the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/issues&#34;&gt;existing issues&lt;/a&gt; and see if others are also experiencing the same issue before opening a new issue. Please include the version of AWS SDK for Go, Go language, and OS you’re using. Please also include reproduction case when appropriate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The GitHub issues are intended for bug reports and feature requests. For help and questions with using AWS SDK for Go please make use of the resources listed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/main/#getting-help&#34;&gt;Getting Help&lt;/a&gt; section. Keeping the list of open issues lean will help us respond in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feedback and contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The v2 SDK will use GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; to track feature requests and issues with the SDK. In addition, we&#39;ll use GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; to track large tasks spanning multiple pull requests, such as refactoring the SDK&#39;s internal request lifecycle. You can provide feedback to us in several ways.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub issues&lt;/strong&gt;. To provide feedback or report bugs, file GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; on the SDK. This is the preferred mechanism to give feedback so that other users can engage in the conversation, +1 issues, etc. Issues you open will be evaluated, and included in our roadmap for the GA launch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contributing&lt;/strong&gt;. You can open pull requests for fixes or additions to the AWS SDK for Go 2.0. All pull requests must be submitted under the Apache 2.0 license and will be reviewed by an SDK team member before being merged in. Accompanying unit tests, where possible, are appreciated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/aws-sdk-go-v2/docs/&#34;&gt;SDK Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt; - Use this document to learn how to get started and use the AWS SDK for Go V2.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.github.io/aws-sdk-go-v2/docs/migrating/&#34;&gt;SDK Migration Guide&lt;/a&gt; - Use this document to learn how to migrate to V2 from the AWS SDK for Go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pkg.go.dev/mod/github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2&#34;&gt;SDK API Reference Documentation&lt;/a&gt; - Use this document to look up all API operation input and output parameters for AWS services supported by the SDK. The API reference also includes documentation of the SDK, and examples how to using the SDK, service client API operations, and API operation require parameters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/documentation/&#34;&gt;Service Documentation&lt;/a&gt; - Use this documentation to learn how to interface with AWS services. These guides are great for getting started with a service, or when looking for more information about a service. While this document is not required for coding, services may supply helpful samples to look out for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.aws.amazon.com/forum.jspa?forumID=293&#34;&gt;Forum&lt;/a&gt; - Ask questions, get help, and give feedback&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/aws-sdk-go-v2/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; - Report issues, submit pull requests, and get involved (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://aws.amazon.com/apache2.0/&#34;&gt;Apache 2.0 License&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>aws/karpenter-provider-aws</title>
    <updated>2024-05-23T01:36:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-23:/aws/karpenter-provider-aws</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Karpenter is a Kubernetes Node Autoscaler built for flexibility, performance, and simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/karpenter/actions/workflows/ci.yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws/actions/workflows/ci.yaml/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;CI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/stars/aws/karpenter-provider-aws&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub stars&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/forks/aws/karpenter-provider-aws&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub forks&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/License-Apache%202.0-ff69b4.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/report/github.com/aws/karpenter&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://goreportcard.com/badge/github.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws&#34; alt=&#34;Go Report Card&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://coveralls.io/github/aws/karpenter?branch=main&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/aws/karpenter-provider-aws/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws/issues&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/contributions-welcome-brightgreen.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;contributions welcome&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aws/karpenter-provider-aws/main/website/static/banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Karpenter is an open-source node provisioning project built for Kubernetes. Karpenter improves the efficiency and cost of running workloads on Kubernetes clusters by:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt; for pods that the Kubernetes scheduler has marked as unschedulable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evaluating&lt;/strong&gt; scheduling constraints (resource requests, nodeselectors, affinities, tolerations, and topology spread constraints) requested by the pods&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisioning&lt;/strong&gt; nodes that meet the requirements of the pods&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removing&lt;/strong&gt; the nodes when the nodes are no longer needed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Come discuss Karpenter in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.slack.com/archives/C02SFFZSA2K&#34;&gt;#karpenter&lt;/a&gt; channel, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.k8s.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes slack&lt;/a&gt; or join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://karpenter.sh/docs/contributing/working-group/&#34;&gt;Karpenter working group&lt;/a&gt; bi-weekly calls. If you want to contribute to the Karpenter project, please refer to the Karpenter docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://karpenter.sh/docs/&#34;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Talks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;09/08/2022 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/BnksdJ3oOEs&#34;&gt;Workload Consolidation with Karpenter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;05/19/2022 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UBb8wbfSc34&#34;&gt;Scaling K8s Nodes Without Breaking the Bank or Your Sanity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;03/25/2022 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/sxDtmzbNHwE?t=3931&#34;&gt;Karpenter @ AWS Community Day 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;12/20/2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/C-2v7HT-uSA&#34;&gt;How To Auto-Scale Kubernetes Clusters With Karpenter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;11/30/2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3QsVRHVdOnM&#34;&gt;Karpenter vs Kubernetes Cluster Autoscaler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;11/19/2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/qxWJRUF6JJc&#34;&gt;Karpenter @ Container Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;05/14/2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=43g8uPohTgc&#34;&gt;Groupless Autoscaling with Karpenter @ Kubecon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;05/04/2021 &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/MZ-4HzOC_ac?t=7137&#34;&gt;Karpenter @ Container Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>