<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-01T01:51:59Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ERGeorgiev/WindowsUtilities</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:51:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/ERGeorgiev/WindowsUtilities</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ERGeorgiev/WindowsUtilities" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/OfficeDocs-OfficeUpdates-pr.es-ES</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:51:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/MicrosoftDocs/OfficeDocs-OfficeUpdates-pr.es-ES</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/OfficeDocs-OfficeUpdates-pr.es-ES" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;microsoft-open-source-code-of-conduct&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Código de conducta de código abierto de Microsoft&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Este proyecto ha adoptado el &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; (Código de conducta de código abierto de Microsoft). Para obtener más información, consulte las &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; (Preguntas más frecuentes del código de conducta) o póngase en contacto con &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; con otras preguntas o comentarios.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>goatcorp/DalamudPlugins</title>
    <updated>2022-08-01T01:51:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-01:/goatcorp/DalamudPlugins</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/goatcorp/DalamudPlugins" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository hosts plugins for XIVLauncher/Dalamud&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Dalamud plugin repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository hosts plugin binaries that are used with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goatcorp/Dalamud&#34;&gt;Dalamud&lt;/a&gt;, which is managed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goaaats/FFXIVQuickLauncher&#34;&gt;FFXIVQuickLauncher&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are made and maintained by third party developers. Plugins being on here doesn&#39;t mean that we endorse them, it just means that they follow our rules/standards for submissions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing Plugins&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install plugins, you&#39;ll need to use XIVLauncher with the in-game addon (Dalamud) enabled. Once Dalamud has loaded, you can type &lt;code&gt;/xlplugins&lt;/code&gt; in game to open a plugin installed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You do not need to download any of the plugins here manually. Plugin installation is handled inside of the game directly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Making a plugin&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://goatcorp.github.io/Dalamud/api/index.html&#34;&gt;API documentation&lt;/a&gt; for information about creating plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What should my plugin not do?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make sure that your plugin does not directly interact with the game servers in a way that is: &lt;br&gt;a) &lt;em&gt;automatic&lt;/em&gt;, as in polling data or making requests without direct interaction from the user. &lt;br&gt;b) &lt;em&gt;outside of specification&lt;/em&gt;, as in allowing the player to do submit things to the server that would not be possible by normal means.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Publishing/updating your plugin&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a pull request with your own subfolder in the plugins directory of this folder. It should be named the &#34;internal&#34; name(name of the DLL) of your plugin and contain a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goatcorp/DalamudPlugins/raw/master/plugins/owofy/owofy.json&#34;&gt;plugin definition file&lt;/a&gt; with the same name. It should also contain a zip called &#34;latest.zip&#34; containing your plugin DLL, dependencies, resources and the plugin definition json in the same folder as the plugin DLL.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An icon for your plugin has to be in &#34;YourPlugin/images/&#34; as &#34;icon.png&#34;. The icon has to be representative of what your plugin does, ideally have transparency and be at max, 512 by 512 pixels.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the AssemblyVersion of the locally installed plugin doesn&#39;t match the &#34;AssemblyVersion&#34; field of the plugin definition json pushed to this repository, a redownload of the plugin is forced.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a sample of this, please see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goatcorp/DalamudPlugins/raw/master/plugins/owofy&#34;&gt;sample plugin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Plugin testing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When releasing a new plugin or making bigger changes, please PR your plugin inside the &lt;code&gt;testing&lt;/code&gt; folder on this repository first - this lets users that opt into receiving testing releases see the plugin in their installer. You can join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/3NMcUV5&#34;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; to make an announcement in our testers channel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This should usually not take more than a week - but it helps weeding out bigger issues that could cause crashes or prevent the plugin from being updated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When submitting a plugin, please consider our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goatcorp/FFXIVQuickLauncher/wiki/Acceptable-Use-Policy-(Official-Plugin-Repository)&#34;&gt;Acceptable Use Policy&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/goatcorp/FFXIVQuickLauncher/wiki/Terms-and-Conditions-of-Use-(XIVLauncher,-Dalamud-&amp;amp;-Official-Plugin-Repository)&#34;&gt;Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt;, which, for example, detail the rights you need to grant us when uploading a plugin to this repository.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>