<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-09-17T01:36:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>AzureAD/MSIdentityTools</title>
    <updated>2022-09-17T01:36:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-09-17:/AzureAD/MSIdentityTools</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AzureAD/MSIdentityTools" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Identity Tools PowerShell Module&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MSIdentityTools&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/v/MSIdentityTools.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Version&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MSIdentityTools&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/dt/MSIdentityTools.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Downloads&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Downloads&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MSIdentityTools&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/p/MSIdentityTools.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Platform&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Platform&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Identity Tools PowerShell module provides various tools for performing enhanced Identity administration activities. It is intended to address more complex business scenarios that can&#39;t be met solely with the use of MS Graph PowerShell SDK module.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is contained in the MSIdentityTools module?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A collection of cmdlets that use the MS Graph SDK PowerShell module to simplify common tasks for administrators of Azure AD tenants.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find a description of each cmdlet and it&#39;s usage documentation in the repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AzureAD/MSIdentityTools/wiki&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I install the module?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The module can be found and installed from the PowerShell gallery at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MSIdentityTools&#34;&gt;PowerShell Gallery: MSIdentity Tools&lt;/a&gt; or can be downloaded from the releases page on this repo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For issues, questions, and feature requests please review the guidance on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AzureAD/MSIdentityTools/raw/main/SUPPORT.md&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt; page for this project for filing issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>