<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-09-29T01:33:11Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts</title>
    <updated>2023-09-29T01:33:11Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-09-29:/Azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Azure Monitor Baseline Alerts&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Azure Monitor Baseline Alerts (AMBA)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts&#34; title=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/resolution/azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts&#34; title=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/open/azure/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Please check out our the &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.github.io/azure-monitor-baseline-alerts/welcome&#34;&gt;AMBA GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; site for more interactive access to the content in this repo.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Azure Monitor Baseline Alerts (AMBA)&lt;/strong&gt; repo! The purpose of this site is to provide best practice guidance around key alerts metrics and their thresholds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This sites is broken down into two main sections:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Services:&lt;/strong&gt; This section provides guidance for individual Azure services. For each service, there is a list of key alert metrics and the recommended thresholds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patterns / Scenarios:&lt;/strong&gt; This section provides guidance for common patterns / scenarios (like Azure Landing Zones), as well as policy definition and initiatives for deploying the alerts in your environment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why is configuring alerts important?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When deploying Azure resources, it is crucial to configure alerts to ensure the health, performance, and security of your resources. By setting up alerts, you can proactively monitor your resources and take timely actions to address any issues that may arise.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are the key reasons why configuring alerts is important:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early detection of issues&lt;/strong&gt;: Alerts enable you to identify potential problems or anomalies in your Azure resources at an early stage. By monitoring key metrics and logs, you can detect issues such as high CPU usage, low memory, network connectivity problems, or security breaches. This allows you to take immediate action and prevent any negative impact on your applications or services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced downtime&lt;/strong&gt;: By configuring alerts, you can minimize downtime by being notified of critical events or failures in real-time. This allows you to quickly investigate and resolve issues before they escalate, ensuring the availability and reliability of your applications.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimized resource utilization&lt;/strong&gt;: Alerts help you optimize resource utilization by providing insights into resource usage patterns and trends. By monitoring metrics such as CPU utilization, memory consumption, or storage capacity, you can identify opportunities for optimization and cost savings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance and security&lt;/strong&gt;: Configuring alerts is essential for maintaining compliance with regulatory requirements and ensuring the security of your Azure resources. By monitoring security logs and detecting suspicious activities or unauthorized access attempts, you can take immediate action to mitigate potential risks and protect your data.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proactive capacity planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Alerts provide valuable information for capacity planning and scaling your resources. By monitoring resource utilization trends over time, you can identify patterns and forecast future resource requirements. This helps you avoid performance bottlenecks and ensure a smooth user experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>