<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-30T01:52:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>AzureAD/AzureADAssessment</title>
    <updated>2022-07-30T01:52:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-30:/AzureAD/AzureADAssessment</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/AzureAD/AzureADAssessment" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tooling for assessing an Azure AD tenant state and configuration&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft Azure AD Assessment&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/AzureADAssessment&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/v/AzureADAssessment.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Version&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Version&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/AzureADAssessment&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/dt/AzureADAssessment.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Downloads&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Downloads&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/AzureADAssessment&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/powershellgallery/p/AzureADAssessment.svg?style=flat&amp;amp;logo=powershell&amp;amp;label=PSGallery%20Platform&#34; alt=&#34;PSGallery Platform&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Assessor Guide&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are a Microsoft employee or partner performing the assessment for a customer please see the Wiki for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AzureAD/AzureADAssessment/wiki&#34;&gt;Assessment Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install from the PowerShell Gallery&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you run into any errors please see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AzureAD/AzureADAssessment/master/#faq&#34;&gt;FAQ section&lt;/a&gt; at the end of this document.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;Install-Module AzureADAssessment -Force -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&#xA;## If you have already installed the module, run the following instead to ensure you have the latest version.&#xA;Update-Module AzureADAssessment -Force -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Run the Data Collection&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data collection from Azure AD can be run from any client with access to Azure AD. However, data collection from hybrid components such as AD FS, AAD Connect, etc. are best run locally on those servers. The AAD Connect data collection needs to be run on both Primary and Staging servers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify that you have authorized credentials to access these workloads:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Azure Active Directory as Global Administrator or Global Reader&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Domain or local administrator access to ADFS Servers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Domain or local administrator access to Azure AD Proxy Connector Servers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Domain or local administrator access to Azure AD Connect Server (Primary)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Domain or local administrator access to Azure AD Connect Server (Staging Server)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;When Connecting for the first time you will be asked to consent to the permissions needed by the assessment. An admin will be needed to provide consent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run following commands to produce a package of all the Azure AD data necessary to complete the assessment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Authenticate using a Global Admin or Global Reader account.&#xA;Connect-AADAssessment&#xA;&#xA;## Export data to &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment&#34; into a single output package.&#xA;Invoke-AADAssessmentDataCollection&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On each server running hybrid components, install the same module and run the Invoke-AADAssessmentHybridDataCollection command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Export Data to &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment&#34; into a single output package.&#xA;Invoke-AADAssessmentHybridDataCollection&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The output package will be named according to the following pattern: &lt;code&gt;AzureADAssessmentData-&amp;lt;TenantDomain&amp;gt;.aad&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once data collection is complete, provide the output packages to whoever is completing the assessment. Please avoid making any changes to the generated files including the name of the file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Complete Assessment Reports&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are generating and reviewing the output yourself, please see the Wiki for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AzureAD/AzureADAssessment/wiki&#34;&gt;Assessment Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;I don&#39;t have internet access to install the module on AAD Connect, ADFS, App Proxy servers&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To collect data from hybrid components (such as AAD Connect, AD FS, AAD App Proxy), you can export a portable version of this module that can be easily copied to servers with no internet connectivity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Export Portable Module to &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment&#34;.&#xA;Export-AADAssessmentPortableModule &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On each server running hybrid components, copy the module file &#34;AzureADAssessmentPortable.psm1&#34; and import it there.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Import the module on each server running hybrid components.&#xA;Import-Module &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment\AzureADAssessmentPortable.psm1&#34;&#xA;&#xA;## Export Data to &#34;C:\AzureADAssessment&#34; into a single output package.&#xA;Invoke-AADAssessmentHybridDataCollection&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;I want to use a service principal identity to run the assessment instead of a user identity&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## If you prefer to use your own app registration (service principal) for automation purposes, you may connect using your own ClientId and Certificate like the example below. Your app registration should include Directory.Read.All and Policy.Read.All permissions to MS Graph for a complete assessment. Once added, ensure you have completed admin consent on the service principal for those application permissions.&#xA;Connect-AADAssessment -ClientId &amp;lt;ClientId&amp;gt; -ClientCertificate (Get-Item &#39;Cert:\CurrentUser\My\&amp;lt;Thumbprint&amp;gt;&#39;) -TenantId &amp;lt;TenantId&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;## If you would like to specify a different directory, use the OutputDirectory parameter.&#xA;Invoke-AADAssessmentDataCollection &#34;C:\Temp&#34;&#xA;Invoke-AADAssessmentHybridDataCollection &#34;C:\Temp&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;When trying to install the module I&#39;m receiving the error &#39;A parameter cannot be found that matches parameter name &#39;AcceptLicense&#39;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run the following command to update PowerShellGet to the latest version before attempting to install the AzureADAssessment module again.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Update Nuget Package and PowerShellGet Module&#xA;Install-PackageProvider NuGet -Scope CurrentUser -Force&#xA;Install-Module PowerShellGet -Scope CurrentUser -Force -AllowClobber&#xA;## Remove old modules from existing session&#xA;Remove-Module PowerShellGet,PackageManagement -Force -ErrorAction Ignore&#xA;## Import updated module&#xA;Import-Module PowerShellGet -MinimumVersion 2.0 -Force&#xA;Import-PackageProvider PowerShellGet -MinimumVersion 2.0 -Force&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;If at any point you see the error, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Path&amp;gt; cannot be loaded because running scripts is disabled on this system. For more information, see about_Execution_Policies at http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=135170.&lt;/code&gt;, you must enable local scripts to be run.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;## Set globally on device&#xA;Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned&#xA;## Or set for just for current PowerShell session.&#xA;Set-ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned -Scope Process&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;MSAL.PS Certificate Error (Authenticode issuer)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The signing certificate for MSAL.PS is changing to use Microsoft&#39;s code signing process. If you see the following error, &lt;code&gt;PackageManagement\Install-Package : Authenticode issuer &#39;CN=Microsoft Corporation, O=Microsoft Corporation, L=Redmond, S=Washington, C=US&#39; of the new module &#39;MSAL.PS&#39; with version &#39;x.x.x.x&#39; from root certificate authority &#39;CN=Microsoft Root Certificate Authority 2011, O=Microsoft Corporation, L=Redmond, S=Washington, C=US&#39; is not matching with the authenticode issuer &#39;CN=Jason Thompson, O=Jason Thompson, L=Cincinnati, S=Ohio, C=US&#39; of the previously-installed module &#39;MSAL.PS&#39; with version &#39;x.x.x.x&#39; from root certificate authority &#39;CN=DigiCert Assured ID Root CA, OU=www.digicert.com, O=DigiCert Inc, C=US&#39;. If you still want to install or update, use -SkipPublisherCheck parameter.&lt;/code&gt;, you can resolve it using the following command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;Install-Module MSAL.PS -SkipPublisherCheck -Force&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unable to sign in with device code flow&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using PowerShell Core (ie PowerShell 6 or 7) and your tenant has a conditional access policy that requires a Compliant or Hybrid Azure AD Joined device, you may not be able to sign in.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To work around this issue use Windows PowerShell (instead of PowerShell 6 or 7). To launch Windows PowerShell go to &lt;strong&gt;Start &amp;gt; Windows PowerShell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unable to load data in PowerBI templates&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you open the powerbi templates, you will be asked to reference the folder where the extracted data resides (csv and json). Once selected PowerBI will load the data. While doing so PowerBI might complain with errors crossreferncing data sources:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Query &#39;*&#39; (step &#39;*&#39;) references other queries or steps, so it may not directly access a datasource. Please rebuild this data combination.  &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To workarround this, configure PowerBI file settings to ignore privacy settings:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Options and settings &amp;gt; Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Options&lt;/strong&gt; under &lt;strong&gt;CURRENT FILE&lt;/strong&gt; find the &lt;strong&gt;Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Privacy Levels&lt;/strong&gt; select &lt;strong&gt;Ignore the Privacy Levels and potentially improve performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;File/folder&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;build&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Scripts to package, test, sign, and publish the module.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;src&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Module source code.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;tests&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Test scripts for module.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;.gitignore&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Define what to ignore at commit time.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;This README file.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;The license for the module.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NuGet/docs.microsoft.com-nuget</title>
    <updated>2022-07-30T01:52:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-30:/NuGet/docs.microsoft.com-nuget</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/NuGet/docs.microsoft.com-nuget" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documentation for NuGet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;docs.microsoft.com-nuget&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The NuGet documentation contained in this repository is hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/&#34;&gt;docs.microsoft.com/nuget&lt;/a&gt;. This repository was migrated from the former NuGetDocs repository, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NuGet/NuGetDocs&#34;&gt;https://github.com/NuGet/NuGetDocs&lt;/a&gt;, which is no longer in active use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to this docset are welcome. Please submit PRs to the &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt; branch. The main branch is used for staging changes which is periodically merged into the &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; branch which is what&#39;s published to the live docs site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NuGet follows the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dotnet/home/raw/master/guidance/be-nice.md&#34;&gt;.NET Foundation Contributors Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. Please take a few minutes to review it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Repository structure&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All markdown files are in the docs folder and various subfolders.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The docs/index.md file defines the landing (hub) page as it appears on docs.microsoft.com/nuget.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The docs/TOC.md file defines the left-hand navigation panel that appears when you navigate to any page other than the hub page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Images are contained within media folders within each subfolder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The docs/docfx.json file contains various defaults, especially for metadata.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The docs/.openpublishing.redirection.json file contains redirects for old filenames; if you rename a file, create an entry here that maps the old to the new.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The docs/_breadcrumb/toc.yml file defines the breadcrumbs that appear on the site and their target pages. Be mindful of this if you make changes to filenames or placement of articles.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribution workflow&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No contribution is too big or too small.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Visit the page to edit on &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/&#34;&gt;docs.microsoft.com/nuget&lt;/a&gt;, then click the &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; button on the top right. This brings you to the appropriate markdown page in the repo.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit the markdown: &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re including images (use PNGs, generally), place them in the media folder that&#39;s in the topic&#39;s folder. Links are then &lt;code&gt;media/&amp;lt;image_name&amp;gt;.png&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Relative links to other pages in this docset should be in the form &lt;code&gt;../&amp;lt;folder&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;topic-file&amp;gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; including the training &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;. If you&#39;re linking to another topic in the same folder, then &lt;code&gt;../&amp;lt;folder&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt; can be omitted. When using anchors, always remember to include the &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; before the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When using external links, especially to docs.microsoft.com (or msdn.microsoft.com for any older content), omit any language tag like &#34;en-us&#34; so that a reader in another language lands on a target page in that same language if it&#39;s available.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When you&#39;re done, enter a commit message below, and click &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send a pull request for your change. We review PRs on a regular basis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Thank you!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re creating a new topic, keep the following in mind as well:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Always place the new topic in an appropriate subfolder, and follow the conventions for filenames as you see them used here.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;You must include a metadata block as you see on other topics. Typical defaults (such as for ms.workload and ms.reviewer) are set within docs/docjx.json, so you need only change the following:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;title: The title that appears in search results. For SEO, this ideally isn&#39;t the same as the top-level # (H1) of the article.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;description: The abstract of the article that appears in search results.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;author: the author&#39;s GitHub ID, to which issues files for this article are assigned.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ms.author: if the author is a Microsoft employee, this is the Microsoft alias. Used for reporting and forwarding feedback from other channels.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;manager: Microsoft alias of the author&#39;s manager, if applicable.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ms.date: the date of the last revision or review of the article in mm/dd/yyyy format (use leading zeros). This is a communication to the reader about freshness, so it&#39;s not updated for minor changes, only for more significant revisions OR when the article has reverified even if there are no changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ms.topic: used to categorize the article in reports. See table below. Most articles are &#34;conceptual&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In addition to adding your page, edit docs/TOC.md to add a link to that page.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re adding a top-level node to the TOC, also make an entry for it in docs/index.md.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;ms.topic category&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;conceptual&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Use for any content that doesn&#39;t fall into another. This is set as the default in docfx.json.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;overview&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Use for any overview or user-guide articles, typically only those that live under an &#34;Overview&#34; node in the TOC.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;quickstart&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Anything under the &#34;Quickstart&#34; node in the TOC that&#39;s authored according to Quickstart guidelines.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;tutorial&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Anything under the &#34;Tutorial&#34; node in the TOC that&#39;s authored according to Tutorial guidelines.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;reference&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Any reference-type article that isn&#39;t auto-generated.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;article&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Use for community-contributed content (that is, anything from outside the engineering team or the docs team at Microsoft.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Conventions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, if you don&#39;t see something described here, look in editing markdown files for examples, with the exception of files in the Release Notes which are legacy content and haven&#39;t been as thoroughly edited.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Language level and terms&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because our docs can be localized into many languages other than English, topics should be written at what&#39;s called the &#34;fifth-grade&#34; reading level, or what a typical 11-12-year-old child would understand. In other words, avoid using college-level words if possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To keep the tone more casual, use contractions like &#34;you&#39;ll&#34; and &#34;don&#39;t&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, avoid any cultural references or idioms that do not translate easily.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When describing UI actions, use terms like &#34;select&#34; instead of &#34;click&#34; or &#34;check&#34; because &#34;select&#34; translates better. Use &#34;clear&#34; instead of &#34;uncheck&#34;, and prefer &#34;run&#34; over &#34;execute&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t worry too much, though. We&#39;ll thoroughly review your contributions and edit for these things.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Naming&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow these naming conventions and capitalizations when referring to NuGet and related components.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NuGet: refers to the technology.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NuGet Package Manager UI, NuGet Package Manager Console, etc.: refers to other components build on NuGet.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;nuget.exe: refers to the command-line executable; you can use &#34;nuget&#34; by itself when followed by other arguments. When referring to the command by itself, as in &#34;when you run nuget&#34;, include the .exe as in &#34;when you run nuget.exe&#34; so your meaning is clear.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;packages.config (or the deprecated project.json): refer to NuGet files in a project.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NuGet.Config and NuGetDefaults.Config: these files appear with this capitalization so be sure to follow them.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.nuspec: refers to a NuGet specification for creating a package; generally, we speak of a .nuspec file with the period, because it&#39;s always used as a file extension.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For items not listed here, search in the repository for the term and see how it&#39;s used.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Heading capitalizations&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All headings need only capitalize the first word and proper names. Refer to most topics for examples.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;UI terms, boldface, and italics&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;boldface&lt;/strong&gt; for any string that a reader will see in UI, such as &#34;Select the &lt;strong&gt;File&lt;/strong&gt; menu,&#34; except when referring to common window titles like Solution Explorer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &#34;&amp;gt;&#34; to indicate UI hierarchies, as in the &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; New Project...&lt;/strong&gt; menu, or &lt;strong&gt;Tools &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; NuGet &amp;gt; NuGet Package Manager &amp;gt; Package Sources&lt;/strong&gt;. Notice how in this example you can use &#34;&amp;gt;&#34; to traverse a hierarchy from a menu, into a dialog box, into tabs, sub-tabs, and fields. In other words, readers can work with the chain of items to follow and don&#39;t need every click spelled out for them. In general, think of how to get the reader to where they need to go in the most efficient way.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With boldface used for UI elements, use &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt; for emphasis in the text.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Tables&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use standard markdown tables, starting with &#34;| heading | heading | heading |&#34;, followed by &#34;| --- | --- | --- |&#34;, followed by your rows. The row with &#34;---&#34; is necessary for docs.microsoft.com to read the markdown as a table.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Items in the first column are bolded by default, so you don&#39;t need to do that explicitly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Screenshots and images&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Make all images purposeful and easy to consume; avoid graphics for the sake of graphics. When using a screenshot, include a red rounded-rectangle outline of where the reader&#39;s eyes should go. That is, do the work to help the reader look at what you want them to look at, rather than burdening them with having to figure that out for themselves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an image has white bleed areas on the edges, draw a 1-pixel gray outline around the entire graphic.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Always include a meaningful description of the image in the markdown alt-text between the []&#39;s. These descriptions are also a great place to put SEO terms that you don&#39;t otherwise want to appear in the text.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Inline code&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Delineate inline code with grave accents (backticks), as in `nuget pack`. This inline formatting is used for the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Identifiers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;File names, folder names, and extensions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Command line strings and arguments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Except for the following cases:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When part of a surrounding code block.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When appearing in the left-hand column of a table, because these are automatically bolded.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When appearing in quoted strings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When appearing in links (although when the term appears by itself, it&#39;s OK)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Markdown and HTML are ignored within inline code.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Code blocks&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Code blocks on docs.microsoft.com are delineated by with three grave accents (backticks), ```, at the beginning and the end. You do not need to indent code blocks unless they are contained within a list.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The opening ``` should be followed by a language code for proper syntax coloring, such as &#34;xml&#34;, &#34;json&#34;, &#34;csharp&#34;, etc. Use &#34;cli&#34; for command-line examples and &#34;output&#34; for command-line results.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only case when you should use ``` without a language tag is when creating a block of fixed-point text that isn&#39;t related to any kind of code. In these cases you can also just indent the code block, which can be preferable because it visually separates the code in an editor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Callouts&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;docs.microsoft.com uses blockquotes for callouts, that is, lines starting with &#34;&amp;gt;&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Callout sections with &#34;&amp;gt;&#34; only will appear with a solid gray line to the left. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/create-packages/creating-a-package&#34;&gt;Creating NuGet packages&lt;/a&gt; for examples.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also use one of the following callout tags on the first line that will create a shaded callout in the indicated color:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Tag&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Callout use&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Topic with examples&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; [!Note]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Callouts without any special emphasis.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/create-packages/creating-a-package&#34;&gt;Creating NuGet packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; [!Tip]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Callouts that share special tips and tricks or other helpful knowledge.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/consume-packages/overview-and-workflow&#34;&gt;Package consumption overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; [!Important]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Callouts that describe cautions.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/hosting-packages/nuget-server&#34;&gt;NuGet.Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; [!Warning]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Callouts that warn readers about situations that could cause data loss or unexpected consequences.&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/nuget/consume-packages/dependency-resolution&#34;&gt;Dependency resolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In general, always use the title of the target page as the link text rather than words like &#34;see here&#34; or &#34;this documentation&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Relative links to other pages in this docset should be in the form &lt;code&gt;../&amp;lt;folder&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;topic-file&amp;gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; including the trailing &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Links to other markdown files on docs.microsoft.com are case-insensitive (unlike links to files in GitHub, which are).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you&#39;re linking to another topic in the same folder, then &lt;code&gt;../&amp;lt;folder&amp;gt;/&lt;/code&gt; can be omitted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When using anchors, always remember to include the &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt; before the &lt;code&gt;#&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When using external links, especially to docs.microsoft.com (or msdn.microsoft.com for any older content), omit any language tag like &#34;en-us&#34; so that a reader in another language lands on a target page in that same language if it&#39;s available.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Bare URLs are not automatically converted into links.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Inline HTML&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need to do something that Markdown can&#39;t handle, use inline HTML. An example is creating a bullet list inside a table.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for &amp;lt; and &amp;gt; characters outside a code block or inline code (delimited by backticks `).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Block-level HTML elements have a few restrictions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;They must be separated from surrounding text by blank lines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The begin and end tags of the outermost block element must not be indented.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Markdown can&#39;t be used within HTML blocks.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/dynamics-365-unified-operations-public</title>
    <updated>2022-07-30T01:52:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-30:/MicrosoftDocs/dynamics-365-unified-operations-public</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/dynamics-365-unified-operations-public" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documentation for Microsoft Dynamics 365 apps such as Dynamics 365 Finance, Dynamics 365 Commerce, Dynamics 365 Supply Chain Management, and Dynamics 365 Human Resources&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>