<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-08-16T01:32:55Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/MSRC-Microsoft-Security-Updates-API</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T01:32:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-08-16:/microsoft/MSRC-Microsoft-Security-Updates-API</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/MSRC-Microsoft-Security-Updates-API" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Repo with getting started projects for the Microsoft Security Updates API (msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft provides an API for programmatic access to security update details using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icasi.org/cvrf/&#34;&gt;Common Vulnerability Reporting Format&lt;/a&gt;. View our &lt;a href=&#34;https://msrc-blog.microsoft.com/2016/11/08/furthering-our-commitment-to-security-updates/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft &lt;a href=&#34;https://msrc.microsoft.com/update-guide&#34;&gt;Security Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; is the web experience to find security update detail.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains sample code and documentation for the Microsoft Security Updates API (&lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.msrc.microsoft.com/en-us/developer&#34;&gt;https://portal.msrc.microsoft.com/en-us/developer&lt;/a&gt;), including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;source code for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MsrcSecurityUpdates&#34;&gt;MsrcSecurityUpdates PowerShell module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;sample code for using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MsrcSecurityUpdates&#34;&gt;MsrcSecurityUpdates PowerShell module&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/MSRC-Microsoft-Security-Updates-API/main/docs&#34;&gt;OpenAPI/Swagger definition&lt;/a&gt; for the Microsoft Security Updates CVRF API&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Getting the MsrcSecurityUpdates PowerShell Module&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Getting started with the MsrcSecurityUpdates module can be done like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-PowerShell&#34;&gt;### Install the module from the PowerShell Gallery&#xA;Install-Module -Name MsrcSecurityUpdates -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&#xA;### Load the module if PowerShell is at least version 5.1&#xA;if ($PSVersionTable.PSVersion -gt [version]&#39;5.1&#39;) {&#xA; Import-Module -Name MsrcSecurityUpdates&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the module is loaded, check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Microsoft/MSRC-Microsoft-Security-Updates-API/raw/master/src/README.md&#34;&gt;PowerShell samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Change Log&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;For up to date major changes, please read the psd1 included in the src folder. This can also be seen on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/MsrcSecurityUpdates&#34;&gt;the Microsoft Powershell Gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Support&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Developer Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Customers should treat this repository as custom code. Bug fixes or enhancements can be requested by opening a new issue from the Issues tab.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security Update Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For questions about CVEs, security updates and patches, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Contributing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is Microsoft’s mission to empower every person and every organization on the planet to achieve more. We thank you for helping shape that future by keeping the world a more secure place by tooling security into your organization’s practices. We would love to hear your feedback on features to add or bugs to fix.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/securedworkstation</title>
    <updated>2024-08-16T01:32:55Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-08-16:/Azure/securedworkstation</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/securedworkstation" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Intune managed Secured workstation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Secure Workstation configuration and policy baselines for Microsoft Intune and Windows 10&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site is the companion to the Secured Workstation how-to guidance, providing the scripts to deploy the baseline for the Enterprise, Specialized, and Privileged configurations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is highly recommended, that you familiarize yourself with the guidance prior to cloning, or use the files in this repo. Documentation for the solution can be found at - &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/securedworkstation&#34;&gt;https://aka.ms/securedworkstation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These files are provided as samples, and a starting point to consider when you build your secured solution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The scripts has been tested in a EN-US enviroment only, international langugages may require changes to the script for any geo location related errors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Three Security Profiles&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Security&lt;/strong&gt; - is suitable for all enterprise users and productivity scenarios. Enterprise also serves as the starting point for specialized and privileged access as they progressively build on the security controls used in enterprise security configuration. The Enterprise profile has the following characteristics&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;assumes that the user has Privileged rights on the local device&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;allows local Windows Defender Firewall rules to be merged with applied Device Configuration profile settings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/securedworkstation/master/ENT/Readme.md&#34;&gt;Enterprise policy settings and deployment script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialized&lt;/strong&gt; - provides increased security controls for roles with a significantly elevated business impact (if compromised by an attacker or malicious insider). The Specialized profile has the highlighted differences from the Enterprise Profile&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;assumes that the user has Standard Privileges on the devices&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;implements Application Execution Control in Audit mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;does not merge local Windows Defender Firewall rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/securedworkstation/master/SPE/Readme.md&#34;&gt;Specialized policy settings and deployment script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privileged&lt;/strong&gt; - is the highest level of security designed for roles that could easily cause a major incident and potential material damage to the organization in the hands of an attacker or malicious insider. This typically includes technical roles with administrative permissions on most or all enterprise systems (and sometimes includes a select few business critical roles). The Privileged profile has the highlighted differences from the Specialized Profile&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;implements Application Execution Control in Enforced mode&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;blocks all outbound connections apart from defined Windows Defender Firewall rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/securedworkstation/master/PAW/Readme.md&#34;&gt;Privileged policy settings and deployment script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy&lt;/strong&gt; - The content of this directory reflects V1 of Azure Secure Workstation&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>