<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-17T01:42:37Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>r1cksec/cheatsheets</title>
    <updated>2023-04-17T01:42:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-17:/r1cksec/cheatsheets</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/r1cksec/cheatsheets" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Collection of knowledge about information security&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;table&gt; &#xA; &lt;thead&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;   &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/thead&gt; &#xA; &lt;tbody&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Exploits&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Sorted by CVE&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Fuzzing&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Lists with various contents&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Linux&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Command line for Linux&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Other&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Everything that does not belong elsewhere&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Snippets&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Code snippets for different languages&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Theorie&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Background knowledge on specific topics&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Urls&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Resources on the Internet&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA;  &lt;tr&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Windows&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;   &lt;td&gt;Command line for Windows&lt;/td&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/tr&gt; &#xA; &lt;/tbody&gt; &#xA;&lt;/table&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard</title>
    <updated>2023-04-17T01:42:37Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-17:/rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AutoGPT-easy-install is a bash/powershell script designed for non-experts to easily install and run the AutoGPT application in a Docker container. The script checks if Docker is installed and installs it if necessary. It prompts the user for API keys, workspace folder path, and whether to run AutoGPT in continuous mode&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Auto-GPT Sandbox Wizard - Easy Installer&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script allows you to easily install and run the Auto-GPT application inside a Docker container. Running the application inside a Docker container provides a secure sandboxed environment, preventing any potential harm to your computer from continuous mode malfunctions. However, please note that you still need to supervise the application when running in continuous mode to avoid any unintended damage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The speech mode is not currently supported when running inside the Docker container.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically installs Docker if not already installed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prompts for API keys and workspace folder path&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clones the Auto-GPT repository and configures the environment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Builds and runs the application inside a Docker container&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to use the Auto-GPT Easy Installer, you will need API keys for both OpenAI and Pinecone. You can obtain an OpenAI API key by following the instructions provided here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys&#34;&gt;https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys&lt;/a&gt;. For Pinecone, which is used for long-term memory, you must have an API key as well. To find your Pinecone API key, open the Pinecone console and click on API Keys. This view will also display the environment for your project, so make sure to note both your API key and your environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you register for OpenAI, you will receive $18 in API credits, which provides ample room for testing and experimenting without incurring any costs. Simply follow the steps in the provided script to set up and run the Auto-GPT application inside a Docker container, ensuring a secure environment for your project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation and Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unix/Mac&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;code&gt;auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a terminal and navigate to the directory where the script is located.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make the script executable: &lt;code&gt;chmod +x auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the script: &lt;code&gt;./auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows (currently untested)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;code&gt;auto_gpt_easy_install.ps1&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a PowerShell and navigate to the directory where the script is located.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the script: &lt;code&gt;.\auto_gpt_easy_install.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;For Users Without Git&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do not have Git installed on your system, the script will attempt to install it using a suitable package manager. If this is not possible, you will need to install Git manually before running the script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you encounter issues with Docker installation or permissions, please refer to the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker documentation&lt;/a&gt; for guidance.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you have trouble installing Git, visit the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-Installing-Git&#34;&gt;Git documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information on installing Git on your system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you need further assistance, consider opening an issue on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Torantulino/Auto-GPT&#34;&gt;Auto-GPT GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Auto-GPT application is designed to be run inside a Docker container for added security. However, you can still run the application outside the container if you prefer. Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Torantulino/Auto-GPT&#34;&gt;Auto-GPT GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to set up and run the application manually.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Remember to supervise the application when running in continuous mode to avoid any unintended damage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The speech mode is not currently supported when running inside the Docker container.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>