<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-04-19T01:36:45Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/winget-dsc</title>
    <updated>2025-04-19T01:36:45Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-04-19:/microsoft/winget-dsc</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/winget-dsc" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;DSC Resources for WinGet Configuration&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is intended to support WinGet Configuration. Some of these Desired State Configuration (DSC) Resources are exploratory and may not be published in the PowerShell Gallery. Other resources may be moved to their own projects or removed entirely. Samples for using these resources are available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/winget-dsc/main/samples/&#34;&gt;samples&lt;/a&gt; directory. They are also available via the URL: &lt;code&gt;https://aka.ms/dsc.yaml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Contributor License Agreement (CLA)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The documentation can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/winget-dsc/main/doc/&#34;&gt;doc&lt;/a&gt; directory. Each DSC resource stored in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/winget-dsc/main/resources/Help/&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;, provide synopsis and examples to get yourself started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>