<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-23T01:49:48Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/mdefordownlevelserver</title>
    <updated>2022-06-23T01:49:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-23:/microsoft/mdefordownlevelserver</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/mdefordownlevelserver" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Project&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is used to host the PowerShell install and upgrade helper script (install.ps1) for the modern, unified Microsoft Defender for Endpoint installer package for Windows Server 2012 R2 and Windows Server 2016. This script is not intended for use with Microsoft Defender for Cloud as currently, when using the preview solution, alert and TVM integration does not work. For more information, please go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/security/defender-endpoint/server-migration?view=o365-worldwide&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/security/defender-endpoint/server-migration?view=o365-worldwide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Always use the latest available package, downloaded from the onboarding section of the Defender for Endpoint portal, for new installations. Some of the functionality contained in the script can depend on changes introduced in the package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SYNOPSIS&lt;br&gt; Helper script for installing/uninstalling Microsoft Defender for Downlevel Servers.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;br&gt; On install scenario:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It can remove the OMS workspace when the workspace ID is provided with the parameter &lt;strong&gt;RemoveMMA&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;NOTE: this step is for cleanup purposes only&lt;/strong&gt;. ****When installing the new package, the previous sensor will stop running and the workspace is no longer used. You may however still need the MMA for other workspaces/functionality such as OMS, Log Analytics. ****&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The next step uninstalls SCEP - if it is present, and only on Windows Server 2012 R2 (on Windows Server 2016, SCEP is only a management component and is not required).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Then, it checks for prerequisites and downloads and installs two hotfixes on Windows Server 2012 R2 if the prerequisites have not been met (files are not found)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If Defender is not running on Windows Server 2016, it will attempt to activate it. If the feature is not installed, it attempts to enable the feature. If this requires a reboot, the script will stop; please reboot and run again to continue.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If Defender is installed and running but outdated, it updates to the latest platform version on Windows Server 2016 if required (NOTE: Defender must be in an upgradeable state, this requires at least one servicing stack and cumulative update to have been applied). If you have placed updateplatform.exe in the same directory, the script can use this in case the download location is not accessible.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Next, it installs the Microsoft Defender for Downlevel Servers MSI (md4ws.msi downloaded from the onboarding page for Windows Server 2012 R2 and 2016). If the file is in the same directory as the script, no input is required. If the product was already installed, it will attempt to perform a reinstallation with the provided MSI, but only if the machine is not in an onboarded state.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Finally, it runs the onboarding script, if provided using the parameter &lt;strong&gt;OnboardingScript&lt;/strong&gt;. Please use the script for &lt;strong&gt;Group Policy&lt;/strong&gt; as it is non-interactive; the local onboarding script will fail.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;NOTE on machines that have received recent monthly update rollup packages, the prerequisites will have been met and most steps above will not be needed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On uninstall scenario:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It will run the offboarding script, if provided using the parameter &lt;strong&gt;OffboardingScript&lt;/strong&gt;. Otherwise it is assumed that the machine is in an offboarded state. &lt;strong&gt;NOTE: Uninstallation is only possible if the machine has been offboarded first.&lt;/strong&gt; Please use the script for Windows Server 2019 for &lt;strong&gt;Group Policy&lt;/strong&gt; as it is non-interactive; the local offboarding script will fail.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Uninstall the product.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Removes the Defender Powershell module, if it was loaded inside current Powershell session.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Install the MSI if it is present in the smae location as the script. The script executes install steps 2 through 6 mentioned above.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as #1 except it will display the installer UI and disables verbose logging.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -UI -NoMSILog -NoEtl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as #2 except it will set Defender Antivirus to not become the active antimalware immediately after installation to avoid interference with non-Microsoft antimalware solutions before onboarding. Make sure to set the &#34;ForceDefenderPassiveMode&#34; registry key on all servers where you wish to run protection capabilities in passive mode after onboarding. For more information on Passive mode, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/security/defender-endpoint/microsoft-defender-antivirus-on-windows-server?#passive-mode-and-windows-server&#34;&gt;Need to set Microsoft Defender Antivirus to passive mode?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -UI -Passive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 4&lt;/strong&gt;: Perform uninstall steps 2 and 3.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -Uninstall&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 5&lt;/strong&gt;: Same as example #3 except with additional logging disabled.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -Uninstall -NoMSILog -NoEtl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 6&lt;/strong&gt;: Fully automate (including optional OMS workspace removal) installation and onboarding. In this case, the onboarding script is located in the same directory as the installer script and the installation package (MSI). Substitute &amp;lt;WORKSPACE_ID&amp;gt; with the ID found on the onboarding page (for Windows Server 2008 R2) in your tenant.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -RemoveMMA &amp;lt;WORKSPACE_ID&amp;gt; -OnboardingScript &#34;.\WindowsDefenderATPOnboardingScript.CMD&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXAMPLE 7&lt;/strong&gt;: Offboard then uninstall the MSI.&lt;br&gt; &lt;code&gt;.\Install.ps1 -Uninstall -OffboardingScript &#34;.\WindowsDefenderATPOffboardingScript.CMD&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit</title>
    <updated>2022-06-23T01:49:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-23:/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Project Homepage &amp; Forums&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit/master/AppDeployToolkitLogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit Logo&#34;&gt; PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is the PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit provides a set of functions to perform common application deployment tasks and to interact with the user during a deployment. It simplifies the complex scripting challenges of deploying applications in the enterprise, provides a consistent deployment experience and improves installation success rates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit can be used to replace your WiseScript, VBScript and Batch wrapper scripts with one versatile, re-usable and extensible tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What are the main features of the PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy To Use&lt;/strong&gt; - Any PowerShell beginner can use the template and the functions provided with the Toolkit to perform application deployments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistent&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides a consistent look and feel for all application deployments, regardless of complexity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerful&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides a set of functions to perform common deployment tasks, such as installing or uninstalling multiple applications, prompting users to close apps, setting registry keys, copying files, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Interface&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides user interaction through customizable user interface dialogs boxes, progress dialogs and balloon tip notifications. Supports completely silent script execution as well.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Localized&lt;/strong&gt; - The UI is localized in several languages and more can easily be added using the XML configuration file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration&lt;/strong&gt; - Integrates well with System Center Configuration Manager(SCCM); provides installation and uninstallation deployment types with options on how to handle exit codes, such as supressing reboots or returning a fast retry code. The toolkit also supports logging in CMTrace-compatible format.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updatable&lt;/strong&gt; - The logic engine and functions are separated from per-application scripts, so that you can update the toolkit when a new version is released and maintain backwards compatibility with your deployment scripts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensible&lt;/strong&gt; - The Toolkit can be easily extended to add custom scripts and functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helpful&lt;/strong&gt; - The Toolkit provides detailed logging of all actions performed and even includes a graphical console to browse the help documentation for the Toolkit functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Powershell 2.0+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.NET Framework 3.5+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.psappdeploytoolkit.com/&#34;&gt;Community Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com/screenshots/&#34;&gt;Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com/about/&#34;&gt;About Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Tool is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-23T01:49:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-23:/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Public repo for Intune content in OPS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Docs.microsoft.com Github repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve found one of the GitHub repositories that houses the source for content published to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/.&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;, home of all technical content for Microsoft&#39;s Cloud and Enterprise Division.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute to your documentation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We &lt;strong&gt;want and encourage contributions&lt;/strong&gt; from our community (users, customers, partners, friends on other planets) and Microsoft employees to improve your documentation. Here are some tips:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a GitHub account&lt;/strong&gt;: Sign up is free at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;GitHub.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your browser&lt;/strong&gt;: There are two options:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 1: Edit directly from docs.microsoft.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Go to the topic, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs/main/intune/protect/troubleshoot-policies-in-microsoft-intune.md&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/intune/troubleshoot-policies-in-microsoft-intune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; (top right). This shows the markdown file in the GitHub repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Select the pencil icon. When you hover over the pencil icon, you&#39;ll see the &lt;strong&gt;Edit this file&lt;/strong&gt; tooltip.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make your changes, and then &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; your changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Create the pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Option 2: Find the article in this repository, and update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Most topics are in &lt;code&gt;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs/tree/master/intune&lt;/code&gt;. In this folder, search for the topic name, such as &lt;code&gt;troubleshoot-policies-in-microsoft-intune&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Select the link, and click the pencil icon. When you hover over the pencil icon, you&#39;ll see the &lt;strong&gt;Edit this file&lt;/strong&gt; tooltip.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Make your changes, and then &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt; your changes.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Create the pull request.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you make an update, you may be prompted to sign a license agreement. This is a one-time task. So any future updates by your GitHub username won&#39;t need to sign again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The value in the &lt;code&gt;author&lt;/code&gt; metadata (at the top of every topic) lists the GitHub author. In the &lt;code&gt;troubleshoot-policies-in-microsoft-intune&lt;/code&gt; example, you&#39;ll see &lt;code&gt;MandiOhlinger&lt;/code&gt;. In your pull request, you can also mention (@&lt;em&gt;authorValue&lt;/em&gt;) the author if you like.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MSFT Employees&lt;/strong&gt;: After you create a GitHub account, link it to your Microsoft email address. When your account is linked, you don&#39;t have to sign a license agreement to make an update. Steps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;On a device with corpnet, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://review.docs.microsoft.com/en-us/help/contribute/contribute-get-started-setup-github?branch=master&#34;&gt;GitHub account setup&lt;/a&gt;. If you&#39;re not on corpnet, this link returns a 404.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;Creating a GitHub account, and linking to your Microsoft account is a one-time thing. When your account is linked, you don&#39;t have to sign a license agreement to make an update.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;In your browser, go to the article, and select &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;. Switch to the private repo (IntuneDocs-pr):&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;From&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs/&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;To&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs-pr/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/IntuneDocs-pr/&lt;/a&gt;...&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Select the pencil icon, and make your changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Use markdown to format your topic&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the articles in this repository use GitHub-flavored markdown. Here&#39;s a list of resources to get started:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/basic-writing-and-formatting-syntax/&#34;&gt;Markdown basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/pdfs/markdown-cheatsheet-online.pdf&#34;&gt;Printable markdown cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>