<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-11-24T02:23:50Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>troennes/private-secure-windows</title>
    <updated>2023-11-24T02:23:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-24:/troennes/private-secure-windows</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/troennes/private-secure-windows" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Privacy and security baseline for personal Windows 10 and Windows 11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/troennes/private-secure-windows/main/Media/logo.png&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Privacy and security baseline for personal Windows 10 and Windows 11&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will apply basic privacy and security settings for Windows 10 and Windows 11&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;powershell.exe -ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted -File .\Install.ps1 -Level Basic&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What is this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a handpicked collection of privacy and security settings for standalone Windows 10 and Windows 11 systems that tries to strike a good balance between privacy, security and usability. It uses group policy and is mainly based on Microsoft&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/security/threat-protection/windows-security-configuration-framework/security-compliance-toolkit-10&#34;&gt;Windows security baselines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/privacy/manage-connections-from-windows-operating-system-components-to-microsoft-services&#34;&gt;Windows Restricted Traffic Limited Functionality Baseline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It comes with two security levels, based on your threat profile:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Basic security and privacy&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contains privacy and security settings that limits sharing of your personal information and improves the security configuration without extensively reducing performance or usability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;👤&lt;/span&gt; For standalone and personal use systems&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;🪲&lt;/span&gt; Helps protect against passive attacks (malware and attacks against many people at once)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;High-level security and privacy&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Includes extra security settings for individuals with a higher threat profile. This includes enterprise-grade security settings and protections against physical attacks. This might reduce usability and performance, compared to the basic level.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;👥&lt;/span&gt; For standalone, personal use systems and small domains/enterprises&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;🎯&lt;/span&gt; Helps protect against targeted attacks (dedicated hackers or other malicious agents trying to access your device specifically)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the Basic security and privacy baseline:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Optional, but recommended) Download the newest LGPO.exe tool from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/confirmation.aspx?id=55319&#34;&gt;Microsoft Security Compliance Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; and place it in the Tools folder.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Optional, but recommended) Backup your current settings so you can revert later. Run &lt;code&gt;Backup.ps1&lt;/code&gt; from the Utils folder. E.g. &lt;code&gt;.\Backup.ps1 -OutputDir C:\tmp\&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;(Optional, but recommended) Review the list of changed settings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/troennes/private-secure-windows/main/Lists/SettingsOverview.xlsx&#34;&gt;Lists/SettingsOverview.xlsx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;Install.ps1&lt;/code&gt; with PowerShell with administrative privileges.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;.\Install.ps1 -Level Basic&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use another value for &lt;code&gt;-Level&lt;/code&gt; to select another baseline:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;-Level Basic                 [default] Basic security and privacy&#xA;-Level HighSecurity          High security settings (assumes basic security setting are in place)&#xA;&#xA;Advanced use and more granular control: &#xA;-Level BasicSecurity         Basic security, with no privacy settings added&#xA;-Level BasicPrivacy          Basic privacy, with no security settings added&#xA;-Level HighSecurityBitlocker A subset of high security settings: Disk encryption settings&#xA;-Level HighSecurityCredGuard A subset of high security settings: Virtualization-based security&#xA;-Level HighSecurityComputer  A subset of high security settings: Computer settings&#xA;-Level HighSecurityDomain    A subset of high security settings: Domain computer settings&#xA;-Level ExtremePrivacy        [experimental] Privacy settings that degrade security and usability&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Which Windows versions are supported?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Install script will detect your version and apply supported settings. The current versions are supported:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows 10 (21H1, 21H2 and 22H2)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows 11 (21H2, 22H2 and 23H2)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the &lt;strong&gt;Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt; editions of Windows are recommended. Pro will partially work, but some settings, such as telemetry, cannot be set to the desired level.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Windows Home edition is not supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why use this instead of CIS benchmark or Microsoft&#39;s security baseline?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although both CIS&#39; and Microsoft&#39;s security baselines are great, they are geared towards organizations using domain-joined computers. This baseline is made for personal/standalone computers, and includes additional settings for increased privacy.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is more important, privacy or security?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both are important. This baseline tries both, but there are conflicts between them. In the following cases, privacy wins over security:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows Defender does not send samples to Microsoft.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Smartscreen is disabled&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security and usability wins in some cases too, detailed below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Does this baseline stop all traffic sent to Microsoft services?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. Traffic to Microsoft is limited, but for usability and security reasons, the following services still sends information to Microsoft:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows Update is enabled to automatically download security updates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Windows Defender signature updates are enabled to automatically download anti-malware definition updates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatic Root Certificates Update is enabled to automatically check the list of trusted authorities on Windows Update to see if an update is available&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Network Connection Status Indicator (NCSI) sends a DNS request and HTTP query to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.msftconnecttest.com/connecttest.txt&#34;&gt;http://www.msftconnecttest.com/connecttest.txt&lt;/a&gt; to determine if the device can communicate with the Internet. This is required to get Windows Updates and some other features&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The &#34;Microsoft Account Sign-in Assistant&#34; service (wlidsvc) is enabled. This is required to get Windows Updates.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Telemetry is set to the lowest level availble for your Windows version. If you don&#39;t have the Enterprise/Education edition, some telemetry is still &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/privacy/configure-windows-diagnostic-data-in-your-organization&#34;&gt;sent to Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This baseline might have flaws and does not cover all possibilities. Please submit an issue if you see room for improvement.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What are the usability implications of installing this?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Functionality related to Microsoft accounts, Cortana, OneDrive, Store, cloud, feedback and customer experience improvement are disabled or reduced.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;I want to change some of the settings&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything is customizable through group policy:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To get an overview of your current settings, run &lt;code&gt;gpresult.exe /h GPreport.html&lt;/code&gt; with administrative privileges. Then open the report in a browser and click &#34;Show all&#34;. Identify the setting(s) you want to change and note their path.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To change a setting, run &lt;code&gt;gpedit.msc&lt;/code&gt; with administrative privileges, and change the setting(s) identified in the step above. The paths in the GPreport corresponds with the gpedit tool. To reset a setting its default state, set it to &#34;Not configured&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is the difference between the Basic and High security levels?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The High level has the following security improvements compared to the Basic level:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Stronger User Account Control (UAC) settings&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Increased protection against physical attacks (Direct Memory Attack (DMA) protections, Sleep mode disabled, machine inactivity limit)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Virtualization-based security features enabled (Hypervisor-Protected Code Integrity (HVCI), Secure launch)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enhanced logging enabled (audit, powershell, firewall)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hardening of Enterprise/domain features (Domain security settings, remote access like RDP and WinRM)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;More strict password policy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The privacy settings are equal in both levels.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How to verify changed settings before installing?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download Microsoft&#39;s Policy Analyzer tool from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/download/details.aspx?id=55319&#34;&gt;Security Compliance Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;, then import GPOs to view which settings they change.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Does this baseline improve any applications?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. Only the Windows operating system and built-in Windows components are covered. There are no improvements to Microsoft Edge and Internet Explorer included here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t be afraid to contribute! For now, create an issue if you see room for improvement, and we&#39;ll take it from there.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main components of this baseline are&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Microsoft&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/security/threat-protection/windows-security-configuration-framework/windows-security-baselines&#34;&gt;Windows Security baselines&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/confirmation.aspx?id=55319&#34;&gt;Microsoft Security Compliance Toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Microsoft&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/privacy/manage-connections-from-windows-operating-system-components-to-microsoft-services&#34;&gt;Restricted Traffic Limited Functionality Baseline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot from mxk&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mxk/win10-secure-baseline-gpo&#34;&gt;Windows 10 and Server 2019 Secure Baseline GPO&lt;/a&gt; and included some adjustments based on that baseline.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>kulvind3r/GamingGaiden</title>
    <updated>2023-11-24T02:23:50Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-11-24:/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Track game play time and generate long term statstics on your gaming hobby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/GamingGaidenBanner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gaming Gaiden&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;外伝 (Gaiden)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Japanese&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;noun (common)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Tale; Side Story;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A simple application written in powershell to track your gaming time and review how you have spent your hours at leisure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Time Tracking and Emulator Support&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Tracks runtime for any PC or emulated game.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automatically track all new emulated games by just registering the emulator only once.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Retroarch supported. Track different retroarch cores as distinct emulated platforms.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Works best with command line based emulation frontends like EmulationStation, LaunchBox and other standalone emulators.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Stop or resume tracking anytime without exiting the app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;HWiNFO64 Sensor. Track game time recording status in RTSS / HWiNFO overlays.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;UI and Statistics&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detailed Games list UI with search and sorting. Editable game icons. Games can be marked finished for backlog records.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shows most played games and number of games played per platform.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Daily, Monthly and Yearly play time statstics.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Quality of Life Features&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Extremely lightweight. 7 MB install size. Single process. Uses less than 50 MB Memory and less than 1% CPU.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Completely offline and portable. No internet required. All data stored locally.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automated data backup on every gaming session. Keeps 5 latest backups.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automated scheduled task setup on install to run at startup and start tracking.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detailed how to use manual. Just click Help from menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Detailed logging to identify bugs and errors.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature Screenshots&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/GamesList.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;180&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/MostPlayedGames.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;180&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/TimeSpentGamingMonthly.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;180&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/TimeSpentGamingYearly.png&#34; width=&#34;320&#34; height=&#34;180&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/GamesPlayedPerPlatform.png&#34; width=&#34;180&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/HWiNFOSensor.png&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;190&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature Demos&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/QHVJvWrDWC4&#34;&gt;Tracking PC Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/ltRJVeOxr1s&#34;&gt;Tracking Emulated Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/RvE6_fYAiRM&#34;&gt;Tracking Retroarch Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/gIqdKGoQDGM&#34;&gt;Gaming Stastics &amp;amp; Other Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/pFe80EzFog8&#34;&gt;HWiNFO Sensor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Vs Steam, Playnite etc.&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For purely tracking play time, Gaming Gaiden has much more features than the above launchers. Ease of use with Emulators is much higher. You don&#39;t need to add each emulated game individually. HWiNFO integration and lightweight background process that you can launch and forget are other important ones.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Biggest feature though are the stastics that it generates from your data. The launchers do time tracking at best as a side feature. Gaming Gaiden is designed to give you insights to your hobby. It&#39;s stastics feature will answer questions like&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you really gaming for same hours as you used to? Is your beloved hobby still alive?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you playing too much, is gaming affecting your life?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did you play enough games / enough hours since you bought that new PC to justify it&#39;s cost?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You setup such complex emulation setup, how many emulated games you actually played?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This application should add value to your gaming hobby by gathering data quietly in background and then making it super easy for you to draw conclusions and bring changes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GamingGaiden.zip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/releases/latest&#34;&gt;latest release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract &#34;GamingGaiden&#34; folder and copy it to a location where you would like to run it from. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do Not Use &#34;C:/Program Files&#34; or any other protected location that needs admin rights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Right click &lt;code&gt;Install.bat&lt;/code&gt; and click &lt;code&gt;Run as administrator&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally choose to setup a scheduled task to autostart at user login.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once installation is done, you will have a shortcut to run the application on desktop and start menu.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you move the application to another directory, simply run &lt;code&gt;Install.bat&lt;/code&gt; once again as administrator, to setup from the new location.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install.bat&lt;/code&gt; needs to be run as administrator to create the scheduled task for starting automatically on system startup.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;All shortcuts and scheduled tasks will include the parameter &lt;code&gt;-ExecutionPolicy bypass&lt;/code&gt; so that powershell scripts can be run. Windows by default doesn&#39;t allow powershell scripts to be executed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Attributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Made with love using&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.powershellgallery.com/packages/PSSQLite&#34;&gt;PSSQLite&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RamblingCookieMonster&#34;&gt;Warren Frame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://datatables.net/&#34;&gt;DataTables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jquery.com/&#34;&gt;Jquery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chartjs.org/&#34;&gt;ChartJs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various Icons from &lt;a href=&#34;https://icons8.com&#34;&gt;Icons8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Game Cartridge Icon from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flaticon.com/free-icons/game-cartridge&#34;&gt;FreePik on Flaticon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cute &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freepik.com/free-vector/cute-ninja-gaming-cartoon-vector-icon-illustration-people-technology-icon-concept-isolated-flat_42903434.htm&#34;&gt;Ninja Vector by Catalyststuff on Freepik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fontspace.com/ninja-garden-font-f32923&#34;&gt;Ninja Garden Font&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fontspace.com/iconian-fonts&#34;&gt;Iconian Fonts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Raising Bugs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the included manual first before raising issues. You might be able to solve it without needing help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a single dev, i have tested the application to best of my ability before making it public. However a large number of users is the first rigrous QA process the application is going to get. Bugs that i missed are bound to be found so kindly be patient. Bug reports in current feature set are welcome. Please share.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will try my best to fix bugs that are valid for the current set of features. If a bug report looks more like a new feature being requested instead of something broken in existing features. I may chose not to work on that. I believe the application is feature complete for what it is trying to do and i don&#39;t plan to add any additional features for most part.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would much rather actually play games than keep on developing this.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;I have More Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kulvind3r/GamingGaiden/main/readme-files/FAQ.md&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>