<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-10T01:32:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>aappuupatell/Microsoft-Intune</title>
    <updated>2024-05-10T01:32:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-10:/aappuupatell/Microsoft-Intune</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/aappuupatell/Microsoft-Intune" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PowerShell Scripts, Tools, and Modules for Microsoft Intune&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft-Intune&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell Scripts, Tools, and Modules for Microsoft Intune.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft-Intune&lt;/strong&gt; repository! This repository is a comprehensive resource dedicated to providing useful scripts, remediations, tips, and tricks to help administrators and IT professionals manage their Intune environments more effectively.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started with these resources, simply clone this repository to your local machine using the following command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aappuupatell/Microsoft-Intune.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to this repository are welcome! If you have a script, tip, or solution that can help others with Intune management, please follow these steps to contribute:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fork the repository&lt;/strong&gt; to your GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clone your forked repository&lt;/strong&gt; to your local machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new branch&lt;/strong&gt; for your contribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add your scripts, tips, or other content&lt;/strong&gt; to the new branch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit your changes&lt;/strong&gt; with a clear message describing the contribution.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push your changes&lt;/strong&gt; to your fork.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open a pull request&lt;/strong&gt; from your fork back to the main repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is licensed under the MIT License - see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aappuupatell/Microsoft-Intune/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is not officially affiliated with or endorsed by Microsoft. It is maintained by the community to aid those who manage Intune environments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you need help or have questions about the content here, please open an issue in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thank you for visiting! We hope you find the resources here helpful in managing your Intune environment.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>