<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-02-04T01:39:22Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/Azure-Verified-Modules</title>
    <updated>2024-02-04T01:39:22Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-02-04:/Azure/Azure-Verified-Modules</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/Azure-Verified-Modules" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Azure Verified Modules (AVM) is an initiative to consolidate and set the standards for what a good Infrastructure-as-Code module looks like. Modules will then align to these standards, across languages (Bicep, Terraform etc.) and will then be classified as AVMs and available from their respective language specific registries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;📄 &lt;strong&gt;Please note&lt;/strong&gt; that our documentation is published over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/avm&#34;&gt;aka.ms/AVM&lt;/a&gt;. Please visit this site for more information and guidance! 📄 &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; This repository is used for proposing and tracking the state of modules, tracking issues and feature requests as well as hosting documentation for the Azure Verified Modules (AVM) project. If you are looking for the AVM code repositories, please visit the Bicep and Terraform &lt;a href=&#34;https://azure.github.io/Azure-Verified-Modules/indexes/&#34;&gt;module indexes&lt;/a&gt; on the AVM portal for references.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- markdownlint-restore --&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Azure Verified Modules (AVM)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- [![Average time to resolve an issue](http://isitmaintained.com/badge/resolution/azure/azure-verified-modules.svg)](http://isitmaintained.com/project/azure/azure-verified-modules &#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;)&#xA;[![Percentage of issues still open](http://isitmaintained.com/badge/open/azure/azure-verified-modules.svg)](http://isitmaintained.com/project/azure/azure-verified-modules &#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;) --&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/Azure-Verified-Modules/main/docs/static/img/avm_logo.png&#34; width=&#34;20%&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welcome to the Azure Verified Modules (AVM) repository!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azure Verified Modules (AVM), as &#34;One Microsoft&#34;, we want to provide and define the single definition of what a good IaC module is;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;How they should be constructed and built &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Enforcing consistency and testing where possible&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;How they are to be consumed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;What they deliver for consumers in terms of resources deployed and configured&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And where appropriate aligned across IaC languages (e.g. Bicep, Terraform, etc.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information on AVM, &lt;strong&gt;please visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/AVM&#34;&gt;AVM portal (https://aka.ms/AVM)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;AVM Mission Statement&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to deliver a comprehensive Azure Verified Modules library in multiple IaC languages, following the principles of the well-architected framework, serving as the trusted Microsoft source of truth. Supported by Microsoft, AVM will accelerate deployment time for Azure resources and architectural patterns, empowering every person and organization on the planet on their IaC journey.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To contribute to Azure Verified Modules please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/AVM/Contribute&#34;&gt;aka.ms/AVM/Contribute&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data Collection&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The software may collect information about you and your use of the software and send it to Microsoft. Microsoft may use this information to provide services and improve our products and services. You may turn off the telemetry as described in the repository. There are also some features in the software that may enable you and Microsoft to collect data from users of your applications. If you use these features, you must comply with applicable law, including providing appropriate notices to users of your applications together with a copy of Microsoft’s privacy statement. Our privacy statement is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=824704&#34;&gt;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=824704&lt;/a&gt;. You can learn more about data collection and use in the help documentation and our privacy statement. Your use of the software operates as your consent to these practices.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>