<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-11T01:37:07Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tarikguney/usa-visa-appointment-checker</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T01:37:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-11:/tarikguney/usa-visa-appointment-checker</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tarikguney/usa-visa-appointment-checker" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;USA Visa Appointment Checker&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tarikguney/usa-visa-appointment-checker/main/visa-logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Example Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hello, Visa Seeker!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script automates the process of checking for available visa interview appointments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It logs into your account on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ais.usvisa-info.com&#34;&gt;https://ais.usvisa-info.com&lt;/a&gt; using your username and password, and then scans the appointment page for availability.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can run the script at regular intervals to receive timely alerts on new appointment slots.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Optionally, you can configure it to send email notifications about appointment availability to you or someone else.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rest assured, the script runs locally on your computer, ensuring that your login details are not shared.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to run&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the visa-appointment-checker.ps1 file onto your computer. You can also clone this repo if you know Git.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open up your preferred terminal app, like Windows Terminal or iTerm.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In your terminal, run this command to enter the Powershell shell: &lt;code&gt;pwsh&lt;/code&gt;. If this command seems unavailable, restart your terminal app.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Navigate to the directory where you placed the visa-appointment-checker.ps1 file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run this command and make sure you provide your username, password, and schedule id &lt;code&gt;./visa-appointment-checker.ps1 -email &#34;hello@world.com&#34; -password &#34;12abc&#34; -scheduleId 456677&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You must download and install Powershell to run this script on your computer.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell?view=powershell-7.3&#34;&gt;Dowload it here&lt;/a&gt; if you don&#39;t have it already.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;More Help&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.PARAMETER email&#xA;The email that you use to log in at https://ais.usvisa-info.com/en-tr/iv/users/sign_in&#xA;&#xA;.PARAMETER password&#xA;The password that you use to log in at https://ais.usvisa-info.com/en-tr/iv/users/sign_in&#xA;&#xA;.PARAMETER scheduleId&#xA;ScheduleId comes from the URL where you make the visa payment https://ais.usvisa-info.com/en-tr/iv/schedule/{scheduleId}/payment&#xA;&#xA;.EXAMPLE&#xA;.\visa-appointment-checker.ps1 -email &#34;hello@world.com&#34; -password &#34;12abc&#34; -scheduleId 456677&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>yourwishismine1989/PowerShell_Getting-Started</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T01:37:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-11:/yourwishismine1989/PowerShell_Getting-Started</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yourwishismine1989/PowerShell_Getting-Started" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A quick how to with your first script example&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PowerShell_Getting-Started&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quick how to with your first script example&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;install PowerShell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup linux distro (tested on Ubuntu 22.04 on 09/26/2023)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell-on-linux?view=powershell-7.3&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setup Windows (tested on Windows 11 on 09/26/2023)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell-on-windows?view=powershell-7.3&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hello-world&lt;/strong&gt; (tested on Ubuntu 22.04 on 09/26/2023)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/pwsh&#xA;touch hello-world.ps1&#xA;nano ./hello-world.ps1&#xA;[String]$message = &#34;Hello World&#34;&#xA;Write-Host -BackgroundColor $bgClr -ForegroundColor $fgClr &#34;$message&#34;&#xA;CTRL-o -&amp;gt; ENTER&#xA;CTRL-x&#xA;./hello-world.ps1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>codewario/PocketLibraryImages</title>
    <updated>2023-10-11T01:37:07Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-11:/codewario/PocketLibraryImages</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImages" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This tool will prepare an image library for use with cartridges (and openFPGA cores if Analogue ever supports them) on Analogue OS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Analogue Pocket Library Image Generator&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an interactive tool to assist with downloading image libraries from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libretro-thumbnails/libretro-thumbnails&#34;&gt;libretro-thumbnail&lt;/a&gt; and converting them to Analogue OS&#39; &lt;code&gt;.bin&lt;/code&gt; format.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that at this time image libraries only seem to work with cartridge-based games.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Note about OpenFPGA Cores&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presumably, OpenFPGA cores would follow the same image library format when displaying game details. However, Analogue has yet to support Library images for titles launched through OpenFPGA cores. Until such a time that OpenFPGA cores support Library images, using these image libraries with ROMs launched through OpenFPGA cores cannot be supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started, run &lt;code&gt;AnalogueOSLibraryImageGenerator.ps1&lt;/code&gt; in PowerShell. An interactive menu will guide you. It is recommended to read the &lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt; before using the tool for the first time to get a feel for how it works.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default the output is minimal. You can use the following flags to control whether to show additional output when launching the script. Note that these flags will increase the conversion time a bit as writing to the console is not an instant operation:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-OutputConvertedFiles&lt;/code&gt;: Output the files which are converted to the console&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-Verbose&lt;/code&gt;: Additional debugging output, useful when troubleshooting the script&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-Verbosity&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code&gt;Minimal&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Extra&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;Noisy&lt;/code&gt;. Controls how much information is displayed when &lt;code&gt;-Verbose&lt;/code&gt; is set. No effect otherwise. &lt;code&gt;Minimal&lt;/code&gt; is the default.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What game libraries can I convert?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At this time of writing only GBA, GB, GBC, and GG images are useful for conversion, but any libretro-thumbnail repository should be compatible. This ensures future compatibility as official converters are released or if Library images ever become supported on openFPGA cores.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why didn&#39;t it generate a thumbnail for one of my games?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note that since this tool relies on both &lt;strong&gt;libretro&lt;/strong&gt; and DAT files, it may miss thumbnails for games which don&#39;t have a &lt;strong&gt;libretro-thumbnail&lt;/strong&gt; image or if entries are not found in your DAT file. For the latter, if you know the CRC of your cart or ROM, you can add to your DAT file at any time using the text editor of your choice. In particular, rom hacks are likely going to be missing from the DAT file you pull from &lt;a href=&#34;https://datomatic.no-intro.org/&#34;&gt;DAT-O-MATIC&lt;/a&gt;, but there are a few missing retail games or revisions of them as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that DAT-O-MATIC does split some classes of games into their own System. For example, GBA video cartridges have a special system classification and are not included in the normal DAT with most actual games.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Where can I run this script?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool is only supported on Windows as it relies on .NET types which are not available on MacOS or Linux. You may see some remnants in the source of a cross-platform direction, but this was quashed when I found the built-in namespaces for image manipulation are Windows-only or deprecated in non-Windows environments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am aware that there are third-party libs/tools that can be leveraged for image manipulation, however, one of the goals of this project is portability and not requiring additional items to be installed. It is also why this script crawls the GitHub site to obtain the zip URLs instead of requiring &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to be installed for cloning &lt;code&gt;libretro-thumbnails&lt;/code&gt; and its submodules directly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, if anybody wants to contribute such functionality for Mac OS or Linux, pull requests are welcomed. Just try to keep any external dependencies to a &#34;standard enough&#34; minimum.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting a &#34;connection closed&#34; error when downloading one of the &lt;code&gt;libretro-thumbnails&lt;/code&gt; image libraries&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s not a whole lot I can do about this, I hit this sometimes too when trying to convert the GBA library due to its size. GitHub terminates the code archive download if it runs for longer than 20 minutes, in my experience. This is likely due to the fact that GitHub creates code archives on-demand, and the time the exported archive remains cached is limited.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a workaround when this happens, if you choose &lt;code&gt;Download Console Image Library (Manual)&lt;/code&gt;, and provide a file path (instead of a URL) to an archive that you&#39;ve either:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImages/master/create-local-archive.md&#34;&gt;exported yourself from a cloned copy of the &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; repo&lt;/a&gt;; or&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;been able to obtain from &lt;code&gt;libretro-thumbnails&lt;/code&gt; yourself via other means&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;then the script will work with the local archive you&#39;ve pointed to instead of attempting to obtain it from GitHub. Note that this script expects a &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;/code&gt; file; &lt;code&gt;.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt; is not supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;I would just like an image library please&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImages/releases/latest&#34;&gt;Release&lt;/a&gt; page for the most recent sample image packs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have a problem with the latest version, all &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImages/releases/&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; have sample packs provided, so you may try one of those. You can find older stable versions of the script along with image packs for supported games at the time of release as well as prior versions of the script. Don&#39;t forget if you have a problem with the latest sample packs to please create an issue on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImages/master/%5Burl%5D(https://github.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImageConversion/issues)https://github.com/codewario/PocketLibraryImageConversion/issues&#34;&gt;project&#39;s issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>