<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-17T01:31:52Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/PowerBI-LogAnalytics-Template-Reports</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T01:31:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-17:/microsoft/PowerBI-LogAnalytics-Template-Reports</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/PowerBI-LogAnalytics-Template-Reports" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The repository hosts Power BI template files that can be used to analyze Power BI data after you send it to Azure Log Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Power BI Log Analytics Template Reports&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Power BI allows users to configure connections to Azure Log Analytics where they can retain detailed historical activity data. This repo hosts Power BI Templates (.pbit) reports that you can point to your Azure Log Analytics workspaces to load data and get insights.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Available templates:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/PowerBI-LogAnalytics-Template-Reports/main/FabricASEngineAnalytics/README.md&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabric Analysis Services Engine Analytics report template:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This template adds the model layer to the ocean of the Analysis Services engine trace events and enables you to go from data to insight to action quickly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/PowerBI-LogAnalytics-Template-Reports/main/PBIASEngine/README.md&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Analytics for Analysis Services Engine report template:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; This template allows you to visualize the activity of datasets hosted in the Analysis Services Engine in Power BI workspaces. You can use it to identify load patterns, investigate user actions, look at query performance trends, visualize refreshes, and much more!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>