<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-05-21T01:41:21Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mr-r3b00t/GoDark</title>
    <updated>2023-05-21T01:41:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-21:/mr-r3b00t/GoDark</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mr-r3b00t/GoDark" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Go Dark&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;GoDark&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go Dark Not fully tested - use at own risk. If you need to hide maybe don&#39;t use a Windows PC/Server&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This goes quite dark...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;#Do not use this on production systems&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftLearning/AI-900-AIFundamentals</title>
    <updated>2023-05-21T01:41:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-21:/MicrosoftLearning/AI-900-AIFundamentals</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftLearning/AI-900-AIFundamentals" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Includes labs for AI Fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AI-900: Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository contains the hands-on lab exercises for Microsoft course &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/certifications/courses/ai-900t00&#34;&gt;AI-900 &lt;em&gt;Microsoft Azure AI Fundamentals&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/learn/certifications/azure-ai-fundamentals&#34;&gt;self-paced modules on Microsoft Learn&lt;/a&gt;. The labs are designed to accompany the learning materials and enable you to practice using the technologies they describe.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you a MCT?&lt;/strong&gt; - Have a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoftlearning.github.io/MCT-User-Guide/&#34;&gt;GitHub User Guide for MCTs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What are we doing?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To support this course, we will need to make frequent updates to the course content to keep it current with the Azure services used in the course. We are publishing the lab instructions and lab files on GitHub to allow for open contributions between the course authors and MCTs to keep the content current with changes in the Azure platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;We hope that this brings a sense of collaboration to the labs like we&#39;ve never had before - when Azure changes and you find it first during a live delivery, go ahead and make an enhancement right in the lab source. Help your fellow MCTs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How should I use these files relative to the released MOC files?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The instructor handbook and PowerPoints are still going to be your primary source for teaching the course content.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;These files on GitHub are designed to be used in conjunction with the student handbook, but are in GitHub as a central repository so MCTs and course authors can have a shared source for the latest lab files.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;It will be recommended that for every delivery, trainers check GitHub for any changes that may have been made to support the latest Azure services, and get the latest files for their delivery.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What about changes to the student handbook?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We will review the student handbook on a quarterly basis and update through the normal MOC release channels as needed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I contribute?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any MCT can submit a pull request to the code or content in the GitHub repro, Microsoft and the course author will triage and include content and lab code changes as needed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can submit bugs, changes, improvement and ideas. Find a new Azure feature before we have? Submit a new demo!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs</title>
    <updated>2023-05-21T01:41:21Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-05-21:/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repo is no longer accepting new issues. To request changes, create a branch, make changes, add @lindalu-MSFT as reviewer, then submit a PR. For more resources, see README.MD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About VBA-docs repo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We no longer have resources to respond to new issues. We welcome PRs that include documentation fixes, code samples, or improved comments. Please create a branch, make your changes, then open a PR to merge your change to master. We try to review new PRs monthly, but you can tag &lt;code&gt;@lindalu-MSFT&lt;/code&gt; in a comment for faster response!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get Office VBA support on Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a new forum on Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A for your VBA questions. To ask the developer community questions about your VBA code, go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/answers/questions/topics/single/192523.html&#34;&gt;Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A office-vba-dev forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Join the Microsoft 365 Developer Program&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get a free sandbox, tools, and other resources you need to build solutions for the Microsoft 365 platform.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/dev-program#Subscription&#34;&gt;Free developer sandbox&lt;/a&gt; Get a free, renewable 90-day Microsoft 365 E5 developer subscription.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/dev-program#Sample&#34;&gt;Sample data packs&lt;/a&gt; Automatically configure your sandbox by installing user data and content to help you build your solutions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/dev-program#Experts&#34;&gt;Access to experts&lt;/a&gt; Access community events to learn from Microsoft 365 experts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/microsoft-365/dev-program#Recommendations&#34;&gt;Personalized recommendations&lt;/a&gt; Find developer resources quickly from your personalized dashboard.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The published articles for this repo are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/office/vba/api/overview/&#34;&gt;Office VBA Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information about how to contribute to this documentation, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs/main/contributing.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>