<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-08-28T01:37:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/go</title>
    <updated>2023-08-28T01:37:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-08-28:/microsoft/go</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/go" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft build of the Go toolset&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;The Go Programming Language&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go is an open source programming language that makes it easy to build simple, reliable, and efficient software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/go&#34;&gt;microsoft/go&lt;/a&gt;, contains the infrastructure Microsoft uses to build Go. The submodule named &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; contains the Go source code. By default, the submodule&#39;s remote URL is the official GitHub mirror of Go, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go&#34;&gt;golang/go&lt;/a&gt;. The canonical Git repository for Go source code is located at &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.googlesource.com/go&#34;&gt;https://go.googlesource.com/go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is not involved in producing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/dl/&#34;&gt;official binary distributions of Go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise noted, the Go source files are distributed under the BSD-style license found in the LICENSE file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are using this fork and have a Microsoft corporate account, consider &lt;a href=&#34;https://idwebelements.microsoft.com/GroupManagement.aspx?Group=golang-announce&amp;amp;Operation=join&#34;&gt;clicking here to instantly join the Microsoft Go Toolset Announcements email distribution list 📧&lt;/a&gt; and receive notifications about Microsoft releases of Go and breaking changes. We also maintain an &lt;a href=&#34;https://eng.ms/docs/more/languages-at-microsoft/go/articles/overview&#34;&gt;internal doc page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Why does this fork exist?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository produces a modified version of Go that can be used to build FIPS 140-2 compliant applications. Our goal is to share this implementation with others in the Go community who have the same requirement, and to merge this capability into upstream Go as soon as possible. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/go/microsoft/main/eng/doc/fips&#34;&gt;eng/doc/fips&lt;/a&gt; for more information about this feature and the history of FIPS 140-2 compliance in Go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The binaries produced by this repository are also intended for general use within Microsoft instead of the official binary distribution of Go.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We call this repository a fork even though it isn&#39;t a traditional Git fork. Its branches do not share Git ancestry with the Go repository. However, the repository serves the same purpose as a Git fork: maintaining a modified version of the Go source code over time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project follows the upstream Go &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/doc/devel/release#policy&#34;&gt;Release Policy&lt;/a&gt;. This means we support each major release (1.X) until there are two newer major releases. A new Go major version is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/golang/go/wiki/Go-Release-Cycle&#34;&gt;released every six months&lt;/a&gt;, so each Go major version is supported for about one year.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When upstream Go releases a new minor version (1.X.Y), we release a corresponding microsoft/go version that may also include fork-specific changes. This normally happens once a month. At any time, we may release a new revision (1.X.Y-Z) to fix an issue without waiting for the next upstream minor release. Revision releases are uncommon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each microsoft/go release is announced in &lt;a href=&#34;https://idwebelements.microsoft.com/GroupManagement.aspx?Group=golang-announce&amp;amp;Operation=join&#34;&gt;the internal Microsoft Go Toolset Announcements email distribution list 📧&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download and install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository&#39;s infrastructure currently supports these OS/Arch combinations:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;linux_amd64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;linux_armv6l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;linux_arm64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows_amd64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/go/microsoft/main/eng/README.md&#34;&gt;eng/README.md&lt;/a&gt; for more details about the infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Binary distribution&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/go-images&#34;&gt;microsoft/go-images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; distributes the binaries of this Go fork by producing Docker images that are published to the Microsoft Container Registry. This is the recommended way to use the Microsoft build of Go.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/go/raw/microsoft/main/eng/doc/Downloads.md&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binary archives&lt;/strong&gt;: visit the &lt;code&gt;microsoft/main&lt;/code&gt; branch &lt;code&gt;eng/doc/Downloads.md&lt;/code&gt; file&lt;/a&gt; to download binaries and source tarballs built by supported release branches.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/go/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Releases&lt;/strong&gt;: the microsoft/go GitHub releases&lt;/a&gt; have source code archive attachments and an &lt;code&gt;assets.json&lt;/code&gt; file that can be used to locate the binaries for that release.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t see an option that works for you? Let us know! File a GitHub issue, or comment on an existing issue in this tag: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/go/labels/Area-Acquisition&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/labels/microsoft/go/Area-Acquisition&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Build from source&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell&#34;&gt;PowerShell 6+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://go.dev/doc/install/source&#34;&gt;Go install from source prerequisites&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Exception: this repository&#39;s build script automatically downloads a bootstrap version of Go.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After cloning the repository, use the following build command. You can pass the &lt;code&gt;-help&lt;/code&gt; flag to show more options:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pwsh eng/run.ps1 build -refresh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The resulting Go binary can then be found at &lt;code&gt;go/bin/go&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;If you download a source archive from a GitHub release, use the official Go install from source instructions. These source archives only include the &lt;code&gt;go&lt;/code&gt; directory, not the microsoft/go build infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>