<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-24T01:40:00Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>xAranaktu/FIFA-23-CM-Cheat-Table</title>
    <updated>2023-01-24T01:40:00Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-24:/xAranaktu/FIFA-23-CM-Cheat-Table</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/xAranaktu/FIFA-23-CM-Cheat-Table" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;FIFA 23 Career Mode Cheat Table&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;FIFA 23 Career Mode Cheat Table&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/xAranaktu/FIFA-23-CM-Cheat-Table/main/changelog.txt&#34;&gt;Changes in latest version of the tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/F23-LE-CT-DEV-BOARD&#34;&gt;FIFA 23 Live Editor &amp;amp; Cheat Table Development Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/F23-Projects-Release-Schedule&#34;&gt;FIFA 23 Live Editor &amp;amp; Cheat Table Release Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xAranaktu/FIFA-23-CM-Cheat-Table/wiki&#34;&gt;WIKI&lt;/a&gt; for Guides and Tutorials&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Read Me Before You Pledge or Buy The Game&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This year the game is protected with brand new EA Anticheat. Using the tool may flag your account and EA may ban it later on. You are using the tool at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The tool is at early stage of developement, many features may not work or may be bugged. Wait until at least until December if you expect somewhat finished tool&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you are scared of being banned then don&#39;t use the tool (at least for a while until, situation will clarify)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This tool doesn&#39;t work online. You won&#39;t be able to connect with EA servers while using it. This is intended, and won&#39;t be &#34;fixed&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;I can&#39;t guarantee for how long the tool will be working. EA may update the game at any time and since then it may be not possible to update the Live Editor to make it compatible with latest game update.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because of the EA Anticheat you &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; run the cheat engine alongside my other tool, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xAranaktu/FIFA-23-Live-Editor&#34;&gt;FIFA 23 Live Editor&lt;/a&gt; which is able to bypass the anticheat. Cheat Engine on it&#39;s own won&#39;t work (unless you have undetected version, but I can&#39;t help you with obtaining one).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cheat_Engine#Cheat_Tables&#34;&gt;What is Cheat Table?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#34;Cheat Tables&#34; is a file format used by Cheat Engine to store data such as cheat addresses, scripts including Lua scripts and code locations&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recommend to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://cheatengine.org/downloads.php&#34;&gt;Cheat Engine 7.3&lt;/a&gt; or newer for the FIFA 23 cheat table.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FIFA 23 Career Mode Cheat Table allows you to modify many aspects of you career mode. For example you can edit players (potential, attributes, name etc.), transfer budget, boost/nerf players development, play single career for more than 15 seasons, change weather/stadium/time of the day before match, send youth academy scout to any country... and many more!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/A9V8U0F.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/5SXaStY.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/GemoWvH.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/RmVpokr.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>