<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-31T01:34:42Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>XxpichoclesxX/GtaVScripts</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T01:34:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-31:/XxpichoclesxX/GtaVScripts</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/XxpichoclesxX/GtaVScripts" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some Gta V Online lua scripts for diferent modding engines like stand or kiddions for free&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;How To Use&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For every script there is a different use and ways to fully take advantage on other modders.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Kiddions script is just puting the script into scripts directory, inside the Kiddions files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Stand it is actually the same way, but first before initiating the script you will need to go into library and search for the native-1663599433 and then you will be able to use the script and his various functions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;GtaVScripts&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Im presenting you some Gta V Scripts for online or campaign, these are made by me so if you find an error please dm to discord. (XxpichoclesxX#0427) 1- A really nice lua, complement for kiddions modding engine for Gta V, im not aware of use you can do to this shitty lua script. 2- A nice lua for Stand!, a paid modding engine that has more features and a super nice lua api, so no problems in this one, coming soon boys with a lot of online features and player op lua crashes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Questions Ryze-Kiddions-GtaV:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The kiddions lua is for the modding engine yall maybe know for Gta-V called &#34;Kiddions&#34;, it is made for everyone who doesn&#39;t like to be annoyed by any type of modder, and if you want to make youre account op. This has recovery features, protection features and some Online features more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This has no ETA by now, im just making this for fun and i started making it because my friends asked for me and i dont know im going to continue this lua by now, im updating it sooner but im not sure. thx for reading this and im keeping you updated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Questions Ryze-Stand-GtaV&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a lua also for the paid modding engine called stand, it is a complement of various scripts also known, im just improving the code and adding some extra features that the menu doesn&#39;t have like more protections to make unable to the modders to grief you, lag you etc. Im also thinking on some extra features, like more protections and trolling options and much more than i have in today&#39;s version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No ETA also because as i said in kiddions script i dont know actually if im going to continue this by now, because of my classes and everything so, this is just a fun and helpfull project, if anyone want&#39;s to use it, is free and you can use my script has a template for free.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Probably Stand script is going to take a little bit more than kiddions, by now, kiddions script is in stand by me &amp;lt;3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;By the way to anyone who ask&#39;s about the stand script, is not entire mine, there is actually in credits every single person who i taked code from and who helped me with this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Last Kiddions update: 27/12/2022&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Last Stand update: 25/12/2022&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>mattmight/advent-of-code-2022</title>
    <updated>2022-12-31T01:34:42Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-31:/mattmight/advent-of-code-2022</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mattmight/advent-of-code-2022" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Matt Might&#39;s Advent of Code 2022 Challenge&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo documents my (ultimately successful) attempt to complete each day for &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com/2022/events&#34;&gt;Advent of Code 2022&lt;/a&gt; using a different programming languages.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a rundown of the languages by day:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Day 01: Awk           &#xA;Day 02: LaTeX         &#xA;Day 03: C             &#xA;Day 04: Java          &#xA;Day 05: MATLAB        &#xA;&#xA;Day 06: C#            &#xA;Day 07: Ruby         &#xA;Day 08: Julia        &#xA;Day 09: Bash         &#xA;Day 10: vimscript    &#xA;&#xA;Day 11: C++          &#xA;Day 12: R            &#xA;Day 13: JavaScript   &#xA;Day 14: Erlang       &#xA;Day 15: Go           &#xA;&#xA;Day 16: Python        &#xA;Day 17: Standard ML   &#xA;Day 18: PHP           &#xA;Day 19: Common Lisp   &#xA;Day 20: TypeScript    &#xA;&#xA;Day 21: sed &amp;amp; bc      &#xA;Day 22: Lua           &#xA;Day 23: Haskell       &#xA;Day 24: Scala         &#xA;Day 25: Racket       &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>