<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-07T01:32:38Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2</title>
    <updated>2025-03-07T01:32:38Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-07:/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Path of Building 2 Community&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Welcome to Path of Building 2, an offline build planner for Path of Exile 2!&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p float=&#34;middle&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Tree tab&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/225bf25f-1ac4-4639-b280-565a24d2a2fc&#34; width=&#34;48%&#34;&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;Items tab&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/de8e6dc0-1e1a-46c5-b8a4-18877e67d48d&#34; width=&#34;48%&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; page to download the install wizard or portable zip.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive offence + defence calculations: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Calculate your skill DPS, damage over time, life/mana/ES totals and much more!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can factor in auras, buffs, charges, curses, monster resistances and more, to estimate your effective DPS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Also calculates life/mana reservations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Shows a summary of character stats in the side bar, as well as a detailed calculations breakdown tab which can show you how the stats were derived&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supports all skills and support gems, and most passives and item modifiers &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Throughout the program, supported modifiers will show in blue and unsupported ones in red&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Full support for minions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for party play and support builds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Passive skill tree planner: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Support for jewels including most radius/conversion and timeless jewels&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Features alternate path tracing (mouse over a sequence of nodes while holding shift, then click to allocate them all)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fully integrated with the offence/defence calculations; see exactly how each node will affect your character!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can import PathOfExile.com and PoEPlanner.com passive tree links; links shortened with PoEURL.com also work&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Skill planner: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Add any number of main or supporting skills to your build&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Supporting skills (auras, curses, buffs) can be toggled on and off&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automatically applies Socketed Gem modifiers from the item a skill is socketed into&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automatically applies support gems granted by items&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Item planner: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Add items from in game by copying and pasting them straight into the program!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automatically adds quality to non-corrupted items&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search the trade site for the most impactful items&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Fully integrated with the offence/defence calculations; see exactly how much of an upgrade a given item is!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Contains a searchable database of all uniques that are currently in game (and some that aren&#39;t yet!) &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;You can choose the modifier rolls when you add a unique to your build&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Includes all league-specific items and legacy variants&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Features an item crafting system: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;You can select from any of the game&#39;s base item types&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;You can select prefix/suffix modifiers from lists&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Custom modifiers can be added, with Master and Essence modifiers available&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Also contains a database of rare item templates: &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Allows you to create rare items for your build to approximate the gear you will be using&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Choose which modifiers appear on each item, and the rolls for each modifier, to suit your needs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Has templates that should cover the majority of builds&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Other features: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;You can import passive tree, items, and skills from existing characters&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Share builds with other users by generating a share code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Automatic updating; most updates will only take a couple of seconds to apply&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the full version history &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2/dev/CHANGELOG.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find instructions on how to contribute code and bug reports &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2/dev/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licence&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For 3rd-party licences, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PathOfBuildingCommunity/PathOfBuilding-PoE2/dev/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;. The licencing information is considered to be part of the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>