<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-04-21T03:16:18Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>yorickpeterse/nvim-tree-pairs</title>
    <updated>2024-04-21T03:16:18Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-04-21:/yorickpeterse/nvim-tree-pairs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/yorickpeterse/nvim-tree-pairs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;NeoVim plugin for jumping to the other end of the current Tree-sitter node&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;nvim-tree-pairs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A NeoVim plugin that uses Tree-sitter to allow jumping between the matching opposing end of a Tree-sitter node, such as brackets, quotes, and more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asciinema.org/a/654974&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://asciinema.org/a/654974.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;A recording of using the plugin&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;What does it do?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the cursor is on the start or end of a Tree-sitter node (e.g. a &lt;code&gt;{&lt;/code&gt;), jump to the other end&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If the cursor is somewhere in the middle of a Tree-sitter node, jump to the end of the node&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When using Tree-sitter, the &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; motion of NeoVim doesn&#39;t always work reliably, as it requires syntax information not present when using Tree-sitter. This is most notable when you&#39;re jumping between matching brackets (e.g. &lt;code&gt;{&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;), but there are a lot of lines in between, as in this case &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; might jump to some random location in the middle.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This plugin solves this issue by using Tree-sitter when enabled, falling back to the default &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; behaviour if Tree-sitter isn&#39;t enabled. When Tree-sitter is available, you can jump between the start and end of any Tree-sitter node. Take this Lua code for example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lua&#34;&gt;example&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you place the cursor on the &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;example&lt;/code&gt; and press &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt;, the cursor jumps to the closing &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;. If you then press &lt;code&gt;%&lt;/code&gt; again, it jumps back to the starting &lt;code&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Requirements&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;NeoVim &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt;, 0.9.5 &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; also work but I haven&#39;t verified this&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nvim-treesitter/nvim-treesitter/&#34;&gt;nvim-treesitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add &lt;code&gt;yorickpeterse/nvim-tree-pairs&lt;/code&gt; using your favourite package manager, then add the following somewhere to your &lt;code&gt;init.lua&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lua&#34;&gt;require(&#39;tree-pairs&#39;).setup()&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This creates a &#34;pairs&#34; Tree-sitter module that&#39;s enabled automatically. You can disable it (if needed) using &lt;code&gt;:TSDisable pairs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This plugin doesn&#39;t have any language specific handling or Tree-sitter queries, meaning it can&#39;t handle jumping from e.g. the Lua &lt;code&gt;then&lt;/code&gt; keyword to the next &lt;code&gt;elseif&lt;/code&gt; keyword. This is by design, as the intent of this plugin is to be as simple as possible. Patches that apply language specific handling won&#39;t be accepted.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All source code in this repository is licensed under the Mozilla Public License version 2.0, unless stated otherwise. A copy of this license can be found in the file &#34;LICENSE&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>