<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-13T01:41:32Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>L7NEG/Ultimate-Menu</title>
    <updated>2023-07-13T01:41:32Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-13:/L7NEG/Ultimate-Menu</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/L7NEG/Ultimate-Menu" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello Its Me L7NEG Im Back Again With my own Write Script I Call It Ultimate Menu And It Dose What it says It Is Basiclly A Menu Inside Kiddons Menu With No1 Money Method A Trusted Menu Made With Love To You All&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ultimate Menu&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;For Original thread you can find it here====&amp;gt; https://www.unknowncheats.me/forum/grand-theft-auto-v/565688-1-64-ultimate-unlocker.html&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How To Use Ultimate Menu Script&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For every Version of the ultimate menu (Kiddion/YimMenu) there is a different use and ways to fully Run It.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Kiddions script is just puting the script into scripts directory, inside the Kiddions files.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For YimMenu it is actually the same way, but first before initiating the script you will need to go to Settings &amp;gt; Lua &amp;gt; Open Folder Option&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From There Go To Scripts Folder Then Paste The Ultimate Menu In There&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Gta V Scripts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Im presenting you some Gta V Scripts for online or campaign, these are made by me so if you find an error please dm to discord. (@l7neg)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions And Answers:&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;1: How Do I Install Kiddions Modest Menu? A: Answered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&#34;&gt;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;2- Why Ultimate Menu Script Not Showing Up In Kiddions? A: Make Sure Ultimate Menu.lua Script Is In Kiddions Scrips Folder&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;3- How To Do The 6 Mil Crates Method? A: Answered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&#34;&gt;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;4- What Are The Limits And The Best 5 Ways To Make Money In Gta Online? A: Answered in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&#34;&gt;https://sub.l7neg.tk/discord&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Meaning Emojis: 🟢 Undetected 🟠 Working on / In Progress / In Testing Stage 🔴 Detected&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No ETA for big updates also because i don&#39;t know actually if im going to be able to continue this script (boths) because i have a life and i need to study. This is a helpfull and fun project for everyone who wants to use it, is free and you can use my script has a template.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;By the way to anyone who ask&#39;s about the Ultimate-Menu script, is not entire mine, there is actually in credits every single person who i taked code from and who helped me with this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Latest Ultimate Menu Kiddions update was on: 7/05/2023&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Latest Ultimate Menu Stand update was on: 8/07/2023&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>