<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-07T01:32:08Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ErinaSugino/Starbound-SBR-Mod</title>
    <updated>2024-06-07T01:32:08Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-07:/ErinaSugino/Starbound-SBR-Mod</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ErinaSugino/Starbound-SBR-Mod" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adult only modification &#34;Sexbound Reborn&#34; for the game Starbound.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Starbound-SBR-Mod&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adult only modification &lt;code&gt;Sexbound Reborn&lt;/code&gt; for the game Starbound.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Content Warning&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sexbound Reborn&lt;/code&gt; is an adult only modification containing assets and mechanics to enable explicit sexual interaction in the game. The source files present in this GitHub Repository &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; contain part-separated pixelart sprites used to depict nude characters during sex, as well as contain numerous references in source code, comments and file names to these interactions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are not interested in, comfortable with, or legally allowed to use this kind of content, then please ignore this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sexbound Reborn&lt;/code&gt; is a fork of the original mod &lt;code&gt;Sexbound&lt;/code&gt; (Version 5.12.1 from December 2021), originally created by Locuturus and their contributors.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal and purpose of this mod is to introduce the mechanics and concepts of natural reproduction into the universe of Starbound, including all the difficulties and downsides the harsh environments of the game&#39;s original world building concept bring with them. Unlike its predecessor, which was a half-baked mashup between no content API and minimal showcase mod, &lt;code&gt;Sexbound Reborn&lt;/code&gt; aims to be an enjoyable standalone mod while still offering all the easy to use core API features needed for other mod creators to build upon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ErinaSugino/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt; contain newest public versions. Stable major releases are suitable for normal use, preview builds are mainly for testing and modding purposes and not suited for use in a normal playthrough. Major changes are noted on the releases, detailed changelog can always be found inside the released files. Detailed usage information, FAQs and modding tutorials can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ErinaSugino/wiki&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. When you found a bug or incompatibility with another mod you can report this in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ErinaSugino/issues&#34;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt;. Only issues following standard reporting procedures will be taken into consideration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Official Mod Sources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Due to the GPL Open-Source nature of the mod, people have been starting to distribute copies in other places. The following list is a complete list of all &lt;strong&gt;official, maintained&lt;/strong&gt; sources where the mod can be found:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;This GitHub Repository&lt;br&gt; LoversLab (Mod ID &lt;strong&gt;26132&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;br&gt; Nexusmods (Mod ID &lt;strong&gt;1015&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any other source where the mod might be found is &lt;strong&gt;inofficial&lt;/strong&gt;, not affiliated with me, and will most likely not receive any form of maintenance or support. Use at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>