<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-30T01:32:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:32:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-30:/Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Grokitach/Stalker_GAMMA" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Anomaly G.A.M.M.A. modpack definition files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. G.A.M.M.A.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Anomaly G.A.M.M.A. modpack &#34;actively updated&#34; files are stored in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the complete client (heavy, rarely modified files) necessary for this repository to work, you need to download it from the associated discord server where a team of people is ready to help you with your questions and potential issues related to this project:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/stalker-gamma&#34;&gt;https://discord.gg/stalker-gamma&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any Pull Request should be made &lt;strong&gt;to the dev2 branch&lt;/strong&gt;. Anyone can contribute to this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;GAMMA is a large project using the work of many talented modders, and each and everyone one of them are contributing to making Stalker Anomaly a better experience. I would thus like to thank all the modders involved in this project by making all the GAMMA addons free to use, edit and repost with modifications as long as the source is indicated (original addon author, from Stalker GAMMA). For numbered addons (105-), original authors must be contacted before repost and modifications. Repost of unmodified individual parts of this project are not recommended and may harm the community in the long run because updates happen quite often in this repository and it is thus better to directly post links to the relevant files stored here.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.A.M.M.A. stands for Gigantic Automated Modular Modpack for Anomaly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;G.A.M.M.A. aims at providing a balanced survival, scavenging, cooking, crafting and repairing focused experience with a long progression and smooth gameplay.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main motivation behind this project is to provide an easy to install, automatically updated and modular modding platform for Stalker Anomaly, with base parameters and gameplay mechanics setup to create a meaningful and enjoyable sense of progression.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This modpack is 100% copyright free since it redistributes little to no copyrighted content developed by other modders. Indeed, G.A.M.M.A. downloads every add-on directly from moddb or github, and installs them automatically. You will thus directly support modders by installing G.A.M.M.A. On top of this, each addon original source (moddb or github page) is directly accessible from the Mod Organizer 2 instance by right-clicking addons &amp;gt; visit moddb.com.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many addons are developped exclusively for this project, including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A new UI.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A rebalanced survival experience focused on crafting, repairing and cooking.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;A new economy where traders will only sell you supplies, and where good ammunition will only be available to trustful stalkers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New starting loadouts focused on providing pistols, SMGs or WW2 guns to have a smoother start with calibers for which you can buy ammo. It also gives you the basic tools to wander the Zone, which is nice for Ironman runs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced close quarter combat to make knives more useful and to free even more inventory slots, yup you can equip 2 pistols and 2 main weapons and still profit from your best knife with a reworked quick melee motion and system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced actor damage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced sleep.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rebalanced Skill System from Haruka.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Overhauled radiations effects and dynamic radiation areas.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Many fixes for some major addons including the Boomsticks and Sharpsticks gunpack.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;And more!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fluorohydride/ygopro-scripts</title>
    <updated>2024-03-30T01:32:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-30:/Fluorohydride/ygopro-scripts</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Fluorohydride/ygopro-scripts" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;scripts of official cards for ygopro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>