<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Lua Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-01-08T01:37:51Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Lua in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>rohKane/Kane-qb-hud-Nopixel-4.0-inspired</title>
    <updated>2024-01-08T01:37:51Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-01-08:/rohKane/Kane-qb-hud-Nopixel-4.0-inspired</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rohKane/Kane-qb-hud-Nopixel-4.0-inspired" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a Heavily edited of QBCore Hud by kane into Nopixel 4.0 inspired design with manual transmission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Heavily edited of QBCore Hud by me into Nopixel 4.0 inspired design with manual transmission.&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/rohKane/Kane-qb-hud-Nopixel-4.0-inspired/assets/47999933/c373f7a0-5c9c-4c2f-96d3-1745b8ee0b44&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot 2024-01-04 234436&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Things you should know:&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;To open the menu in-game the &lt;strong&gt;default key&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;&#34;I&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; or you can type &lt;strong&gt;&#34;/menu&#34;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Your settings will &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; be &lt;strong&gt;stored locally&lt;/strong&gt;, so even if you delete the resource it &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; keep your current settings. The &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; way you can wipe the local storage sucessfully is by clicking the &lt;strong&gt;&#34;Reset Settings&#34;&lt;/strong&gt; button on the in-game menu&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you want the new super snazzy sound effects for the menu, you&#39;ll need to download the latest update of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qbcore-framework/interact-sound&#34;&gt;interact-sound&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt; (comes with new open menu sound, close menu sound, click menu sound)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you receive &lt;code&gt;attempt to index a nil value (global &#39;Lang&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; in your F8 console, the fastest way you can fix that issue is by downloading a new version via txAdminRecipe but if you are unable to do that because of the progress you’ve made on your existing build; you’ll have to unfortunately go through and download each one from the GitHub which I do not recommend. Save yourself a lot of time and pain by just downloading the recipe!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;FAQ&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Why do my borders not align with the maps?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Most of the time it generally means your safezone is not set to default in your GTA settings. (Settings/Display/&#34;Restore Defaults&#34;)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; How do I enable dev mode?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Simple! All you have to do is type /admin and navigate through the menu to the last section called &#34;Developer Options&#34; and inside there you should see &#34;Dev Mode&#34;, this will keep you invincible and add a cool developer icon in your circles/radials&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What does the purple circle/radial do?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; That is your harness indicator! When you have the item &#34;harness&#34; in your inventory and while in a vehicle it will appear. Also, when you use your item &#34;harness&#34;, the circle/radial will reflect the amount of uses left and decrease overtime.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>