<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-29T01:42:43Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>Enitoni/pulseshitter</title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T01:42:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-29:/Enitoni/pulseshitter</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Enitoni/pulseshitter" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An overengineered workaround to Discord not supporting audio when screensharing on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;pulseshitter&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Enitoni/pulseshitter/raw/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/Enitoni/pulseshitter.svg?style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Enitoni/pulseshitter/main/screenshot.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of pulseshitter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;pulseshitter is a shitty solution to a shitty problem.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;you see, it all started back in 2015, when discord announced discord, an instant messaging social platform for gamers, until they decided that it was for everyone too.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;however, they clearly don&#39;t support everyone because they hate us blessed linux users. to this day, discord still &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.discord.com/hc/en-us/community/posts/360050971374-Linux-Screen-Share-Sound-Support&#34;&gt;doesn&#39;t support&lt;/a&gt; sharing audio via screen sharing on linux.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;attention current maintainers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;the project had an issue in the git history, which led to a force push, you should run this in your cloned repo:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git fetch &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git reset --hard origin/HEAD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;what is this?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;this overengineered project is a workaround to make it possible to share audio via a &lt;strong&gt;bot&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;it does not pipe your audio through your microphone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; this has two advantages:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;other people can mute your stream without muting you&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;the audio is stereo (ＷＩＤＥ)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;shits your audio into a voice channel&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;based terminal user interface&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;automatically reconnects to an application when parec stops streaming it (it does that a lot)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;cool good sound meter™️&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;follows you around so you can always bother your friends&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;says fuck you to discord (fuck you discord)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;🚀 blazingly fa--&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;caveats&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;you need a bot in a server to use it&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;linux audio sources are very inconsistent so it&#39;s not guaranteed it will reconnect properly, or even show a meaningful name, but you can always just select the app you want to stream again&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git&#34;&gt;linux&lt;/a&gt; (duh)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/PulseAudio/&#34;&gt;pulseaudio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://pipewire.org&#34;&gt;pipewire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manpages.debian.org/testing/pulseaudio-utils/parec.1.en.html&#34;&gt;parec&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com/search?q=discord+bot+token+generator&#34;&gt;discord bot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Enitoni/pulseshitter/releases/latest&#34;&gt;download latest release&lt;/a&gt; and run the binary in your terminal. you can also add it to path for easy access.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;./pulseshitter&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;faq (you)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Is this a joke?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Parts of this README, yes. The project itself, no. It&#39;s actually something I worked really hard on and it is actually a successor to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/itsMapleLeaf/pulsecord&#34;&gt;pulsecord&lt;/a&gt; which my friend was using. It had some issues, and that&#39;s what led to this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why can&#39;t I stream Spotify?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spotify streaming is disabled by default due to me not wanting to get in trouble for distributing a binary that allows you to bypass the measures Discord has in place to stop you from streaming Spotify through their service.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can enable it by compiling the project yourself with the &lt;code&gt;ALLOW_SPOTIFY_STREAMING&lt;/code&gt; environment variable set to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Are you open to suggestions/bug reports?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Please make a GitHub issue if you want to report a bug or suggest a feature.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;build&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rust-lang.org/&#34;&gt;rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;pulseaudio / pipewire&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;libopus&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;compile it by typing this in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cargo build --release&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;then you&#39;re done (wow!)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;license&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/2.0/&#34;&gt;MPL-2 license&lt;/a&gt; (very original do not steal)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>memorysafety/sudo-rs</title>
    <updated>2023-04-29T01:42:43Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-29:/memorysafety/sudo-rs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/memorysafety/sudo-rs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A memory safe implementation of sudo and su.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;sudo-rs&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A safety oriented and memory safe implementation of sudo and su written in Rust.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;⚠️ WARNING&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sudo-rs is currently under active development and is not suited for any production environment. Using sudo-rs is only recommended for development and testing purposes, but you should expect any system that has sudo-rs installed to break easily and to not be secure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sudo-rs currently only supports Linux-based operating systems, although other unix-based operating systems may work, they are currently not actively supported or maintained.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sudo-rs is written in Rust. We currently only support the latest stable compiler toolchain. To get a recent compiler toolchain we recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://rustup.rs/&#34;&gt;rustup&lt;/a&gt;. To build sudo-rs run&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo build --release&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This produces a binary &lt;code&gt;target/release/sudo&lt;/code&gt;. However this binary must have the setuid flag set and must be owned by the root user in order to provide any useful functionality. Because we are in such an early stage we also require an environment variable &lt;code&gt;SUDO_RS_IS_UNSTABLE&lt;/code&gt; to be set, and it must have the value &lt;code&gt;I accept that my system may break unexpectedly&lt;/code&gt;. If you are unsure about how to set this up, then the current version of sudo is not intended for you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sudo-rs needs the sudoers configuration file, but it currently reads it at &lt;code&gt;/etc/sudoers.test&lt;/code&gt;, instead of the default location. You must make sure that a valid sudoers configuration exists at that location. For an explanation of the sudoers syntax you can look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sudo.ws/docs/man/sudoers.man/&#34;&gt;original sudo man page&lt;/a&gt;. While most syntax should be supported as is, most functionality will currently not be implemented. Sudo-rs currently may not always warn about this, so your sudoers file may have a different meaning compared to the original sudo implementation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sudo-rs always uses PAM for authentication at this time, your system must be setup for PAM. Sudo-rs will use the &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; service configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our current target is to build a drop-in replacement for most basic use cases of sudo. For the sudoers config syntax this means that we aim to at least support the default configuration files of some common Linux distributions (we currently aim to suppor both the Fedora and Debian default sudoers configs). Our implementation should eventually at least support all commonly used CLI flags from the original sudo implementation (e.g. flags like &lt;code&gt;-u&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;-g&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some parts of the original sudo are explicitly not in scope. Sudo has a large and rich history and some of the features available in the original sudo implementation are largely unused or only available for legacy platforms. In order to determine which features make it we both consider whether the feature is relevant for modern systems, and whether it will receive at very least decent usage. Finally of course a feature should not compromise the safety of the whole program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;su&lt;/code&gt; program is a much simpler program and will only include basic functionality. However, we think that the building blocks that make up our sudo implementation will be suited to be used for creating a simple su implementation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While we are still working on getting the basic infrastructure and architecture of sudo-rs up and running, accepting arbitrary contributions will be difficult. If you have any small changes or suggestions please do leave those, but if you want to work on larger parts of sudo-rs please ask first, or we may risk doing work twice or not being able to include your work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Future work&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While our initial target is a drop-in replacement for most basic use cases of sudo, our work may evolve beyond that target. We are also looking into alternative ways to configure sudo without the sudoers config file syntax and to extract parts of our work in usable crates for other people.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>