<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-03-16T01:37:24Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>PowerShell/DSC</title>
    <updated>2025-03-16T01:37:24Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-03-16:/PowerShell/DSC</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PowerShell/DSC" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repo is for the DSC v3 project&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;DSCv3&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] This repo isn&#39;t accepting code contributions. It&#39;s public and open source to show progress and enable feedback. Once we&#39;re at a feature complete state, we can start taking code contributions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s DSCv3?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DSCv3 is the latest iteration of Microsoft&#39;s Desired State Configuration platform. DSCv3 is an open source command line application that abstracts the management of software components declaratively and idempotently. DSCv3 runs on Linux, macOS, and Windows without any external dependencies.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With DSCv3, you can:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Author resources to manage your systems in any language&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Invoke individual resources&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create configuration documents that define the desired state of a system&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Differences from PowerShell DSC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DSCv3 differs from PowerShell DSC in a few important ways:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DSCv3 doesn&#39;t depend on PowerShell. You can use DSCv3 without PowerShell installed and manage resources written in bash, python, C#, Go, or any other language.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DSCv3 use of PowerShell based resources does not depend on PSDesiredStateConfiguration module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DSCv3 doesn&#39;t include a local configuration manager. DSCv3 is invoked as a command. It doesn&#39;t run as a service.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Non-PowerShell resources define their schemas with JSON files, not MOF files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configuration documents are defined in JSON or YAML files, not PowerShell script files.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Importantly, while DSCv3 represents a major change to the DSC platform, DSCv3 is able to invoke PowerShell DSC Resources, including script-based and class-based DSC Resources, as they exist today. The configuration documents aren&#39;t compatible, but all published PowerShell DSC Resources are. You can use PowerShell DSC resources in DSCv3 with both Windows PowerShell and PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installing DSCv3&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install DSC v3:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShell/DSC/releases/latest&#34;&gt;latest release from this repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Expand the release archive.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add the folder containing the expanded archive contents to the &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Explore DSCv3&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re new to DSC or configuration management, we recommend reviewing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/powershell/dsc/overview?view=dsc-3.0&amp;amp;preserve-view=true&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Learning and authoring tutorials&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re already familiar with DSC or just want to start experimenting with v3, we recommend reviewing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShell/DSC-Samples&#34;&gt;Samples repository&lt;/a&gt; and the accompanying &lt;a href=&#34;https://powershell.github.io/DSC-Samples&#34;&gt;tutorial site&lt;/a&gt;. The Samples repo is ready to accept Pull Requests, which is a great way to contribute while v3 is in early phases of development.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Integrating with DSCv3&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DSCv3 is a platform tool that abstracts the concerns for defining and invoking resources. Higher order tools, like Azure Machine Configuration, Azure Automanaged VM, and WinGet are early partners for DSCv3 as orchestration agents.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;DSCv3 uses JSON schemas to define the structure of resources, configuration documents, and the outputs that DSCv3 returns. These schemas make it easier to integrate DSCv3 with other tools, because they standardize and document how to interface with DSCv3.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PowerShell/DSC/main/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt; before participating in this project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Security Policy&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For any security issues, please see our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PowerShell/DSC/main/SECURITY.md&#34;&gt;Security Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>