<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-07-30T01:45:17Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>GraphiteEditor/Graphite</title>
    <updated>2023-07-30T01:45:17Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-07-30:/GraphiteEditor/Graphite</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/GraphiteEditor/Graphite" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;2D raster &amp; vector editor that melds traditional layers &amp; tools with a modern node-based, fully non-destructive procedural workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.rs/&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;picture&gt; &#xA;  &lt;source media=&#34;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&#34; srcset=&#34;https://static.graphite.rs/readme/graphite-readme-logo-dark-theme.svg&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;source media=&#34;(prefers-color-scheme: light)&#34; srcset=&#34;https://static.graphite.rs/readme/graphite-readme-logo-light-theme.svg&#34;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;img alt=&#34;Graphite logo&#34; src=&#34;https://static.graphite.rs/readme/graphite-readme-logo-dark-theme.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;/picture&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Redefining state-of-the-art graphics editing&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphite is an in-development raster and vector 2D graphics editor that is free and open source. It is powered by a node graph compositing engine that supercharges your layer stack, providing a completely non-destructive editing experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graphite is a lightweight vector graphics editor that runs in your browser. Its nascent node-based compositor lets you apply raster effects and co-create amazing art with AI in a non-destructive workflow. Fully-featured raster image editing and a native desktop application are the current focus of development and will be made available in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Launch the latest alpha release of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://editor.graphite.rs&#34;&gt;Graphite editor&lt;/a&gt; and learn more on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.rs/&#34;&gt;project website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;⭐ Please remember to star this project here on GitHub! ⭐&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://static.graphite.rs/content/index/gui-demo-valley-of-spires.png&#34; alt=&#34;Vector artwork: &amp;quot;Valley of Spires&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Discord community&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.graphite.rs&#34;&gt;Join our Discord community&lt;/a&gt; to chat with the community and development team. Feel free to lurk, ask questions, give suggestions, or get involved in the project. We are always seeking new collaborators to help test, design, and develop the software and this is where we communicate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Building/contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need Rust and web developers! See &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.rs/contribute/&#34;&gt;instructions here&lt;/a&gt; for setting up the project and getting started.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are also in search of artists to create beautiful sample work in Graphite and illustrations for the website and social media. Please &lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.rs/contact/&#34;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt; if you are able to help out.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Feature and roadmap&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphite.rs/features/&#34;&gt;See the web page for this information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support the project&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please consider pledging a monthly donation using the &#34;♥ Sponsor&#34; button to the right part of this project repository page. Your contribution helps sustain this volunteer-run open source project and brings powerful, free creative tools to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>