<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-02-13T01:37:34Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>n0-computer/sendme</title>
    <updated>2025-02-13T01:37:34Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-02-13:/n0-computer/sendme</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/n0-computer/sendme" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A tool to send files and directories, based on iroh&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Sendme&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an example application using &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/iroh&#34;&gt;iroh&lt;/a&gt; with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/iroh-blobs&#34;&gt;iroh-blobs&lt;/a&gt; protocol to send files and directories over the internet.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is also useful as a standalone tool for quick copy jobs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iroh will take care of hole punching and NAT traversal whenever possible, and fall back to a relay if hole punching does not succeed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iroh-blobs will take care of &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/blake3&#34;&gt;blake3&lt;/a&gt; verified streaming, including resuming interrupted downloads.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sendme works with 256 bit node ids and is, therefore, location transparent. A ticket will remain valid if the IP address changes. Connections are encrypted using TLS.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Installation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cargo install sendme&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Usage&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Send side&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sendme send &amp;lt;file or directory&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will create a temporary &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/iroh&#34;&gt;iroh&lt;/a&gt; node that serves the content in the given file or directory. It will output a ticket that can be used to get the data.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The provider will run until it is terminated using &lt;code&gt;Control-C&lt;/code&gt;. On termination, it will delete the temporary directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This currently will create a temporary directory in the current directory. In the future this won&#39;t be needed anymore.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Receive side&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sendme receive &amp;lt;ticket&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will download the data and create a file or directory named like the source in the &lt;strong&gt;current directory&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will create a temporary directory in the current directory, download the data (single file or directory), and only then move these files to the target directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On completion, it will delete the temp directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All temp directories start with &lt;code&gt;.sendme-&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>