<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-07-11T01:35:23Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>googleapis/google-cloud-rust</title>
    <updated>2025-07-11T01:35:23Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-11:/googleapis/google-cloud-rust</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud Platform Rust Client Libraries&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Google Cloud API Client Libraries for Rust&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/actions/workflows/sdk.yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/actions/workflows/sdk.yaml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;build status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://deps.rs/repo/github/googleapis/google-cloud-rust&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://deps.rs/repo/github/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/status.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;dependency status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Idiomatic Rust client libraries for &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt; services.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; this project is under development, all APIs are subject to change without notice. Some documentation is aspirational.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://googleapis.github.io/google-cloud-rust&#34;&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt; includes basic tutorials to get started with the Google Cloud client libraries for Rust.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Non-public API&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some crates export &#34;public&#34; types and functions that are intended only for use as implementation details of other crates in this repository. Chief amongst these are all the symbols exported by the &lt;code&gt;google-cloud-gax-internal&lt;/code&gt; crate. As the name indicates, this crate is intended to hold internal-only types. No application should take a direct dependency on this crate or use their types in their code. We reserve the right to make changes to this crate without notice.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In other crates, any public symbol that is not part of the public API have the &lt;code&gt;#[doc(hidden)]&lt;/code&gt; attribute set. This is conventional in Rust.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, we also use a number of crate features prefixed with &lt;code&gt;_internal-&lt;/code&gt;. None of these features (or the symbols they enable) are intended for application developers to use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Unstable APIs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rust does not have a stable API for asynchronous iterators (also known as asynchronous streams, or simply streams). Where needed, we provide implementations of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.rs/futures/latest/futures/stream/trait.Stream.html&#34;&gt;futures::stream::Stream&lt;/a&gt; trait.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For crates that offer implementations of the trait, the functionality is gated by the &lt;code&gt;unstable-streams&lt;/code&gt; feature. As the name indicates, this feature is unstable. When Rust stabilizes the streams trait, we may choose to rename the feature, and may even need to change the trait implementation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Minimum Supported Rust Version&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We require Rust &amp;gt;= 1.85, as we anticipate this will be at least six months old by the time this project is stabilized (GA may be even later).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, we have not defined a policy on how often we will update this minimum version. We do intend to publish our policy before declaring that the project is generally available.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to this library are always welcome and highly encouraged.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to get started. You may also find the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/main/doc/contributor/howto-guide-set-up-development-environment.md&#34;&gt;Set Up Development Environment&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/main/ARCHITECTURE.md&#34;&gt;Architecture&lt;/a&gt; guides useful.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apache 2.0 - See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/googleapis/google-cloud-rust/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>