<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Rust Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-10-19T01:34:56Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Rust in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/openvmm</title>
    <updated>2024-10-19T01:34:56Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-10-19:/microsoft/openvmm</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/openvmm" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Home of OpenVMM and OpenHCL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;OpenVMM&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/openvmm/actions/workflows/openvmm-ci.yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/openvmm/actions/workflows/openvmm-ci.yaml/badge.svg?branch=main&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenVMM is a modular, cross-platform Virtual Machine Monitor (VMM), written in Rust.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although it can function as a traditional VMM, OpenVMM&#39;s development is currently focused on its role in the OpenHCL paravisor.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repo is the home for both projects.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://openvmm.dev/&#34;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt; or our &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/windows-os-platform-blog/openhcl-the-new-open-source-paravisor/ba-p/4273172&#34;&gt;introductory blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For info on how to run, build, and use OpenVMM, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/openvmmguide&#34;&gt;The OpenVMM Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guide is published out of this repo via &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/microsoft/openvmm/main/Guide/src/SUMMARY.md&#34;&gt;Markdown files&lt;/a&gt;. Please keep them up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Trademarks&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project may contain trademarks or logos for projects, products, or services. Authorized use of Microsoft trademarks or logos is subject to and must follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/legal/intellectualproperty/trademarks/usage/general&#34;&gt;Microsoft&#39;s Trademark &amp;amp; Brand Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Use of Microsoft trademarks or logos in modified versions of this project must not cause confusion or imply Microsoft sponsorship. Any use of third-party trademarks or logos are subject to those third-party&#39;s policies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>