<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-03-31T01:52:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs</title>
    <updated>2024-03-31T01:52:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-03-31:/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repo is no longer accepting new issues. To request changes, create a branch, make changes, add @lindalu-MSFT as reviewer, then submit a PR. For more resources, see README.MD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;About VBA-docs repo&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We no longer have resources to respond to new issues. We welcome PRs that include documentation fixes, code samples, or improved comments. Please create a branch, make your changes, then open a PR to merge your change to master. We try to review new PRs monthly, but you can tag &lt;code&gt;@lindalu-MSFT&lt;/code&gt; in a comment for faster response!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get Office VBA support on Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a new forum on Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A for your VBA questions. To ask the developer community questions about your VBA code, go to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/answers/questions/topics/single/192523.html&#34;&gt;Microsoft Q&amp;amp;A office-vba-dev forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Join the Microsoft 365 Developer Program&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/m365devprogram&#34;&gt;Microsoft 365 Developer Program&lt;/a&gt; to get resources and information to help you build solutions for the Microsoft 365 platform, including recommendations tailored to your areas of interest.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might also qualify for a free developer subscription that&#39;s renewable for 90 days and comes configured with sample data; for details, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/office/developer-program/microsoft-365-developer-program-faq#who-qualifies-for-a-microsoft-365-e5-developer-subscription-&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The published articles for this repo are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/office/vba/api/overview/&#34;&gt;Office VBA Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information about how to contribute to this documentation, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/VBA-Docs/main/contributing.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>