<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-07-06T01:44:57Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>anthropics/claude-code</title>
    <updated>2025-07-06T01:44:57Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-07-06:/anthropics/claude-code</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Claude Code is an agentic coding tool that lives in your terminal, understands your codebase, and helps you code faster by executing routine tasks, explaining complex code, and handling git workflows - all through natural language commands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Claude Code&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/Node.js-18%2B-brightgreen?style=flat-square&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@anthropic-ai/claude-code&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/npm/v/@anthropic-ai/claude-code.svg?style=flat-square&#34; alt=&#34;npm&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Claude Code is an agentic coding tool that lives in your terminal, understands your codebase, and helps you code faster by executing routine tasks, explaining complex code, and handling git workflows -- all through natural language commands. Use it in your terminal, IDE, or tag @claude on Github.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn more in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.anthropic.com/en/docs/claude-code/overview&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/anthropics/claude-code/main/demo.gif&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install Claude Code:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34;&gt;npm install -g @anthropic-ai/claude-code&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Navigate to your project directory and run &lt;code&gt;claude&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Reporting Bugs&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We welcome your feedback. Use the &lt;code&gt;/bug&lt;/code&gt; command to report issues directly within Claude Code, or file a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anthropics/claude-code/issues&#34;&gt;GitHub issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Data collection, usage, and retention&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you use Claude Code, we collect feedback, which includes usage data (such as code acceptance or rejections), associated conversation data, and user feedback submitted via the &lt;code&gt;/bug&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How we use your data&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We may use feedback to improve our products and services, but we will not train generative models using your feedback from Claude Code. Given their potentially sensitive nature, we store user feedback transcripts for only 30 days.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you choose to send us feedback about Claude Code, such as transcripts of your usage, Anthropic may use that feedback to debug related issues and improve Claude Code&#39;s functionality (e.g., to reduce the risk of similar bugs occurring in the future).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Privacy safeguards&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have implemented several safeguards to protect your data, including limited retention periods for sensitive information, restricted access to user session data, and clear policies against using feedback for model training.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For full details, please review our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/legal/commercial-terms&#34;&gt;Commercial Terms of Service&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthropic.com/legal/privacy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>