<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-01-15T02:02:58Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T02:02:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-15:/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository is used for Windows client for IT Pro content on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn how to contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is interested can contribute to the topics. When you contribute, your work will go directly into the content set after being merged. It will then be published to &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Learn&lt;/a&gt; and you will be listed as a contributor at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-docs-pr/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-docs-pr/graphs/contributors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Quickly update an article using GitHub.com&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributors who only make infrequent or small updates can edit the file directly on GitHub.com without having to install any additional software. This article shows you how. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/videoplayer/embed/RE1XQTG&#34;&gt;This two-minute video&lt;/a&gt; also covers how to contribute.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Make sure you&#39;re signed in to GitHub.com with your GitHub account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Browse to the page you want to edit on Microsoft Learn.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the right-hand side of the page, click &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt; (pencil icon).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/quick-update-edit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Edit button on Microsoft Learn.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The corresponding topic file on GitHub opens, where you need to click the &lt;strong&gt;Edit this file&lt;/strong&gt; pencil icon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/quick-update-github.png&#34; alt=&#34;Edit button on github.com.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The topic opens in a line-numbered editing page where you can make changes to the file. Files in GitHub are written and edited using Markdown language. For help on using Markdown, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&#34;&gt;Mastering Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Select the &lt;strong&gt;Preview changes&lt;/strong&gt; tab to view your changes as you go.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re finished making changes, go to the &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; section at the bottom of the page:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;A brief title is required. By default, the title is the name of the file, but you can change it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Optionally, you can enter more details in the &lt;strong&gt;Add an optional extended description&lt;/strong&gt; box.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you&#39;re ready, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/propose-file-change.png&#34; alt=&#34;Propose file change section.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Comparing changes&lt;/strong&gt; page that appears, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Create pull request&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/comparing-changes-page.png&#34; alt=&#34;Comparing changes page.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;On the &lt;strong&gt;Open a pull request&lt;/strong&gt; page that appears, click the green &lt;strong&gt;Create pull request&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/compliance/media/open-a-pull-request-page.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open a pull request page.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!NOTE] Your permissions in the repo determine what you see in the last several steps. People with no special privileges will see the &lt;strong&gt;Propose file change&lt;/strong&gt; section and subsequent confirmation pages as described. People with permissions to create and approve their own pull requests will see a similar &lt;strong&gt;Commit changes&lt;/strong&gt; section with extra options for creating a new branch and fewer confirmation pages.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The point is: click any green buttons that are presented to you until there are no more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The writer identified in the metadata of the topic will be notified and will eventually review and approve your changes so the topic will be updated on Microsoft Learn. If there are questions or issues with the updates, the writer will contact you.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA-bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., label, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Legal Notices&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors grant you a license to the Microsoft documentation and other content in this repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs/public/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt; file, and grant you a license to any code in the repository under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-itpro-docs/public/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, Windows, Microsoft Azure and/or other Microsoft products and services referenced in the documentation may be either trademarks or registered trademarks of Microsoft in the United States and/or other countries.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The licenses for this project do not grant you rights to use any Microsoft names, logos, or trademarks. Microsoft&#39;s general trademark guidelines can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&#34;&gt;https://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=254653&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy information can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;https://privacy.microsoft.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and any contributors reserve all others rights, whether under their respective copyrights, patents, or trademarks, whether by implication, estoppel or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T02:02:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-15:/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cmdlets reference help docs for Powershell Azure AD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Microsoft AzureAD 2.0 PowerShell Module and AzureAD 2.0 Preview PowerShell Module Documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the open-source &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/azure&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/powershell/module/azuread/?view=azureadps-2.0&#34;&gt;Microsoft AzureAD 2.0 PowerShell Module&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/powershell/module/azuread/?view=azureadps-2.0-preview&#34;&gt;Microsoft AzureAD 2.0 Preview PowerShell Module&lt;/a&gt;. Please review this README file to understand how you can assist in contributing to the Microsoft Azure documentation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source is more than just providing updates, it&#39;s also about letting us know when there is an issue. Read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing guidance&lt;/a&gt; to find out more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;[!IMPORTANT] New pull requests &lt;strong&gt;MUST&lt;/strong&gt; always be created against the master branch which is the default branch in the main repository and not the live branch. PRs created against the live branch will not be accepted.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve decided to contribute, that&#39;s great! To contribute to the documentation, you need a few tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the documentation requires a GitHub account. If you don&#39;t have an account, follow the instructions for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/contribute/get-started-setup-github&#34;&gt;GitHub account setup&lt;/a&gt; from our contributor guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Download&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install the following tools:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/download&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/Download&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=docsmsft.docs-authoring-pack&#34;&gt;Docs Authoring Pack&lt;/a&gt; extension for Visual Studio Code&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Install&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions provided in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/contribute/get-started-setup-tools&#34;&gt;Install content authoring tools&lt;/a&gt; from our contributor guide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread/main/LICENSE&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread/main/LICENSE-CODE&#34;&gt;LICENSE-CODE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Azure/azure-docs-powershell-azuread/main/ThirdPartyNotices.md&#34;&gt;ThirdPartyNotices&lt;/a&gt; for all Licensing information.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Current State of Repo&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are currently aware of the backlog for this repo and are working to address this. Please be aware that if you have any updates to automatically generated reference content, you should create an issue and not a PR. The issue will then be created into a bug and triaged accordingly. We do this because the reference content must mirror the *dll-help.xml file and subsequent updates to the reference content may overwrite any changes made through the repo. Capturing it in the source code ensures that this does not occur. Any PR with changes to automatically generated reference content will be closed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automatically generated reference content is any of the content under this Reference node, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/powershell/module/AzureAD/Get-AzureADUser?view=azureadps-2.0&#34;&gt;Get-AzureADUser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This only applies to reference content and not conceptual content. Pull requests for changes to conceptual content are accepted and encouraged. An example of the conceptual content is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/powershell/azure/active-directory/overview?view=azureadps-2.0&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt; or a scenario such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/powershell/azure/active-directory/importing-data?view=azureadps-2.0&#34;&gt;importing data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit</title>
    <updated>2023-01-15T02:02:58Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-01-15:/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Project Homepage &amp; Forums&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit/master/AppDeployToolkitLogo.png&#34; alt=&#34;PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What is the PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit provides a set of functions to perform common application deployment tasks and to interact with the user during a deployment. It simplifies the complex scripting challenges of deploying applications in the enterprise, provides a consistent deployment experience and improves installation success rates.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit can be used to replace your WiseScript, VBScript and Batch wrapper scripts with one versatile, re-usable and extensible tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What are the main features of the PowerShell App Deployment Toolkit?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy To Use&lt;/strong&gt; - Any PowerShell beginner can use the template and the functions provided with the Toolkit to perform application deployments.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistent&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides a consistent look and feel for all application deployments, regardless of complexity.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerful&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides a set of functions to perform common deployment tasks, such as installing or uninstalling multiple applications, prompting users to close apps, setting registry keys, copying files, etc.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Interface&lt;/strong&gt; - Provides user interaction through customizable user interface dialogs boxes, progress dialogs and balloon tip notifications. Supports completely silent script execution as well.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Localized&lt;/strong&gt; - The UI is localized in several languages and more can easily be added using the XML configuration file.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration&lt;/strong&gt; - Integrates well with System Center Configuration Manager(SCCM); provides installation and uninstallation deployment types with options on how to handle exit codes, such as supressing reboots or returning a fast retry code. The toolkit also supports logging in CMTrace-compatible format.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Updatable&lt;/strong&gt; - The logic engine and functions are separated from per-application scripts, so that you can update the toolkit when a new version is released and maintain backwards compatibility with your deployment scripts.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensible&lt;/strong&gt; - The Toolkit can be easily extended to add custom scripts and functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helpful&lt;/strong&gt; - The Toolkit provides detailed logging of all actions performed and even includes a graphical console to browse the help documentation for the Toolkit functions.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;System Requirements&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Powershell 2.0+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;.NET Framework 3.5+&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com&#34;&gt;Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.psappdeploytoolkit.com/&#34;&gt;Community Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PSAppDeployToolkit/PSAppDeployToolkit/releases&#34;&gt;Releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com/screenshots/&#34;&gt;Screenshots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://psappdeploytoolkit.com/about/&#34;&gt;About Us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The PowerShell App Deployment Tool is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU Lesser General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>