<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-01-19T01:44:59Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>SpecterOps/BloodHound-Legacy</title>
    <updated>2025-01-19T01:44:59Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-01-19:/SpecterOps/BloodHound-Legacy</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/SpecterOps/BloodHound-Legacy" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Six Degrees of Domain Admin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Latest Version of BloodHound Community Edition is Released&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the latest version of BloodHound you may follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SpecterOps/BloodHound&#34;&gt;this link to the BloodHound Community Edition repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Deprecation Notice&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository will be archived in the near future.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound/actions/workflows/build.yml&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound/actions/workflows/build.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Build&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound/releases/latest&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub release (latest SemVer)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/downloads/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound/total&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub all releases&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Getting Started with BloodHound&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To get started with BloodHound, check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bloodhound.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html&#34;&gt;BloodHound docs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;About BloodHound&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodHound is a single page Javascript web application, built on top of &lt;a href=&#34;http://linkurio.us/&#34;&gt;Linkurious&lt;/a&gt;, compiled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://electron.atom.io/&#34;&gt;Electron&lt;/a&gt;, with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://neo4j.com/&#34;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt; database fed by a C# data collector.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodHound uses graph theory to reveal the hidden and often unintended relationships within an Active Directory or Azure environment. Attackers can use BloodHound to easily identify highly complex attack paths that would otherwise be impossible to quickly identify. Defenders can use BloodHound to identify and eliminate those same attack paths. Both blue and red teams can use BloodHound to easily gain a deeper understanding of privilege relationships in an Active Directory or Azure environment.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodHound was created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/_wald0&#34;&gt;@_wald0&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CptJesus&#34;&gt;@CptJesus&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/harmj0y&#34;&gt;@harmj0y&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodHound is maintained by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bloodhoundenterprise.io/&#34;&gt;BloodHound Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;About BloodHound Enterprise&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bloodhoundenterprise.io/&#34;&gt;BloodHound Enterprise&lt;/a&gt; is an Attack Path Management solution that continuously maps and quantifies Active Directory Attack Paths. You can remove millions, even billions of Attack Paths within your existing architecture and eliminate the attacker’s easiest, most reliable, and most attractive techniques.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Downloading BloodHound Binaries&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pre-Compiled BloodHound binaries can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound/releases&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The rolling release will always be updated to the most recent source. Tagged releases are considered &#34;stable&#34; but will likely not have new features or fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Creating example data&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A sample database generator can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/BloodHoundAD/BloodHound-Tools/tree/master/DBCreator&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can create your own example Active Directory environment using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davidprowe/BadBlood&#34;&gt;BadBlood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;License&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodHound uses graph theory to reveal hidden relationships and attack paths in an Active Directory environment. Copyright (C) 2016-2023 Specter Ops Inc.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>