<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-17T02:21:02Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>mgeeky/Penetration-Testing-Tools</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:21:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/mgeeky/Penetration-Testing-Tools</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/mgeeky/Penetration-Testing-Tools" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A collection of more than 170+ tools, scripts, cheatsheets and other loots that I have developed over years for Red Teaming/Pentesting/IT Security audits purposes. Most of them came handy on at least one of my real-world engagements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;A collection of my Penetration Testing Tools, Scripts, Cheatsheets&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of more than a &lt;strong&gt;160+&lt;/strong&gt; tools, scripts, cheatsheets and other loots that I&#39;ve been developing over years for Penetration Testing and IT Security audits purposes. Most of them came handy at least once during my real-world engagements.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; In order to clone this repository properly - use &lt;code&gt;--recurse-submodules&lt;/code&gt; switch:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recurse https://github.com/mgeeky/Penetration-Testing-Tools.git&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of these files were initially shared on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/mgeeky&#34;&gt;Gists&lt;/a&gt; but eventually got moved into this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every time I stumbled upon a problem that could be better scripted or resolved programatically - I made effort to do just that and thus improve my technical assurance capabilities or to optimize time spent on repetitive actions during projects I&#39;ve been delivering.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The collection is divided further onto following sections:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;clouds&lt;/code&gt; - Tools I came up with during my cloud assessments&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;file-formats&lt;/code&gt; - file-format related utilities, fuzzers and alike.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;linux&lt;/code&gt; - small bunch of Linux-based scripts and tools.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;networks&lt;/code&gt; - Network devices &amp;amp; protocols Penetration Testing toolery&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;others&lt;/code&gt; - Others related somehow to this craftmanship&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;phishing&lt;/code&gt; - Scripts and tools used to deliver Phishing Awareness and Red Team simulations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;red-teaming&lt;/code&gt; - Lots of toolings I&#39;ve been using during my Purple/Red-Teaming engagements&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;web&lt;/code&gt; - Web applications security assessment related utilities.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;windows&lt;/code&gt; - Windows goodies, scripts, exploits.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The base of these tools do not contain any customer/client related sensitive information as well as there are no engagement-specific tools developed as PoCs.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;☕ Show Support ☕&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This and other projects are outcome of sleepless nights and &lt;strong&gt;plenty of hard work&lt;/strong&gt;. If you like what I do and appreciate that I always give back to the community, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sponsors/mgeeky&#34;&gt;Consider buying me a coffee&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(or better a beer)&lt;/em&gt; just to say thank you! 💪&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mariusz Banach / mgeeky, (@mariuszbit)&#xA;&amp;lt;mb [at] binary-offensive.com&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:21:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Collection of Scripts Which Disable / Remove Windows 10 Features and Apps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Debloat Windows 10&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note about Windows 11:&lt;/strong&gt; This project does not directly support Windows 11. Things might work, or might not work - find out if you are brave. Do not expect this project to transition to Windows 11 as the maintainer lacks the time to do so.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project collects PowerShell scripts which help to &lt;em&gt;debloat&lt;/em&gt; Windows 10, tweak common settings and install basic software components.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I test these scripts on a Windows 10 Professional 64-Bit (English) virtual machine. Please let me know if you encounter any issues. Home Edition and different languages are not supported. These scripts are intended for tech-savvy administrators, who know what they are doing and just want to automate this phase of their setup. If this profile does not fit you, I recommend using a different (more interactive) tool -- and there are a lot of them out there.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, note that gaming-related apps and services will be removed/disabled. If you intend to use your system for gaming, adjust the scripts accordingly.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no undo&lt;/strong&gt;, I recommend only using these scripts on a fresh installation (including Windows Updates). Test everything after running them before doing anything else. Also, there is no guarantee that everything will work after future updates since I cannot predict what Microsoft will do next.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Translations&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MagicLike/Debloat-Windows-10/raw/master/README.de-de.md&#34;&gt;Fork with German version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Interactivity&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scripts are designed to run without any user interaction. Modify them beforehand. If you want a more interactive approach check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/10se1ucgo/DisableWinTracking&#34;&gt;DisableWinTracking&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/10se1ucgo&#34;&gt;10se1ucgo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Download Latest Version&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Code located in the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch is always considered under development, but you&#39;ll probably want the most recent version anyway.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10/archive/master.zip&#34;&gt;Download [zip]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Execution&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enable execution of PowerShell scripts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS&amp;gt; Set-ExecutionPolicy Unrestricted -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unblock PowerShell scripts and modules within this directory:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS&amp;gt; ls -Recurse *.ps*1 | Unblock-File&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripts can be run individually, pick what you need.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install all available updates for your system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Edit the scripts to fit your need.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the scripts you want to apply from a PowerShell with administrator privileges (Explorer &lt;code&gt;Files &amp;gt; Open Windows PowerShell &amp;gt; Open Windows PowerShell as administrator&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS &amp;gt; Restart-Computer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;disable-windows-defender.ps1&lt;/code&gt; one more time if you ran it in step 3&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;PS &amp;gt; Restart-Computer&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Start menu&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the past I included small fixes to make the start menu more usable, like removing default tiles, disabling web search and so on. This is no longer the case since I am fed up with it. This fucking menu breaks for apparently no reason, is slow, is a pain to configure / script and even shows ads out of the box!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please replace it with something better, either use &lt;a href=&#34;https://open-shell.github.io/Open-Shell-Menu/&#34;&gt;Open Shell&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://startisback.com/&#34;&gt;Start is Back&lt;/a&gt;, but stop using that shit.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Start menu Search&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After running the scripts, the start menu search-box may no longer work on newly created accounts. It seems like there is an issue with account initialization that is triggered when disabling the GeoLocation service. Following workaround has been discovered by BK from Atlanta:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Delete registry key &lt;code&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Services\lfsvc\TriggerInfo\3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Re-enable GeoLocation service (set startup type to &lt;code&gt;Automatic&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Reboot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Login with the account having the stated issue&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start Cortana and set your preferences accordingly (web search and whatnot)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You may now disable the GeoLocation service again, the search box should remain functional.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Sysprep will hang&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are deploying images with MDT and running these scripts, the sysprep step will hang unless &lt;code&gt;dmwappushservice&lt;/code&gt; is active.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Xbox Wireless Adapter&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apparently running the stock &lt;code&gt;remove-default-apps&lt;/code&gt; script will cause Xbox Wireless Adapters to stop functioning. I suspect one should not remove the Xbox App when wanting to use one. But I haven&#39;t confirmed this yet, and there is a workaround to re-enable it afterwards. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10/issues/78&#34;&gt;#78&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Issues with Skype&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some of the domains blocked by adding them to the hosts-file are required for Skype. I highly discourage using Skype, however some people may not have the option to use an alternative. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10/issues/79&#34;&gt;#79&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Fingerprint Reader / Facial Detection not Working&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ensure &lt;em&gt;Windows Biometric Service&lt;/em&gt; is running. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/W4RH4WK/Debloat-Windows-10/issues/189&#34;&gt;#189&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Liability&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All scripts are provided as-is and you use them at your own risk.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would be happy to extend the collection of scripts. Just open an issue or send me a pull request.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Thanks To&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/10se1ucgo&#34;&gt;10se1ucgo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Plumebit&#34;&gt;Plumebit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aramboi&#34;&gt;aramboi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maci0&#34;&gt;maci0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/narutards&#34;&gt;narutards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tumpio&#34;&gt;tumpio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#34;THE BEER-WARE LICENSE&#34; (Revision 42):&#xA;&#xA;As long as you retain this notice you can do whatever you want with this&#xA;stuff. If we meet someday, and you think this stuff is worth it, you can&#xA;buy us a beer in return.&#xA;&#xA;This project is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT&#xA;ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or&#xA;FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>tihanyin/PSSW100AVB</title>
    <updated>2022-07-17T02:21:02Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-17:/tihanyin/PSSW100AVB</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tihanyin/PSSW100AVB" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A list of useful Powershell scripts with 100% AV bypass (At the time of publication).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PSSW100AVB&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the PSSW100AVB (Powershell Scripts With 100% AV Bypass) Framework.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A list of useful Powershell scripts with 100% AV bypass ratio. (At the time of publication).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Latest Reverse shell tested on Windows 11 (ReverseShell_2022_06.ps1):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/62064939/174448685-d6beddd0-cdc3-4d8d-a2da-7b88882d2e7e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lsass Dump tested on Windows 11 (LsassDump_2022_03.ps1):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img width=&#34;1601&#34; alt=&#34;LSASS&#34; src=&#34;https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/62064939/160251464-8c4d64fe-1095-48f9-96aa-ef9b747d4ff0.png&#34;&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>