<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-04-30T02:03:52Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T02:03:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-30:/rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/rgalloni/Auto-GPT-sandbox-wizard" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;AutoGPT-easy-install is a bash/powershell script designed for non-experts to easily install and run the AutoGPT application in a Docker container. The script checks if Docker is installed and installs it if necessary. It prompts the user for API keys, workspace folder path, and whether to run AutoGPT in continuous mode&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Auto-GPT Sandbox Wizard - Easy Installer&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This script allows you to easily install and run the Auto-GPT application inside a Docker container. Running the application inside a Docker container provides a secure sandboxed environment, preventing any potential harm to your computer from continuous mode malfunctions. However, please note that you still need to supervise the application when running in continuous mode to avoid any unintended damage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;UPDATE 22/04/2023&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following updates have been made:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Now it works with the official Dockerfile, ensuring future-proof implementations.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;It will keep your Auto-GPT updated with the latest release, if requested.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Additionally, user interactions and information requests have been improved throughout the script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Automatically installs Docker if not already installed&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prompts for API keys and workspace folder path&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Clones the Auto-GPT repository and configures the environment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Builds and runs the application inside a Docker container&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order to use the Auto-GPT Easy Installer, you will need an API key for OpenAI. You can obtain an OpenAI API key by following the instructions provided here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys&#34;&gt;https://platform.openai.com/account/api-keys&lt;/a&gt;. You may need to edit your .env file to enable more features.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you register for OpenAI, you will receive $18 in API credits, which provides ample room for testing and experimenting without incurring any costs. Simply follow the steps in the provided script to set up and run the Auto-GPT application inside a Docker container, ensuring a secure environment for your project.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation and Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unix/Mac&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;code&gt;auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a terminal and navigate to the directory where the script is located.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Make the script executable: &lt;code&gt;chmod +x auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the script: &lt;code&gt;./auto_gpt_easy_install.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Windows (currently untested)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the &lt;code&gt;auto_gpt_easy_install.ps1&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Open a PowerShell and navigate to the directory where the script is located.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the script: &lt;code&gt;.\auto_gpt_easy_install.ps1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;For Users Without Git&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do not have Git installed on your system, the script will attempt to install it using a suitable package manager. If this is not possible, you will need to install Git manually before running the script.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you encounter issues with Docker installation or permissions, please refer to the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/get-docker/&#34;&gt;Docker documentation&lt;/a&gt; for guidance.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you have trouble installing Git, visit the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Getting-Started-Installing-Git&#34;&gt;Git documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more information on installing Git on your system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If you need further assistance, consider opening an issue on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Significant-Gravitas/Auto-GPT&#34;&gt;Auto-GPT GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Auto-GPT application is designed to be run inside a Docker container for added security. However, you can still run the application outside the container if you prefer. Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Significant-Gravitas/Auto-GPT&#34;&gt;Auto-GPT GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for more information on how to set up and run the application manually.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Remember to supervise the application when running in continuous mode to avoid any unintended damage.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The speech mode is not currently supported when running inside the Docker container.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T02:03:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-30:/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Auto-GPT PowerShell project, it is for windows, and is now designed to use offline, and online GPTs. This project uses a plugin system, and with this I created a GPT3.5+ plugin, that will automatically ask the GPT something, and it will make &#34;&lt;DALLE dest=&#39;filename&#39;&gt;&#34; tags, then on response, will download these tags with DallE2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;AutoGPT_PS 😄&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AutoGPT_PS is a PowerShell script that runs Local/Online GPT (LM) programs, in a automatic fashion. The main goal is to ask the user&#39;s prompt, and keep feeding the idea to the AI (in a loop) and see what happens. The plugin System allows changing the Prompt from the &#34;Start&#34;, then on every Loop a plugin &#34;System&#34; (to change the &#34;System Prompt&#34;) and &#34;Input&#34; (to change the &#34;Prompt&#34;) then ask the GPT, then a plugin for &#34;Output&#34;, then Loops back to &#34;System&#34;. The plugins are made to pass the prompt from one to the others in the sections (&#34;Start&#34;, &#34;System&#34;, &#34;Input&#34;, and &#34;Output&#34;) plugin list is based of a &#34;Order&#34; property.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Updates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everything from here down is old.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage 🚀&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the AutoGPT_PS repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Place the GPT-4 model file in the same directory as the AutoGPT.ps1 script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run the AutoGPT.ps1 script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; to go to the Options.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enter the Starting Prompt (If using OpenAI GPT 3.5 or higher, then you will also be asked for a System Prompt.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;The Main Loop will run; if you have set the Loop Count to Infinite, press Ctrl-C to cancel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once completed, there will be a time-stamped &#34;session_[time]&#34; folder in the &#34;sessions&#34; folder, containing &#34;session_[time].txt&#34; file with the prompts and responses passed back and forth. If &#34;Output Session Log Plugin&#34; is enabled.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;How to get the GPT4ALL model! 💾&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;code&gt;gpt4all-lora-quantized.bin&lt;/code&gt; file from &lt;a href=&#34;https://the-eye.eu/public/AI/models/nomic-ai/gpt4all/gpt4all-lora-quantized.bin&#34;&gt;Direct Link&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyurl.com/gpt4all-lora-quantized&#34;&gt;[Torrent-Magnet]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Workflow 🔄&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start the script.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask if you want to change the options (if yes, then change options then return here, if no continue on).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask for your &#34;Start Prompt&#34; - what to first ask the GPT, then &#34;Start System&#34; (if using OpenAI ChatGPT).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Call the plugins for the &#34;Start&#34; (this is only called once) to change the prompt.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create the &#34;Main&#34; loop.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In the &#34;Main Loop&#34;, run the &#34;System&#34; plugins against the &#34;Start System&#34;, then run the plugins for &#34;Input&#34; on the prompt.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Send the prompt and the System to the GPT.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;When a response is received, run the &#34;Output&#34; plugins on the response.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Once the response has been processed, save the response to the prompt and loop back to &#34;Main&#34;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Options ⚙️&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Model&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows selection of a .bin file to use for GPT4All. Example: &lt;code&gt;gpt4all-lora-quantized.bin&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toggle Pause&lt;/strong&gt;: Enables or disables pausing after every iteration of the main loop. Default value: &lt;code&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; (pause).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Seed&lt;/strong&gt;: Sets the seed value for GPT4All. Default value: `` (use the first generated seed) (&#39;0&#39; will use a random seed every time).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Loop Count&lt;/strong&gt;: Sets the number of loops for the main loop. Default value: &lt;code&gt;10&lt;/code&gt; (ten loops).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toggle Use ChatGPT&lt;/strong&gt;: Enables or disables the use of the OpenAI Chat API. Default value: &lt;code&gt;False&lt;/code&gt; (disabled).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set OpenAI Key&lt;/strong&gt;: Sets the OpenAI API key.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI Models&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows selection of an OpenAI model from the available options: &lt;code&gt;text-davinci-003&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gpt-3.5-turbo&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gpt-4&lt;/code&gt;. Default value: &lt;code&gt;text-davinci-003&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow GPT in plugins&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows plugins to use the settings for OpenAI. Default value: &lt;code&gt;False&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn On Debug&lt;/strong&gt;: Enables or disables debug messages at most steps of the scripts. Default value: &lt;code&gt;False&lt;/code&gt; (disabled).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin Settings&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows you to Enable and change settings of Plugins.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To update these options, select &#34;y&#34; when it prompts &#34;Do you want to check options? (y)es/(n)o:&#34; at the start.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Default Plugins 🔌&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plugin system is based on separate modules for different types of plugins:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;RunStartPlugins.ps1: Searches for and runs start plugins in the &#34;plugins&#34; folder. Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;plugins/Start_Sample.ps1: A sample start plugin that leaves the start message unchanged&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;RunInputPlugins.ps1: Searches for and runs input plugins in the &#34;plugins&#34; folder. Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;plugins/Input_Sample.ps1: A sample input plugin that leaves the prompt unchanged&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;RunSystemPlugins.ps1: Searches for and runs system plugins in the &#34;plugins&#34; folder. Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;plugins/System_Sample.ps1: A sample system plugin that leaves the system message unchanged&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;RunOutputPlugins.ps1: Searches for and runs output plugins in the &#34;plugins&#34; folder. Example:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;plugins/Output_CodeSaver.ps1: Strips code out into &#34;source_[time].txt&#34; unless &#34;Allow GPT in plugins&#34; is enabled, then it will try to use ChatGPT to get the filename. (This will save multiple files, as some seem to get overy written with bad data.)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;plugins/Output_SessionLog.ps1: A sample output plugin that logs the output to a session file&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Creating Plugins 🛠️&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AutoGPT_PS includes a plugin system that allows for easy customization of input processing, output formatting, and more. There are four types of plugins:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;System plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Input plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Output plugins&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the base setup of each plugin type, see the scripts provided in the &#34;plugins&#34; folder.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;To Do 📝&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Improve error handling and user feedback.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Add more plugin examples to showcase the versatility of the plugin system.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enhance the plugin system by allowing for more customization options.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create a user-friendly interface for managing plugin configuration.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Streamline the process of adding new plugins and managing existing ones.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Keep the project up-to-date with the latest GPT-4 model improvements and enhancements.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute 🤝&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you would like to Contribute, and join the project, please see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell/discussions/10&#34;&gt;https://github.com/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell/discussions/10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to Donate Money check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell/discussions/11&#34;&gt;https://github.com/TheCompAce/Auto-GPT-Powershell/discussions/11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Credits 🏆&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&#34;gpt4all-lora-quantized-win64.exe&#34; is used from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nomic-ai/gpt4all&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nomic-ai/gpt4all&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ChatGPT 4.0 it has written about 60% of this code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/windows-powershell-docs</title>
    <updated>2023-04-30T02:03:52Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-04-30:/MicrosoftDocs/windows-powershell-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-powershell-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repo is used to contribute to Windows 10, Windows Server 2016, and MDOP PowerShell module documentation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Windows IT professional documentation&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository houses the Windows client, Windows Server, and MDOP PowerShell module docs that are written for IT professionals.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edits to this content are published in the following places:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Various versions of &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/powershell/windows/get-started&#34;&gt;Windows client and Windows Server&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/powershell/mdop/get-started&#34;&gt;Microsoft Desktop Optimization Pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;PowerShell Updatable Help (CabGen) CI Build Status&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apidrop.visualstudio.com/Content%20CI/_build/latest?definitionId=5077&amp;amp;repoName=MicrosoftDocs%2Fwindows-powershell-docs&amp;amp;branchName=live&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://apidrop.visualstudio.com/Content%20CI/_apis/build/status/PROD/CabGen(PowerShell_Updatable_Help)/GitHub_MicrosoftDocs_windows-powershell-docs/46a32786-a1f6-1250-e1e1-2a4554025dc9_cabgen_Publish-Updatable-Help?repoName=MicrosoftDocs%2Fwindows-powershell-docs&amp;amp;branchName=live&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We actively merge contributions into this repository via &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/using-pull-requests/&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; into the &lt;em&gt;main&lt;/em&gt; branch. If you are not a Microsoft employee, before you submit a pull request you must sign a &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Contribution License Agreement&lt;/a&gt; to ensure that the community is free to use your submissions. For more information on contributing, read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MicrosoftDocs/windows-powershell-docs/main/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;contributions guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;!-- link references --&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>