<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoftgraph/powershell-intune-samples</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/microsoftgraph/powershell-intune-samples</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoftgraph/powershell-intune-samples" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This repository of PowerShell sample scripts show how to access Intune service resources. They demonstrate this by making HTTPS RESTful API requests to the Microsoft Graph API from PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;page_type: sample products:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ms-graph languages:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;powershell extensions: contentType: samples technologies: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Graph services:&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Intune createdDate: 4/4/2017 9:41:27 AM noDependencies: true&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Intune Graph Samples&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository of PowerShell sample scripts show how to access Intune service resources. They demonstrate this by making HTTPS RESTful API requests to the Microsoft Graph API from PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documentation for Intune and Microsoft Graph can be found here &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/api/resources/intune-graph-overview?view=graph-rest-1.0&#34;&gt;Intune Graph Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;These samples demonstrate typical Intune administrator or Microsoft partner actions for managing Intune resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following samples are included in this repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AdminConsent&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AndroidEnterprise&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AppleEnrollment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Applications&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ApplicationSync&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;AppProtectionPolicy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Auditing&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Authentication&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CertificationAuthority&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CheckStatus&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CompanyPortalBranding&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CompliancePolicy&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;CorporateDeviceEnrollment&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;DeviceConfiguration&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;EnrollmentRestrictions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;IntuneDataExport&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;LOB_Application&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ManagedDevices&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Paging&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RBAC&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;RemoteActionAudit&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;SoftwareUpdates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;TermsAndConditions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;UserPolicyReport&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scripts are licensed &#34;as-is.&#34; under the MIT License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some script samples retrieve information from your Intune tenant, and others create, delete or update data in your Intune tenant.&amp;nbsp; Understand the impact of each sample script prior to running it; samples should be run using a non-production or &#34;test&#34; tenant account.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using the Intune Graph API&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Intune Graph API enables access to Intune information programmatically for your tenant, and the API performs the same Intune operations as those available through the Azure Portal.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Intune provides data into the Microsoft Graph in the same way as other cloud services do, with rich entity information and relationship navigation.&amp;nbsp; Use Microsoft Graph to combine information from other services and Intune to build rich cross-service applications for IT professionals or end users.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use of these Microsoft Graph API Intune PowerShell samples requires the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install the AzureAD PowerShell module by running &#39;Install-Module AzureAD&#39; or &#39;Install-Module AzureADPreview&#39; from an elevated PowerShell prompt&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An Intune tenant which supports the Azure Portal with a production or trial license (&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/intune-azure/introduction/what-is-microsoft-intune&#34;&gt;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/intune-azure/introduction/what-is-microsoft-intune&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Using the Microsoft Graph APIs to configure Intune controls and policies requires an Intune license.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;An account with permissions to administer the Intune Service&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;PowerShell v5.0 on Windows 10 x64 (PowerShell v4.0 is a minimum requirement for the scripts to function correctly)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Note: For PowerShell 4.0 you will require the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=51451&#34;&gt;PowershellGet Module for PS 4.0&lt;/a&gt; to enable the usage of the Install-Module functionality&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;First time usage of these scripts requires a Global Administrator of the Tenant to accept the permissions of the application&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the prerequisites are installed or met, perform the following steps to use these scripts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;1. Script usage&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download the contents of the repository to your local Windows machine&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Extract the files to a local folder (e.g. C:\IntuneGraphSamples)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run PowerShell x64 from the start menu&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Browse to the directory (e.g. cd C:\IntuneGraphSamples)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For each Folder in the local repository you can browse to that directory and then run the script of your choice&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Example Application script usage: &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;To use the Manage Applications scripts, from C:\IntuneGraphSamples, run &#34;cd .\Applications&#34;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Once in the folder run .\Application_MDM_Get.ps1 to get all MDM added applications This sequence of steps can be used for each folder....&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;2. Authentication with Microsoft Graph&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first time you run these scripts you will be asked to provide an account to authenticate with the service:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Please specify your user principal name for Azure Authentication:&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have provided a user principal name a popup will open prompting for your password. After a successful authentication with Azure Active Directory the user token will last for an hour, once the hour expires within the PowerShell session you will be asked to re-authenticate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are running the script for the first time against your tenant a popup will be presented stating:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Microsoft Intune PowerShell needs permission to:&#xA;&#xA;* Sign you in and read your profile&#xA;* Read all groups&#xA;* Read directory data&#xA;* Read and write Microsoft Intune Device Configuration and Policies (preview)&#xA;* Read and write Microsoft Intune RBAC settings (preview)&#xA;* Perform user-impacting remote actions on Microsoft Intune devices (preview)&#xA;* Sign in as you&#xA;* Read and write Microsoft Intune devices (preview)&#xA;* Read and write all groups&#xA;* Read and write Microsoft Intune configuration (preview)&#xA;* Read and write Microsoft Intune apps (preview)&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: If your user account is targeted for device based conditional access your device must be enrolled or compliant to pass authentication.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to contribute to this sample, see CONTRIBUTING.MD.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct. For more information see the Code of Conduct FAQ or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Questions and comments&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d love to get your feedback about the Intune PowerShell sample. You can send your questions and suggestions to us in the Issues section of this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Your feedback is important to us. Connect with us on Stack Overflow. Tag your questions with [MicrosoftGraph] and [intune].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Additional resources&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/docs&#34;&gt;Microsoft Graph API documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/graph-explorer&#34;&gt;Microsoft Graph Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/code-samples-and-sdks&#34;&gt;Microsoft code samples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/graph/api/resources/intune-graph-overview?view=graph-rest-1.0&#34;&gt;Intune Graph Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Copyright&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2017 Microsoft. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>petripaavola/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/petripaavola/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/petripaavola/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Intune Device Details GUI&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Intune Device Details GUI ver. 2.95 (updated 17.5.2022)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to script &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/petripaavola/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI/main/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1&#34;&gt;IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version 2.95 is a huge update to the script&#39;s functionalities. Built-in search helps using this tool a lot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Powershell based GUI/report helps Intune admins to see Intune device data in one view&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Especially it shows what &lt;strong&gt;Azure AD Groups and Intune filters&lt;/strong&gt; are used in Application and Configuration Assignments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assignment group information helps admins to understand why apps and configurations are targeted to devices and find possible bad assignments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;GUI view&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/petripaavola/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI/raw/main/pics/IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI_v2.95.gif&#34; alt=&#34;IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI_v2.95.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Features&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search&lt;/strong&gt; with free keyword or use built-in Quick Filters &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Keyword search with device name, serial, user email address, operating system, deviceId&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;searching with user email address also shows devices where user has logged-in (this is not shown in MEM/Intune search)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show Application Assignments with AzureAD Groups and Filters information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Show Configurations Assignments with AzureAD Groups and Filters information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Highlight assignment states with colors to easily see what is happening &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For example highlight Not Applicable application assignment with yellow and usually you notice that Filter is reason for Not Applicable state&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show Recently logged in user(s)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show OS Version support dates&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show Device Group Memberships and membership rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show Primary User Group Memberships and membership rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show Latest Signed-In User Group Memberships and membership rules&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Intune JSON information on right side (this helps to understand what data there is inside Intune)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hover on&lt;/strong&gt; to get ToolTip on Device, PrimaryUser, Latest logged-in user, Group, Application, Configuration, AssignmentGroup, Filter and many other places to get more information &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;There is lot of work done to get these (hover) ToolTips to show relevant information in easily readable format&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right click menus&lt;/strong&gt; to &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Copy data to clipboard&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Copy Dynamic Azure AD Group Membership rules to clipboard&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Open specific resource in MEM/Intune web UI (device, autopilot device, user, group, application)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Copy Win32 Application custom detection and requirement scripts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Script uses caching a lot. All used data is automatically downloaded once a day and during the day delta checks are done to Intune data &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Idea is to use cached data but still every time double check that there are no changes in Intune&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This saves Graph API bandwidth but still makes sure that data relevant (real time)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Show Autopilot information &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Applied Autopilot deployment profile&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Applied Enrollment Status Page&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Applied Enrollment Restrictions&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Autopilot Deployment Profile JSON&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Autopilot device JSON&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Support for Shared devices &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Search with user email address and get devices where user has logged in&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Latest logged in user information ToolTip (hover on)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Latest logged in user Azure AD Group memberships (and membeship rules)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Application and Configuration assignment are checked against latest logged in user&#39;s group memberships (if there is no PrimaryUser in device)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;make sure you have installed Intune Powershell module and allow running Powershell scripts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Install Intune Powershell module&#xA;Install-Module -Name Microsoft.Graph.Intune -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&#xA;# Allow running Powershell scripts&#xA;&#xA;# This allows running all signed scripts for current user&#xA;# This shows warning if script is not signed&#xA;Set-ExecutionPolicy -ExecutionPolicy RemoteSigned -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&#xA;# This allows running all scripts for current user&#xA;Set-ExecutionPolicy -ExecutionPolicy Bypass -Scope CurrentUser&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Running the script&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1&#xA;.\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1 -Verbose&#xA;&#xA;.\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1 -Id 2e6e1d5f-b18a-44c6-989e-9bbb1efafbff&#xA;.\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1 -IntuneDeviceId 2e6e1d5f-b18a-44c6-989e-9bbb1efafbff&#xA;&#xA;# Pipe Intune objects to script&#xA;Get-IntuneManagedDevice -Filter &#34;devicename eq &#39;MyLoveMostPC&#39;&#34; | .\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1&#xA;&#xA;# Or create Device Management UI with Out-GridView&#xA;# Show devices in Out-GridView and for selected device show IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI&#xA;Get-IntuneManagedDevice | Out-GridView -OutputMode Single | .\IntuneDeviceDetailsGUI.ps1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Intune user permissions needed to run this script&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Script uses user login so login with user who has at least &lt;strong&gt;read permissions&lt;/strong&gt; to Intune and permissions to use Intune Powershell module&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Script does only GET operations and 2 POST operations (to get Intune report) so at this time this is read only tool&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For most restrictive permissions this script has been tested even with &lt;strong&gt;Intune Read Only Operators role&lt;/strong&gt; and script works with that role also&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Future possible plans&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Never ever create Powershell UIs without using syncHash and multiple threads &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;This script was originally part of multithreaded tool so syncHash was not used inside this script and threading was done outside this script&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Now this tool is self containing so in the next major version update syncHash and threading needs to be implemented to create responsive UI&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Integrate my other Application and Configuration Assignment reports into this toolset&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Create other views to show information about users, Azure AD Groups, Applications and Configurations&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Any other feature requests ?-)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This tool is provided &#34;AS IS&#34; without any warranties so please evaluate it in test environment before production use. It is provided as Powershell script so there is no closed code and you can evaluate everything it does. Trust is important when using Administrative user rights and tools in your production environment. I use this tool daily in production environments I manage myself.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ScoopInstaller/Scoop</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/ScoopInstaller/Scoop</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A command-line installer for Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;!--&lt;img src=&#34;scoop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Long live Scoop!&#34;/&gt;--&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Scoop&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop#what-does-scoop-do&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; | &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop#installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; | &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/wiki&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/languages/code-size/ScoopInstaller/Scoop.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Code Size&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/repo-size/ScoopInstaller/Scoop.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Repository size&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/actions/workflows/ci.yml&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/actions/workflows/ci.yml/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Scoop Core CI Tests&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/s9yRQHt&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/chat-on%20discord-7289DA.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Discord Chat&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/lukesampson/scoop&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.gitter.im/lukesampson/scoop.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gitter Chat&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/raw/master/LICENSE&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/ScoopInstaller/Scoop.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scoop is a command-line installer for Windows.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What does Scoop do?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scoop installs programs from the command line with a minimal amount of friction. It:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Eliminates permission popup windows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Hides GUI wizard-style installers&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Prevents PATH pollution from installing lots of programs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Avoids unexpected side-effects from installing and uninstalling programs&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Finds and installs dependencies automatically&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Performs all the extra setup steps itself to get a working program&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scoop is very scriptable, so you can run repeatable setups to get your environment just the way you like, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;scoop install sudo&#xA;sudo scoop install 7zip git openssh --global&#xA;scoop install aria2 curl grep sed less touch&#xA;scoop install python ruby go perl&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve built software that you&#39;d like others to use, Scoop is an alternative to building an installer (e.g. MSI or InnoSetup) — you just need to zip your program and provide a JSON manifest that describes how to install it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run the following command from a &lt;strong&gt;non-admin&lt;/strong&gt; PowerShell to install scoop to its default location &lt;code&gt;C:\Users\&amp;lt;YOUR USERNAME&amp;gt;\scoop&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;iwr -useb get.scoop.sh | iex&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Advanced installation instruction and full documentation of the installer are available in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Install&#34;&gt;ScoopInstaller/Install&lt;/a&gt;. Please create new issues there if you have questions about the installation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/wiki&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Multi-connection downloads with &lt;code&gt;aria2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scoop can utilize &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aria2/aria2&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;aria2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to use multi-connection downloads. Simply install &lt;code&gt;aria2&lt;/code&gt; through Scoop and it will be used for all downloads afterward.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-powershell&#34;&gt;scoop install aria2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, &lt;code&gt;scoop&lt;/code&gt; displays a warning when running &lt;code&gt;scoop install&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;scoop update&lt;/code&gt; while &lt;code&gt;aria2&lt;/code&gt; is enabled. This warning can be suppressed by running &lt;code&gt;scoop config aria2-warning-enabled false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can tweak the following &lt;code&gt;aria2&lt;/code&gt; settings with the &lt;code&gt;scoop config&lt;/code&gt; command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;aria2-enabled (default: true)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;aria2-warning-enabled (default: true)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aria2.github.io/manual/en/html/aria2c.html#cmdoption-retry-wait&#34;&gt;aria2-retry-wait&lt;/a&gt; (default: 2)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aria2.github.io/manual/en/html/aria2c.html#cmdoption-s&#34;&gt;aria2-split&lt;/a&gt; (default: 5)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aria2.github.io/manual/en/html/aria2c.html#cmdoption-x&#34;&gt;aria2-max-connection-per-server&lt;/a&gt; (default: 5)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aria2.github.io/manual/en/html/aria2c.html#cmdoption-k&#34;&gt;aria2-min-split-size&lt;/a&gt; (default: 5M)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://aria2.github.io/manual/en/html/aria2c.html#options&#34;&gt;aria2-options&lt;/a&gt; (default: )&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mxcl.github.io/homebrew/&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/37signals/sub#readme&#34;&gt;sub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;What sort of apps can Scoop install?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The apps that install best with Scoop are commonly called &#34;portable&#34; apps: i.e. compressed program files that run stand-alone when extracted and don&#39;t have side-effects like changing the registry or putting files outside the program directory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since installers are common, Scoop supports them too (and their uninstallers).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scoop is also great at handling single-file programs and Powershell scripts. These don&#39;t even need to be compressed. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main/raw/master/bucket/runat.json&#34;&gt;runat&lt;/a&gt; package for an example: it&#39;s really just a GitHub gist.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contribute to this project&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to improve Scoop by adding features or fixing bugs, please read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/.github/raw/main/.github/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Support this project&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find Scoop useful and would like to support ongoing development and maintenance, here&#39;s how:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_s-xclick&amp;amp;hosted_button_id=DM2SUH9EUXSKJ&#34;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; (one-time donation)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Known application buckets&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following buckets are known to scoop:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Main&#34;&gt;main&lt;/a&gt; - Default bucket for the most common (mostly CLI) apps&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Extras&#34;&gt;extras&lt;/a&gt; - Apps that don&#39;t fit the main bucket&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Scoop/wiki/Criteria-for-including-apps-in-the-main-bucket&#34;&gt;criteria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Calinou/scoop-games&#34;&gt;games&lt;/a&gt; - Open source/freeware games and game-related tools&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/matthewjberger/scoop-nerd-fonts&#34;&gt;nerd-fonts&lt;/a&gt; - Nerd Fonts&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kodybrown/scoop-nirsoft&#34;&gt;nirsoft&lt;/a&gt; - Almost all of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rasa.github.io/scoop-directory/by-apps#kodybrown_scoop-nirsoft&#34;&gt;250+&lt;/a&gt; apps from &lt;a href=&#34;https://nirsoft.net&#34;&gt;Nirsoft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Java&#34;&gt;java&lt;/a&gt; - A collection of Java development kits (JDKs), Java runtime engines (JREs), Java&#39;s virtual machine debugging tools and Java based runtime engines.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/TheRandomLabs/scoop-nonportable&#34;&gt;nonportable&lt;/a&gt; - Non-portable apps (may require UAC)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/PHP&#34;&gt;php&lt;/a&gt; - Installers for most versions of PHP&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ScoopInstaller/Versions&#34;&gt;versions&lt;/a&gt; - Alternative versions of apps found in other buckets&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main bucket is installed by default. To add any of the other buckets, type:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;scoop bucket add bucketname&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, to add the extras bucket, type:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;scoop bucket add extras&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Other application buckets&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many other application buckets hosted on Github can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rasa.github.io/scoop-directory/&#34;&gt;Scoop Directory&lt;/a&gt; or via &lt;a href=&#34;https://rasa.github.io/scoop-directory/#other-search-engines&#34;&gt;other search engines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/power-platform</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/MicrosoftDocs/power-platform</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/power-platform" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Documentation for Microsoft Power Platform&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>redcanaryco/atomic-red-team</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Small and highly portable detection tests based on MITRE&#39;s ATT&amp;CK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://redcanary.com/wp-content/uploads/Atomic-Red-Team-Logo.png&#34; width=&#34;150px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Atomic Red Team&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/actions/workflows/validate-atomics.yml/badge.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Action Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atomic Red Team™ is library of tests mapped to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://attack.mitre.org/&#34;&gt;MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK®&lt;/a&gt; framework. Security teams can use Atomic Red Team to quickly, portably, and reproducibly test their environments.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Get started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can execute atomic tests directly from the command line, no installation required. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/wiki/Getting-Started&#34;&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; page of our wiki.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a more robust testing experience, consider using an execution framework like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/invoke-atomicredteam&#34;&gt;Invoke-Atomic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Learn more&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Atomic Red Team documentation is available as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/wiki/&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For information about the philosophy and development of Atomic Red Team, visit our website at &lt;a href=&#34;https://atomicredteam.io&#34;&gt;https://atomicredteam.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contribute to Atomic Red Team&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Atomic Red Team is open source and community developed. If you&#39;re interested in becoming a contributor, check out these resources:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Join our &lt;a href=&#34;https://slack.atomicredteam.io&#34;&gt;Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt; and get involved with the community. Don&#39;t forget to review the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/master/CODE_OF_CONDUCT.md&#34;&gt;code of conduct&lt;/a&gt; before you join.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Report bugs and request new features by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/issues/new/choose&#34;&gt;submitting an issue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Read our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/wiki/Contributing&#34;&gt;contribution guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information about contributing directly to this repository.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/redcanaryco/atomic-red-team/master/LICENSE.txt&#34;&gt;license&lt;/a&gt; for information regarding the distribution and modification of Atomic Red Team.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MicrosoftDocs/azure-dev-docs</title>
    <updated>2022-06-02T02:20:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-06-02:/MicrosoftDocs/azure-dev-docs</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/MicrosoftDocs/azure-dev-docs" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Public repo for Azure developer SDK documentation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>