<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub PowerShell Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-16T01:43:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of PowerShell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>microsoft/Windows-Containers</title>
    <updated>2024-06-16T01:43:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-16:/microsoft/Windows-Containers</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/microsoft/Windows-Containers" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our Windows Containers GitHub community! Ask questions, report bugs, and suggest features -- let&#39;s work together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Welcome to the Windows Containers GitHub Repository&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository is managed by the Windows Containers platform team and is dedicated to tracking features and issues related to Windows Containers. We monitor this repository to engage with our community, address questions, discuss customer scenarios, and consider feature requests.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you new to Windows Containers?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Start by setting up your local environment and running your first Windows container. Follow our documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://aka.ms/containers/install&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a step-by-step guide.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Next, explore our &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/training/paths/deploy-manage-monitor-wincontainers-aks/&#34;&gt;training module&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to deploy, manage, monitor, and operate Windows containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Product Updates&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Stay informed about the latest features and improvements by visiting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/containers/bg-p/Containers&#34;&gt;Windows Container Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For open-source tools that enhance the Windows Containers experience, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/windows-container-tools&#34;&gt;Windows Container Tools repository&lt;/a&gt;. We encourage you to test the tools, provide feedback, and contribute to the development of Windows Container Tools.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Encountering issues with Windows Containers? Microsoft offers a comprehensive set of resources for troubleshooting Windows Containers:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/virtualization/windowscontainers/troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Windows Containers Troubleshooting Guide&lt;/a&gt;: This guide provides troubleshooting information for common issues encountered while working with Windows Containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/training/modules/troubleshoot-windows-containers/&#34;&gt;Windows Containers Troubleshooting Training Modules&lt;/a&gt;: This training module offers a guided troubleshooting learning path for various aspects of Windows Containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LegacyDotNetAppMigrationWorkshop/raw/main/HOL/06-windows-containers/advanced-troubleshooting.md&#34;&gt;Windows Containers Troubleshooting Workshop&lt;/a&gt;: This lab teaches advanced techniques for configuring, troubleshooting, and debugging Windows containers.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/networking-blog/troubleshooting-kubernetes-networking-on-windows-part-1/ba-p/508648&#34;&gt;Windows Containers Networking Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; This article highlights step-by-step instructions for addressing common networking issues.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Issues&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For specific bugs or issues related to the Windows Container platform, please use the Issues tracker on this GitHub repository. Issues without clear reproduction steps or that remain inactive for more than two weeks will be closed.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project welcomes contributions and suggestions. Most contributions require you to agree to a Contributor License Agreement (CLA) declaring that you have the right to, and actually do, grant us the rights to use your contribution. For details, visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;https://cla.opensource.microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you submit a pull request, a CLA bot will automatically determine whether you need to provide a CLA and decorate the PR appropriately (e.g., status check, comment). Simply follow the instructions provided by the bot. You will only need to do this once across all repos using our CLA.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project has adopted the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Open Source Code of Conduct&lt;/a&gt;. For more information see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.microsoft.com/codeofconduct/faq/&#34;&gt;Code of Conduct FAQ&lt;/a&gt; or contact &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:opencode@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;opencode@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt; with any additional questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>