<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub C++ Weekly Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-06-30T01:39:44Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Weekly Trending of C++ in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>niedev/RTranslator</title>
    <updated>2024-06-30T01:39:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-30:/niedev/RTranslator</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Open source real-time translation app for Android that runs locally&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/raw/v2.00/images/logo_beta_cut.png&#34; width=&#34;280&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;RTranslator is an (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator?tab=readme-ov-file#libraries-and-models&#34;&gt;almost&lt;/a&gt;) open-source, free, and offline real-time translation app for Android.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Connect to someone who has the app, connect Bluetooth headphones, put the phone in your pocket and you can have a conversation as if the other person spoke your language. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/raw/v2.00/images/Conversation_image.png&#34; alt=&#34;Conversation mode&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/raw/v2.00/images/TextTranslation_and_WalkieTalkie.png&#34; alt=&#34;WalkieTalkie mode and Costs&#34;&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Conversation mode&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Conversation mode is the main feature of RTranslator. In this mode, you can connect with another phone that uses this app. If the user accepts your connection request:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When you talk, your phone (or the Bluetooth headset, if connected) will capture the audio.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The audio captured will be converted into text and sent to the interlocutor&#39;s phone.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The interlocutors&#39; phone will translate the text received into his language.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The interlocutors&#39; phone will convert the translated text into audio and will reproduce it from its speaker (or by the Bluetooth headset of the interlocutor if connected to his phone).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;All this in both directions.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each user can have more than one connected phone so that you can translate conversations between more than two people and in any combination. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;WalkieTalkie mode&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If conversation mode is useful for having a long conversation with someone, this mode instead is designed for quick conversations, such as asking for information on the street or talking to a shop assistant.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This mode only translates conversations between two people, it doesn&#39;t work with Bluetooth headsets, and you have to talk in turns. It&#39;s not a real simultaneous translation, but it can work with only one phone.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this mode, the smartphone microphone will listen in two languages (selectable in the same screen of the walkie talkie mode) simultaneously. &lt;br&gt; The app will detect in which language the interlocutor is speaking, translate the audio into the other language, convert the text into audio, and then reproduce it from the phone speaker. When the TTS has finished, it will automatically resume listening. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Text translation mode&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This mode is just a classic text translator, but always useful. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;General&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;RTranslator uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.meta.com/research/no-language-left-behind/&#34;&gt;Meta&#39;s NLLB&lt;/a&gt; for translation and &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/index/whisper/&#34;&gt;OpenAi&#39;s Whisper&lt;/a&gt; for speech recognition, both are (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator?tab=readme-ov-file#libraries-and-models&#34;&gt;almost&lt;/a&gt;) open-source and state of the art AIs, have excellent quality and run directly on the phone, ensuring absolute privacy and the possibility of using RTranslator even offline without loss of quality.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, RTranslator works even in the background, with the phone on standby or when using other apps (only when you use Conversation or WalkieTalkie modes). However, some phones limit the power in the background so in that case it is better to avoid it and keep the app open with the screen on.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/rtranslator?utm_source=badge-featured&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_souce=badge-rtranslator&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://api.producthunt.com/widgets/embed-image/v1/featured.svg?post_id=274849&amp;amp;theme=light&#34; alt=&#34;RTranslator - World&#39;s first open-source simultaneous translation app. | Product Hunt&#34; style=&#34;width: 250px; height: 80px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;What&#39;s new in version 2.0&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Google API&#39;s have been replaced by &lt;a href=&#34;https://ai.meta.com/research/no-language-left-behind/&#34;&gt;Meta&#39;s NLLB&lt;/a&gt; for translation and &lt;a href=&#34;https://openai.com/index/whisper/&#34;&gt;OpenAi&#39;s Whisper&lt;/a&gt; for speech recognition. These AI models run directly on your phone, so now the app is totally free and with no configuration required!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A classic text translation mode has been added.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth LE device search has been improved.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fixed some bugs. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have optimized the AI models a lot to minimize RAM consumption and execution time, despite this however to be able to use the app without the risk of crashing you need a phone with at least &lt;strong&gt;6GB of RAM&lt;/strong&gt;, and to have a good enough execution time you need a phone with a fast enough CPU.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have a pretty crappy phone (or if you want maximum speed) you can always use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/tree/v1.00&#34;&gt;version 1.0 of RTranslator&lt;/a&gt; (but since it uses Google APIs it&#39;s not free and needs some initial setup). &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install the app, download the latest version of the app apk file from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/releases/&#34;&gt;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/releases/&lt;/a&gt; and install it (ignore the other files, those will be downloaded automatically by the app on the first start).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Get it on GitHub&#34; src=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/raw/v2.00/images/get_it_on_github.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 180px; height: 58px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the first launch, you will need to download the models for translation and speech recognition (1.2GB) and once done you can start translating. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Supported languages&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The languages supported are as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arabic, Bulgarian, Catalan, Chinese, Czech, Danish, German, Greek, English, Spanish, Finnish, French, Croatian, Italian, Japanese, Korean, Dutch, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Russian, Slovak, Swedish, Tamil, Thai, Turkish, Ukrainian, Urdu, Vietnamese. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy is a fundamental right. That&#39;s why RTranslator does not collect any personal data (I don&#39;t even have a server). For more information, read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/RTranslator/raw/v2.00/privacy/Privacy_Policy_en.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; (for now is the same privacy policy of RTranslator 1.0, but I will update it in the future). &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Libraries and models&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;RTranslator code is completely open-source, but some of the external libraries it uses have less permissive licenses, these are all the external libraries used by the app (with the indication of their license):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/BluetoothCommunicator&#34;&gt;BluetoothCommunicator&lt;/a&gt; (open-source): Used for Bluetooth LE communication between devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/niedev/GalleryImageSelector&#34;&gt;GalleryImageSelector&lt;/a&gt; (open-source): Used for selecting and cropping the profile image from the gallery.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/microsoft/onnxruntime&#34;&gt;OnnxRuntime&lt;/a&gt; (open-source): Used as an accelerator engine for the AI models.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/google/sentencepiece&#34;&gt;SentencePiece&lt;/a&gt; (open-source): Used for tokenization of the input text for NLLB.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/ml-kit/language/identification&#34;&gt;Ml Kit&lt;/a&gt; (closed-source): Used for the identification of the language in the WalkieTalkie mode. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; And the following AI models:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/facebookresearch/fairseq/tree/nllb&#34;&gt;NLLB&lt;/a&gt; (open-source, but only for non-commercial use): The model used is NLLB-Distilled-600M with KV cache.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openai/whisper&#34;&gt;Whisper&lt;/a&gt; (open-source): The model used is Whisper-Small-244M with KV cache.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I converted both models to onnx format and quantized them in int8 (excluding some weights to ensure almost zero quality loss), also I separated some parts of the models to reduce RAM consumption (without this separation some weights were duplicated at runtime consuming more RAM than expected). &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Donations&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an open-source and completely ad-free app, I don&#39;t make any money from it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, if you like the app and want to say thank you and support the project, you can make a donation via PayPal by clicking on the button below (any amount is well accepted).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com/donate/?business=3VBKS3WC6AFHN&amp;amp;no_recurring=0&amp;amp;currency_code=EUR&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Donate&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/niedev/RTranslator/v2.00/images/Paypal.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 190px; height: 80px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In case you will donate, or just live a star, thank you &lt;span&gt;❤️&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Bugs and problems&lt;/h3&gt; I remind you that the app is still in beta. The bugs found are the following: &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;For some languages, the TTS does not work. Reinstall the text-to-speech engine to solve.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Sometimes the Bluetooth connection drops.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have found any bug please report it by opening an issue, or by writing an email to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact.niedev@gmail.com&#34;&gt;contact.niedev@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy your simultaneous translator.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>zeek/zeek</title>
    <updated>2024-06-30T01:39:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-30:/zeek/zeek</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zeek/zeek" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Zeek is a powerful network analysis framework that is much different from the typical IDS you may know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeek.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zeek.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/zeek-logo-without-text.png&#34; alt=&#34;Zeek Logo&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Zeek Network Security Monitor&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 align=&#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://old.zeek.org/why_choose_zeek.pdf&#34;&gt;powerful&lt;/a&gt; framework for network traffic analysis and security monitoring.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zeek/zeek/master/#key-features&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key Features&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.zeek.org/en/stable/index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Documentation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zeek/zeek/master/#getting-started&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Started&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zeek/zeek/master/#development&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Development&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zeek/zeek/master/#license&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;License&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow us on Twitter at &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zeekurity&#34;&gt;@zeekurity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://coveralls.io/github/zeek/zeek?branch=master&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://coveralls.io/repos/github/zeek/zeek/badge.svg?branch=master&#34; alt=&#34;Coverage Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://cirrus-ci.com/github/zeek/zeek&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/cirrus/github/zeek/zeek&#34; alt=&#34;Build Status&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zeek.org/slack&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/slack-@zeek-brightgreen.svg?logo=slack&#34; alt=&#34;Slack&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.zeek.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/discourse/status?server=https%3A%2F%2Fcommunity.zeek.org&#34; alt=&#34;Discourse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Key Features&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In-depth Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; Zeek ships with analyzers for many protocols, enabling high-level semantic analysis at the application layer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptable and Flexible&lt;/strong&gt; Zeek&#39;s domain-specific scripting language enables site-specific monitoring policies and means that it is not restricted to any particular detection approach.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficient&lt;/strong&gt; Zeek targets high-performance networks and is used operationally at a variety of large sites.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highly Stateful&lt;/strong&gt; Zeek keeps extensive application-layer state about the network it monitors and provides a high-level archive of a network&#39;s activity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best place to find information about getting started with Zeek is our web site &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeek.org&#34;&gt;www.zeek.org&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeek.org/documentation/index.html&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; section there. On the web site you can also find downloads for stable releases, tutorials on getting Zeek set up, and many other useful resources.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find release notes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zeek/zeek/raw/master/NEWS&#34;&gt;NEWS&lt;/a&gt;, and a complete record of all changes in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zeek/zeek/raw/master/CHANGES&#34;&gt;CHANGES&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To work with the most recent code from the development branch of Zeek, clone the master git repository:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recursive https://github.com/zeek/zeek&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With all &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.zeek.org/en/stable/install/install.html#prerequisites&#34;&gt;dependencies&lt;/a&gt; in place, build and install:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo make install&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Write your first Zeek script:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-zeek&#34;&gt;# File &#34;hello.zeek&#34;&#xA;&#xA;event zeek_init()&#xA;    {&#xA;    print &#34;Hello World!&#34;;&#xA;    }&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And run it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;zeek hello.zeek&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For learning more about the Zeek scripting language, &lt;a href=&#34;http://try.zeek.org&#34;&gt;try.zeek.org&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Development&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zeek is developed on GitHub by its community. We welcome contributions. Working on an open source project like Zeek can be an incredibly rewarding experience and, packet by packet, makes the Internet a little safer. Today, as a result of countless contributions, Zeek is used operationally around the world by major companies and educational and scientific institutions alike for securing their cyber infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in getting involved, we collect feature requests and issues on GitHub &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zeek/zeek/issues&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and you might find &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zeek/zeek/labels/good%20first%20issue&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; to be a good place to get started. More information on Zeek&#39;s development can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeek.org/development/index.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and information about its community and mailing lists (which are fairly active) can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeek.org/community/index.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zeek comes with a BSD license, allowing for free use with virtually no restrictions. You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zeek/zeek/raw/master/COPYING&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tooling&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We use the following tooling to help discover issues to fix, amongst a number of others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://clang.llvm.org/extra/clang-tidy/&#34;&gt;Clang-Tidy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scan.coverity.com/projects/bro&#34;&gt;Coverity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pvs-studio.com/en/pvs-studio/?utm_source=github&amp;amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;amp;utm_campaign=open_source&#34;&gt;PVS-Studio&lt;/a&gt; - static analyzer for C, C++, C#, and Java code.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>assimp/assimp</title>
    <updated>2024-06-30T01:39:44Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-06-30:/assimp/assimp</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/assimp/assimp" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The official Open-Asset-Importer-Library Repository. Loads 40+ 3D-file-formats into one unified and clean data structure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Open Asset Import Library (assimp)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Asset Import Library is a library to load various 3d file formats into a shared, in-memory format. It supports more than &lt;strong&gt;40 file formats&lt;/strong&gt; for import and a growing selection of file formats for export.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Current project status&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/all/badge.svg?label=financial+contributors&#34; alt=&#34;Financial Contributors on Open Collective&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/workflows/C/C++%20CI/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;C/C++ CI&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codacy.com/gh/assimp/assimp/dashboard?utm_source=github.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=assimp/assimp&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Badge_Grade&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://app.codacy.com/project/badge/Grade/9973693b7bdd4543b07084d5d9cf4745&#34; alt=&#34;Codacy Badge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/assimp/assimp?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.gitter.im/assimp/assimp.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Join the chat at https://gitter.im/assimp/assimp&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/assimp/assimp&#34; title=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/resolution/assimp/assimp.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Average time to resolve an issue&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/project/assimp/assimp&#34; title=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://isitmaintained.com/badge/open/assimp/assimp.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Percentage of issues still open&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;APIs are provided for C and C++. There are various bindings to other languages (C#, Java, Python, Delphi, D). Assimp also runs on Android and iOS. Additionally, assimp features various &lt;strong&gt;mesh post-processing tools&lt;/strong&gt;: normals and tangent space generation, triangulation, vertex cache locality optimization, removal of degenerate primitives and duplicate vertices, sorting by primitive type, merging of redundant materials and many more.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&#34;https://assimp-docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;our latest documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Pre-built binaries&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download binaries from &lt;a href=&#34;https://kimkulling.itch.io/the-asset-importer-lib&#34;&gt;our Itchi Projectspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Test data&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp-mdb&#34;&gt;our model database&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Communities&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask questions at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/discussions&#34;&gt;the Assimp Discussion Board&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Assimp/&#34;&gt;the Assimp community on Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ask on &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/assimp?sort=newest&#34;&gt;StackOverflow with the assimp-tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Nothing has worked? File a question or an issue-report at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/issues&#34;&gt;The Assimp-Issue Tracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;And we also have a Gitter-channel:Gitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/assimp/assimp?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&amp;amp;utm_content=badge&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://badges.gitter.im/assimp/assimp.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Join the chat at https://gitter.im/assimp/assimp&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Supported file formats&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/raw/master/doc/Fileformats.md&#34;&gt;the complete list of supported formats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Building&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start by reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/raw/master/Build.md&#34;&gt;our build instructions&lt;/a&gt;. We are available in vcpkg, and our build system is CMake; if you used CMake before there is a good chance you know what to do.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Ports&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/assimp/assimp/master/port/AndroidJNI/README.md&#34;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/assimp/assimp/master/port/PyAssimp/README.md&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/Starnick/assimpnet/src/master/&#34;&gt;.NET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/assimp/assimp/master/port/AssimpPascal/Readme.md&#34;&gt;Pascal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/makc/assimp2json&#34;&gt;Javascript (Alpha)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kovacsv/assimpjs&#34;&gt;Javascript/Node.js Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ricardoreis.net/trilib-2/&#34;&gt;Unity 3d Plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/irajsb/UE4_Assimp/&#34;&gt;Unreal Engine Plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kotlin-graphics/assimp&#34;&gt;JVM&lt;/a&gt; Full jvm port (current &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kotlin-graphics/assimp/wiki/Status&#34;&gt;status&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/longde123/assimp-haxe&#34;&gt;HAXE-Port&lt;/a&gt; The Assimp-HAXE-port.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkvargas/russimp&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Other tools&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/acgessler/open3mod&#34;&gt;open3mod&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful 3D model viewer based on Assimp&#39;s import and export abilities. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp_view&#34;&gt;Assimp-Viewer&lt;/a&gt; is an experimental implementation for an Asset-Viewer based on ImGUI and Assimp (experimental).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Repository structure&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Asset Import Library is implemented in C++. The directory structure looks like this:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;/code&#x9;&#x9;Source code&#xA;/contrib&#x9;Third-party libraries&#xA;/doc&#x9;&#x9;Documentation (doxysource and pre-compiled docs)&#xA;/fuzz           Contains the test code for the Google Fuzzer project&#xA;/include&#x9;Public header C and C++ header files&#xA;/scripts &#x9;Scripts are used to generate the loading code for some formats&#xA;/port&#x9;&#x9;Ports to other languages and scripts to maintain those.&#xA;/test&#x9;&#x9;Unit- and regression tests, test suite of models&#xA;/tools&#x9;&#x9;Tools (old assimp viewer, command line `assimp`)&#xA;/samples&#x9;A small number of samples to illustrate possible use cases for Assimp&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The source code is organized in the following way:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;code/Common&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;The base implementation for importers and the infrastructure&#xA;code/CApi                       Special implementations which are only used for the C-API&#xA;code/Geometry                   A collection of geometry tools&#xA;code/Material                   The material system&#xA;code/PBR                        An exporter for physical-based models&#xA;code/PostProcessing&#x9;&#x9;The post-processing steps&#xA;code/AssetLib/&amp;lt;FormatName&amp;gt;&#x9;Implementation for import and export of the format&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Contributing&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contributions to assimp are highly appreciated. The easiest way to get involved is to submit a pull request with your changes against the main repository&#39;s &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributors&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Code Contributors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project exists thanks to all the people who contribute. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/assimp/assimp/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/assimp/assimp/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/contributors.svg?width=890&amp;amp;button=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Financial Contributors&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Become a financial contributor and help us sustain our community. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/contribute&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Individuals&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/individuals.svg?width=890&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Organizations&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Support this project with your organization. Your logo will show up here with a link to your website. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/contribute&#34;&gt;Contribute&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/organization/0/website&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://opencollective.com/assimp/organization/0/avatar.svg?sanitize=true&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our license is based on the modified, &lt;strong&gt;3-clause BSD&lt;/strong&gt;-License.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An &lt;em&gt;informal&lt;/em&gt; summary is: do whatever you want, but include Assimp&#39;s license text with your product - and don&#39;t sue us if our code doesn&#39;t work. Note that, unlike LGPLed code, you may link statically to Assimp. For the legal details, see the &lt;code&gt;LICENSE&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why this name&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sorry, we&#39;re germans :-), no English native speakers ...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>