<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-07-15T01:53:48Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>tj/git-extras</title>
    <updated>2022-07-15T01:53:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-15:/tj/git-extras</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/tj/git-extras" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GIT utilities -- repo summary, repl, changelog population, author commit percentages and more&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Git Extras&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Little git extras.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Screencasts&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just getting started? Check out these screencasts:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/45506445&#34;&gt;introduction&lt;/a&gt; -- covering git-ignore, git-setup, git-changelog, git-release, git-effort and more&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tj/git-extras/master/Installation.md&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Commands&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tj/git-extras/master/Commands.md&#34;&gt;Commands&lt;/a&gt; page for basic usage and examples.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GIT utilities&lt;/strong&gt; -- repo summary, repl, changelog population, author commit percentages and more&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interested in contributing? Awesome!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tj/git-extras/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;Contributing&lt;/a&gt; before you make a PR, thanks!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;The change of the default branch&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of Git Extras 6.4 the assumed default branch name changed from &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt;. This affects the Git Extras commands &lt;code&gt;git archive-file&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git delete-merged-branches&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git delta&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git pull-request&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git show-merged-branches&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git show-unmerged-branches&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;git squash&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To change the default branch name to &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;: change either the configuration &lt;code&gt;git-extras.default-branch&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;init.defaultBranch&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt;, the former takes precedence.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;code&gt;git config git-extras.default-branch master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Drewsif/PiShrink</title>
    <updated>2022-07-15T01:53:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-15:/Drewsif/PiShrink</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/Drewsif/PiShrink" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Make your pi images smaller!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PiShrink&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PiShrink is a bash script that automatically shrink a pi image that will then resize to the max size of the SD card on boot. This will make putting the image back onto the SD card faster and the shrunk images will compress better. In addition the shrunk image can be compressed with gzip and xz to create an even smaller image. Parallel compression of the image using multiple cores is supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Usage: $0 [-adhrspvzZ] imagefile.img [newimagefile.img]&#xA;&#xA;  -s         Don&#39;t expand filesystem when image is booted the first time&#xA;  -v         Be verbose&#xA;  -r         Use advanced filesystem repair option if the normal one fails&#xA;  -z         Compress image after shrinking with gzip&#xA;  -Z         Compress image after shrinking with xz&#xA;  -a         Compress image in parallel using multiple cores&#xA;  -p         Remove logs, apt archives, dhcp leases and ssh hostkeys&#xA;  -d         Write debug messages in a debug log file&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you specify the &lt;code&gt;newimagefile.img&lt;/code&gt; parameter, the script will make a copy of &lt;code&gt;imagefile.img&lt;/code&gt; and work off that. You will need enough space to make a full copy of the image to use that option.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-s&lt;/code&gt; prevents automatic filesystem expansion on the images next boot&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-v&lt;/code&gt; enables more verbose output&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-r&lt;/code&gt; will attempt to repair the filesystem using additional options if the normal repair fails&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-z&lt;/code&gt; will compress the image after shrinking using gzip. &lt;code&gt;.gz&lt;/code&gt; extension will be added to the filename.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-Z&lt;/code&gt; will compress the image after shrinking using xz. &lt;code&gt;.xz&lt;/code&gt; extension will be added to the filename.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-a&lt;/code&gt; will use option -f9 for pigz and option -T0 for xz and compress in parallel.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;-d&lt;/code&gt; will create a logfile &lt;code&gt;pishrink.log&lt;/code&gt; which may help for problem analysis.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Default options for compressors can be overwritten by defining PISHRINK_GZIP or PSHRINK_XZ environment variables for gzip and xz.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are running PiShrink in VirtualBox you will likely encounter an error if you attempt to use VirtualBox&#39;s &#34;Shared Folder&#34; feature. You can copy the image you wish to shrink on to the VM from a Shared Folder, but shrinking directctly from the Shared Folder is know to cause issues.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If using Ubuntu, you will likely see an error about &lt;code&gt;e2fsck&lt;/code&gt; being out of date and &lt;code&gt;metadata_csum&lt;/code&gt;. The simplest fix for this is to use Ubuntu 16.10 and up, as it will save you a lot of hassle in the long run.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;wget https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Drewsif/PiShrink/master/pishrink.sh&#xA;chmod +x pishrink.sh&#xA;sudo mv pishrink.sh /usr/local/bin&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;[user@localhost PiShrink]$ sudo pishrink.sh pi.img&#xA;e2fsck 1.42.9 (28-Dec-2013)&#xA;Pass 1: Checking inodes, blocks, and sizes&#xA;Pass 2: Checking directory structure&#xA;Pass 3: Checking directory connectivity&#xA;Pass 4: Checking reference counts&#xA;Pass 5: Checking group summary information&#xA;/dev/loop1: 88262/1929536 files (0.2% non-contiguous), 842728/7717632 blocks&#xA;resize2fs 1.42.9 (28-Dec-2013)&#xA;resize2fs 1.42.9 (28-Dec-2013)&#xA;Resizing the filesystem on /dev/loop1 to 773603 (4k) blocks.&#xA;Begin pass 2 (max = 100387)&#xA;Relocating blocks             XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX&#xA;Begin pass 3 (max = 236)&#xA;Scanning inode table          XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX&#xA;Begin pass 4 (max = 7348)&#xA;Updating inode references     XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX&#xA;The filesystem on /dev/loop1 is now 773603 blocks long.&#xA;&#xA;Shrunk pi.img from 30G to 3.1G&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you find a bug please create an issue for it. If you would like a new feature added, you can create an issue for it but I can&#39;t promise that I will get to it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pull requests for new features and bug fixes are more than welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>christianhaitian/PortMaster</title>
    <updated>2022-07-15T01:53:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-07-15:/christianhaitian/PortMaster</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/christianhaitian/PortMaster" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A simple tool that allows you to download various game ports that are available for 351Elec, ArkOS, JelOS, RetroOZ, and TheRA for RK3326 based devices and the RG552..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;What is PortMaster?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;PortMaster is a simple tool that is designed similarly to JohnIrvine&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JohnIrvine1433/ThemeMaster&#34;&gt;ThemeMaster&lt;/a&gt; themes management tool that allows you to download various game ports that are available for 351Elec, ArkOS, JelOS, RetroOZ, and TheRA for RK3326 based devices. Support for the RG552 has been added as well. A number of ports have been tested and confirmed working with TheRA and RetroOZ. Ports such as Freedom Planet and Maldita Castilla will be working for TheRA soon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the goals of PortMaster is to not install or upgrade any existing OS libraries for any ports. Any of the ports that need a particular non standard library are maintained within the ports&#39; folder and made available specifically to that port during execution.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the the ports available through PortMaster have been configured to launch with proper controls for the Gameforce Chi, Powkiddy RGB10, Anbernic RG351P/M/V/MP, RK2020 and the Odroid Go Advance units. Controls for the Anbernic RG552, Odroid Go Super and the Powkiddy RGB10 Max are also included and have been tested but not as much as the 3.5&#34; RK3326 devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install info&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For ArkOS on supported devices, PortMaster was included with a recent online update. You can locate it in the Options &amp;gt; Tools menu. &lt;br&gt; For 351Elec, just unzip the contents of PortMaster.zip to your storage/roms/ports folder then run PortMaster.sh from the Ports menu in 351Elec. &lt;br&gt; For JelOS, it&#39;s been intergrated into their most recent releases. Just launch from tools and enjoy! &lt;br&gt; If you don&#39;t have PortMaster there or need to install it manually, you can do the following:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Place the PortMaster folder in /roms/tools. The .sh file &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; remain in the PortMaster folder! &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;For ArkOS on the RG351V or RG351MP, if SD2 is being used for roms, installation must be in /roms2/tools/. The .sh file &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; remain in the PortMaster folder!&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run PortMaster from ArkOS, TheRA or RetroOZ through Options &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; PortMaster menu, 351Elec from Ports &amp;gt; PortMaster menu&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Do I have to use PortMaster to install ports?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. You can simply go to the PortMaster repo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/christianhaitian/PortMaster&#34;&gt;https://github.com/christianhaitian/PortMaster&lt;/a&gt;), find the .zip of the port you want, download it and unzip the contents of it to the /roms/ports folder. You&#39;ll also need to copy the PortMaster folder to your /roms/ports folder. If you don&#39;t want the PortMaster folder to show up in your Ports menu in Emulationstation, just delete the PortMaster.sh file as it won&#39;t be needed if you don&#39;t plan to install or update your ports online via this tool. \&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: For ArkOS on the RG351V or RG351MP, if SD2 is being used for roms, unzip the port to the /roms2/ports folder instead and copy the PortMaster folder to the /roms2/tools location. A few additional ports are available on the large releases repo (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PortsMaster/PortMaster-Releases/releases&#34;&gt;https://github.com/PortsMaster/PortMaster-Releases/releases&lt;/a&gt;) due to their size (ex. SuperTux, Ur Quan Masters, and FreedroidRPG).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How do I get more info about the ports in this repo like the sources used and additional asset needs if applicable?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find that information via the ArkOS Emulators and Ports information wiki link &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/christianhaitian/arkos/wiki/ArkOS-Emulators-and-Ports-information#ports&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;If there are updates to Ports, how will that work?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just run PortMaster and reinstall the port. You can also unzip the associated .zip for the port you want and unzip the contents of it to the ports folder. This should install the latest port related files if they&#39;ve been updated in PortMaster. In most cases, it should not impact any existing game data you had to provide or existing saves unless the updated port made changes to the port backend that impacts previous saves.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How can I help add ports to PortMaster?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See the packaging documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/christianhaitian/PortMaster/raw/main/docs/packaging.md&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more info on this. Once you&#39;re port packaging has met these minimum requirements, you can either submit a Pull Request of this port package with details about the port such as a description of it and how to add any gamefiles or assets if needed or contact me on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/Jd2azKX&#34;&gt;RGHandhelds&lt;/a&gt; discord for further review and advisement.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>