<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2023-10-02T01:39:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl</title>
    <updated>2023-10-02T01:39:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2023-10-02:/1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Docker image and Pterodactyl eggs to support CS2 and CS:GO (after archival), based on SteamRT3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CS2 on Pterodactyl&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Docker image and Pterodactyl egg to prepare for upcoming CS (CS:GO/CS2) updates. The Docker image is based on the Valve provided SteamRT3 Sniper package, with the Pterodactyl egg featuring a few exposed variables such as Beta selection variables and allowing for skipping SteamCMD on launch (i.e, preventing updates). This should allow existing CSGO servers to easily stay on the opt-in CS:GO branch once CS2 releases.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This setup is very similar to the stock Pterodactyl Source server setup, so things should be familiar once imported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The underlying Docker image is based on Valve&#39;s Steam Runtime 3 (Sniper), which should be able to run both CS:GO and CS2 without any issues. The image also can be rebuilt easily as soon as Valve updates their base SteamRT3 image, so we can stay on top of their updates without worrying too much about it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Download egg(s) from the &lt;code&gt;/pterodactyl&lt;/code&gt; directory. &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cs2.json&lt;/code&gt;: Egg for CS2 &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;A Steam account that has CS2 in its library is required to download from the &lt;code&gt;730&lt;/code&gt; app depot that CS2 is in. Configure access to this account in your server&#39;s start-up variables.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;Please ensure Steam Guard is disabled on this account, else your first-time install will likely not be able to proceed.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;csgo.json&lt;/code&gt;: Egg for CS:GO&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Import into your Pterodactyl nest of choice. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/parkervcp/eggs#how-to-import-an-egg&#34;&gt;Read here if you need a guide on how to do this.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;I want to use the SteamRT3 Docker image directly&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Docker image is hosted on the GitHub Container Registry. You can grab it from here:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghcr.io/1zc/steamrt3-pterodactyl:latest&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can find a full list of builds here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl/packages&#34;&gt;https://github.com/1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl/packages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Running CS:GO post-CS2 launch will cause the server to constantly spam that it needs an update, you can use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/accelerator74/Cleaner/tree/master&#34;&gt;Cleaner SourceMod extension&lt;/a&gt; to get rid of these messages if they&#39;re annoying. Edit &lt;code&gt;addons/sourcemod/configs/cleaner.cfg&lt;/code&gt; and add the following&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/1zc/CS2-Pterodactyl/issues/2&#34;&gt;#2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MasterRequestRestart&#xA;Your server needs to be restarted in order to receive the latest update.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;If your server on the CS:GO egg keeps trying to restart itself to update (or spamming messages about auto-restarting for updates), remove &lt;code&gt;-autoupdate&lt;/code&gt; from your server&#39;s start-up command.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>