<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-11-08T01:39:33Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>CryoByte33/steam-deck-utilities</title>
    <updated>2022-11-08T01:39:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-08:/CryoByte33/steam-deck-utilities</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/CryoByte33/steam-deck-utilities" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Scripts to help make the Steam Deck the best it can be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;CryoUtilities&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scripts and utilities to enhance the Steam Deck experience, particularly performance.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Immediate TRIM in microSDs is currently disabled because of Valve&#39;s statement here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/23415294/valve-steam-deck-microsd-card-slow-download-speed-fix-how-to&#34;&gt;https://www.theverge.com/23415294/valve-steam-deck-microsd-card-slow-download-speed-fix-how-to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;TRIM will still be run on /home in the meantime!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Functionality:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swap File Resizer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Swappiness Changer&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Enable/Disable TRIM&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Immediately run TRIM on all mounted volumes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look below for common questions and answers, or go check out my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJ2wc4hCWI8bEki48Zv45fQ&#34;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; for examples on how to use this and what performance you can expect.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support Me&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@cryobyte33&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/youtube/channel/subscribers/UCJ2wc4hCWI8bEki48Zv45fQ?color=%23FF0000&amp;amp;label=Subscribe%20on%20YouTube&amp;amp;style=flat-square&#34; alt=&#34;Watch me on YouTube:&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patreon.com/cryobyte33&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/endpoint.svg?url=https%3A%2F%2Fshieldsio-patreon.vercel.app%2Fapi%3Fusername%3Dcryobyte33%26type%3Dpatrons&amp;amp;style=flat&#34; alt=&#34;Support me on Patreon&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; This &lt;strong&gt;REQUIRES&lt;/strong&gt; a password set on the Steam Deck. That can be done with the &lt;code&gt;passwd&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;After installation, just run the &#34;CryoUtilities&#34; icon on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Easy&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download InstallCryoUtilities.desktop from this repository with &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/CryoByte33/steam-deck-utilities/main/InstallCryoUtilities.desktop&#34;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; on your Steam Deck, then run it. (Right click and save file)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will install a script and create a few desktop icons for the swap resizer tool.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Local Storage / Clone&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This method lets you download the script locally to have on hand. You can also modify it if you&#39;d like, but I don&#39;t recommend that unless you know what you&#39;re doing!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git clone https://github.com/CryoByte33/steam-deck-utilities.git&#xA;cd steam-deck-utilities&#xA;chmod +x cryo_utilities.sh&#xA;./cryo_utilities.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Upgrade&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Double-click the &#34;Update CryoUtilities&#34; icon on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Uninstall&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Double-click the &#34;Uninstall CryoUtilities&#34; icon on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Common Questions&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;What games benefit from the swap fix?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any game that uses a combined 16GB for RAM and VRAM will likely benefit from the swap fix. How much the swap fix helps will depend on a few factors including asset compression, asset size, and churn of data in memory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Do the swap changes work for all games?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, as a matter of fact, they work for any program on SteamOS loaded from any location. That means that even Google Chrome installed on an external hard drive would benefit from these changes (If the trigger conditions are met).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Will an update revert the swap fix?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, but reformatting the Deck will revert it. I tested with several updates and both the swap file and swap tendency settings were left in place.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Does the swap fix work on Windows?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, but Windows does have an equivalent called a page file, and its size is automatically managed by Windows. I haven&#39;t tested performance implications yet, but I believe that it won&#39;t bring quite the same amount of performance boost as the NTFS filesystem is abysmally slow.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Are there any situations where the swap fix isn&#39;t a good option?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the swap tendency update, extremely memory-heavy CPU-bound processes could take a performance hit from the fix. I hadn&#39;t found an instance of it in gaming, but I confirmed that KDEnLive and Blender would both cause this to happen and worked better without the swap fix.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest version with the swap tendency tweak doesn&#39;t have this issue, and I&#39;ve been unable to trigger worse performance in any situation during testing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Does the swap fix hurt emulators?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, but I haven&#39;t done exhaustive testing yet. That said, many viewers have reported better performance in newer emulators like RPCS3, Yuzu and CEMU. I hope to do an emulation-focused video soon since I&#39;ve been emulating for 13-ish years.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Will the swap fix hurt my SSD?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, setting the swap tendency to 1 will reduce wear on the SSD over the stock configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;How much SSD wear does the stock configuration cause?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, a swap tendency of 100 will try to put data into swap prior to RAM. Because of that, a large percentage of all memory operations would wear your SSD. I don&#39;t have a spare SSD to test this, but I would guess that the default wear pattern would reduce the SSD&#39;s life to about 4 years of average gameplay on modern games.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting the swap tendency to 1 won&#39;t quite prevent data from making it into swap at all times, but it will reduce the frequency to only when the Deck overflows its total memory.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Do differently sized SSDs have a performance difference for swapping?&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, the read and write speeds both make a difference in the speed of swapping, and therefore performance. That said, Valve did a pretty good job at choosing good quality parts with relatively similar speeds so we&#39;d all have a consistent experience.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general, the larger the SSD the faster it is, but there&#39;s a lot more to it than that. But that does mean that by upgrading your SSD size you could upgrade the performance during swap scenarios. Something to keep in mind, but it will likely be a very small difference.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Right-clicking the link to save it doesn&#39;t open a dialog box&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reboot the Deck or restart desktop mode, afterwards the link should work.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The .desktop file just opens with KWrite after I download it.&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;chmod +x ~/Downloads/InstallCryoUtilities.desktop&lt;/code&gt; and then try again. If that still doesn&#39;t work, add it as a Non-Steam game and run it from Steam.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>hachyderm/hack</title>
    <updated>2022-11-08T01:39:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-08:/hachyderm/hack</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/hachyderm/hack" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hachyderm Administration&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Hack&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hacks for Mastodon. We suggest using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=tootctl&amp;amp;oq=tootctl&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j69i59j69i60.1285j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&#34;&gt;tootctl&lt;/a&gt; whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are global variables you should set to interact with the API.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;MASTODON_SERVER=&#34;hachyderm.io&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will need to &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.joinmastodon.org/spec/oauth/&#34;&gt;generate a client key and secret&lt;/a&gt; you can just do this by creating a new application in your settings. You should also be able to get an access token from your settings, but you can also get it from the OAuth authorize and token scheme.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;MASTODON_ACCESS_TOKEN=&#34;abc123def&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then you can run the scripts!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A docker compose file makes it handy for you to run it scoped without modifying your environment :&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Run the complete blocklist&#xA;docker compose up&#xA;# or &#xA;docker compose run hack domain_block_from_blocklist&#xA;&#xA;# Block a specific domain&#xA;docker compose run hack domain_block &amp;lt;domain&amp;gt;&#xA;&#xA;# Unblock the complete unblocklist&#xA;docker compose run hack domain_unblock_from_unblocklist&#xA;&#xA;# Unblock a specific domain&#xA;docker compose run hack domain_unblock &amp;lt;domain&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>lxqt/lxqt</title>
    <updated>2022-11-08T01:39:33Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-11-08:/lxqt/lxqt</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/lxqt/lxqt" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Checkout all LXQt components at once by using git submodule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;LXQt&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;LXQt is the next generation of LXDE, the Lightweight Desktop Environment. It is the product of the merge between Razor-qt and LXDE-Qt.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About this repository&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a superproject which contains all LXQt components. After checking out this repo please do the following to initialize git submodules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule init&#xA;git submodule update --remote --rebase&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: We require git &amp;gt;= 1.8.5&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contributing&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in helping or joining LXQt, please take a look at our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lxqt/lxqt/raw/master/CONTRIBUTING.md&#34;&gt;CONTRIBUTING document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Translation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translations can be done in &lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.lxqt-project.org/&#34;&gt;LXQt-Weblate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.lxqt-project.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://translate.lxqt-project.org/widgets/lxqt-desktop/-/287x66-grey.png&#34; alt=&#34;Translation status&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.lxqt-project.org/&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://translate.lxqt-project.org/widgets/lxqt-desktop/-/multi-auto.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Translation status&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>