<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2025-04-04T01:41:53Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>nix-community/nixos-anywhere</title>
    <updated>2025-04-04T01:41:53Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2025-04-04:/nix-community/nixos-anywhere</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Install NixOS everywhere via SSH [maintainers=Mic92, Lassulus, phaer, Enzime]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Install NixOS everywhere via ssh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/logo.png&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34;&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/INDEX.md&#34;&gt;Documentation Index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;README&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new machine is time-consuming, and becomes complicated when it needs to be done remotely. If you&#39;re installing NixOS, the &lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; tool allows you to pre-configure the whole process including:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Disk partitioning and formatting&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Configuring and installing NixOS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Installing additional files and software&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can then initiate an unattended installation with a single CLI command. Since &lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; can access the new machine using SSH, it&#39;s ideal for remote installations.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have initiated the command, there is no need to &#39;babysit&#39; the installation. It all happens automatically.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can use the stored configuration to repeat the same installation if you need to.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have machines on a mix of platforms, you&#39;ll need a common installation solution that works anywhere. &lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; is ideal in this situation.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; can be used equally well for cloud servers, bare metal servers such as Hetzner, and local servers accessible via a LAN. You can create standard configurations, and use the same configuration to create identical servers anywhere.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You first create Nix configurations to specify partitioning, formatting and NixOS configurations. Further options can be controlled by a flake and by run-time switches.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the configuration has been created, a single command will:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Connect to the remote server via SSH&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Detect whether a NixOS installer is present; if not, it will use the Linux &lt;code&gt;kexec&lt;/code&gt; tool to boot into a Nixos installer.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nix-community/disko&#34;&gt;disko&lt;/a&gt; tool to partition and format the hard drive&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Install NixOS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally install any Nix packages and other software required.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Optionally copy additional files to the new machine&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s also possible to use &lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; to simplify the installation on a machine that has no current operating system, first booting from a NixOS installer image. This feature is described in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/howtos/no-os.md#installing-on-a-machine-with-no-operating-system&#34;&gt;how-to guide&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s useful because you can pre-configure your required software and preferences, and build the new machine with a single command.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Never use a production server as the target. It will be completely overwritten and all data lost. This tool should only be used for commissioning a new computer or repurposing an old machine once all important data has been migrated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Source Machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Can be any machine&amp;nbsp;with Nix installed, e.g. a NixOS machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Target Machine:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;Unless you&#39;re using the option to boot from a NixOS installer image, or providing your own &lt;code&gt;kexec&lt;/code&gt; image, it must be running x86-64 Linux with kexec support. Most &lt;code&gt;x86_64&lt;/code&gt; Linux systems do have kexec support. By providing your own &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/howtos/custom-kexec.md#using-your-own-kexec-image&#34;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt; you can also perform kexec for other architectures eg aarch64&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;The machine must be reachable over the public internet or local network. Nixos-anywhere does not support wifi networks. If a VPN is needed, define a custom installer via the --kexec flag which connects to your VPN.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;When &lt;code&gt;kexec&lt;/code&gt; is used the target must have at least 1 GB of RAM, excluding swap.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How to use nixos-anywhere&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/quickstart.md&#34;&gt;Quickstart Guide&lt;/a&gt; gives more information on how to run &lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; in its simplest form. For more specific instructions to suit individual requirements, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/nix-community/nixos-anywhere/main/docs/howtos/INDEX.md&#34;&gt;How To Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Related Tools&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/strong&gt; makes use of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nix-community/disko&#34;&gt;disko&lt;/a&gt; tool to handle the partitioning and formatting of the disks.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;For questions, come join us in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://matrix.to/#/%23nixos-anywhere:nixos.org&#34;&gt;nixos-anywhere&lt;/a&gt; matrix room.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Licensing and Contribution details&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This software is provided free under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://opensource.org/licenses/MIT&#34;&gt;MIT License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is supported by &lt;a href=&#34;https://numtide.com/&#34;&gt;Numtide&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&#34;https://codahosted.io/docs/6FCIMTRM0p/blobs/bl-sgSunaXYWX/077f3f9d7d76d6a228a937afa0658292584dedb5b852a8ca370b6c61dabb7872b7f617e603f1793928dc5410c74b3e77af21a89e435fa71a681a868d21fd1f599dd10a647dd855e14043979f1df7956f67c3260c0442e24b34662307204b83ea34de929d&#34; alt=&#34;Untitledpng&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are a team of independent freelancers that love open source. &amp;nbsp;We help our customers make their project lifecycles more efficient by:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Providing and supporting useful tools such as this one&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Building and deploying infrastructure, and offering dedicated DevOps support&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Building their in-house Nix skills, and integrating Nix with their workflows&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Developing additional features and tools&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Carrying out custom research and development.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://numtide.com/contact&#34;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt; if you have a project in mind, or if you need help with any of our supported tools, including this one. We&#39;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>