<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-14T01:39:31Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>HEADLIGHTER/Born2BeRoot-42</title>
    <updated>2022-12-14T01:39:31Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-14:/HEADLIGHTER/Born2BeRoot-42</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/HEADLIGHTER/Born2BeRoot-42" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;monitoring.sh script, walk through installation and setting up, evaluation Q&amp;A&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Born2BeRoot 42/21&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;GRADE: 110/100&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you make only partition from bonus part.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developed for Debian so i&#39;m not sure that it will run properly on CentOS distributive. Anyway, PM me on Discord if its working on CentOS or you have a suggestion/issues: MMBHWR#0793&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;monitoring.sh script&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Known issues:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cron may refuse to running script on boot due to bug in Debian (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=635473&#34;&gt;https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=635473&lt;/a&gt;). How to fix? [https://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?att=0;bug=635473;msg=70]. Good luck :) Theres also another way to fix it in my rebootfix.txt file, but it may not work anyway... Try to explain this to your evaluator if he ask you. Because i haven&#39;t seen &#34;monitoring.sh script on boot&#34; in evaluation checklist and almost nobody asked me about this.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;Please, DO NOT copie + paste this thing with emptiness in your eyes and blank in your head!&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s highly recommended to know what u use and how&amp;amp;why it works even if i leaved an explanation in commentary. At least, it will be usefull for YOURS and ONLY YOURS defense. Google&amp;amp;man all the commands listed here and read about it&#39;s options/parameters/etc. Be intellegent, be adaptive, be SMART. Know the tool you use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;To make this works u need to [$ chmod +x monitoring.sh] (ofc lol). &#xA;Please note that you should run script as root because journalctl won&#39;t&#xA;work from user without sudo.&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;How to use&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;First off [$ sudo crontab -e] (yep, you need sudo to make cron runnig script as root.[$ crontab-e] will open another file that will run your script as user). Set nano/vi as your text editor for cron and add next lines in your crontab file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@reboot /path/to/file/monitoring.sh&#xA;*/10 * * * * /path/to/file/monitoring.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dont forget that you should write FULL PATH TO FILE (no ~/*/etc.) due to cron&#39;s pecularity.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;walkthrough37.txt&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guide how to correctly setup and configure both Debian and software. Including bonus-part partition set up.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;evalknowledge.txt&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Little Q&amp;amp;A from Subject and whattocheck as evaluator.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it&#39;s done for now. I won&#39;t make &#34;full guide with bonus part&#34; just because you can easly find it in another B2BR repo. I highly recommend repeating the installation process several times, if possible, in order to remember and understand everything well. Especially if this is your first time working both Linux and a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>