<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2024-05-17T01:32:48Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>zauceee/PPLGPwn</title>
    <updated>2024-05-17T01:32:48Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2024-05-17:/zauceee/PPLGPwn</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/zauceee/PPLGPwn" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A method of executing PPPwn through rooted LGTV&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;PPLGPwn&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A method of executing PPPwn through rooted LGTV&#39;s. This method is using the C++ version of PPPwn, made by xfangfang, the link to the repo it&#39;s this one: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/xfangfang/PPPwn_cpp&#34;&gt;https://github.com/xfangfang/PPPwn_cpp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It provides a new way of jailbreaking your PS4, using a rooted LGTV. For more information of which firmwares are supported, visit the link above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/zauceee/PPLGPwn/assets/37784801/068d16b5-051e-4f22-bdf7-b0e3b46e6590&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Changelog v1.2 -- 16/05/2024&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Added Support for aarch64 TV&#39;s&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;New option to select if you want PPLGPwn to start when you turn your TV on (Thanks llbranco for the help!)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Rooted LGTV&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Ethernet cable&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Device to connect to the TV thru ssh (You can use a phone)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How can I do it?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly you&#39;ll need to root your LGTV, the root itself it supported by a couple of models, check both exploits to see if your TV is capable of doing so, more steps on how to root it and activate SSH aswell are available there:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Root my TV: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rootmy.tv/&#34;&gt;https://rootmy.tv/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Dejavuln: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/throwaway96/dejavuln-autoroot&#34;&gt;https://github.com/throwaway96/dejavuln-autoroot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, after you jailbreak your own TV (ironic on how we use a jailbroken TV to jailbreak another device lol), you will need to run the &lt;code&gt;install.sh&lt;/code&gt; present in the releases tab on your TV, do it thru this command:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget https://github.com/zauceee/PPLGPwn/releases/download/v1.2/install.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; source ./install.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connect your PS4 to your TV through the Ethernet port, and go in your PS4 set up LAN &amp;gt; PPPoE, and the exploit should be working!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How can I execute this with just a click of a button?&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Head to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webosbrew.org/&#34;&gt;Homebrew Store&lt;/a&gt; app and download &lt;a href=&#34;https://repo.webosbrew.org/apps/org.webosbrew.inputhook/&#34;&gt;LG Input Hook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Open the LG Input Hook and head to the link the app gives you in a device that has a web browser (you can also do this in your TV, but it will take more time)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Setup this custom &lt;strong&gt;Execute&lt;/strong&gt; action to any button you&#39;d like:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /media/internal/downloads/PPLGPwn &amp;amp;&amp;amp; chmod +x ./run.sh &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ./run.sh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Save your changes&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And done!&lt;/strong&gt; The button you setup with the custom action will know execute the exploit everytime you press it!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h1&gt;NOTES&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;!! This exploit is made for TV&#39;s with the armv7 or aarch64 architectures, I&#39;m unsure if it works on any other different arch, to know your TV chip architecture run &lt;code&gt;uname -m&lt;/code&gt; !!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;!! This exploit stage2 runs LightningMod&#39;s load from usb payload !!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proudly &lt;strong&gt;🇵🇹&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the OpenLGTV and the RootMyTV communities that gave us this TV Jailbreak Also a thanks to everyone in the PS4 jailbreaking community that gave us the exploits! And also thanks to all the contributors!&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>