<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>GitHub Shell Daily Trending</title>
  <id>http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS</id>
  <updated>2022-12-10T01:37:12Z</updated>
  <subtitle>Daily Trending of Shell in GitHub</subtitle>
  <link href="http://mshibanami.github.io/GitHubTrendingRSS"></link>
  <entry>
    <title>ayoub0x1/born2beroot</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T01:37:12Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-10:/ayoub0x1/born2beroot</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Born2beroot (42cursus). This project aims to introduce you to the wonderful world of virtualization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;42cursus - Born2beroot&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#Virtual-Machine&#34;&gt;What is a Virtual Machine?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#Virtual-Machines-work&#34;&gt;How do Virtual Machines work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#What-is-LVM?&#34;&gt;What is LVM?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#What-is-AppArmor?&#34;&gt;What is AppArmor?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#Apt-and-Aptitute&#34;&gt;What is the difference between Apt and Aptitute?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#How-to-use-SSH?&#34;&gt;How to use SSH?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#UFW-with-SSH&#34;&gt;How to implement UFW with SSH?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#what-is-cron&#34;&gt;What is cron and what is wall?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#sudo&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-1-installing-sudo&#34;&gt;Step 1: Installing &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-2-adding-user-to-sudo-group&#34;&gt;Step 2: Adding User to &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-3-running-root-privileged-commands&#34;&gt;Step 3: Running &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;-Privileged Commands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-4-configuring-sudo&#34;&gt;Step 4: Configuring &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#ssh&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-1-installing--configuring-ssh&#34;&gt;Step 1: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring SSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-2-installing--configuring-ufw&#34;&gt;Step 2: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring UFW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-3-connecting-to-server-via-ssh&#34;&gt;Step 3: Connecting to Server via SSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#user-management&#34;&gt;User Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-1-setting-up-a-strong-password-policy&#34;&gt;Step 1: Setting Up a Strong Password Policy&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#password-age&#34;&gt;Password Age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#password-strength&#34;&gt;Password Strength&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-2-creating-a-new-user&#34;&gt;Step 2: Creating a New User&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-3-creating-a-new-group&#34;&gt;Step 3: Creating a New Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#cron&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#setting-up-a-cron-job&#34;&gt;Setting Up a &lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt; Job&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#monitoring&#34;&gt;Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#bonus&#34;&gt;Bonus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#1-installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#2-linux-lighttpd-mariadb-php-llmp-stack&#34;&gt;Linux Lighttpd MariaDB PHP &lt;em&gt;(LLMP)&lt;/em&gt; Stack&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-1-installing-lighttpd&#34;&gt;Step 1: Installing Lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-2-installing--configuring-mariadb&#34;&gt;Step 2: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring MariaDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-3-installing-php&#34;&gt;Step 3: Installing PHP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-4-downloading--configuring-wordpress&#34;&gt;Step 4: Downloading &amp;amp; Configuring WordPress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-5-configuring-lighttpd&#34;&gt;Step 5: Configuring Lighttpd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#3-file-transfer-protocol-ftp&#34;&gt;File Transfer Protocol &lt;em&gt;(FTP)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-1-installing--configuring-ftp&#34;&gt;Step 1: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring FTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#step-2-connecting-to-server-via-ftp&#34;&gt;Step 2: Connecting to Server via FTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#peereval&#34;&gt;Submission and peer-evaluation for 1337/42 Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ayoub0x1/born2beroot/main/#evalknowledge&#34;&gt;evalknowledge.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will create your first machine in VirtualBox (or UTM if you can’t use VirtualBox) under specific instructions. Then, at the end of this project, you will be able to set up your own operating system while implementing strict rules.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Virtual-Machine&#34;&gt;What is a Virtual Machine?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A virtual machine is a &lt;strong&gt;software capable of installing an Operating System within itself, making the OS think that it is hosted on a real computer&lt;/strong&gt;. With virtual machines we can create virtual devices that will behave in the same way as physical devices, using their own CPU, memory, network interface and storage. This is possible because &lt;strong&gt;the virtual machine is hosted on a physical device&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the one that provides the hardware resources to the VM. The software program that creates virtual machines is &lt;strong&gt;the hypervisor&lt;/strong&gt;. The hypervisor is responsible for isolating the VM resources from the system hardware and making the necessary implementations so that the VM can use these resources.&lt;br&gt; The devices that provide the hardware resources are called &lt;strong&gt;host machines or hosts&lt;/strong&gt;. The different virtual machines that can be assigned to a host are called &lt;strong&gt;guests or guest machines&lt;/strong&gt;. The hypervisor uses a part of the host machine&#39;s CPU, storage, etc., and distributes them among the different VMs.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; There can be multiple virtual machines on the same host and each of these will be isolated from the rest of the system. Thanks to this, we can run different operating systems on our machine. For each virtual machine, we can run a different operating system distribution. Each of these operating systems will behave as if they were hosted on a physical device, so we will have the same experience when using an OS on a physical machine and on a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Virtual-Machines-work&#34;&gt;How do Virtual Machines work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Virtualization allow us share a system with multiple virtual environments. The hypervisor manages the hardware system and separate the physical resources from the virtual environments. &lt;strong&gt;The resources are managed followitn the needs, from the host to the guests.&lt;/strong&gt; When an user from a VM do a task that requires additional resources from the physical environment, the hypervisor manages the request so that the guest OS could access the resources of the physical environment.&lt;br&gt; Once we know how they work, it is a good idea to see all the advantages we get from using virtual machines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Different guest machines hosted on our computer &lt;b&gt;can run different operating systems&lt;/b&gt;, so we will have different OS working on the same machine.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;They provide an environment in which &lt;b&gt;to safely test unstable programs&lt;/b&gt; to see if they will affect the system or not.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We get &lt;b&gt;better use of shared resources.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;We &lt;b&gt;reduce costs&lt;/b&gt; by reducing physical architecture.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;They are &lt;b&gt;easy to implement&lt;/b&gt; because they provide mechanisms to clone a virtual machine to another physical device.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;What-is-LVM?&#34;&gt;What is LVM?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LVM (Logical Volume Manager)&lt;/strong&gt; is an &lt;strong&gt;abstraction layer between a storage device and a file system&lt;/strong&gt;. We get many advantages from using LVM, but the main advantage is that we have much more flexibility when it comes to managing partitions. Suppose we create four partitions on our storage disk. If for any reason we need to expand the storage of the first three partitions, we will not be able to because there is no space available next to them. In case we want to extend the last partition, we will always have the limit imposed by the disk. In other words, we will not be able to manipulate partitions in a friendly way. Thanks to LVM, all these problems are solved.&lt;br&gt; By using LVM, &lt;strong&gt;we can expand the storage of any partition&lt;/strong&gt; (now known as a logical volume) whenever we want without worrying about the contiguous space available on each logical volume. We can do this with available storage located on different physical disks (which we cannot do with traditional partitions). We can also move different logical volumes between physical devices. Of course, &lt;strong&gt;services and processes will work the same way they always have&lt;/strong&gt;. But to understand all this, we have to know:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Physical Volume (PV):&lt;/b&gt; physical storage device. It can be a hard disk, an SD card, a floppy disk, etc. This device provides us with storage available to use.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Volume Group (VG):&lt;/b&gt; to use the space provided by a PV, it must be allocated in a volume group. It is like a virtual storage disk that will be used by logical volumes. VGs can grow over time by adding new VPs.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Logical volume (LV):&lt;/b&gt; these devices will be the ones we will use to create file systems, swaps, virtual machines, etc. If the VG is the storage disk, the LV are the partitions that are made on this disk.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;What-is-AppArmor?&#34;&gt;What is AppArmor?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AppArmor provides &lt;strong&gt;Mandatory Access Control (MAC) security&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, &lt;strong&gt;AppAmor allows the system administrator to restrict the actions that processes can perform&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, if an installed application can take photos by accessing the camera application, but the administrator denies this privilege, the application will not be able to access the camera application. If a vulnerability occurs (some of the restricted tasks are performed), AppArmor blocks the application so that the damage does not spread to the rest of the system.&lt;br&gt; In AppArmor, &lt;strong&gt;processes are restricted by profiles&lt;/strong&gt;. Profiles can work in complain-mode and in enforce-mode. In enforce mode, AppArmor prohibits applications from performing restricted tasks. In complain-mode, AppArmor allows applications to do these tasks, but creates a registry entry to display the complaint.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Apt-and-Aptitute&#34;&gt;What is the difference between Apt and Aptitute?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Debian-based OS distributions, &lt;strong&gt;the default package manager we can use is dpkg&lt;/strong&gt;. This tool allows us to install, remove and manage programs on our operating system. However, in most cases, these programs come with a list of dependencies that must be installed for the main program to function properly. One option is to manually install these dependencies. However, &lt;strong&gt;APT (Advanced Package Tool)&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a tool that uses dpkg, &lt;strong&gt;can be used to install all the necessary dependencies when installing a program&lt;/strong&gt;. So now we can install a useful program with a single command.&lt;br&gt; APT can work with different back-ends and fron-ends to make use of its services. One of them is &lt;strong&gt;apt-get&lt;/strong&gt;, which &lt;strong&gt;allows us to install and remove packages&lt;/strong&gt;. Along with apt-get, there are also many tools like apt-cache to manage programs. In this case, &lt;strong&gt;apt-get and apt-cache are used by apt&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to apt we can install .deb programs easily and without worrying about dependencies. But in case we want to use a graphical interface, we will have to use aptitude. &lt;strong&gt;Aptitude also does better control of dependencies&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing the user to choose between different dependencies when installing a program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;How-to-use-SSH?&#34;&gt;How to use SSH?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSH or &lt;strong&gt;Secure Shell&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;remote administration protocol that allows users to control and modify their servers&lt;/strong&gt; over the Internet thanks to an authentication mechanism. Provides a mechanism to authenticate a user remotely, transfer data from the client to the host, and return a response to the request made by the client.&lt;br&gt; SSH was created as an alternative to Telnet, which does not encrypt the information that is sent. &lt;strong&gt;SSH uses encryption techniques&lt;/strong&gt; to ensure that all client-to-host and host-to-client communications are done in encrypted form. One of the advantages of SSH is that a user using Linux or MacOS can use SSH on their server to communicate with it remotely through their computer&#39;s terminal. Once authenticated, that user will be able to use the terminal to work on the server.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; The command used to connect to a server with ssh is:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh {username}@{IP_host} -p {port}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are three different techniques that SSH uses to encrypt:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Symmetric encryption:&lt;/b&gt; a method that uses the same secret key for both encryption and decryption of a message, for both the client and the host. Anyone who knows the password can access the message that has been transmitted.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Asymmetric encryption:&lt;/b&gt; uses two separate keys for encryption and decryption. These are known as the public key and the private key. Together, they form the public-private key pair.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hashing:&lt;/b&gt; another form of cryptography used by SSH. Hash functions are made in a way that they don&#39;t need to be decrypted. If a client has the correct input, they can create a cryptographic hash and SSH will check if both hashes are the same.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;UFW-with-SSH&#34;&gt;How to implement UFW with SSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UFW (Uncomplicated Firewall)&lt;/strong&gt; is a software application responsible for ensuring that the system administrator can &lt;strong&gt;manage iptables in a simple way&lt;/strong&gt;. Since it is very difficult to work with iptables, UFW provides us with an interface to modify the firewall of our device &lt;strong&gt;(netfilter)&lt;/strong&gt; without compromising security. Once we have UFW installed, we can choose which ports we want to allow connections, and which ports we want to close. This will also be very useful with SSH, greatly improving all security related to communications between devices.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;what-is-cron&#34;&gt;What is cron and what is wall?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once we know a little more about how to build a server inside a Virtual Machine (remember that you also have to look in other pages apart from this README), we will see two commands that will be very helpful in case of being system administrators. These commands are:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cron:&lt;/strong&gt; Linux task manager that allows us to execute commands at a certain time. We can automate some tasks just by telling cron what command we want to run at a specific time. For example, if we want to restart our server every day at 4:00 am, instead of having to wake up at that time, cron will do it for us.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wall:&lt;/strong&gt; command used by the root user to send a message to all users currently connected to the server. If the system administrator wants to alert about a major server change that could cause users to log out, the root user could alert them with wall.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, the latest stable version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;Debian 10 Buster&lt;/em&gt;. Watch &lt;em&gt;bonus&lt;/em&gt; installation walkthrough &lt;em&gt;(no audio)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/2w-2MX5QrQw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 1: Installing &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Switch to &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; and its environment via &lt;code&gt;su -&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ su -&#xA;Password:&#xA;#&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;apt install sudo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# apt install sudo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep sudo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# dpkg -l | grep sudo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Adding User to &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; Group&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add user to &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; sudo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; sudo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, add user to &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# usermod -aG sudo &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether user was successfully added to &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;getent group sudo&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ getent group sudo&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;reboot&lt;/code&gt; for changes to take effect, then log in and verify &lt;em&gt;sudopowers&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo -v&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# reboot&#xA;&amp;lt;---&amp;gt;&#xA;Debian GNU/Linux 10 &amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt; tty1&#xA;&#xA;&amp;lt;hostname&amp;gt; login: &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;Password: &amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&#xA;&amp;lt;---&amp;gt;&#xA;$ sudo -v&#xA;[sudo] password for &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;: &amp;lt;password&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Running &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;-Privileged Commands&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;From here on out, run &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;-privileged commands via prefix &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt;. For instance:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt update&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 4: Configuring &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/sudoers.d/&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; shall not end in &lt;code&gt;~&lt;/code&gt; or contain &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/sudoers.d/&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To limit authentication using &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; to 3 attempts &lt;em&gt;(defaults to 3 anyway)&lt;/em&gt; in the event of an incorrect password, add below line to the file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults        passwd_tries=3&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To add a custom error message in the event of an incorrect password:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults        badpass_message=&#34;&amp;lt;custom-error-message&amp;gt;&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To log all &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; commands to &lt;code&gt;/var/log/sudo/&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mkdir /var/log/sudo&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;Defaults        logfile=&#34;/var/log/sudo/&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&#34;&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To archive all &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; inputs &amp;amp; outputs to &lt;code&gt;/var/log/sudo/&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults        log_input,log_output&#xA;Defaults        iolog_dir=&#34;/var/log/sudo&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To require &lt;em&gt;TTY&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults        requiretty&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set &lt;em&gt;sudo&lt;/em&gt; paths to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/sbin:/usr/local/bin:/usr/sbin:/usr/bin:/sbin:/bin:/snap/bin&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Defaults        secure_path=&#34;/usr/local/sbin:/usr/local/bin:/usr/sbin:/usr/bin:/sbin:/bin:/snap/bin&#34;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SSH&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 1: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring SSH&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;openssh-server&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install openssh-server&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install openssh-server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;openssh-server&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep ssh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep ssh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure SSH via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/ssh/sshd_config&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set up SSH using Port 4242, replace below line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;13 #Port 22&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;13 Port 4242&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To disable SSH login as &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; irregardless of authentication mechanism, replace below line&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;32 #PermitRootLogin prohibit-password&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;32 PermitRootLogin no&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check SSH status via &lt;code&gt;sudo service ssh status&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo service ssh status&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, check SSH status via &lt;code&gt;systemctl status ssh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ systemctl status ssh&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring UFW&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;ufw&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install ufw&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install ufw&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;ufw&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep ufw&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep ufw&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enable Firewall via &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw enable&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo ufw enable&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allow incoming connections using Port 4242 via &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow 4242&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo ufw allow 4242&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check UFW status via &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw status&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo ufw status&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Connecting to Server via SSH&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;SSH into your virtual machine using Port 4242 via &lt;code&gt;ssh &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;ip-address&amp;gt; -p 4242&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ssh &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;ip-address&amp;gt; -p 4242&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terminate SSH session at any time via &lt;code&gt;logout&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ logout&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, terminate SSH session via &lt;code&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ exit&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;User Management&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 1: Setting Up a Strong Password Policy&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Password Age&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure password age policy via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/login.defs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/login.defs&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set password to expire every 30 days, replace below line&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;160 PASS_MAX_DAYS   99999&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;160 PASS_MAX_DAYS   30&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set minimum number of days between password changes to 2 days, replace below line&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;161 PASS_MIN_DAYS   0&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;161 PASS_MIN_DAYS   2&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To send user a warning message 7 days &lt;em&gt;(defaults to 7 anyway)&lt;/em&gt; before password expiry, keep below line as is.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;162 PASS_WARN_AGE   7&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Password Strength&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, to set up policies in relation to password strength, install the &lt;em&gt;libpam-pwquality&lt;/em&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install libpam-pwquality&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;libpam-pwquality&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep libpam-pwquality&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep libpam-pwquality&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure password strength policy via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/pam.d/common-password&lt;/code&gt;, specifically the below line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/pam.d/common-password&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;25 password        requisite                       pam_pwquality.so retry=3&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set password minimum length to 10 characters, add below option to the above line.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;minlen=10&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To require password to contain at least an uppercase character and a numeric character:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ucredit=-1 dcredit=-1&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set a maximum of 3 consecutive identical characters:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;maxrepeat=3&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To reject the password if it contains &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; in some form:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;reject_username&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set the number of changes required in the new password from the old password to 7:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;difok=7&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To implement the same policy on &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;enforce_for_root&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it should look like the below:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;password        requisite                       pam_pwquality.so retry=3 minlen=10 ucredit=-1 dcredit=-1 maxrepeat=3 reject_username difok=7 enforce_for_root&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 2: Creating a New User&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create new user via &lt;code&gt;sudo adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether user was successfully created via &lt;code&gt;getent passwd &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ getent passwd &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify newly-created user&#39;s password expiry information via &lt;code&gt;sudo chage -l &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo chage -l &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;Last password change&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;: &amp;lt;last-password-change-date&amp;gt;&#xA;Password expires&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;: &amp;lt;last-password-change-date + PASS_MAX_DAYS&amp;gt;&#xA;Password inactive&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;: never&#xA;Account expires&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;&#x9;: never&#xA;Minimum number of days between password change&#x9;&#x9;: &amp;lt;PASS_MIN_DAYS&amp;gt;&#xA;Maximum number of days between password change&#x9;&#x9;: &amp;lt;PASS_MAX_DAYS&amp;gt;&#xA;Number of days of warning before password expires&#x9;: &amp;lt;PASS_WARN_AGE&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Step 3: Creating a New Group&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create new &lt;em&gt;user42&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;sudo addgroup user42&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo addgroup user42&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Add user to &lt;em&gt;user42&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;sudo adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; user42&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo adduser &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; user42&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, add user to &lt;em&gt;user42&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;sudo usermod -aG user42 &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo usermod -aG user42 &amp;lt;username&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether user was successfully added to &lt;em&gt;user42&lt;/em&gt; group via &lt;code&gt;getent group user42&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ getent group user42&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Setting Up a &lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt; Job&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure &lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo crontab -u root -e&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo crontab -u root -e&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To schedule a shell script to run every 10 minutes, replace below line&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;23 # m h  dom mon dow   command&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;23 */10 * * * * sh /path/to/script&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;em&gt;root&lt;/em&gt;&#39;s scheduled &lt;em&gt;cron&lt;/em&gt; jobs via &lt;code&gt;sudo crontab -u root -l&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo crontab -u root -l&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Monitoring&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have to create a simple script called &lt;code&gt;monitoring.sh&lt;/code&gt; It must be developed in bash. At server startup, the script will display some information (listed below) on all ter- minals every 10 minutes (take a look at wall). The banner is optional. No error must be visible. Your script must always be able to display the following information:&lt;br&gt; • The architecture of your operating system and its kernel version.&lt;br&gt; • The number of physical processors.&lt;br&gt; • The number of virtual processors.&lt;br&gt; • The current available RAM on your server and its utilization rate as a percentage.&lt;br&gt; • The current available memory on your server and its utilization rate as a percentage.&lt;br&gt; • The current utilization rate of your processors as a percentage.&lt;br&gt; • The date and time of the last reboot.&lt;br&gt; • Whether LVM is active or not.&lt;br&gt; • The number of active connections.&lt;br&gt; • The number of users using the server.&lt;br&gt; • The IPv4 address of your server and its MAC (Media Access Control) address.&lt;br&gt; • The number of commands executed with the sudo program.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the script &lt;code&gt;monitoring.sh&lt;/code&gt; in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Bonus&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;#1: Installation&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;em&gt;bonus&lt;/em&gt; installation walkthrough &lt;em&gt;(no audio)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/2w-2MX5QrQw&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;#2: Linux Lighttpd MariaDB PHP &lt;em&gt;(LLMP)&lt;/em&gt; Stack&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Installing Lighttpd&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;lighttpd&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install lighttpd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install lighttpd&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;lighttpd&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep lighttpd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep lighttpd&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allow incoming connections using Port 80 via &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow 80&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo ufw allow 80&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring MariaDB&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;mariadb-server&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install mariadb-server&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install mariadb-server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;mariadb-server&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep mariadb-server&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep mariadb-server&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Start interactive script to remove insecure default settings via &lt;code&gt;sudo mysql_secure_installation&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mysql_secure_installation&#xA;Enter current password for root (enter for none): #Just press Enter (do not confuse database root with system root)&#xA;Set root password? [Y/n] n&#xA;Remove anonymous users? [Y/n] Y&#xA;Disallow root login remotely? [Y/n] Y&#xA;Remove test database and access to it? [Y/n] Y&#xA;Reload privilege tables now? [Y/n] Y&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Log in to the MariaDB console via &lt;code&gt;sudo mariadb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mariadb&#xA;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create new database via &lt;code&gt;CREATE DATABASE &amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; CREATE DATABASE &amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create new database user and grant them full privileges on the newly-created database via &lt;code&gt;GRANT ALL ON &amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;.* TO &#39;&amp;lt;username-2&amp;gt;&#39;@&#39;localhost&#39; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&amp;lt;password-2&amp;gt;&#39; WITH GRANT OPTION;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; GRANT ALL ON &amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;.* TO &#39;&amp;lt;username-2&amp;gt;&#39;@&#39;localhost&#39; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;&amp;lt;password-2&amp;gt;&#39; WITH GRANT OPTION;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flush the privileges via &lt;code&gt;FLUSH PRIVILEGES;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; FLUSH PRIVILEGES;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exit the MariaDB shell via &lt;code&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; exit&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether database user was successfully created by logging in to the MariaDB console via &lt;code&gt;mariadb -u &amp;lt;username-2&amp;gt; -p&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mariadb -u &amp;lt;username-2&amp;gt; -p&#xA;Enter password: &amp;lt;password-2&amp;gt;&#xA;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Confirm whether database user has access to the database via &lt;code&gt;SHOW DATABASES;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; SHOW DATABASES;&#xA;+--------------------+&#xA;| Database           |&#xA;+--------------------+&#xA;| &amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;    |&#xA;| information_schema |&#xA;+--------------------+&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exit the MariaDB shell via &lt;code&gt;exit&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MariaDB [(none)]&amp;gt; exit&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 3: Installing PHP&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;php-cgi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;php-mysql&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install php-cgi php-mysql&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install php-cgi php-mysql&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;php-cgi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;em&gt;php-mysql&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep php&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep php&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 4: Downloading &amp;amp; Configuring WordPress&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install &lt;em&gt;wget&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install wget&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install wget&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Download WordPress to &lt;code&gt;/var/www/html&lt;/code&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo wget http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz -P /var/www/html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo wget http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz -P /var/www/html&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Extract downloaded content via &lt;code&gt;sudo tar -xzvf /var/www/html/latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo tar -xzvf /var/www/html/latest.tar.gz&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remove tarball via &lt;code&gt;sudo rm /var/www/html/latest.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo rm /var/www/html/latest.tar.gz&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copy content of &lt;code&gt;/var/www/html/wordpress&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/var/www/html&lt;/code&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo cp -r /var/www/html/wordpress/* /var/www/html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo cp -r /var/www/html/wordpress/* /var/www/html&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remove &lt;code&gt;/var/www/html/wordpress&lt;/code&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo rm -rf /var/www/html/wordpress&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo rm -rf /var/www/html/wordpress&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Create WordPress configuration file from its sample via &lt;code&gt;sudo cp /var/www/html/wp-config-sample.php /var/www/html/wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo cp /var/www/html/wp-config-sample.php /var/www/html/wp-config.php&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure WordPress to reference previously-created MariaDB database &amp;amp; user via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /var/www/html/wp-config.php&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /var/www/html/wp-config.php&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Replace the below&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;23 define( &#39;DB_NAME&#39;, &#39;database_name_here&#39; );^M&#xA;26 define( &#39;DB_USER&#39;, &#39;username_here&#39; );^M&#xA;29 define( &#39;DB_PASSWORD&#39;, &#39;password_here&#39; );^M&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;with:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;23 define( &#39;DB_NAME&#39;, &#39;&amp;lt;database-name&amp;gt;&#39; );^M&#xA;26 define( &#39;DB_USER&#39;, &#39;&amp;lt;username-2&amp;gt;&#39; );^M&#xA;29 define( &#39;DB_PASSWORD&#39;, &#39;&amp;lt;password-2&amp;gt;&#39; );^M&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 5: Configuring Lighttpd&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enable below modules via &lt;code&gt;sudo lighty-enable-mod fastcgi; sudo lighty-enable-mod fastcgi-php; sudo service lighttpd force-reload&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo lighty-enable-mod fastcgi&#xA;$ sudo lighty-enable-mod fastcgi-php&#xA;$ sudo service lighttpd force-reload&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;#3: File Transfer Protocol &lt;em&gt;(FTP)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 1: Installing &amp;amp; Configuring FTP&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install FTP via &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install vsftpd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo apt install vsftpd&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Verify whether &lt;em&gt;vsftpd&lt;/em&gt; was successfully installed via &lt;code&gt;dpkg -l | grep vsftpd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ dpkg -l | grep vsftpd&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Allow incoming connections using Port 21 via &lt;code&gt;sudo ufw allow 21&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo ufw allow 21&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure &lt;em&gt;vsftpd&lt;/em&gt; via &lt;code&gt;sudo vi /etc/vsftpd.conf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/vsftpd.conf&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To enable any form of FTP write command, uncomment below line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;31 #write_enable=YES&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To set root folder for FTP-connected user to &lt;code&gt;/home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/ftp&lt;/code&gt;, add below lines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo mkdir /home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/ftp&#xA;$ sudo mkdir /home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/ftp/files&#xA;$ sudo chown nobody:nogroup /home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/ftp&#xA;$ sudo chmod a-w /home/&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;/ftp&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;user_sub_token=$USER&#xA;local_root=/home/$USER/ftp&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To prevent user from accessing files or using commands outside the directory tree, uncomment below line:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;114 #chroot_local_user=YES&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To whitelist FTP, add below lines:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo vi /etc/vsftpd.userlist&#xA;$ echo &amp;lt;username&amp;gt; | sudo tee -a /etc/vsftpd.userlist&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;userlist_enable=YES&#xA;userlist_file=/etc/vsftpd.userlist&#xA;userlist_deny=NO&#xA;&amp;lt;~~~&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Step 2: Connecting to Server via FTP&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;FTP into your virtual machine via &lt;code&gt;ftp &amp;lt;ip-address&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ftp &amp;lt;ip-address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Terminate FTP session at any time via &lt;code&gt;CTRL + D&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;peereval&#34;&gt;Submission and peer-evaluation for 1337/42 Students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You only have to turn in a signature.txt file at the root of your Git repository. You must paste in it the signature of your machine’s virtual disk. To get this signature, you first have to open the default installation folder (it is the folder where your VMs are saved):&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Windows: &lt;code&gt;%HOMEDRIVE%%HOMEPATH%\VirtualBox VMs\&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Linux: &lt;code&gt;~/VirtualBox VMs/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• MacM1: &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Containers/com.utmapp.UTM/Data/Documents/ &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• MacOS: &lt;code&gt; ~/VirtualBox VMs/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then, retrieve the signature from the &#34;.vdi&#34; file (or &#34;.qcow2 for UTM’users) of your virtual machine in sha1 format. Below are 4 command examples for a centos_serv.vdi file:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Windows: &lt;code&gt;certUtil -hashfile centos_serv.vdi sha1 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• Linux: &lt;code&gt;sha1sum centos_serv.vdi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• For Mac M1: &lt;code&gt;shasum Centos.utm/Images/disk-0.qcow2 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• MacOS: &lt;code&gt;shasum centos_serv.vdi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an example of what kind of output you will get:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;• &lt;code&gt;6e657c4619944be17df3c31faa030c25e43e40af&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;evalknowledge&#34;&gt;Evalknowledge.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Little Q&amp;amp;A from Subject and whattocheck as evaluator. You can find it in this repository.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think it&#39;s done for now. I highly recommend repeating the installation process several times, if possible, in order to remember and understand everything well. Especially if this is your first time working both Linux and a virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>VR-25/acc</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T01:37:12Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-10:/VR-25/acc</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/VR-25/acc" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Advanced Charging Controller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Advanced Charging Controller (ACC)&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#description&#34;&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#license&#34;&gt;LICENSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#disclaimer&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#warnings&#34;&gt;WARNINGS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#donations&#34;&gt;DONATIONS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#prerequisites&#34;&gt;PREREQUISITES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#quick-start-guide&#34;&gt;QUICK START GUIDE&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#building-andor-installing-from-source&#34;&gt;BUILDING AND/OR INSTALLING FROM SOURCE&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#dependencies-build&#34;&gt;Dependencies (Build)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#build-tarballs-and-flashable-zips&#34;&gt;Build Tarballs and Flashable Zips&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#notes-1&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#install-from-local-source-or-github&#34;&gt;Install from Local Source or GitHub&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;    &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#notes-2&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;DEFAULT CONFIGURATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#setupusage&#34;&gt;SETUP/USAGE&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#terminal-commands&#34;&gt;Terminal Commands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#plugins&#34;&gt;PLUGINS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#notestips-for-front-end-developers&#34;&gt;NOTES/TIPS FOR FRONT-END DEVELOPERS&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#basics&#34;&gt;Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#installingupgrading-acc&#34;&gt;Installing/Upgrading ACC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#uninstalling-acc&#34;&gt;Uninstalling ACC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#initializing-acc&#34;&gt;Initializing ACC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#managing-acc&#34;&gt;Managing ACC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#the-output-of---info&#34;&gt;The Output of --info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#profiles&#34;&gt;Profiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#more&#34;&gt;More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#troubleshooting&#34;&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#acc--t-results-seem-inconsistent&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;acc -t&lt;/code&gt; Results Seem Inconsistent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#battery-capacity--level-doesnt-seem-right&#34;&gt;Battery Capacity (% Level) Doesn&#39;t Seem Right&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#charging-switch&#34;&gt;Charging Switch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#custom-max-charging-voltage-and-current-limits&#34;&gt;Custom Max Charging Voltage And Current Limits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#diagnosticslogs&#34;&gt;Diagnostics/Logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#finding-additionalpotential-charging-switches-quickly&#34;&gt;Finding Additional/Potential Charging Switches Quickly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#install-upgrade-stop-and-restart-processes-seem-to-take-too-long&#34;&gt;Install, Upgrade, Stop and Restart Processes Seem to Take Too Long&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#restore-default-config&#34;&gt;Restore Default Config&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#samsung-charging-always-stops-at-70-capacity&#34;&gt;Samsung, Charging &lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt; Stops at 70% Capacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#slow-charging&#34;&gt;Slow Charging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#unable-to-charge&#34;&gt;Unable to Charge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#unexpected-reboots&#34;&gt;Unexpected Reboots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#warp-vooc-and-other-fast-charging-tech&#34;&gt;WARP, VOOC and Other Fast Charging Tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#why-did-accd-stop&#34;&gt;Why Did accd Stop?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#power-supply-logs-help-needed&#34;&gt;POWER SUPPLY LOGS (HELP NEEDED)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#localization&#34;&gt;LOCALIZATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#tips&#34;&gt;TIPS&lt;/a&gt; &#xA;  &lt;ul&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#always-limit-the-charging-current-if-your-battery-is-old-andor-tends-to-discharge-too-fast&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt; Limit the Charging Current If Your Battery is Old and/or Tends to Discharge Too Fast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#current-and-voltage-based-charging-control&#34;&gt;Current and Voltage Based Charging Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#generic&#34;&gt;Generic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#google-pixel-devices&#34;&gt;Google Pixel Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/override_battery_mah_capacity&#34;&gt;Override Battery mAh Capacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/override_broken_temperature_sensor&#34;&gt;Override Broken Temperature Sensor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;  &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS (FAQ)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#links&#34;&gt;LINKS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DESCRIPTION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC is an Android software mainly intended for &lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-808-how-to-prolong-lithium-based-batteries&#34;&gt;extending battery service life&lt;/a&gt;. In a nutshell, this is achieved through limiting charging current, temperature, and voltage. Any root solution is supported. Regardless of whether the system is rooted with Magisk, the installation is always &#34;systemless&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LICENSE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2017-2022, VR25&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the GNU General Public License for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program. If not, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&#34;&gt;https://www.gnu.org/licenses/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Always read/reread this reference prior to installing/upgrading this software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;While no cats have been harmed, the author assumes no responsibility for anything that might break due to the use/misuse of it.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To prevent fraud, do NOT mirror any link associated with this project. Do NOT share builds (tarballs/zips)! Share official links instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;WARNINGS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC manipulates Android low level (&lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/lite/?q=kernel+android&#34;&gt;kernel&lt;/a&gt;) parameters which control the charging circuitry. The author assumes no responsibility under anything that might break due to the use/misuse of this software. By choosing to use/misuse it, you agree to do so at your own risk!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some devices, notably from Xiaomi, have a buggy PMIC (Power Management Integrated Circuit) that can be triggered by acc. The issue blocks charging. Ensure your battery does not discharge too low. Using acc&#39;s auto shutdown feature is highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.xda-developers.com/t/rom-official-arrowos-11-0-android-11-0-vayu-bhima.4267263/post-85119331&#34;&gt;this XDA post&lt;/a&gt; for additional details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lybxlpsv&#34;&gt;lybxlpsv&lt;/a&gt; suggests booting into bootloader and then back into system to reset the PMIC.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DONATIONS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please, support the project with donations (&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#links&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom). As the project gets bigger and more popular, the need for coffee goes up as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;PREREQUISITES&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-808-how-to-prolong-lithium-based-batteries&#34;&gt;Must read - how to prolong lithium ion batteries lifespan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Android or Android based OS&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Any root solution (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/topjohnwu/Magisk&#34;&gt;Magisk&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Magisk-Modules-Repo/busybox-ndk&#34;&gt;Busybox*&lt;/a&gt; (only if not rooted with Magisk)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Non-Magisk users can enable acc auto-start by running /data/adb/vr25/acc/service.sh, a copy of, or a link to it - with init.d or an app that emulates it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Terminal emulator&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Text editor (optional)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;* A busybox binary can simply be placed in /data/adb/vr25/bin/. Permissions (0700) are set automatically, as needed. Precedence: /data/adb/vr25/bin/busybox &amp;gt; Magisk&#39;s busybox &amp;gt; system&#39;s busybox&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other executables or static binaries can also be placed in /data/adb/vr25/bin/ (with proper permissions) instead of being installed system-wide.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;QUICK START GUIDE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;0&#34;&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;All commands/actions require root.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Install/upgrade: flash* the zip or use a front-end app. There are two additional ways of upgrading: &lt;code&gt;acc --upgrade&lt;/code&gt; (online) and &lt;code&gt;acc --flash&lt;/code&gt; (zip flasher). Rebooting after installation/removal is generally unnecessary. Manual uninstall before upgrade is unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[Optional] run &lt;code&gt;acc&lt;/code&gt; (wizard). That&#39;s the main command to remember.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[Optional] run &lt;code&gt;acc pause_capacity resume_capacity&lt;/code&gt; (default &lt;code&gt;75 70&lt;/code&gt;) to set the battery levels at which charging should pause and resume, respectively.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you come across any issues, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#troubleshooting&#34;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#tips&#34;&gt;tips&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#frequently-asked-questions-faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt; sections below. Read as much as you can, prior to reporting issues and/or asking questions. Oftentimes, solutions/answers will be right before your eyes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Steps &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;3&lt;/code&gt; are optional because there are default settings. For details, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; section below. Users are encouraged to try step &lt;code&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; - to familiarize themselves with the available options.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Settings can be overwhelming. Start with what you understand. The default configuration has you covered. Don&#39;t ever feel like you have to configure everything. You probably shouldn&#39;t anyway - unless you really know what you&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Uninstall: run &lt;code&gt;acc --uninstall&lt;/code&gt; or flash* &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/acc-uninstaller.zip&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC runs in some recovery environments as well. Unless the zip is flashed again, manual initialization is required. The initialization command is &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc/service.sh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;BUILDING AND/OR INSTALLING FROM SOURCE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Dependencies (Build)&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;git, wget, or curl (pick one)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;zip&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Build Tarballs and Flashable Zips&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Download and extract the source code: &lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/VR-25/acc.git&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;wget https://github.com/VR-25/acc/archive/master.tar.gz -O - | tar -xz&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;curl -L# https://github.com/VR-25/acc/archive/master.tar.gz | tar -xz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd acc*&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sh build.sh&lt;/code&gt; (or double-click &lt;code&gt;build.bat&lt;/code&gt; on Windows 10, if you have Windows subsystem for Linux (with zip) installed)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;build.sh automatically sets/corrects &lt;code&gt;id=*&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;*.sh&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;update-binary&lt;/code&gt; files. Refer to framework-details.txt for a full list of tasks carried out by it. To skip generating archives, run the build script with a random argument (e.g. bash build.sh h).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;To update the local source code, run &lt;code&gt;git pull --force&lt;/code&gt; or re-download it (with wget/curl) as described above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Install from Local Source or GitHub&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[export installDir=&amp;lt;parent install dir&amp;gt;] sh install.sh&lt;/code&gt; installs acc from the extracted source.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sh install-online.sh [-c|--changelog] [-f|--force] [-k|--insecure] [-n|--non-interactive] [%parent install dir%] [commit]&lt;/code&gt; downloads and installs acc from GitHub - e.g., &lt;code&gt;sh install-online.sh dev&lt;/code&gt;. The order of arguments doesn&#39;t matter. For upgrades, if &lt;code&gt;%parent install dir%&lt;/code&gt; is not supplied, the original/current is used.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sh install-tarball.sh [module id, default: acc] [parent install dir (e.g., /data/data/mattecarra.accapp/files)]&lt;/code&gt; installs the tarball (acc*gz) from the script&#39;s location. The archive must be in the same directory as this script - and obtained from GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/archive/$commit.tar.gz&#34;&gt;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/archive/$commit.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt; ($commit examples: master, dev, v2020.5.20-rc).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h4&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;install-online.sh&lt;/code&gt; is the &lt;code&gt;acc --upgrade&lt;/code&gt; back-end.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The default parent installation directories, in order of priority, are: &lt;code&gt;/data/data/mattecarra.accapp/files/&lt;/code&gt; (ACC App, but only if Magisk is not installed), &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/modules/&lt;/code&gt; (Magisk) and &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/&lt;/code&gt; (other root solutions).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;No argument/option is strictly mandatory. The exception is &lt;code&gt;--non-interactive&lt;/code&gt; for front-end apps.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;--force&lt;/code&gt; option to &lt;code&gt;install-online.sh&lt;/code&gt; is meant for re-installation and downgrading.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sh install-online.sh --changelog --non-interactive&lt;/code&gt; prints the version code (integer) and changelog URL (string) when an update is available. In interactive mode, it also asks the user whether they want to download and install the update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;You may also want to read &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#terminal-commands&#34;&gt;Terminal Commands&lt;/a&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Exit Codes&lt;/code&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;DEFAULT CONFIGURATION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#DC#&#xA;&#xA;configVerCode=202207300&#xA;&#xA;ampFactor=&#xA;battStatusWorkaround=true&#xA;capacity=(5 50 15 75 auto false)&#xA;cooldownCurrent=&#xA;cooldownRatio=()&#xA;currentWorkaround=false&#xA;dischargePolarity=&#xA;forceOff=false&#xA;idleThreshold=40&#xA;language=en&#xA;offMid=true&#xA;prioritizeBattIdleMode=true&#xA;rebootResume=false&#xA;resetBattStats=(false false false)&#xA;temperature=(35 45 90 55)&#xA;tempLevel=0&#xA;voltFactor=&#xA;&#xA;applyOnBoot=()&#xA;&#xA;applyOnPlug=()&#xA;&#xA;battStatusOverride=&#39;&#39;&#xA;&#xA;chargingSwitch=()&#xA;&#xA;cooldownCustom=()&#xA;&#xA;maxChargingCurrent=()&#xA;&#xA;maxChargingVoltage=()&#xA;&#xA;runCmdOnPause=&#39;&#39;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# WARNINGS&#xA;&#xA;# Do not edit this in Windows Notepad, ever!&#xA;# It replaces LF (Linux/Unix) with CRLF (Windows) line endings.&#xA;&#xA;# Nullifying values that should not be null causes unexpected behavior.&#xA;# However, doing so with &#34;--set var=&#34; restores the default value of &#34;var&#34;.&#xA;# In other words, for regular users, &#34;--set&#34; is safer than modifying the config file directly.&#xA;&#xA;# Do not feel like you must configure everything!&#xA;# Do not change what you don&#39;t understand.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# NOTES&#xA;&#xA;# The daemon does not have to be restarted after making changes to this file - unless one of the changes is charging_switch.&#xA;&#xA;# A change to current_workaround (cw) only takes effect after an acc [re]initialization. Install, upgrade, &#34;accd --init&#34; and system reboot actions do it.&#xA;&#xA;# If those 2 variables are updated with &#34;acc --set&#34; (does NOT apply to acca --set), accd is restarted automatically (--init is implied, as needed).&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# INTERNAL FUNCTIONS&#xA;&#xA;# at H:MM &#39;command...&#39;   scheduler&#xA;# e.g.,&#xA;#   at 2:14 acc --notif &#39;2:14 AM now!&#39;&#xA;#   at 22:30 acc --notif &#39;22:30 now!&#39;&#xA;&#xA;# calc &amp;lt;operation...&amp;gt;   float  calculator&#xA;&#xA;# set_temp_level &amp;lt;0-100&amp;gt;   refer to temp_level (tl) below&#xA;&#xA;# $(voltage_now)   prints the instantaneous charging voltage&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# INTERNAL VARIABLES&#xA;&#xA;# $batt   expands to the /sys/class/power_supply/battery (or equivalent) directory&#xA;# $battCapacity   $batt/capacity file&#xA;# $battStatus   $batt/status file&#xA;# $currFile   current_now file&#xA;# $temp   temperature reporting file&#xA;# ${isAccd:-false}   true|false (whether accd in running)&#xA;# _$status   Charging|Discharging|Idle&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# DATE&#xA;# $(date +FORMAT)&#xA;# FORMAT specifies display format string using strftime(3) syntax:&#xA;&#xA;# %% literal %             %n newline              %t tab&#xA;# %S seconds (00-60)       %M minute (00-59)       %m month (01-12)&#xA;# %H hour (0-23)           %I hour (01-12)         %p AM/PM&#xA;# %y short year (00-99)    %Y year                 %C century&#xA;# %a short weekday name    %A weekday name         %u day of week (1-7, 1=mon)&#xA;# %b short month name      %B month name           %Z timezone name&#xA;# %j day of year (001-366) %d day of month (01-31) %e day of month ( 1-31)&#xA;# %N nanosec (output only)&#xA;&#xA;# %U Week of year (0-53 start sunday)   %W Week of year (0-53 start monday)&#xA;# %V Week of year (1-53 start monday, week &amp;lt; 4 days not part of this year)&#xA;&#xA;# %F &#34;%Y-%m-%d&#34;     %R &#34;%H:%M&#34;        %T &#34;%H:%M:%S&#34;    %z numeric timezone&#xA;# %D &#34;%m/%d/%y&#34;     %r &#34;%I:%M:%S %p&#34;  %h &#34;%b&#34;          %s unix epoch time&#xA;# %x locale date    %X locale time    %c locale date/time&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# VALUES&#xA;&#xA;# ampFactor=amp_factor=MULTIPLIER NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# applyOnBoot=apply_on_boot=([CTRL_FILE1::RAW_VALUE[::DEFAULT]] [CTRL_FILE2::RAW_VALUE[::DEFAULT]...] [--exit]) NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# applyOnPlug=apply_on_plug=([CTRL_FILE1::RAW_VALUE[::DEFAULT]] [CTRL_FILE2::RAW_VALUE[::DEFAULT]...]) NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# battStatusOverride=batt_status_override=Idle|Discharging|&#39;code to PRINT value for _status&#39; NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# battStatusWorkaround=batt_status_workaround=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# capacity=(shutdown_capacity=INT cooldown_capacity=INT resume_capacity=INT pause_capacity=INT capacity_sync=auto|true|false capacity_mask=BOOLEAN)&#xA;&#xA;# chargingSwitch=charging_switch=([CTRL_FILE1 ON OFF [CTRL_FILE2 ON OFF...] [--] | MILLIAMPS | 3700-4300 MILLIVOLTS]) NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# cooldownCurrent=cooldown_current=MILLIAMPS NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# cooldownCustom=cooldown_custom=(FILE THRESHOLD CHARGE_SECONDS PAUSE_SECONDS) NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# cooldownRatio=(cooldown_charge cooldown_pause) SECONDS,NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# currentWorkaround=current_workaround=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# dischargePolarity=discharge_polarity=+|- NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# forceOff=force_off=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# idleThreshold=idle_threshold=MILLIAMPS&#xA;&#xA;# language=lang=LANGUAGE_CODE NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# maxChargingCurrent=max_charging_current=(MILLIAMPS CTRL_FILE1::RAW_VALUE::DEFAULT CTRL_FILE2::RAW_VALUE::DEFAULT...)&#xA;&#xA;# maxChargingVoltage=max_charging_voltage=(MILLIVOLTS CTRL_FILE1::RAW_VALUE::DEFAULT CTRL_FILE2::RAW_VALUE::DEFAULT... [--exit]) NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# offMid=off_mid=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# prioritizeBattIdleMode=prioritize_batt_idle_mode=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# rebootResume=reboot_resume=BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# resetBattStats=(reset_batt_stats_on_pause reset_batt_stats_on_unplug reset_batt_stats_on_plug) BOOLEAN&#xA;&#xA;# runCmdOnPause=run_cmd_on_pause=&#39;COMMAND...&#39; NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;# temperature=(cooldown_temp=ºC max_temp=ºC max_temp_pause=SECONDS shutdown_temp=ºC)&#xA;&#xA;# tempLevel=temp_level=PERCENT (0-100)&#xA;&#xA;# voltFactor=volt_factor=MULTIPLIER NULLABLE&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# ALIASES (for use with --set only)&#xA;&#xA;# amp_factor af&#xA;# apply_on_boot ab&#xA;# apply_on_plug ap&#xA;# batt_status_override bso&#xA;# batt_status_workaround bsw&#xA;# capacity_mask cm&#xA;# capacity_sync cs&#xA;# charging_switch s&#xA;# cooldown_capacity cc&#xA;# cooldown_charge cch&#xA;# cooldown_current cdc&#xA;# cooldown_custom ccu&#xA;# cooldown_pause cp&#xA;# cooldown_temp ct&#xA;# current_workaround cw&#xA;# discharge_polarity dp&#xA;# force_off fo&#xA;# idle_threshold it&#xA;# lang l&#xA;# max_charging_current mcc&#xA;# max_charging_voltage mcv&#xA;# max_temp mt&#xA;# max_temp_pause mtp&#xA;# off_mid om&#xA;# pause_capacity pc&#xA;# prioritize_batt_idle_mode pbim&#xA;# reboot_resume rr&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_pause rbsp&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_plug rbspl&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_unplug rbsu&#xA;# resume_capacity rc&#xA;# run_cmd_on_pause rcp&#xA;# shutdown_capacity sc&#xA;# shutdown_temp st&#xA;# temp_level tl&#xA;# volt_factor vf&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# FINE, BUT WHAT DOES EACH OF THESE VARIABLES ACTUALLY MEAN?&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# configVerCode #&#xA;# This is checked during updates to determine whether the config should be patched. Do NOT modify.&#xA;# The value is not necessarily the same as acc version code.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# amp_factor (af) # Default: null&#xA;# volt_factor (vf) #&#xA;# Unit multiplier for conversion (e.g., 1V = 1000000 microvolts).&#xA;# ACC can automatically determine the units, but the mechanism is not 100% foolproof.&#xA;# Leave those properties alone, unless current/voltage info is wrong.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# apply_on_boot (ab) # Default: null&#xA;# Kernel settings to apply on boot and on daemon start/restart.&#xA;# The --exit flag (refer back to applyOnBoot=...) tells the daemon to stop after applying settings.&#xA;# If that flag is not included, default values are restored when the daemon stops.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# apply_on_plug (ap) # Default: null&#xA;# Kernel settings to apply on plug.&#xA;# This exists because certain devices reset control files (e.g., current_max) when the charger is re-plugged.&#xA;# Default values are restored when the daemon stops.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# batt_status_override (bso) # Default: null&#xA;&#xA;# Overrides the battery status determined by the not_charging function.&#xA;# It can be Idle, Discharging (both case sensitive), or logic to PRINT the desired value for the _status variable.&#xA;# When set to Idle or Discharging, _status will be set to that value if the enforced* charging switch state is off.&#xA;# It only works in conjunction with an enforced charging switch (set manually, has a trailing &#34; --&#34;).&#xA;&#xA;# Usage scenario: the switch &#34;main/cool_mode 0 1&#34; supports idle mode. However, sometimes it does not respond soon enough (e.g., due to fast charging). The user can then enforce it with &#34;acc -ss&#34; and set &#34;batt_status_override=Idle&#34;. This means, when &#34;main/cool_mode&#34; is &#34;on&#34; (0), _status will be determined by the not_charging function (as usual), but when it&#39;s off (1), _status will be Idle, bypassing the not_charging function.&#xA;&#xA;# If the user were to write their own logic, it would be something like the following:&#xA;# batt_status_override=&#39;[ $(cat main/cool_mode) -eq 1 ] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; printf Idle || :&#39;&#xA;# The &#34;|| :&#34; part is mandatory to avoid issues with &#34;set -e&#34;, which acc uses extensively.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# batt_status_workaround (bsw) # Default: true&#xA;# With this enabled, in addition to just reading POWER_SUPPLY_STATUS, if the battery is &#34;Charging&#34; and current is within -11 and 11 mA (inclusive), battery status is considered &#34;Idle&#34;.&#xA;# Status is considered &#34;Discharging&#34;, if current polarity changes after calling the disable_charging function.&#xA;# By not relying solely on the information provided by POWER_SUPPLY_STATUS, this approach dramatically boosts compatibility.&#xA;# This must be disabled on systems that report wrong/misleading charging current values.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# capacity_mask (cm) # Default: false&#xA;# Implies capacity_sync.&#xA;# This forces Android to report &#34;capacity = capacity * 100 / pause_capacity&#34;, effectively masking capacity limits.&#xA;# It also prevents Android from getting capacity readings below 2%, since some systems shutdown before battery level actually drops to 0%.&#xA;# Use case: secretly install acc on a relative&#39;s device, and enable this, so that they see pause_capacity as 100%.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# capacity_sync (cs) # Default: auto&#xA;# Some devices, notably from the Pixel lineup, have a capacity discrepancy issue between Android&#39;s battery service and the kernel.&#xA;# capacity_sync forces Android to report the actual battery capacity reported by the kernel.&#xA;# Besides, it also prevents Android from getting capacity readings below 2%, since some systems shutdown before battery level actually drops to 0%.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# charging_switch (s) # Default: null (automatic)&#xA;&#xA;# If unset, acc cycles through its database and sets the first switch/group that successfully disables charging.&#xA;# If later the set switch/group fails, acc unsets it and repeats the above.&#xA;# If all switches fail to disable charging, chargingSwitch is unset and acc/d exit with error code 7.&#xA;&#xA;# This automated process can be disabled by appending &#34; --&#34; to the switch/group.&#xA;# e.g., acc -s s=&#34;battery/charging_enabled 1 0 --&#34;&#xA;# &#34;acc -ss&#34; always appends &#34; --&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;# charging_switch=milliamps (e.g., 0-250) enables current-based charging control.&#xA;# If charging switch is set to 3700-4300 (millivolts), acc stops charging by limiting voltage.&#xA;# For details, refer to the readme&#39;s tips section.&#xA;&#xA;# Unlike the original variant, this kind of switch is never unset automatically.&#xA;# Thus, in this case, appending &#34; --&#34; to it leads to invalid syntax.&#xA;&#xA;# Unless charging is enabled first, a daemon restart is required after changing this setting (automated by &#34;acc --set&#34; (synchronous), but not by &#34;acca --set&#34; (asynchronous)).&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# cooldown_capacity (cc) # Default: 50&#xA;# Battery level or millivolts at which the cooldown cycle starts.&#xA;# Cooldown reduces battery stress induced by prolonged exposure to high temperature and high charging voltage.&#xA;# It does so through periodically pausing charging for a few seconds (cooldown_pause, more details below).&#xA;# Requires cooldown_current or cooldown_charge and cooldown_pause, explained next.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# cooldown_charge (cch) # Default: null&#xA;# cooldown_pause (cp) # Default: null&#xA;&#xA;# Those two dictate the cooldown cycle intervals (seconds).&#xA;# When not set, the cycle is disabled, unless cooldown_current is set.&#xA;# Suggested values are cch=50 and cp=10.&#xA;# If charging gets a bit slower than desired, try cch=50 and cp=5.&#xA;# Note that cooldown_capacity and cooldown_temp can be disabled individually by assigning them values that would never be reached under normal circumstances.&#xA;# cooldown_current optionally works with ratios as well (cooldown_charge: regular current, cooldown_pause: cooldown_current).&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# cooldown_current (cdc) # Default: null&#xA;# Instead of pausing charging for cooldown_pause seconds, limit the max charging current (e.g., to 500 mA).&#xA;# cooldown_pause and cooldown_charge are optional.&#xA;# Note: devices don&#39;t support just about any current value. Multiples of 500 mA tend to have higher compatibility.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# cooldown_custom (ccu) # Default: null&#xA;# When cooldown_capacity and/or cooldown_temp don&#39;t suit your needs, this comes to the rescue.&#xA;# It overrides the regular cooldown settings.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# cooldown_temp (ct) # Default: 35&#xA;# Temperature (°C) at which the cooldown cycle starts.&#xA;# Cooldown reduces the battery degradation rate by lowering the device&#39;s temperature.&#xA;# Requires cooldown_current or cooldown_charge and cooldown_pause, explained above.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# current_workaround (cw) # Default: false&#xA;# Only use current control files whose paths match &#34;batt&#34;.&#xA;# This is necessary only if the current limit affects both input and charging current values (breaking idle mode when charging_switch=milliamps).&#xA;# Try this if low current values don&#39;t work.&#xA;# &#34;accd --init&#34; is required after changing this (automated by &#34;acc --set&#34;).&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# discharge_polarity (dp) # Default: null&#xA;# This overrides the automatic current polarity (+|-) detection.&#xA;# It&#39;s only relevant when batt_status_workaround=true.&#xA;# Polarity may change with a kernel upgrade. If this setting is wrong, charging control won&#39;t work if batt_status_workaround is on.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# force_off (fo) # Default: false&#xA;# Enable this only if the set charging switch is stubbornly reset by the system.&#xA;# Oftentimes, userspace thermal management daemons (e.g., mi_thermald) and/or driver issues are behind charging control issues.&#xA;# Some people &#34;systemlessly&#34; disable certain thermal daemons with Magisk. While this is not a general recommendation, they swear by it.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# idle_threshold (it) # Default: 40&#xA;# Current threshold (absolute value) in milliamps to consider _status=Idle.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# lang (l) # Default: en&#xA;# Display language, when null, English (en) is assumed.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# max_charging_current (mcc) # Default: null&#xA;# max_charging_voltage (mcv) # Default: null&#xA;&#xA;# Control files are automatically added.&#xA;&#xA;# Notes:&#xA;#   Devices don&#39;t support just about any current value. Multiples of 500 mA tend to have higher compatibility.&#xA;#   The maximum current that can be set via dedicated commands is 9999 mA. For voltage, the max is 4300 mV. One can override those by manually editing the config.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# max_temp (mt) # Default: 45&#xA;# max_temp_pause (mtp) # Default: 90&#xA;&#xA;# Those two work together and are NOT tied to the cooldown cycle.&#xA;# Think of max_temp as the cooldown plan B (for when the cooldown cycle doesn&#39;t help).&#xA;# On max_temp (°C), charging is paused for max_temp_pause (seconds).&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# off_mid (om) # Default: true&#xA;# Whether to turn off charging after rebooting the system or restarting accd, if capacity is within resume_capacity and pause_capacity.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# one-line scripts # Default: none&#xA;&#xA;# Every line that begins with &#34;: &#34; is interpreted as a shell (mksh) script.&#xA;# This feature can be useful for many things, including setting up persistent config profiles (source a file that overrides the main config).&#xA;# All script lines are executed whenever the config is loaded/sourced.&#xA;# This happens regularly while the daemon is running, and at least once per command run.&#xA;&#xA;# Note: due to user data encryption, files used in one-line scripts must reside somewhere in /data/adb/, just like acc&#39;s own data files. Ignore if your data isn&#39;t encrypted.&#xA;&#xA;# Tip: One can schedule tasks with the following construct:&#xA;# : sleep profile; at 22:00 &#39;acc -s pc=50 mcc=500 mcv=3900; acc -n &#34;Switched to night profile&#34;&#39;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# pause_capacity (pc) # Default: 75&#xA;# Battery level or millivolts at which charging should pause.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# prioritize_batt_idle_mode (pbim) # Default: true&#xA;&#xA;# Battery idle mode, also called &#34;standby mode&#34; or &#34;charging bypass&#34;, is the ability of running off the charger, as if the battery were disconnected from the device.&#xA;# Not all devices support this, but there&#39;s also emulated idle mode (refer to the readme).&#xA;# Emulated idle mode works on all devices.&#xA;&#xA;# If enabled, charging switches that support battery idle mode take precedence.&#xA;# This is only relevant when the switch is automatically determined -- i.e., charging_switch is not set or it has no trailing &#34; --&#34;.&#xA;# In other words, this variable is only used when acc is automatically testing charging switches.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# reboot_resume (rr) # Default: false&#xA;# Reboot (when capacity capacity is at or below resume_capacity) to re-enable charging.&#xA;# This is only for devices whose switches can&#39;t re-enable charging.&#xA;# A warning notification is posted 60 seconds prior, for the user to block the action, if they so please.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_pause (rbsp) # Default: false&#xA;# Reset battery stats after pausing charging.&#xA;&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_plug (rbspl) # Default: false&#xA;# Reset battery stats seconds after plugging the charger.&#xA;&#xA;# reset_batt_stats_on_unplug (rbsu) # Default: false&#xA;# Reset battery stats seconds after unplugging the charger.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# resume_capacity (rc) # Default: 15&#xA;# Battery level or millivolts at which charging should resume.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# run_cmd_on_pause (rcp) # Default: null&#xA;# Run commands* after pausing charging.&#xA;# * Usually a script (&#34;sh some_file&#34; or &#34;. some_file&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# shutdown_capacity (sc) # Default: 5&#xA;# When the battery is discharging, its level/millivolts is at or below shutdown_capacity, and the device has been running for 15 minutes or more, acc daemon turns the device off to reduce the discharge rate, and protect the battery from potential damage, induced by voltage below the operating range.&#xA;# A value of -1 disables it.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# shutdown_temp (st) # Default: 55&#xA;# Shutdown the system if battery temperature is at or below this value.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;# temp_level (tl) # Default: 0&#xA;# This is a current limiting hack.&#xA;# Some devices have adjustable &#34;temperature levels&#34;. At the highest level, charging current is blocked.&#xA;# The stock values are generally integers, ranging from 0 to 6, 7 or slightly more.&#xA;# For greater flexibility, this variable stores a percentage value -- which is internally converted to the system&#39;s scales.&#xA;&#xA;#/DC#&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;SETUP/USAGE&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; (above) suggests, ACC is designed to run out of the box, with little to no customization/intervention.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only command you have to remember is &lt;code&gt;acc&lt;/code&gt;. It&#39;s a wizard you&#39;ll either love or hate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you feel uncomfortable with the command line, skip this section and use a front-end app instead.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can use a &lt;code&gt;text editor&lt;/code&gt; to modify &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/config.txt&lt;/code&gt;. The config file itself has configuration instructions. Those are the same found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; section, above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Terminal Commands&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#TC#&#xA;&#xA;Usage&#xA;&#xA;  acc   Wizard&#xA;&#xA;  accd   Start/restart accd&#xA;&#xA;  accd.   Stop acc/daemon&#xA;&#xA;  accd,   Print acc/daemon status (running or not)&#xA;&#xA;  acc [pause_capacity/millivolts [resume_capacity/millivolts, default: pause_capacity/millivolts - 5%/50mV]]&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc 75 70&#xA;      acc 80 (resume_capacity defaults to 80% - 5)&#xA;      acc 3900 (same as acc 3900 3870, great idle mode alternative)&#xA;&#xA;  acc [options] [args]   Refer to the list of options below&#xA;&#xA;  acca [options] [args]   acc optimized for front-ends&#xA;&#xA;  acc[d] -x [options] [args]   Sets log=/sdcard/Download/acc[d]-${device}.log; useful for debugging unwanted reboots&#xA;&#xA;  A custom config path can be specified as first parameter (second if -x is used).&#xA;  If the file doesn&#39;t exist, the current config is cloned.&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc /data/acc-night-config.txt --set pause_capacity=45 resume_capacity=43&#xA;      acc /data/acc-night-config.txt --set --current 500&#xA;      accd /data/acc-night-config.txt --init&#xA;&#xA;  Notes regarding accd:&#xA;    - The order of &#34;--init|-i&#34; does not matter.&#xA;    - The config path string shall not contain &#34;--init|-i&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Options&#xA;&#xA;  -b|--rollback   Undo upgrade&#xA;&#xA;  -c|--config [editor] [editor_opts]   Edit config (default editor: nano/vim/vi)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -c (edit w/ nano/vim/vi)&#xA;      acc -c less&#xA;      acc -c cat&#xA;&#xA;  -c|--config a|d string|regex   Append (a) or delete (d) string/pattern to/from config&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -c a &#34;: sleep profile; at 22:00 acc -s pc=50 mcc=500 mcv=3900&#34; (append a schedule)&#xA;      acc -c d sleep (remove all lines matching &#34;sleep&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;  -d|--disable [#%, #s, #m, #h or #mv (optional)]   Disable charging&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -d 70% (do not recharge until capacity &amp;lt;= 70%)&#xA;      acc -d 1h (do not recharge until 1 hour has passed)&#xA;      acc -d 4000mv (do not recharge until battery voltage &amp;lt;= 4000mV)&#xA;&#xA;  -D|--daemon   Print daemon status, (and if running) version and PID&#xA;    e.g., acc -D (alias: &#34;accd,&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;  -D|--daemon [start|stop|restart]   Manage daemon&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -D start (alias: accd)&#xA;      acc -D restart (alias: accd)&#xA;      accd -D stop (alias: &#34;accd.&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;  -e|--enable [#%, #s, #m, #h or #mv (optional)]   Enable charging&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -e 75% (recharge to 75%)&#xA;      acc -e 30m (recharge for 30 minutes)&#xA;      acc -e 4000mv (recharge to 4000mV)&#xA;&#xA;  -f|--force|--full [capacity]   Charge once to a given capacity (default: 100%), without restrictions&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -f 95 (charge to 95%)&#xA;      acc -f (charge to 100%)&#xA;    Note: if the desired % is less than pause_capacity, use acc -e #%&#xA;&#xA;  -F|--flash [&#34;zip_file&#34;]   Flash any zip files whose update-binary is a shell script&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -F (lauches a zip flashing wizard)&#xA;      acc -F &#34;file1&#34; &#34;file2&#34; &#34;fileN&#34; ... (install multiple zips)&#xA;      acc -F &#34;/sdcard/Download/Magisk-v20.0(20000).zip&#34;&#xA;&#xA;  -i|--info [case insensitive egrep regex (default: &#34;.&#34;)]   Show battery info&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -i&#xA;      acc -i volt&#xA;      acc -i &#39;volt\|curr&#39;&#xA;&#xA;  -l|--log [-a|--acc] [editor] [editor_opts]   Print/edit accd log (default) or acc log (-a|--acc)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -l (same as acc -l less)&#xA;      acc -l rm&#xA;      acc -l -a cat&#xA;      acc -l grep &#39;: &#39; (show explicit errors only)&#xA;&#xA;  -la   Same as -l -a&#xA;&#xA;  -l|--log -e|--export   Export all logs to /sdcard/Download/acc-logs-$deviceName.tgz&#xA;    e.g., acc -l -e&#xA;&#xA;  -le   Same as -l -e&#xA;&#xA;  -n|--notif [[&#34;STRING&#34; (default: &#34;:)&#34;)] [USER ID (default: 2000 (shell))]]   Post Android notification; may not work on all systems&#xA;    e.g., acc -n &#34;Hello, World!&#34;&#xA;&#xA;  -p|--parse [&amp;lt;base file&amp;gt; &amp;lt;file to parse&amp;gt;] | &amp;lt;file to parse&amp;gt;]   Helps find potential charging switches quickly, for any device&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -p   Parse /logs/power_supply-\*.log and print potential charging switches not present in /ch-switches&#xA;      acc -p /sdcard/power_supply-harpia.log   Parse the given file and print potential charging switches that are not already in /ch-switches&#xA;      acc -p /sdcard/charging-switches.txt /sdcard/power_supply-harpia.log   Parse /sdcard/power_supply-harpia.log and print potential charging switches absent from /sdcard/charging-switches.txt&#xA;&#xA;  -r|--readme [editor] [editor_opts]   Print/edit README.md&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -r (same as acc -r less)&#xA;      acc -r cat&#xA;&#xA;  -R|--resetbs   Reset battery stats&#xA;    e.g., acc -R&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set   Print current config&#xA;    e.g., acc -s&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set prop1=value &#34;prop2=value1 value2&#34;   Set [multiple] properties&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -s charging_switch=&#xA;      acc -s pause_capacity=60 resume_capacity=55 (shortcuts: acc -s pc=60 rc=55, acc 60 55)&#xA;      acc -s &#34;charging_switch=battery/charging_enabled 1 0&#34; resume_capacity=55 pause_capacity=60&#xA;    Note: all properties have short aliases for faster typing; run &#34;acc -c cat&#34; to see them&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set c|--current [milliamps|-]   Set/print/restore_default max charging current (range: 0-9999 Milliamps)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -s c (print current limit)&#xA;      acc -s c 500 (set)&#xA;      acc -s c - (restore default)&#xA;&#xA;  -sc [milliamps|-]   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set l|--lang   Change language&#xA;    e.g., acc -s l&#xA;&#xA;  -sl   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set d|--print-default [egrep regex (default: &#34;.&#34;)]   Print default config without blank lines&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -s d (print entire defaul config)&#xA;      acc -s d cap (print only entries matching &#34;cap&#34;)&#xA;&#xA;  -sd [egrep regex (default: &#34;.&#34;)]   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set p|--print [egrep regex (default: &#34;.&#34;)]   Print current config without blank lines (refer to previous examples)&#xA;&#xA;  -sp [egrep regex (default: &#34;.&#34;)]   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set r|--reset [a]   Restore default config (&#34;a&#34; is for &#34;all&#34;: config and control file blacklists, essentially a hard reset)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -s r&#xA;&#xA;  -sr [a]   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set s|charging_switch   Enforce a specific charging switch&#xA;    e.g., acc -s s&#xA;&#xA;  -ss    Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set s:|chargingSwitch:   List known charging switches&#xA;    e.g., acc -s s:&#xA;&#xA;  -ss:   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -s|--set v|--voltage [millivolts|-] [--exit]   Set/print/restore_default max charging voltage (range: 3700-4300 Millivolts)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -s v (print)&#xA;      acc -s v 3900 (set)&#xA;      acc -s v - (restore default)&#xA;      acc -s v 3900 --exit (stop the daemon after applying settings)&#xA;&#xA;  -sv [millivolts|-] [--exit]   Same as above&#xA;&#xA;  -t|--test [ctrl_file1 on off [ctrl_file2 on off]]   Test custom charging switches&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -t battery/charging_enabled 1 0&#xA;      acc -t /proc/mtk_battery_cmd/current_cmd 0::0 0::1 /proc/mtk_battery_cmd/en_power_path 1 0 (&#34;::&#34; is a placeholder for &#34; &#34; - MTK only)&#xA;&#xA;  -t|--test [file]   Test charging switches from a file (default: /ch-switches)&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -t (test known switches)&#xA;      acc -t /sdcard/experimental_switches.txt (test custom/foreign switches)&#xA;&#xA;  -t|--test [p|parse]   Parse potential charging switches from the power supply log (as &#34;acc -p&#34;), test them all, and add the working ones to the list of known switches&#xA;    Implies -x, as acc -x -t p&#xA;    e.g., acc -t p&#xA;&#xA;  -T|--logtail   Monitor accd log (tail -F)&#xA;    e.g., acc -T&#xA;&#xA;  -u|--upgrade [-c|--changelog] [-f|--force] [-k|--insecure] [-n|--non-interactive]   Online upgrade/downgrade&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -u dev (upgrade to the latest dev version)&#xA;      acc -u (latest version from the current branch)&#xA;      acc -u master^1 -f (previous stable release)&#xA;      acc -u -f dev^2 (two dev versions below the latest dev)&#xA;      acc -u v2020.4.8-beta --force (force upgrade/downgrade to v2020.4.8-beta)&#xA;      acc -u -c -n (if update is available, prints version code (integer) and changelog link)&#xA;      acc -u -c (same as above, but with install prompt)&#xA;&#xA;  -U|--uninstall   Completely remove acc and AccA&#xA;    e.g., acc -U&#xA;&#xA;  -v|--version   Print acc version and version code&#xA;    e.g., acc -v&#xA;&#xA;  -w#|--watch#   Monitor battery uevent&#xA;    e.g.,&#xA;      acc -w (update info every 3 seconds)&#xA;      acc -w0.5 (update info every half a second)&#xA;      acc -w0 (no extra delay)&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Exit Codes&#xA;&#xA;  0. True/success&#xA;  1. False or general failure&#xA;  2. Incorrect command syntax&#xA;  3. Missing busybox binary&#xA;  4. Not running as root&#xA;  5. Update available (&#34;--upgrade&#34;)&#xA;  6. No update available (&#34;--upgrade&#34;)&#xA;  7. Failed to disable charging&#xA;  8. Daemon already running (&#34;--daemon start&#34;)&#xA;  9. Daemon not running (&#34;--daemon&#34; and &#34;--daemon stop&#34;)&#xA;  10. All charging switches fail (--test)&#xA;  11. Current (mA) out of 0-9999 range&#xA;  12. Initialization failed&#xA;  13. Failed to lock /acc.lock&#xA;  14. ACC won&#39;t initialize, because the Magisk module disable flag is set&#xA;  15. Idle mode is supported (--test)&#xA;  16. Failed to enable charging (--test)&#xA;&#xA;  Logs are exported automatically (&#34;--log --export&#34;) on exit codes 1, 2 and 7.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Tips&#xA;&#xA;  Commands can be chained for extended functionality.&#xA;    e.g., charge for 30 minutes, pause charging for 6 hours, charge to 85% and restart the daemon&#xA;    acc -e 30m &amp;amp;&amp;amp; acc -d 6h &amp;amp;&amp;amp; acc -e 85 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; accd&#xA;  One can take advantage of one-line scripts and the built-in &#34;at&#34; function to schedule profiles (refer back to -c|--config).&#xA;&#xA;  Sample profile&#xA;    acc -s pc=60 mcc=500 mcv=3900&#xA;      This keeps battery capacity between 55-60%, limits charging current to 500 mA and voltage to 3900 millivolts.&#xA;      It&#39;s great for nighttime and &#34;forever-plugged&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;  Refer to acc -r (or --readme) for the full documentation (recommended)&#xA;&#xA;#/TC#&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;PLUGINS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those are scripts that override functions and some global variables. They should be placed in &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/plugins/&lt;/code&gt;. Files are sorted and sourced. Filenames shall not contain spaces. Hidden files and those without the &lt;code&gt;.sh&lt;/code&gt; extension are ignored.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are also &lt;em&gt;volatile&lt;/em&gt; plugins (gone on reboot, useful for debugging): &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/plugins/&lt;/code&gt;. Those override the permanent.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A daemon restart is required to load new/modified plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;NOTES/TIPS FOR FRONT-END DEVELOPERS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Basics&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC does not require Magisk. Any root solution is fine.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca&lt;/code&gt; instead of regular &lt;code&gt;acc&lt;/code&gt;. It&#39;s optimized for front-ends, guaranteed to be readily available after installation/upgrades and significantly faster than its &lt;code&gt;acc&lt;/code&gt; counterpart. &lt;code&gt;acca --set prop1=bla prop2=&#34;bla bla&#34; ...&lt;/code&gt; runs asynchronously (non-blocking mode) - meaning, multiple instances of it work in parallel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It may be best to use long options over short equivalents - e.g., &lt;code&gt;--set charging_switch=&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;-s s=&lt;/code&gt;. This makes code more readable (less cryptic).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Include provided descriptions of ACC features/settings in your app(s). Provide additional information (trusted) where appropriate. Explain settings/concepts as clearly and with as few words as possible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Take advantage of exit codes. Refer back to &lt;code&gt;SETUP/USAGE &amp;gt; [Terminal Commands](#terminal-commands) &amp;gt; Exit Codes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Installing/Upgrading ACC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This should be trivial. The simplest way is flashing acc from Magisk manager.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, &lt;code&gt;install.sh&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;install-online.sh&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;install-tarball.sh&lt;/code&gt; can be used. For details, refer back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#install-from-local-source-or-github&#34;&gt;install from local source or GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developers can also use the &lt;em&gt;updateJSON&lt;/em&gt; API. The front-end downloads and parses &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/master/module.json&#34;&gt;this JSON file&lt;/a&gt;. The format is as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{&#xA;    &#34;busybox&#34;: &#34;https://github.com/Magisk-Modules-Repo/busybox-ndk&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;changelog&#34;: &#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/master/changelog.md&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;curl&#34;: &#34;https://github.com/Zackptg5/Cross-Compiled-Binaries-Android/tree/master/curl&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;tgz&#34;: &#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/releases/download/$version/acc_${version}_${versionCode}.tgz&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;tgzInstaller&#34;: &#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/releases/download/$version/install-tarball.sh&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;version&#34;: &#34;STRING&#34;,&#xA;    &#34;versionCode&#34;: INT,&#xA;    &#34;zipUrl&#34;: &#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/releases/download/$version/acc_${version}_${versionCode}.zip&#34;&#xA;}&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Uninstalling ACC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Either run &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/uninstall&lt;/code&gt; (no reboot required; &lt;strong&gt;charger must be plugged&lt;/strong&gt;) or uninstall from Magisk manager and reboot.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Initializing ACC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;On boot_completed receiver and main activity, run:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[ -f /dev/.vr25/acc/acca ] || /data/adb/vr25/acc/service.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explanation:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC&#39;s working environment must be initialized - i.e., by updating the stock charging config (for restoring without a reboot) and pre-processing data for greater efficiency. This is done exactly once after boot. If it were done only after installation/upgrade, one would have to reinstall/upgrade acc after every kernel update. That&#39;s because kernel updates often change the default power supply drivers settings.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since acc&#39;s core executables are dynamic ([expected to] change regularly), those are linked to &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/&lt;/code&gt; to preserve the API. The links must be recreated once after boot (/dev/ is volatile).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;accd&lt;/code&gt; is a symbolic link to &lt;code&gt;service.sh&lt;/code&gt;. If service.sh is executed every time the &lt;code&gt;main activity&lt;/code&gt; is launched, accd will be repeatedly restarted for no reason.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;This &#34;manual&#34; initialization is only &lt;em&gt;strictly&lt;/em&gt; required if Magisk is not installed - and only once per boot session. In other words, Magisk already runs service.sh shortly after boot.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;ACC&#39;s installer always initializes it.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Managing ACC&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As already stated, front-ends should use the executable &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#terminal-commands&#34;&gt;terminal commands&lt;/a&gt; sections above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The default config reference has a section entitled variable aliases/shortcuts. Use ONLY those with &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca --set&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To clarify, &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca --set chargingSwitch=...&lt;/code&gt; is not supported! Use either &lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;charging_switch&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;chargingSwitch&lt;/code&gt; and all the other &#34;camelcase&#34; style variables are for internal use only (i.e., private API).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do not parse the config file directly. Use &lt;code&gt;--set --print&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;--set --print-default&lt;/code&gt;. Refer back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#terminal-commands&#34;&gt;terminal commands&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;The Output of --info&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It comes from the kernel, not acc itself. Some kernels provide more information than others.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the lines are either unnecessary (e.g., type: everyone knows that already) or unreliable (e.g., health, speed).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what one should focus on:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;HEALTH=Good # Battery health CAPACITY=50 # Battery level, 0-100 CURRENT_NOW=0 # Charging current (Amps) POWER_NOW=0 # (CURRENT_NOW * VOLTAGE_NOW) (Watts) STATUS=Charging # Charging, Discharging or Idle (Not charging) TEMP=281 # Always in (ºC * 10) VOLTAGE_NOW=3.861 # Charging voltage (Volts)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: the power information refers to what is actually supplied to the battery, not what&#39;s coming from the adapter. External power is always converted before it reaches the battery.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Profiles&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those are simply different config files. A config path can be supplied as first argument to &lt;code&gt;acca&lt;/code&gt; and second to &lt;code&gt;accd&lt;/code&gt; executables.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Copy the config:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current config: &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca --config cat &amp;gt; /path/to/new/file&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Default config: &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca /path/to/new/file --version&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;--version&lt;/code&gt; can be replaced with any option + arguments, as seen below.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit the copy:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/acca /path/to/new/file --set pause_capacity=75 resume_capacity=70&lt;/code&gt; (if the file does not exist, it is created as a copy of the default config.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Use the copy:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/accd --init /path/to/new/file&lt;/code&gt; (the daemon is restarted with the new config.)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back to the main config:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/accd --init&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;More&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC daemon does not have to be restarted after making changes to the config. It picks up new changes within seconds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few exceptions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;charging_switch&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;s&lt;/code&gt;) requires a daemon restart (&lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/accd&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;current_workaround&lt;/code&gt; (&lt;code&gt;cw&lt;/code&gt;) requires a full re-initialization (&lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/accd --init&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This information is in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; section as well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;acc -t Results Are Inconsistent&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to &#34;default config &amp;gt; batt_status_workaround&#34;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Battery Capacity (% Level) Doesn&#39;t Seem Right&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;When Android&#39;s battery level differs from that of the kernel, ACC daemon automatically syncs it by stopping the battery service and feeding it the real value every few seconds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pixel devices are known for having battery level discrepancies for the longest time.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your device shuts down before the battery is actually empty, capacity_sync or capacity_mask may help. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; section above for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Charging Switch&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, ACC uses whichever &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/raw/dev/acc/charging-switches.txt&#34;&gt;charging switch&lt;/a&gt; works (&#34;automatic&#34; charging switch). However, things don&#39;t always go well.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some switches are unreliable under certain conditions (e.g., while display is off).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Others hold a &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/lite/?q=wakelock&#34;&gt;wakelock&lt;/a&gt;. This causes fast battery drain when charging is paused and the device remains plugged.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charging keeps being re-enabled by the system, seconds after acc daemon disables it. As a result, the battery eventually charges to 100% capacity, regardless of pause_capacity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;High CPU load (drains battery) was also reported.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the worst case scenario, the battery status is reported as &lt;code&gt;discharging&lt;/code&gt;, while it&#39;s actually &lt;code&gt;charging&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;In such situations, one has to enforce a switch that works as expected. Here&#39;s how to do it:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;acc --test&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;acc -t&lt;/code&gt;) to see which switches work.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;acc --set charging_switch&lt;/code&gt; (or &lt;code&gt;acc -ss&lt;/code&gt;) to enforce a working switch.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Test the reliability of the set switch. If it doesn&#39;t work properly, try another.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since not everyone is tech savvy, ACC daemon automatically applies settings for certain devices to minimize charging switch issues. These are in &lt;code&gt;acc/oem-custom.sh&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Custom Max Charging Voltage And Current Limits&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, not all kernels support these features. While custom current limits are supported by most (at least to some degree), voltage tweaking support is &lt;em&gt;exceptionally&lt;/em&gt; rare.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, the existence of potential voltage/current control file doesn&#39;t necessarily mean these are writable* or the features, supported.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;* Root is not enough. Kernel level permissions forbid write access to certain interfaces.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, restoring the default current may not work without a system reboot. A workaround is setting the default max current value or any arbitrary high number (e.g., 9000 mA). Don&#39;t worry about frying things. The device will only draw the max it can take.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WARNING&lt;/strong&gt;: limiting voltage causes battery state of charge (SoC) deviation on some devices. The battery management system self-calibrates constantly, though. Thus, as soon as the default voltage limit is restored, it&#39;ll start &#34;fixing&#34; itself.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Limiting current, on the other hand, has been found to be universally safe. Some devices do not support just any current value, though. That&#39;s not to say out-of-range values cause issues. These are simply ignored.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If low current values don&#39;t work, try setting &lt;code&gt;current_workaround=true&lt;/code&gt; (takes effect after &lt;code&gt;accd --init&lt;/code&gt;. Refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#default-configuration&#34;&gt;default configuration&lt;/a&gt; section for details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;One can override the default lists of max charging current/voltage control files by copying &lt;code&gt;acc/ctrl-files.sh&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/plugins/&lt;/code&gt; and modifying it accordingly. Note that default limits must be restored prior to that to avoid the need for a system reboot. Reminder: a daemon restart is required to load new/modified plugins.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Diagnostics/Logs&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volatile logs (gone on reboot) are stored in &lt;code&gt;/dev/.vr25/acc/&lt;/code&gt; (.log files only). Persistent logs reside in &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/logs/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;acc -le&lt;/code&gt; exports all acc logs, plus Magisk&#39;s and extras to &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/acc-data/logs/acc-$device_codename.tgz&lt;/code&gt;. The logs do not contain any personal information and are never automatically sent to the developer. Automatic exporting (local) happens under specific conditions (refer back to &lt;code&gt;SETUP/USAGE &amp;gt; Terminal Commands &amp;gt; Exit Codes&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Install, Upgrade, Stop and Restart Processes Seem to Take Too Long&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The daemon stop process implies complete reversal of changes made to the charging management system. Sometimes, &lt;strong&gt;this requires the charger to be plugged&lt;/strong&gt;. That&#39;s because some devices have kernel bugs and/or bad charging driver implementations. That said, accd is always stopped &lt;em&gt;gracefully&lt;/em&gt; to ensure the restoration takes place. One who knows what they&#39;re doing, can force-stop accd by running &lt;code&gt;pkill -9 -f accd&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Kernel Panic and Spontaneous Reboots&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Control files that trigger these are automatically backlisted (commented out in &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/acc-data/logs/write.log&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Restore Default Config&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This can potentially save a lot of time and grief.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;acc --set --reset&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;acc -sr&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;rm /data/adb/vr25/acc-data/config.txt&lt;/code&gt; (failsafe)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Samsung, Charging &lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt; Stops at 70% Capacity&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a device-specific issue (by design?). It&#39;s caused by the &lt;em&gt;store_mode&lt;/em&gt; charging control file. Switch to &lt;em&gt;batt_slate_mode&lt;/em&gt; to prevent it. Refer back to &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#charging-switch&#34;&gt;charging switch&lt;/a&gt; above for details on that.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Slow Charging&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;At least one of the following may be the cause:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Charging current and/or voltage limits&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Cooldown cycle (non optimal charge/pause ratio, try 50/10 or 50/5)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Troublesome charging switch (refer back to &lt;code&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING &amp;gt; Charging Switch&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Weak adapter and/or power cord&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unable to Charge&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer back to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#warnings&#34;&gt;warnings&lt;/a&gt; section above.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Unexpected Reboots&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wrong/troublesome charging control files may trigger unwanted reboots. ACC blacklist some of these automatically (registered in &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/logs/write.log&lt;/code&gt;, with a leading hashtag). Sometimes, there may be false positives in there - i.e., due to unexpected reboots caused by something else. Thus, if a control file that used to work, suddenly does not, see if it was blacklisted (&lt;code&gt;acc -t&lt;/code&gt; also reveals blacklisted switches). Send &lt;code&gt;write.log&lt;/code&gt; to the developer once the reboots have stopped.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;WARP, VOOC and Other Fast Charging Tech&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Charging switches may not work reliably with the original power adapter. This has nothing to do with acc. It&#39;s bad design by the OEMs themselves. If you face issues, either try a different charging switch or a regular power brick (a.k.a., slow charger). You may also want to try stopping charging by limiting current/voltage.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Why Did accd Stop?&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;acc -l tail&lt;/code&gt; to find out. This will print the last 10 lines of the daemon log file.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A relatively common exit code is &lt;code&gt;7&lt;/code&gt; - meaning all charging switches failed to disable charging. It happens due to kernel issues (refer to the previous subsection - &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/VR-25/acc/dev/#charging-switch&#34;&gt;charging switch&lt;/a&gt;). The daemon only stops due to this if acc is set to automatically determine the switches to use (default behavior). Manually setting a working switch with &lt;code&gt;acc -ss&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;acc -s s=&#34;SWITCHES GO HERE --&#34;&lt;/code&gt; disables auto mode and prevents accd from stopping if the set the charging switches fail.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;POWER SUPPLY LOGS (HELP NEEDED)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please run &lt;code&gt;acc -le&lt;/code&gt; and upload &lt;code&gt;/data/adb/vr25/acc-data/logs/power_supply-*.log&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/request/WYVDyCc0GkKQ8U5mLNlH&#34;&gt;my dropbox&lt;/a&gt; (no account/sign-up required). This file contains invaluable power supply information, such as battery details and available charging control files. A public database is being built for mutual benefit. Your cooperation is greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy Notes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Name: random/fake&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Email: random/fake&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;See current submissions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/rolzxvqxtdkfvfa/AABceZM3BBUHUykBqOW-0DYIa?dl=0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LOCALIZATION&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently Supported Languages and Translation Levels (default, full, good, fair, minimal)&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chinese, simplified (zh-rCN): minimal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Chinese, traditional (zh-rTW): minimal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;English (en): default&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;French (fr): good&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;German (de_DE): fair&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Indonesia (id): minimal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Portuguese, Portugal (pt-PT): minimal&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Turkish (tr): good&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translation Notes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Start with copies of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/raw/dev/acc/strings.sh&#34;&gt;acc/strings.sh&lt;/a&gt; and, optionally, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc/raw/dev/README.md&#34;&gt;README.md&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Modify the header of strings.sh to reflect the translation (e.g., # Español (es)).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anyone is free and encouraged to open translation &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/lite/?q=pull+request&#34;&gt;pull requests&lt;/a&gt;. Alternatively, a &lt;em&gt;compressed&lt;/em&gt; archive of translated &lt;code&gt;strings.sh&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;README.md&lt;/code&gt; files can be sent to the developer via Telegram (link below).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;acc -sl&lt;/code&gt; (--set --lang): language switching wizard or &lt;code&gt;acc -s l=&amp;lt;lang_string&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; to set a language.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;TIPS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always&lt;/em&gt; Limit the Charging Current If Your Battery is Old and/or Tends to Discharge Too Fast&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This extends the battery&#39;s lifespan and may even &lt;em&gt;reduce&lt;/em&gt; its discharge rate.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;750-1000mA is a good range for regular use.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;500mA is a comfortable minimum - and also very compatible.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your device does not support custom current limits, use a dedicated (&#34;slow&#34;) power adapter.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Current and Voltage Based Charging Control&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enabled by setting charging_switch=milliamps or charging_switch=3700-4300 (millivolts) (e.g., &lt;code&gt;acc -s s=0&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;acc -s s=250&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;acc -s s=3900&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;acc -ss&lt;/code&gt; (wizard)).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Essentially, this turns current/voltage control files into &lt;em&gt;[pseudo] charging switches&lt;/em&gt;. Alternatively, one can set a specific current or voltage regulator as charging switch (e.g., acc -s s=&#34;battery/current_max 3000000 0&#34;).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: depending on the device - at &lt;code&gt;pause_capacity&lt;/code&gt;, the charging status may either change (&#34;Discharging&#34; or &#34;Idle&#34; (&#34;Not charging&#34;) or remain still (&#34;Charging&#34; -- not an issue).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Generic&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Force fast charge: &lt;code&gt;appy_on_boot=&#34;/sys/kernel/fast_charge/force_fast_charge::1::0 usb/boost_current::1::0 charger/boost_current::1::0&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Google Pixel Devices&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Force fast wireless charging with third party wireless chargers that are supposed to charge the battery faster: &lt;code&gt;apply_on_plug=wireless/voltage_max::9000000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may not work on all Pixel devices. There are no negative consequences when it doesn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Override Battery mAh Capacity&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;An &#34;extended&#34; battery won&#39;t change fully if the kernel still has the stock &lt;code&gt;charge_full_design&lt;/code&gt; value. Some devices allow that to be modified. If that&#39;s the case for you, use &lt;code&gt;apply_on_boot&lt;/code&gt; to set the desired value(s) in &lt;code&gt;/sys/class/power_supply/*/charge_full_design&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h3&gt;Override Broken Temperature Sensor&lt;/h3&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your battery&#39;s thermistor always reports a negative value, and charging is very slow or even off, see if the following helps:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &#39;: ; if ${isAccd:-false} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; online; then (for i in */temp_cool */temp_cold; do [ -f $i ] || continue; chown 0:0 $i; chmod 0644 $i; echo &#34;-999&#34; &amp;gt; $i; done); fi || :&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $(acca -c echo)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;FREQUENTLY ASKED QUESTIONS (FAQ)&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;How do I report issues?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open issues on GitHub or contact the developer on Facebook, Telegram (preferred) or XDA (links below). Always provide as much information as possible. Attach &lt;code&gt;/sdcard/Download/acc-logs-*.tgz&lt;/code&gt; - generated by &lt;code&gt;acc -le&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;right after&lt;/em&gt; the problem occurs. Refer back to &lt;code&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING &amp;gt; Diagnostics/Logs&lt;/code&gt; for additional details.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Why won&#39;t you support my device? I&#39;ve been waiting for ages!&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Firstly, have some extra patience! Secondly, several systems don&#39;t have intuitive charging control files; I have to dig deeper - and oftentimes, improvise; this takes time and effort. Lastly, some systems don&#39;t support custom charging control at all; in such cases, you have to keep trying different kernels and uploading the respective power supply logs. Refer back to &lt;code&gt;POWER SUPPLY LOGS (HELP NEEDED)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Why, when and how should I calibrate the battery manager?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;With modern battery management systems, that&#39;s generally unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, if your battery is underperforming, you may want to try the procedure described at &lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-603-how-to-calibrate-a-smart-battery&#34;&gt;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-603-how-to-calibrate-a-smart-battery&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC automatically optimizes system performance and battery utilization, by forcing &lt;code&gt;bg-dexopt-job&lt;/code&gt; on daemon [re]start, once after boot, if charging and uptime &amp;gt;= 900 seconds.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;I set voltage to 4080 mV and that corresponds to just about 75% charge. But is it typically safer to let charging keep running, or to have the circuits turn on and shut off between defined percentage levels repeatedly?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not much about which method is safer. It&#39;s specifically about electron stability: optimizing the pressure (voltage) and current flow.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;As long as you don&#39;t set a voltage limit higher than 4200 mV, and don&#39;t leave the device plugged in for extended periods of time, you&#39;re good with that limitation alone. Otherwise, the other option is actually more beneficial - since it mitigates high pressure (voltage) exposure/time to a greater extent. If you use both, simultaneously - you get the best of both worlds. On top of that, if you enable the cooldown cycle, it&#39;ll give you even more benefits.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered why lithium ion batteries aren&#39;t sold fully charged? They&#39;re usually ~40-60% charged. Why is that? Keeping a battery fully drained, almost fully drained or 70%+ charged for a long times, leads to significant (permanent) capacity loss&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Putting it all together in practice...&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Night/heavy-duty/forever-plugged profile: keep capacity within 40-60% (e.g., acc 50 45) and/or voltage around ~3900 mV&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Day/regular profile: max capacity: 75-80% and/or voltage no higher than 4100 mV&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Travel profile: capacity up to 95% and/or voltage no higher than 4200 mV&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-808-how-to-prolong-lithium-based-batteries/&#34;&gt;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-808-how-to-prolong-lithium-based-batteries/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t really understand what the &#34;-f|--force|--full [capacity]&#34; is meant for.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consider the following situation:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;You&#39;re almost late for an important event. You recall that I stole your power bank and sold it on Ebay. You need your device and a good battery backup. The event will take the whole day and you won&#39;t have access to an external power supply in the middle of nowhere. You need your battery charged fast and as much as possible. However, you don&#39;t want to modify ACC config nor manually stop/restart the daemon.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Do I have to install/upgrade both ACC and AccA?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To really get out of this dilemma, you have to understand what ACC and AccA essentially are.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;ACC is a Android program that controls charging. It can be installed as an app (e.g., AccA) module, Magisk module or standalone software. Its installer determines the installation path/variant. The user is given the power to override that.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;A plain text file holds the program&#39;s configuration. It can be edited with any root text editor. ACC has a command line interface (CLI) - which in essence is a set of Application Programing Interfaces (APIs). The main purpose of a CLI/API is making difficult tasks ordinary.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;AccA is a graphical user interface (GUI) for the ACC command line. The main purpose of a GUI is making ordinary tasks simpler. AccA ships with a version of ACC that is automatically installed when the app is first launched.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;That said, it should be pretty obvious that ACC is like a fully autonomous car that also happens to have a steering wheel and other controls for a regular driver to hit a tree. Think of AccA as a robotic driver that often prefers hitting people over trees. Due to extenuating circumstances, that robot may not be upgraded as frequently as the car. Upgrading the car regularly makes the driver happier - even though I doubt it has any emotion to speak of. The back-end can be upgraded by flashing the latest ACC zip. However, unless you have a good reason to do so, don&#39;t fix what&#39;s not broken.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;Does acc work also when Android is off?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;No, but this possibility is being explored. Currently, it does work in recovery mode, though.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;I have this wakelock as soon as charging is disabled. How do I deal with it?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The best solution is enforcing a charging switch that doesn&#39;t trigger a wakelock. Refer back to &lt;code&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING &amp;gt; Charging Switch&lt;/code&gt;. A common workaround is having &lt;code&gt;resume_capacity = pause_capacity - 1&lt;/code&gt;. e.g., resume_capacity=74, pause_capacity=75.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;What&#39;s idle mode, and how do I set it up?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the ability of running off the charger. The battery behaves as if it were physically disconnected from the device. The primary indicator of idle mode is charging current around 0 mA. One can customize idleThreshold (absolute value).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Idle mode is great for extended device use (e.g., GPS navigation, gaming, server). Use it when the charger must be plugged for a long time (or permanently).&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT: lithium batteries have the longest lifespan when kept about 40-60% charged (about 3.7-3.9ish Volts). That said, try not to use idle mode above 60% too often.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not all devices support the &#34;native&#34; idle mode. Hence, variants of &#34;emulated&#34; idle mode are available:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ol&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Limit the charging voltage (requires kernel support) to a value that gets you close to the desired battery level. To avoid false positives, determine the value only after the device has been unplugged for a minute or so.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Pause/resume charging based on voltage thresholds (e.g., acc 3900 keeps voltage within 3850 and 3900 millivolts).&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;Set resume_capacity to (pause_capacity - 1), e.g., acc 50 49.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ol&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Notes&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In idle mode, the battery does discharge, although very slowly. The same happens to a battery that is sitting on a shelf.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt;In emulated idle mode, the battery tends to hold its charge, since it works as a &#34;passthrough&#34; device. Imagine pouring water into a glass that is already full.&lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; &#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt; &#xA; &lt;p&gt;How do I enable &#34;smart charging&#34;?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Configure day and night profiles:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;acc -c a &#34;: day profile; at 6:00 \&#34;acc -s pc=75 mcc= mcv=4100; acc -n &#39;Switched to day profile&#39;\&#34;&#34;; acc -c a &#34;: night profile; at 22:00 \&#34;acc -s pc=50 mcc=500 mcv=3900; acc -n &#39;Switched to night profile&#39;\&#34;&#34;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;hr&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;LINKS&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;ul&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://enroll.zellepay.com/qr-codes?data=eyJuYW1lIjoiSVZBTkRSTyIsInRva2VuIjoiaXByajI1QGdtYWlsLmNvbSIsImFjdGlvbiI6InBheW1lbnQifQ==&#34;&gt;Donate - Zelle: iprj25 @ gmail . com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.airtm.com/send-or-request/send&#34;&gt;Donate - Airtm, username: ivandro863auzqg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com/cgi-bin/webscr?cmd=_donations&amp;amp;business=iprj25@gmail.com&amp;amp;lc=US&amp;amp;item_name=VR25+is+creating+free+and+open+source+software.+Donate+to+suppport+their+work.&amp;amp;no_note=0&amp;amp;cn=&amp;amp;currency_code=USD&amp;amp;bn=PP-DonationsBF:btn_donateCC_LG.gif:NonHosted&#34;&gt;Donate - Credit/Debit Card&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://liberapay.com/vr25&#34;&gt;Donate - Liberapay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://patreon.com/vr25&#34;&gt;Donate - Patreon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/vr25xda&#34;&gt;Donate - PayPal Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fb.me/vr25xda&#34;&gt;Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MatteCarra/AccA/releases&#34;&gt;Frontend - ACC App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CrazyBoyFeng/AccSettings&#34;&gt;Frontend - ACC Settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/article/bu-808-how-to-prolong-lithium-based-batteries&#34;&gt;Must Read - How to Prolong Lithium Ion Batteries Lifespan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/vr25_xda&#34;&gt;Telegram Channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/acc_group&#34;&gt;Telegram Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://t.me/vr25xda&#34;&gt;Telegram Profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/VR-25/acc&#34;&gt;Upstream Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.xda-developers.com/apps/magisk/module-magic-charging-switch-cs-v2017-9-t3668427&#34;&gt;XDA Thread&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared</title>
    <updated>2022-12-10T01:37:12Z</updated>
    <id>tag:github.com,2022-12-10:/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared</id>
    <link href="https://github.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared" rel="alternate"></link>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Connect remotely to your Home Assistant instance without opening any ports using Cloudflared.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h1&gt;Home Assistant Add-on: Cloudflared&lt;/h1&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared/releases&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared?include_prereleases&#34; alt=&#34;GitHub Release&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/project%20stage-production%20ready-brightgreen.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Project Stage&#34;&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared/main/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/github/license/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared&#34; alt=&#34;License&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/aarch64-yes-green.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Supports aarch64 Architecture&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/amd64-yes-green.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Supports amd64 Architecture&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/armhf-yes-green.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Supports armhf Architecture&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/armv7-yes-green.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Supports armv7 Architecture&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/badge/i386-yes-green.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Supports i386 Architecture&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared//actions&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared/workflows/CI/badge.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Github Actions&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.shields.io/maintenance/yes/2022.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Project Maintenance&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Connect remotely to your Home Assistant and other services, without opening ports using Cloudflare Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cloudflared connects your Home Assistant Instance via a secure tunnel to a domain or subdomain at Cloudflare. This allows you to expose your Home Assistant instance and other services to the Internet without opening ports on your router. Additionally, you can utilize Cloudflare Zero Trust to further secure your connection.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To use this add-on, you need a domain name (e.g. example.com) that is using Cloudflare for its DNS entries. If you do not have one, you can get one for free at &lt;a href=&#34;https://freenom.com&#34;&gt;Freenom&lt;/a&gt; following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/what-do-domain-name-how-get-one-free-tobias-brenner?trk=public_post-content_share-article&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared/main/cloudflared/DOCS.md&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;📚&lt;/span&gt; Read the full add-on documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please make sure you comply with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/terms/&#34;&gt;Cloudflare Self-Serve Subscription Agreement&lt;/a&gt; when using this add-on. For example &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/terms/#:~:text=2.8%20Limitation%20on%20Serving%20Non%2DHTML%20Content&#34;&gt;section 2.8&lt;/a&gt; could be breached when streaming videos (e.g. Plex) or other non-HTML content.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;To install this add-on, manually add my HA-Addons repository to Home Assistant using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias/ha-addons&#34;&gt;this GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; or by clicking the button below.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://my.home-assistant.io/redirect/supervisor_add_addon_repository/?repository_url=https%3A%2F%2Fgithub.com%2Fbrenner-tobias%2Fha-addons&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://my.home-assistant.io/badges/supervisor_add_addon_repository.svg?sanitize=true&#34; alt=&#34;Add Repository to HA&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Got questions?&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias/addon-cloudflared/issues&#34;&gt;open an issue here&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Author&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/brenner-tobias&#34;&gt;Tobias Brenner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;h2&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;MIT License&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Copyright (c) 2022 Tobias Brenner&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files (the &#34;Software&#34;), to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the Software.&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED &#34;AS IS&#34;, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>